<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-09-08T08:30:13-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-09-08T08:30:13-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-09-08T08:30:13-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="a "><ImageData src="images/2010_08_31_ML102510153_img_0.jpg"/>a </Figure>Rafael Flores Luminant Power </P><P>Senior Vice President 	POBox 1002 </P><P>&amp; Chief Nuclear Officer 6322 North FM 56 </P><P>rafael.flores@Luminant.com Glen Rose, TX 76043 </P><Part><H1>Luminant 
</H1><P>T 254 897 5550 C 8175590403 F 254 897 6652 </P><P>CP-201001010 TXX -10104 </P><P>August 31,2010 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission A1TN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>SUBJECT: 	COMANCHE PEAK NUCLEAR POWER PLANT DOCKET NO. 50-445 COMPONENT COOLING WATER TRAIN INOPERABLE DUE TO INADEQUATE POST WORK TEST PROCEDURE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT 445/10-004 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Pursuant to 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), Luminant Generation Company, LLC (Luminant Power) is submitting Licensee Event Report (LER) 445/10-004-00, &quot;Component Cooling Water Train Inoperable Due to . Inadequate Post Work Test Procedure,&quot; for Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 1 (see enclosure). </P><P>This communication contains the following new commitment which will be incorporated into the CPNPP licensing basis as noted. </P><P>Number 	Commitment </P><P>4013172 	The CCW to RHR/CS Heat Exchanger outlet valve flow control test procedure will be revised to ensure that the valves will correctly function during a P-signal or subsequent surveillance testing. </P><P>The commitment number is used by Luminant Power for the internal tracking of CPNPP commitments. </P><P>A member of the SfARS (Strategic Teanti:clg and Resource Sharing) Alliance 
Callaway . Comanche Peak . Diablo Canyon . Palo Verde . San Onofre . South Texas Project . Wolf Creek 
</P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory CommIssion lXX·10104 Page 2 </P><P>08/3112010 </P><P>Should you have any questions, please contact Gary Merka at (254) 897-6613. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>Luminant Generation Company LLC </P><P>Rafael Flores </P><P>By, </P></Part><Part><H1>~?[m~</H1><Sect><H2>,;1&lt;'re&lt;i :Madden • </H2><P>Director, Oversight &amp; Regulatory Affairs </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>c -E. E. Collins, Region IV </P><P>B. K. Singal, NRR 
Resident Inspectors, Comanche Peak. 
</P><P>NRC FORM 366 u.s. NUI,;I.;~~ n.1&quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;~ (9-2007) </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (lER) </P><P>(See reverse for required number of dlglts/c~.aracters for each b!ock) </P><P>&amp;'3~}%)-ltfD BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: </P><P>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatoiy collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch IT-5 F52), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, cr by Intemet e-mail to infocollects@r.rc.goll, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs .... ~EOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, uv 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2010_08_31_ML102510153_img_1.jpg"/>MONTH DAY YEAR 07 04 2010 9. OPERATING MODE YEAR 2010 </Figure><P>1. FACIUTY </P><P>Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </P><P>SEQUENTIAL REV MONTH </P><P>DAY </P><P>YEAR </P><P>NO. FACILITY DOCUMENT . BER</P><P>00 </P><P>08 </P><P>31 </P><P>2010 </P><P>05000 </P><P>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check a/l that apply) 20.2201 (b) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(I) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(C) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(vli) 20.2201 (d) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(viii){A) 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) 0 50.73{a){2)(ii)(8) B5O.73(a){2){viii)(8) 20.2203(a)(2)(I) 0 5O.36(c)(1)(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 5O.73(a)(2)(lx)(A) </P><P>20.2203(a)(2)(II) 0 50.36(c){1){ii){A) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(lv)(A) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(x) </P><P>20.2203(a)(2)(lII) 0 50.36(c){2) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(v){A) 0 73.71(a){4) </P><P>20.2203(a)(2)(lv) 0 5O.46(a)(3)(II) 0 5O.73{a)(2)(v){8) 0 73.71(a)(5) </P><P>20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50.73(a)(2)(I)(A) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) 0 OTHER </P><P>20.2203{a){2)(vl) [K] 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(8) 0 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(D) VOLUNTARY LER </P><P>CAUSE </P><P>SYSTEM </P><Table><TR><TH>o </TH><TH>YES (If </TH><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ONO </TH><TH>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TH><TH/></TR></Table><P>ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </P><P>On July 4,2010 during perfonnance of the Unit 1 Train B Safeguards Slave Relay K644 Actuation </P><P>surveillance test, unsatisfactory results were obtained. Operations personnel discovered that the Train </P><P>B Containment Spray Heat Exchanger 1-02 Component Cooling Water Return valve was oscillating </P><P>from 100 percent open to approximately 22 percent 0pen. Troubleshooting subsequently revealed that </P><P>an actuator rotor on this motor operated valve had been incorrectly set during the previous Unit 1 </P><P>outage. </P><P>The cause of this event was the post work test procedure did not provide specific instructions to ensure that an actuator rotor &quot;dead band&quot; was maintained after all of the rotor adjustments had been completed. immediate corrective actions included resetting the actuator rotor to the correct position and successfully performing the Slave Relay Actuation test. Long term corrective actions include procedure changes. . </P><P>All times in this report are approximate a~d Central Time unless Aoted otherwise. </P><Table><TR><TH>rr=====-.:====================================================================~ NRC FORM 366A (9·2007) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LlCENSE:E EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 05000 -445 </TH><TD>6.LER NUMBER YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3. PAGE 2 OF5</TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, us6'additiona/ copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) I. DESCRIPTION OF THE REPORTABLE EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION 10CFRSO.73(a)(2)(i)(B) &quot;Any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications.&quot; B. PLANT CONDITION PRIOR TO EVENT On July 4,2010, Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 1 was in Mode 1 operating at 100% power. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, OR COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE EVENT There were no structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start c·f the event that contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT, INCLUDING DATES AND APPROXIMATE TIMES On April 3, 2010, the 14th refueling outage began on Unit 1. During the outage, the actuator was refurbished on the Train BContainment Spray (CS) Heat Exchanger 1-02 Component Cooling Water (CCW) Return valve [E&quot;S: (CC)(V)], which is a motor operated valve (MOV). On April 21, 2010, during performance of the CCWto Residual Heat Removal (RHR)/CS Heat Exchanger outlet valve flow control test on this valve, adjustments were made to the actuator rotors. During these adjustments, one of the rotors was set incorrectly. Since the CCW to RHR/CS Heat Exchanger outle~ valve flow control test (which was the post work test procedure) did not have any specific steps to verify the position of the rotors, the incorrect rotor adjustment was not detected. On April 22, 2010, following completion of the CCW to RHR/CS Heat Exchanger outlet valve flow control test, the Unit 1 CCW system was declared operable. On April2S, 2010, at 1138 hours, Unit 1 entered Mode 4. Per Technical Specification 3.7.7, two CCW'trains are required to be operable in Modes 1 thru 4. On July 4,2010, Unit 1 was in Mode 1 operating at 100% power. At 1030 hours, the Unit 1 Train B Safeguards Slave Relay K644 Actuation surveillance test procedure was performed. This procedure satisfies part of the Slave Relay Test requirements of Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.3.2.6.2b, part of the Containment Spray Actuation test requirements of TS SR 3.6.6.6, and part of the Engineered Safety Features Actuation test requirements of the CCW System of TS SR 3.7.7.2 by verifying the operabiiity of Train B Slave Relay K644 in the Solid State Protection System. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (~2007) PRINTED ON RE~YClED PAPER </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2.00CKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIAL·I </TD><TD>3. PAGE 3 OF5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR REV NUMBER I NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>. 2010 004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (Ifmore space Is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) During the test, unsatisfactory results were obtained due to the Train B CS Heat Exchanger 1-02 CCW Return valve not opening, to the required position and a monitor light box not illuminating as expected. Operations personnel (Utility, Licensed) . discovered that the CS Heat Exchanger 1-02 CCW Return valve was oscillating from 100 percent open to approximately 22 percent open. At 1050 hours, Train B of the Unit 1 CCW System was declared inoperable. Troubleshooting subsequently revealed that one of the actuator rotors had been incorrectly set during the last Unit 1 outage. The misadjusted rotor caused the valve to oscillate from the throttled position to full open upon receipt of a simulated P-signal. On July 5, 2010, the rotor was readjusted to the correct position, the Unit 1 Train B Safeguards Slave Relay K644 Actuation surveillance test procedure was successfully reperformed, and at 2239 hours Train B of the Unit 1 CCW System was declared operable. E. THE METHOD OF DISCOVERY OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE, OR PROCEDURAL PERSONNEL ERROR Operations personnel (Utility, Licensed) discovered that the Train B CS Heat Exchanger 1-02 CCW Return valve was cycling from the mid position to 100 percent open during performance ofthe Unit 1 Train B Safeguards Slave Relay K644 Actuation surveillance test. Troubleshooting subsequently revealed that an actuator rotor on the motor operated valve had been incorrectly set during the last Unit 1 outage. II. COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURES A. CAUSE OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. B. FAILURE MODE, MECHANISM, AND EFFECTS OF EACH FAILED COMPONENT Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. C. SYSTEMS OR SECONDARY FUNCTIONS THAT WERE AFFECTED BY FAILURE OF COMPONENTS WITH MULTIPLE FUNCTIONS Not applicable -No compollent failures were identified du~ng this event. D. FAILED COMPONEI;~T INFORMATION Not applicable -No component failures were id~ntified during this event. </TH></TR></Table><Sect><H4>rr====--&lt;===================================...c=======i1 </H4><P>L_===========================~===========-'=~==============================~==~ </P><P>NRC FORM 3;.'6A (S-2007) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><Table><TR><TH>F=====:======================-=-==========================================; NRC FORM $66A (9-2007) u~s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>2. DOCKET1. FACILITY NAME f Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit,1 , 05000 -445 </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV , NUMBER NO, </TD><TD>3. PAGE 4 OF5</TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (Ifmore space Is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) III. ANALYSIS OF THE EVENT A. SAFETY SYSTEM RESPONSES THAT OCCURRED Not applicable -No safety system responses occurred as a result of this event. B. DURAT!ON OF SAFETY SYSTEM TRAIN INOPERABILITY During this event, Train B of the Unit 1 CCW system was inoperable because it could not meet all of the applicable surveillance requirements during the time that the rotor was misadjusted on the MOV. Train B of the Unit 1 CCW System was inoperable from 1138 hours on April 25, 2010, to 2239 hours on July 5, 2010, a period of 1,811 hours. However, as discussed below, Train B of the Unit 1 CCW remained capable of performing its specified safety function from April 25, 2010, to July 5,2010. C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE EVENT The specified safety function of the CS Heat Exchanger 1-02 CCW Return Valve is to automatica!ly stroke from closed to fully open and then to a partially open posltion to provide a CCW flow path through the CS heat exchanger on a P-Signal. Flow balancing through the Residual Heat Removal (RHR) and CS heat exchangers is set via manually operated butterfly valves and fine tuned by automatic positioning of the motor operated heat exchanger outlet control valves. The throttled position of the CS Heat Exchanger 102 CCW Return Valve regulates CCW flow through the CS heat exchanger to avoid overheating the CCW system during a P-signal. The throttled position is determined by the CCW to RHR/CS Heat Exchanger outlet valve flow control test procedure. Flow balancing of the CCW safeguards loops in the P-Signal mode of operation is required to emmre post-LOCA operability. A minimum flow to the RHR and CS heat exchangers is required to ensure environmental qualification envelopes are not exceeded. A maximum flow is required to ensure the CCW temperature does not exceed 135 degrees F post-LOCA. The CS and RHR heat exchanger outlet valves may be fully opened during long term post accident conditions (MODES 4, 5, or 6 and when full flow through the heat exchangers is required and/or acceptable). The inlet valves of the CS and RHR heat exchangers are manua!lyoperated, normally closed butterfly valves. These inlet valves have holes in the discs which act as restrictive orifices thus, regulating CCW flow through the CS and RHR heat exchangers during accident conditions. During this event, the CS Heat Exchange.r 1-02 CCW Return Valve was OSCillating from 100 percent open to approximately 22 percent open roughly four times per minute. With the valve 22 percent open, CCW flow through the CS heat exchanger is approximately 3,450 gpm while the flow with the valve 100 percent open is approximately 7,400 gpm. 7,400 gpm is a conservative number based on the CS heat exchanger inlet and outlet valves being fully open. Ac~ual CCW flow through the CS heat exchanger during a Psignal would be smaller due to the restrictive orifices in the inlet valve. The worst case scenario would be for the motor o~rator of the CS Heat Exchanger 1-02 CCW Return </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 36SA (9-2007) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><P>, : </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATiON SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit ~ i 05000-445 </TH><TD>6. LER NuMBERI I </TD><TD>3. PAGE 5 OF5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR SEQUENTIAL REV NUMBER NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 3t?6Aj (17) Valve to fail with the valve in the full open position as this would cause a higher than anticipated heat transfer to the CCW system during a P-signal. Given ~he worst case SSltemperature of 102 degrees F and a CCW heat exchanger fouling factor of 0.00085, analysis shows that the Unit 1 Train B CCW system would have reached a maximum temperature of 131.8 degrees F. However, with the actual SSI high temperature of 95.5 degrees F, calculations show that the Unit 1 Train B CCW system would have reached a maximum temperature of 127.0 degrees F. Therefore, the Unit 1 CCW Train B remained capable of performing its safety function from April 25, 2010, to July 5, 2010, since the analyzed conditions would not have caused CCWtemperatures to rise above the design basis temperature of 135 degrees F during a LOCA. From April 25 to July 5, 2010, no events occurred requiring the Unit 1 CCW system to provide a flow path through the CS or RHR Heat Exchangers. Since at least one Train of the Unit 1 CCW System was available to perform the safety function from April 25 to July 5, 2010, this event is not reportable as a safety system functional failure per 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) and the potential safety significance is very low. Based on the above, this event had minimal safety consequences and the health and safet}' of the pubtic was not affected. </TH></TR><TR><TH>IV. CAUSE OF THE EVENT The cause of this event was the post work test procedure did not provide specific instructions to ensure that an actuator rotor &quot;dead band&quot; was maintained after all of the rotor adjustments had been completed.'\ V. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Immediate correcUve actions included resetiing the actuator rotor to the correct position and successfully re-performing the Unit 1 Train B Safegll.ards Slave Relay K644 Actuation surveillance test. The CCW to RHR/CS Heat Exchanger outlet valve flow control test procedure will be revised to ensure that the valves will correctly function during a P-signal or subsequent surveillance testing. Other similar MOV test procedures will be reviewed and revised as required to ensure that any qualified MOV test personnel can successfully execute the procedure. </TH></TR><TR><TH>VI. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS There have been no previous similar reporta.b!e events at CPNPP in the last three years. </TH></TR></Table><P>~======~================,============--====-===~==================~==========~ </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P></Sect></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>