<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-11-23T07:58:23-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-11-23T07:58:23-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-11-23T07:58:23-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="II "><ImageData src="images/2010_11_16_ML103270060_img_0.jpg"/>II </Figure>Rafael Flores Luminant Power </P><P>Senior Vice President 	POBox 1002 </P><P>&amp; Chief Nuclear Officer 6322 North FM 56 rafael.flores@Luminant.com Glen Rose, Tx 76043 </P><Part><H1>Luminant </H1><P>T 254 897 5550 C 817 559 0403 F 254 897 6652 </P><P>CP-201001468 Ref. # 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) TXX-10150 </P><P>~ovember16,2010 </P><P>u. s. ~uclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washingtcin, DC 20555 </P><P>SUBJECT: 	COMA~CHEPEAK ~UCLEARPOWER PLA~T (CP~PP) DOCKET ~O. 50-445 and 50-446 I~ADEQUATESURVEILLA~CETEST PROCEDURE RESULTI~G I~ FAILURE TO MEET TS REQUIREME~TS LICE~SEE EVE~TREPORT 445/10-003-01, SUPPLEME~T1 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Enclosed is Supplement 01 to Licensee Event Report (LER) 445/10-003-00, &quot; Inadequate Surveillance Test Procedure Resulting In Failure To Meet TS Requirements,&quot; for Comanche Peak ~uclear Power Plant (CP~PP) Units 1 and 2. </P><P>This communication contains the following licensing basis commitments which will be completed or incorporated into the CP~PPlicensing basis as noted: </P><P>~umber 	Commitment Due Date/Event </P><P>4053750 	Surveillance test procedures will be revised to verify isolation of Prior to the next the Control Room circuitry for those devices required for remote performance of SR shutdown capability on transfer of controls to the Remote 3.3.4.2 for each Unit Shutdown Panel from the Control Room. </P><P>Should you have any questions, please contact Gary Merka at (254) 897-6613. </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance </P><P>Callaway . Comanche Peak . Diablo Canyon . Palo Verde . San Onofre· South Texas Project . Wolf Creek </P><P>t: , </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission TXX-10150 Page 2 of 2 11/16/2010 </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>c -E. E. Collins, Region IV </P><P>B. K. Singal, NRR Resident Inspectors, Comanche Peak </P><P>Sincerely, 
Luminant Generation Company LLC 
</P><P>Rafael Flores </P><P>By </P></Part><Part><H1>~lfU}.Jt
</H1><P>/Fred W. Madden Director, Oversight &amp; Regulatory Affairs </P><P>&quot; </P><P>. </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2010_11_16_ML103270060_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMlc:cunl APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 8/31/2010(9-2007) Estimated burden per response to com rely with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons earned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regardin~ burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch F-5 F 2), U.S. LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Nuclear Re?culatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-000 , or br, internet e-mail to in ocollects@nrc.~ov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of In ormation and Regulatory Affairs, NE B-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC digits/characters for each block) f1:1~X not c~~~~~~t?~n~ponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the I I 1 FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 05000 445 1 OF 4 4. TITLE . Inadec uate Surveillance Test Procedure Resulting in Failure to Meet TS Requirements 5.E\lENT DATE ~ LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED DAY YEAR YEAR SEQUENTIAL REV MONTH DAY YEAR FACILITY NAME DOCUMENT NUMBER MONTH CPNPP Unit2 05000446NUMBER NO. 06 18 2010 2010 003 01 11 16 2010 FACILITY NAME DOCUMENT NUMBER 05000 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) 1..-20.2201(b) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 1 Ip 20.2201(d) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) E3 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)1= 20.2203(a)(1 ) D 20.2203(a)(4 ) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) B50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8)!= 20.2203(a)(2)(i) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)'-10. POWER LEVEL I~ 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(x) 1::1 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.36(c)(2) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) 100 :~ 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 0 50.46(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) 0 73.71(a)(5)!B 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) \X] 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) VOLUNTARY LER 12. LICENSEE CONTACT~ORTHIS LER FACILITY NAME I;;~~~;;;~;;~~/nCIUdeArea Code) Timothy A. Hope, Nuclear Licensinq Manaqer 13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH . I=AII IIRI= DF!=:CRIRFn IN THIS REPORT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT ~~~~~:LE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-FACTURER FACTURER TOEPIX 14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR D Q SUBMISSION YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) NO DATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 18, 2010, during performance of the Component Design Bases Inspection, the NRC inspectors determined that surveillance test procedure (STP) OPT-216, &quot;Remote Shutdown Operability Test&quot; was not adequate to meet the Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement (SR). TS SR 3.0.3 was entered for the affected components and risk assessments were completed which supported continued operability until such time as the STP could be verified to adequately implement the testing requirements to meet the SR or the affected components could be adequately tested. The cause of this event was due to a lack of clarity in the description for the basis for SR 3.3.4.2 in the CPNPP Technical Bases. There have been no previous similar occurrences of failure to meet TS SRs due to inadequate STPs in the past three years. All times in this report are approximate and Central Standard Time unless noted otherwise. </Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 003 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) I. DESCRIPTION OF THE REPORTABLE EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) &quot;Any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications&quot; B. PLANT CONDITION PRIOR TO EVENT On June 18, 2010, CPNPP Unit 1 and Unit 2 were both in Mode 1 operating at 100% power. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, OR COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO 'THE EVENT There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components that contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT, INCLUDING DATES AND APPROXIMATE TIMES CPNPP TS SR 3.3.4.2 requires verification every 18 months that each required Hot Shutdown Panel power and control circuit and transfer switch is capable of performing the intended function. Contrary to this requirement, the existing surveillance test procedure (STP) was not adequate to verify that capability. On June 18, 2010, during performance of the Component Design Bases Inspection, the NRC inspectors determined that surveillance test procedure (STP) OPT-216, &quot;Remote Shutdown Operability Test&quot; was not adequate to meet the Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement (SR). The STP provided a method to test the transfer of functional control from the Control Room (CR) to the Hot Shutdown Panel (HSP), but did not provide assurance that a circuit fault affecting control from the HSP would be identified. Engineering personnel (Utility, Non-Licensed) reported the condition to CR personnel (Utility, Licensed) and both units entered TS SR 3.0.'3 for the affected components and risk assessments were completed which supported continued operability. E. THE METHOD OF DISCOVERY OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE, OR PROCEDURAL PERSONNEL ERROR On June 18, 2010, during performance of the Component Design Bases Inspection, the NRC inspectors determined that surveillance test procedure (STP) OPT-216, &quot;Remote Shutdown Operability Test&quot; was not adequate to meet the Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement (SR). </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1.' FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 3 OF4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 003 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) II. COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURES A. CAUSE OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. B. FAILURE MODE, MECHANISM, AND EFFECTS OF EACH FAILED COMPONENT Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. C. SYSTEMS OR SECONDARY FUNCTIONS THAT WERE AFFECTED BY FAILURE OF COMPONENTS WITH MULTIPLE FUNCTIONS Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. D. FAILED COMPONENT INFORMATION Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. III. ANALYSIS OF THE EVENT A. SAFETY SYSTEM RESPONSES THAT OCCURRED Not applicable -No safety system responses occurred as a result of this event. B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM TRAIN INOPERABILITY The current method provided in the STP to test the transfer of functional control from the Control Room (CR) to the Hot Shutdown Panel (HSP) has been utilized since the initial licensing of Unit 1 in 1990 and Unit 2 in 1993. C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE EVENT The existing surveillances verified functional transfer capability to assure the control function did transfer to the Hot Shutdown Panel (HSP) and that the control function from the Control Room (CR) was isolated to the extent that control was not functional from the Control Room (CR). There were no safety system functional failures associated with thisevent. Based on the above, it is concluded that this event did not adversely impact the safe operation of CPNPP or the health and safety of the public. IV. CAUSE OF THE EVENT The cause of this event was due to a lack of clarity in the description for the basis for SR 3.3.4.2 in the CPNPP Technical Bases. </TH></TR></Table><P>I' </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 003 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) , V. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Engineering personnel reported the condition to CR personnel and both units entered TS SR 3.0.3 for the affected components. Risk assessments were completed within 24 hours which supported continued operability. As part of the Corrective Action Program, the CPNPP Technical Specifications Bases for SR 3.3.4.2 will be reviewed and revised as appropriate. Surveillance test procedures will be revised to verify isolation of the Control Room circuitry for those devices required for remote shutdown capability on transfer of controls to the Remote Shutdown Panel from the Control Room. VI. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS There have been no previous similar reportable events at CPNPP in the last three years. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>