<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-11-23T08:14:09-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-11-23T08:14:09-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-11-23T08:14:09-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:326812a8-c6d7-4148-ae68-3d8313c7516a</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:47aac4e8-5e7b-954e-b346-3274b5bfdd58</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>II 	Rafael Flores Luminant Power </P><P>Senior Vice President POBox 1002 &amp; Chief Nuclear Officer 6322 North FM 56 Rafael.flores@Luminant.com Glen Rose, TX 76043 </P><Part><H1>Luminant </H1><P>T 254 897 5550 C 8175590403 F 254 897 6652 </P><P>CP-201101512 Ref. # 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) Log # TXX-11124 </P><P>November 16, 2011 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>SUBJECT: 	COMANCHE PEAK NUCLEAR POWER PLANT DOCKET NO. 50-445 LICENSEE EVENT REPORT 445/11-002-00, UNIT 1 CONTAINMENT PERSONNEL AIRLOCK (PAL) DOOR INOPERABLE </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Enclosed is Licensee Event Report (LER) 445/11-002-00, &quot;Unit 1 Containment Personnel Airlock (PAL) Door Inoperable,&quot; for Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 1. </P><P>This letter contains no new regulatory commitments regarding CPNPP Unit 1. </P><P>Should you have any questions concerning this submittal, please contact Mr. Tim Hope, Manager, Nuclear Licensing, at (254) 897-6370. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>Luminant Generation Company LLC </P><P>Rafael Flores </P><P>By, </P></Part><Part><H1>42f1?/.lL</H1><P>/Fred W. Madden Director, Oversight &amp; Regulatory Affairs </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance Callaway· Comanche Peak . Diablo Canyon . Palo Verde . San Onofre· South Texas Project . Wolf Creek </P><Sect><H1>leB~ </H1><Sect><H2>0(LfL </H2><P>u.s. Nuclear ReguLatory Commission TXX·11124 Page 2 </P><P>11/16/2011 </P><P>Enclosure -LER 1-11-002-00 Unit 1 Containment Personnel Airlock (PAL) Door Inoperable </P><P>c -E. E. Collins, Region IV </P><P>B. K. Singal, NRR 
Resident Inspectors, Comanche Peak 
</P><P>Enclosure to TXX-11124 </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2011_11_16_ML11327A030_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES:10/31/2013(10-2010) Estimated burden ~er response to comply with this mandato~ collection request: 80 hours. eported lessons leamed are incorporated into t e licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments re~ardin~ burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch T-5 53), U.S. Nuclear LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e·mail to infocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Infonnation and Re~ulat0.x Affairs, NEOB-10202 ~3150-0104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Bu get, ashington, DC 20503. I a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may digits/characters for each block) ~_~~ conduct or,~~Pn~nsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the &quot;nil.&quot; 'n 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 1 05000445 1 OF 5 4. TITLE Unit 1 Containment Personnel Airlock (PAL) Door Inoperable 5. EVENT DATE E LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED MONTH DAY YEAR YEAR SEQUENTIAL REV MONTH DAY YEAR FACILITY NAME DOCUMENT NUMBER NUMBER NO. 09 17 2011 11 002 00 11 16 2011 FACILITY NAME DOCUMENT NUMBER 05000 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check al/ that apply) ~ 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 1 :: 20.2201 (d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) = 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) D 50. 73(a)(2)(viii)(B) _ 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 10. POWER LEVEL ~ 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71 (a)(4) 100 B20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71 (a)(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) VOLUNTARY LER 12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME IT~~~?1-10t.JE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Timothy A. Hope, Nuclear LicensinQ ManaQer 254-897-6370 13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH ~cn&quot;lENTFAILURE IN_'HilS REPORT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT FACTURER TO EPIX FACTURER TO EPIX 14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR D GJ SUBMISSION YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO DATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On September 17, 2011, at 2330 hours, Operations personnel were unable to pressurize the Unit 1 Containment Personnel Airlock (PAL) during a routine performance ofOPT-802A, &quot;Appendix J Leak Rate Test ofPersonnel Air-lock Door Seals,&quot; which placed the PAL in an inoperable condition. Due to the time span, approximately 36 hours, since the Unit I PAL door had been operated and closed, a violation ofTechnical Specification LCO 3.6.2, &quot;Containment Air Locks,&quot; occurred. The cause of this event was a piece oftape inadvertently attached to the sealing surface ofthe inner PAL door that prevented proper door sealing. This was due to insufficient controls in place to ensure that the PAL seals remained free of foreign material during modes 1 through 4 containment entries. Corrective actions included removal ofthe tape, satisfactory performance ofOPT-802A, and procedure revisions to prevent recurrence. All times are in Central Daylight Time, unless otherwise noted. </Figure><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 2. DOCKET 05000 </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 2 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) I. DESCRIPTION OF THE REPORTABLE EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION: Any operation or condition prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications. B. PLANT CONDITION PRIOR TO EVENT: On September 17, 2011, at 2330 hours, Comanche Peak Unit 1 was in Mode 1, Power Operation, operating at approximately 100% power. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, OR COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE EVENT There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start ofthe event that contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT, INCLUDING DATES AND APPROXIMATE TIMES: On September 16, at 0727 hours, the Unit 1 Containment Personnel Airlock (PAL) [EllS: (NH)(AL)] was prepared for personnel entry for pre-outage work and personnel began entering the Unit 1 Containment at 0738 hours. On September 16,2011 at 1609 hours, Security verified and notified the Unit I Control Room that all personnel had exited the Unit 1 Containment and the Unit 1 PAL was secured by Operations personnel (Utility, Licensed) at 1653 hours. On September 17, 2011, at 2330 hours, Comanche Peak Operations personnel (Utility, Licensed) were unable to pressurize the Unit 1 PAL during a routine performance of OPT -802A, &quot;Appendix J Leak Rate Test of Personnel Air-lock Door Seals,&quot; which placed the PAL in an inoperable condition. Upon investigation, a 10 inch piece ofyellow and black tape was removed from the inner door sealing surface [EllS: (NH)(AL)(DR)(SEAL)]. The tape had been used to demarcate a tripping hazard caused by the difference in height between the inner loading ramp and the PAL deck. The LCO was exited on September 18, 2011 at 0426 hours upon a satisfactory re-performance of OPT -802A. During the subsequent investigation ofthe event, CPNPP Engineering personnel determined that the PAL inner door was INOPERABLE for approximately 36 hours which violated the time requirements of Technical Specification LCO 3.6.2, &quot;Containment Air Locks.&quot; 16=====================================================~ </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 3 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. I </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) E. THE METHOD OF DISCOVERY OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE, OR PROCEDURAL PERSONNEL ERROR During a routine performance ofOPT-802A, &quot;Appendix J Leak Rate Test of Personnel Air-lock Door Seals,&quot; Maintenance personnel (Utility, Non-licensed) discovered a 10 inch piece oftape on the inner door sealing surface. II. COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURES A. CAUSE OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. B. FAILURE MODE, MECHANISM, AND EFFECTS OF EACH FAILED COMPONENT Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. C. SYSTEMS OR SECONDARY FUNCTIONS THAT WERE AFFECTED BY FAILURE OF COMPONENTS WITH MULTIPLE FUNCTIONS Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. D. FAILED COMPONENT INFORMATION Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. III. ANALYSIS OF THE EVENT A. SAFETY SYSTEM RESPONSES THAT OCCURRED Not applicable -No safety system responses occurred as a result ofthis event. B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM TRAIN INOPERABILITY The Unit 1 Containment Personnel Airlock inner door would not have been able to perform its safety function and was inoperable from September 16, 2011, 1653 to September 18, 2011, 0426, a total ofapproximately 36 hours. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 4 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR 1 SEQUENTIAL J NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE EVENT Containment airlocks form part ofthe containment pressure boundary and provide a means for personnel access during all MODES ofoperation. On both air locks, doors are interlocked to prevent simultaneous opening. During periods when containment is not required to be OPERABLE, the door interlock mechanism may be disabled, allowing both doors ofan air lock to remain open for extended periods when frequent containment entry is necessary. Each airlock door has been designed and tested to certify its ability to withstand a pressure in excess ofthe maximum expected pressure following a Design Basis Accident (DBA) in containment. As such, closure ofa single door supports containment OPERABILITY. The DBAs that result in a release ofradioactive material within containment are a loss of coolant accident (LOCA) and a rod ejection accident. In the analysis ofeach ofthese accidents, it is assumed that containment is OPERABLE such that release offission products to the environment is controlled by the rate ofcontainment leakage. The containment was designed with an allowable leakage rate of0.1 % ofcontainment air weight per day. This allowable leakage rate forms the basis for the acceptance criteria imposed on the SRs associated with the air locks. During the period oftime that the Unit 1 Containment PAL inner door was Inoperable, no LOCA or rod ejection accident occurred that required the door to perform its safety function. Based on the above, it is concluded that the health and safety ofthe public were unaffected by this condition and this event has been evaluated to not meet the definition ofa safety system functional failure per lOCFRSO.73(a)(2)(v). IV. CAUSE OF THE EVENT The cause ofthis event was a piece oftape attached to the sealing surface ofthe inner PAL door due to insufficient controls in place to ensure that the PAL seals remained free offoreign material during modes I through 4 containment entries. V. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS The immediate corrective action was the removal of the tape at the time ofdiscovery, and the OPT802A was re-performed satisfactorily. Procedure STA-620, &quot;Containment Entry,&quot; will be revised to add the requirement that the last person exiting containment is responsible for verifying the PAL or Emergency Airlock (EAL) seals and sealing surfaces are clear ofany foreign material or debris prior to closing the doors during containment entries while in Modes I through 4. This procedure revision is being tracked in the CPNPP corrective action program. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 5 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) VI. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS There have been no previous similar reportable events in the last three years involving inoperable Containment Personnel Airlock doors. </TH></TR></Table></Sect></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>