<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-07-22T08:44:11-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-07-22T08:44:11-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-07-22T08:44:11-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="II "><ImageData src="images/2011_07_17_ML11203A077_img_0.jpg"/>II </Figure>Rafael Flores Lumlnant Power </P><P>Senior Vice PreSident POBox 1002 &amp; Chief Nuclear Officer 6322 North FM 56 </P><P>rafael. f1ores@Luminant.com Glen Rose, TX 76043 </P><Part><H1>Luminant </H1><P>T 254 897 5550 C 8175590403 F 254 897 6652 </P><P>CP-201100761 Ref: 10CFR50.73 TXX-11068 </P><P>July 14, 2011 </P><P>U. S, Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATIN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>SUBJECf: COMANCHE PEAK NUCLEAR POWER PLANT (CPNPP) DOCKET NO, 50-446, LICENSEE EVENT REPORT 446/11-002-00, UNIT 2 MANUAL TRIP DUE TO HIGH STEAM GENERATOR SODIUM CONCENTRATION </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Pursuant to 10CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A), Luminant Generation Company LLC (Luminant Power) hereby submits Licensee Event Report (LER) 446/11-002-00, &quot;Unit 2 Manual Trip Due to High Steam Generator Sodium Concentration,&quot; </P><P>This communication contains no new licensing basis commitments regarding Comanche Peak Units 1 and 2. </P><P>Should you have any questions, please contact Jim Barnette at (254) 897-5866, </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>Luminant Generation Company LLC </P><P>Rafael Flores </P><P>By: </P></Part><Part><H1>/J:-;J1~</H1><P>/Fred W. Madden Director, Oversight &amp; Regulatory Affairs </P><P>Enclosure -Licensee Event Report 446/11-002-00 </P><P>c -E. E. Collins, Region IV </P><P>B. K. Singal, NRR 
Resident Inspectors, CPNPP 
</P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance </P><P>~o~ </P><P>Callaway . Comanche Peak . Diablo Canyon . Palo Verde . San Onofre' South Texas Project . Wolf Creek U ~ </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (1(]''2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digitS/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10131/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. ~orted lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and back to IndUSiI Send commenlS regarding burden estimate to the FOIAIPrivacy Section -5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 205 5-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocolieclS.resour~nrc.~v, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NE 8-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Mana~mentand Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an nformation colledlon does not display a currently vend OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct o~onsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information coli on. . </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comancbe Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER \ 05000 446 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Unit 2 Manual Trip Due to Higb Steam Generator Sodium Concentration </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR !SEQUENTlAL! REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILnY NAME NIA </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>05 </TH><TD>19 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>2011 . 2 . 0 </TD><TD>07 </TD><TD>14 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(viQ o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(II) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(lv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x)o 20.2203(a)(2)(lii) o 5O.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(II) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5)o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o SO.73(a)(2)(I)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50. 73(a)(2)(I)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILnY NAME !TELEPHONE NUMBER (IncludfI AIeIJ Code) Timotby A. Hope, Manager, Nuclear Licensing (254) 897-6370 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPiX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPiX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED DYES (ff yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) IZ1 NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten tines) On 5/1912011, at approximately 1407 hours, Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 2 was manually tripped due to higb sodium concentration in all four steam generators. Unit 2 was operating at 100 percent power at normal operating temperature and pressure when chemistry instrumentation indicated a condenser tube leak. Steam generator sodium concentrations rapidly exceeded the manual trip criteria. All systems responded normally during and follOwing tbe manual reactor trip. Tbe leak from two condenser tubes was caused by a falling object impacting tbe tube exteriors. All tubes considered to bave been susceptible to damage were examined by eddy current testing and visual exams. Leaking or damaged tubes were plugged and the unit was returned to 100 percent power once cbemistry parameters were reestablisbed witbin limits. All times in this report are approximate and Central Standard Time unless noted otberwise . </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000 466 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 002 • 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE I. DESCRIPTION OF REPORTABLE EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION IOCFRSO.73(a)(2)(iv)(A), Any event or condition that resulted in manual or automatic actuation orany ofthe systems listed in paragraph (a)(2)(iv)(B) of this section including: e IOCFRSO.73(a)(Z)(iv)(B)(I), Reactor protection system (RPS) including: reactor scram or reactor trip elOCFRSO.73(a)(2)(iv)(B)(6), PWR auxiliary or emergency feedwater system B. PLANT OPERATING CONDITIONS PRIOR TO THE EVENT On May 19,2011, CPNPP Unit 2 was in Mode 1 operating at 100 percent power. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, OR COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE EVENT There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components that contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT, INCLUDING DATES AND APPROXIMATE TIMES At 1350 on May 19,2011 a Condensate Polishing System alarm occurred on the Comanche Peak Unit 2 Main Control Board foUowed immediately by alarms from other secondary sample points including the Steam Generator Blowdown Sample Panel (SGBD). At 1357, Unit Z operators (Utility, Licensed) entered Abnormal Conditions Procedures Manual, ABN-304, &quot;Main Condenser and Circulating Water System Malfundion&quot; due to indications ofa condenser [EllS: COND] tube leak. Sodium concentration in the Unit Z steam generators [EllS: SG] increased rapidly to approximately 3000 parts per billion. In accordance with ABN-304, the Unit Z reactor was manually tripped at 1407 on 5/1912011, due to steam generator sodium concentration greater than 1000 parts per billion. All control rods fuUy inserted and both Motor Driven Auxiliary Feedwater Pumps [EllS: (BA)(P») started as expected as a result ofthe reactor trip. The Turbine Driven Auxiliary Feedwater Pump also started on receipt oflow level signals from more tban one steam generator immediately after the trip. All systems responded normally during and after the event. There were no safety consequences impacting plant or public safety as a result ofthis event. E. THE METHOD OF DISCOVERY OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE, OR PROCEDURAL OR PERSONNEL ERROR Control board indications and alarms, as weU as local cbemistry instrumentation readings alerted Unit 2 reactor operators (Utility, Licensed) to the condenser tube leak. </TH></TR></Table><Sect><H4>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</H4><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH/><TH>6. LER NUMBER </TH><TH/><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Comancbe Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 2 </TD><TD>05000 </TD><TD>466 </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>3 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>4 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>2011 </TD><TD>002 </TD><TD>00 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>O. COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURES </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>A. FAILURE MODE, MECHANISM, AND EFFECTS OF EACH FAILED COMPONENT 
Not applicable -there were no component failures associated with this event. 
</P><P>B. CAUSE OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE 
Not applicable -tbere were no component or system failures associated with tbis event. 
</P><P>C. SYSTEMS OR SECONDARY FUNCTIONS THAT WERE AFFECTED BY FAILURE OF COMPONENTS WITH MULTIPLE FUNCTIONS </P><P>Not applicable -tbere were no component or system failures associated with tbis event. </P><P>D. FAILED COMPONENT INFORMATION 
Not applicable -tbere were no component failures associated witb tbis event. 
</P><L><LI><LI_Label>III. </LI_Label><LI_Title>ANALYSIS OF THE EVENT </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>A. </LI_Label><LI_Title>SAFETY SYSTEM RESPONSES THAT OCCURRED </LI_Title></LI></L><P>Tbe Reactor Protection System (RPS) was manually actuated to initiate this event. Botb Motor D.riven Auxiliary Feedwater Pumps and tbe Turbine Driven Auxiliary Feedwater Pump started as expected as a result oftbe reactor trip. </P><P>B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM TRAIN INOPERABILITY Not applicable -No safety system was rendered inoperable. </P><P>C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS </P><P>There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components at tbe time that contributed to this event. Tbe plant responded as designed for the manual reactor trip followed by the automatic initiation ofthe auxiliary feedwater system. Tbis event is bounded in severity by tbe analysis of the loss of normal feedwater event presented in Section 15.2.7 of tbe CPNPP Final Safety Analysis Report (FSAR), which assumes conservative initial conditions that bound the plant operating range and otber assumptions wbicb could reduce tbe capability ofsafety systems to mitigate the consequences oftbe transient. </P><P>Higb concentrations ofsodium are a long term concern for steam generator tube integrity; prolonged exposure to out-of-speeifieation sodium levels could sborten steam generator tube life and increase the possibility ofsteam generator tube failure. Based on the short duration ofexposure, this event is not expected to impact nuclear safety. </P><P>Based on the above, it is concluded that the health and safety oftbe public were unaffected by this condition and this event bas been evaluated to not meet tbe definition ofa safety system functional failure per IOCFRSO.73(a)(1)(v). </P></Sect><Sect><H4>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</H4><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH/><TH>6. LER NUMBER </TH><TH/><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Comancbe Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 2 </TD><TD>05000 </TD><TD>466 </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>4 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>4 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2011 </TD><TD>002 </TD><TD>• </TD><TD>00 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>IV. CAUSE OF THE EVENT </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>The Unit 2 reactor was manually tripped due to higb sodium concentrations in the steam generators. Tbe sodium excursion was tbe result of a falling object causing tbe sudden failure of two tubes in tbe Unit 2 main condenser allowing lake water to enter the condensate system and accumulate in tbe steam generators. Tbe sodium concentration in the steam generators rapidly exceeded the ABN-304 manual trip criteria of 1000 parts per billion. </P><P>Evaluation of the condenser tubes using Sodium hexafluoride (SF6) gas and dimple plug testing identified the two breached tubes. Subsequent boroscope and eddy current testing (ECT) revealed indications the two tubes were struck by a falling object. Six additional tubes were identified to have external denting tbat did not exist at tbe conclusion of tbe previous refueling outage. All of the tube damage occurred in the same general location approximately 4.5 feet from the inlet side tube sheet. </P><P>V. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>The two ruptured tubes and six dented tubes were plugged, along with an additional seven adjacent tubes as a preventative measure. </P><P>Following the tube plugging activities, an Engineering evaluation was performed to determine the acceptability of returning the Unit 2 main condenser to service. The Unit 2 main condenser was then returned to service, secondary and steam generator chemistry restored to limits, and Unit 2 was returned to 100 percent power. </P><P>VI. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS </P><P>Tbere bave been no similar events reported from CPNPP in at least the last three years. </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>