<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-05-07T14:11:28-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-05-07T14:11:28-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-05-07T14:11:28-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:a8eb6052-2e4c-40ed-984f-89de925e9fd9</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:33b727cb-1abf-354e-a3ab-01951d61ebeb</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="II "><ImageData src="images/2012_04_30_ML12128A427_img_0.jpg"/>II </Figure>Rafael Flores Luminant Power </P><P>Senior Vice President 	POBox 1002 </P><P>&amp; Chief Nuclear Officer 6322 North FM 56 </P><P>rafael.fiores@Luminant.com Glen Rose, TX 76043 </P><Part><H1>Luminant 
</H1><P>T 254 897 5550 C 817 559 0403 F 254 897 6652 </P><P>CP-201200270 Ref. # 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) Log # TXX-12040 </P><P>April 30, 2012 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>SUBJECT: 	COMANCHE PEAK NUCLEAR POWER PLANT DOCKET NOS. 50-445 AND 50-446 UNANALYZED CONDITION DISCOVEREP FOR THE NORMALLY OPEN BATTERY ROOM FIRE AND CABLE SPREAD ROOM DOORS CLOSE ON MOMENTARY LOSS OF POWER LICENSEE EVENT REPORT 445/12-001-00 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Pursuant to 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B), Luminant Generation Company LLC (Luminant Power) hereby submits enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) 445/12-001-00, &quot;Unanalyzed Condition Discovered for the Normally Open Battery Room Fire and Cable Spread Room Doors Close on Momentary Loss of Power&quot; for Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Units 1 and 2. This event did not affect the health and safety of the public or plant personnel. </P><P>This communication contains no licensing basis commitments regarding Comanche Peak Units 1 and 2. </P><P>Should you have any questions, please contact Ms. Tamera J. Ervin-Walker at (254)897-6902. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>Luminant Generation Company LLC </P><Sect><H4>Rofae~ </H4><P>By: IfrrJeJL /Fred W. Madden </P><P>Director, Oversight &amp; Regulatory Affairs TJEW Enclosure -LER 1-12-001-00 Unanalyzed Condition Discovered for the Normally Open Battery Room Fire and </P><P>Cable Spread Room Doors Close on Momentary Loss of Power </P><P>c -E. E. Collins, Region IV Balwant Singal, NRR Resident Inspectors, Comanche Peak </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance </P><P>Callaway . Comanche Peak . Diablo Canyon . Palo Verde . San Onofre' South Texas Project . Wolf Creek </P><P>Enclosure to TXX-12040 </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES:10/31/2013Estimated burden per response to comrely with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons earned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments refardin~ burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch \ -5 F 3), U.S. Nuclear Re?ulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-000 . or by' internet e-mail to in ocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of In ormation and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 445 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 6 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE UNANALYZED CONDITION DISCOVERED FOR THE NORMALLY OPEN BATTERY ROOM FIRE AND CABLE SPREAD ROOM DOORS CLOSE ON MOMENTARY LOSS OF POWER </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME CPNPP Unit 2 </TD><TD>DOCUMENT NUMBER 05000446 </TD></TR><TR><TH>03 </TH><TD>01 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>001 </TD><TD>00 </TD><TD>04 </TD><TD>30 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCUMENT NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) fa 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1 ) D 20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) B50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71 (a)(4) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71 (a)(5) D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) VOLUNTARY LER </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Timothy A. Hope, Manager Nuclear Licensing 254-897-6370 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>I:~k ',:,' </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED D GJYES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines On 3/1/2012, at 1353 hours, an issue was identified with the doors for the safety related battery rooms and their normal position. Several doors to the battery rooms are held open via electromagnetic door devices. At the time, it was thought that there was no uninterruptible power to the door mechanisms, and that all the doors are expected to close in the event of a loss of offsite power (LOOP). Inadvertent closure of the doors following a momentary loss of power prevents their design function of venting hydrogen from the battery rooms and providing tornado venting pathways in the building. Compensatory measures were taken to secure the doors open to maintain the hydrogen purging and tomado venting functions. A roving fire watch was implemented to comply with the fire protection function of the doors. As an extent of condition on 3/12/12, the cable spread room (CSR) doors were also identified to utilize the same design and electrical supply configuration as the battery room doors. The CSR is located above the battery rooms in the Electric and Control (E&amp;C) Building. Contingency actions were put in place to secure the CSR doors open and implement a fire impairment in the event of a tornado risk. On 4/11/12, it was discovered that the battery room and CSR doors have small battery backup units which could sustain the doors with adequate power to maintain their position for 45 seconds sufficient to allow AC power to be restored through the Emergency Diesel Generators (EDGs) during a tornado. However, the backup units were found to be in a state of degradation, challenging the ability of the backup batteries to maintain their power supply to the door hold-open devices during a tornado even!. No recent preventive maintenance work orders exist for the inspection or replacement of these units. There were no actual safety consequences impacting the plant or public safety as a result of these events. The cause was a design process legacy issue, and current design processes are significantly different from those in place during early operation of CPNPP. The specific conditions have been addressed in the corrective action program and, along with current programs and practices, are adequate to prevent future occurrences. All times in this report are approximate and Central Time unless noted otherwise. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) UCENSEEEVENTREPORT (LE~ CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 2 OF6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. I </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) I. DESCRIPTION OF THE REPORTABLE EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION: This event is reportable per 1 OCFR50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) as any event or condition that resulted in an unanalyzed condition that significantly degraded plant safety. B. PLANT CONDITION PRIOR TO EVENT: On March 1, 2012, Units 1 and 2 were both in Mode 1 operating at 100% power prior to the battery door event. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, OR COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE EVENT There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components that contributed to these events. D.NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT, INCLUDING DATES AND APPROXIMATE TIMES: On March 1, 2012, at 1353 hours, an issue was identified by engineering (Utility, Nonlicensed) with the doors [EllS: (DR)] for the safety related battery rooms and their normal position. Several doors to the battery rooms were found to be held open via electromagnetic door devices. These hold-open devices utilize an electromagnetic lock, which requires a continuous supply of low voltage direct current (DC) power to generate the magnetic forces restraining the doors in the open position. Inadvertent closure of the doors following a momentary loss of power could prevent their design function fulfillment. Door closure is required in response to a fire detection and protection system actuation to protect the battery rooms from fire damage. Conversely, the doors are maintained open for the dual purposes of 1) allowing airflow into the room to support the room exhaust heating, ventilating, and air conditioning (HVAC) within the room (and credited for the removal of hydrogen accumulation), and 2) reduce differential pressures across the rooms structural surfaces during tornado events. Further research determined the hold-open devices are powered from only non-vital AC power sources [EllS: (JX)] (which is converted into DC power within the fire panel) and thought not to include battery backup protection. Compensatory measures were implemented later that day (March 1, 2012) to secure the doors open to maintain the hydrogen purging function. A fire watch was implemented to comply with the fire protection function of the doors. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 3 OF6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) As an extent of condition on 3/12/12, the cable spread room (CSR) doors were also identified to utilize the same design and electrical supply configuration as the battery room doors. The CSR is located above the battery rooms in the Electric and Control (E&amp;C) Building. Contingency actions were put in place to secure the CSR doors open and a fire impairment in the event of a tornado risk. On 4/11/12, it was discovered that the battery room and CSR doors have small battery backup units [EllS: (UJX)] which could sustain the doors with adequate power to maintain their position for 45 seconds, sufficient to allow AC power to be restored through the EOGs [EllS: (EK) (OG)] during a tornado. However, the backup units were found to be in a state of degradation, challenging the ability of the backup batteries to maintain their power supply to the door hold-open devices during a tornado event. No recent preventive maintenance work orders exist for the inspection or replacement of these units. With respect to hydrogen generation; components which are designated as non-safety nonseismic category I, cannot be credited by design to maintain their function during a design basis accident (such as a Loss of Coolant Accident concurrent with a LOOP or a seismic event). and as such the battery room doors could not be ensured to maintain their position. This would result in a 10 second loss of power to the hold-open devices assuming loss of the non-safety batteries and a diesel generator load, allowing the doors to close and challenge the hydrogen generation analysis of the room during hydrogen generating conditions. E. THE METHOD OF DISCOVERY OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE, OR PROCEDURAL PERSONNEL ERROR The battery room condition was identified by engineering on 3/1/2012 to determine if the Unit 1 and 2 fire doors for the Train A, B, and C battery rooms are equipped with electromagnetic hold-open mechanisms. The CSR door condition was identified as an extent of condition of the battery room door closure mechanisms issue on 3/12/12 in that the cable spread room doors were also identified to utilize the same closure mechanism as the battery rooms. II. COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURES A. CAUSE OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. B. FAILURE MODE, MECHANISM, AND EFFECTS OF EACH FAILED COMPONENT Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 4 OF6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. I </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) C. SYSTEMS OR SECONDARY FUNCTIONS THAT WERE AFFECTED BY FAILURE OF COMPONENTS WITH MULTIPLE FUNCTIONS Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this event. D. FAILED COMPONENT INFORMATION Not applicable -No component failures were identified during this evens. III. ANALYSIS OF THE EVENT A. SAFETY SYSTEM RESPONSES THAT OCCURRED Not applicable -No safety systems responses occurred as a result of this event. B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM TRAIN INOPERABILITY Not applicable -No safety systems were rendered inoperable as a result of this event. C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE EVENT There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components at the time that contributed to this event. In the past three years, CPNPP has never experienced a LOOP that caused the battery doors or the CSR doors to close coincident with a tornado. Compensatory measures were taken to secure the battery room doors open to maintain the hydrogen purging and tornado venting functions including a roving fire watch to comply with the fire protection function of the battery room doors. With respect to battery room hydrogen generation, computations performed show that in the most limiting safety related battery room (Unit 1, Train B) the Lower Flamability Limit (LFL) would not be reached until 113 hours at 120 degree F after closure of the doors. The adjacent non-safety rooms (Train C Battery Rooms) may reach the LFL limits earlier than the safety related counterparts on the order of 35 hours into the closure of the doors. If left uncorrected, hydrogen ignition in the adjacent rooms may potentially compromise the function of the safety related counterparts. Existing plant procedures require performance of local Shiftly Surveillances between the hours of 0630 -0930 and 1830 -2130. These Surveillances include Train A battery room and Train B battery room for each Unit. This Surveillance is applicable for any Mode of plant operation. Furthermore, normal Operator rounds which occur twice a Shift, two Shifts per day include a General Area Inspection of Trains A, B, and C battery room ventilation and equipment status. Specifically, any abnormal conditions or out-of-specification readings shall be immediately reported to the Field Support Supervisor, Radiation Waste Supervisor, or Unit Supervisor per procedure. Plant procedures also require checking battery room exhaust fans following severe weather damage from acts of nature. Additionally, guidelines require inspection of the battery room for proper room ventilation for a variety of events </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TD>NRC FORM 366A </TD><TD/><TD>U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TD></TR><TR><TD>(10-2010) </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>CONTINUATION SHEET </TD><TD/></TR></Table><P>3. PAGE</P><P>2. DOCKET </P><P>6. LER NUMBER </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME </P><P>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV</P><P>Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </P><P>05000 -445 </P><P>NUMBER NO. </P><P>2012 001 00 </P><P>5 OF6 </P><P>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) </P><P>including loss of AC power. Nuclear Equipment Operators are also trained on battery room </P><P>ventilation and the flowpath from the battery room corridor, through the battery rooms to the </P><P>exhaust fans. </P><P>Based on the above, there is a reasonable expectation that normal battery room ventilation, </P><P>which includes flow through the doors, would be restored prior to conditions being reached </P><P>that would cause the battery rooms to become inoperable based on hydrogen or </P><P>temperature concerns. </P><P>Tornado venting capabilities are only required during the event of a tornado being present in </P><P>the immediate vicinity of the plant. Actions were taken to provide for the temporary restraint </P><P>of the CSR doors open during periods of elevated tornado risks to ensure tornado venting </P><P>position is maintained and measures for the assurance of fire protection function. </P><P>With respect to battery room and CSR tornado venting, the E&amp;C Building structure is sufficiently robust such that there is reasonable expectation that the equipment inside would fulfill the specified safety functions in the event of a tornado coincident with a LOOP. </P><P>Based on the above, it is concluded that the health and safety of the public were unaffected </P><P>by these conditions and these events has been evaluated to not meet the definition of a </P><P>safety system functional failure per 1 OCFR50. 73(a)(2)(v). </P><P>IV. CAUSE OF THE EVENT </P><P>The electromagnetics were installed in August of 1983 to ensure the battery rooms were </P><P>adequately protected from the propagation of fire in the adjacent rooms and still satisfying the </P><P>HVAC requirements. </P><P>The condition leading to loss of power to the hold-open devices during loss of offsite power was identified in 1989 as non-compliant with the tornado venting analysis requirements. Corrective actions were implemented in the form of a new controller unit to the fire protection panels which utilize small battery backup unit which could sustain the doors with adequate power to maintain their position for 45 seconds, sufficient to allow AC power to be restored through the EDGs during a tornado. </P><P>However, the battery room door controller batteries were inspected on 4/11/2012, and found to be </P><P>in a state of degradation, challenging the ability of the batteries to maintain their power supply to the </P><P>door hold-open devices during a tornado event. Research into the preventative maintenance (PM) </P><P>jobs performed on the batteries indicates that no PM exists for the inspection or replacement of the </P><P>units. Without PMs, the batteries could not be ensured to perform their function under operating </P><P>conditions, resulting in a challenge to the ability of the doors to maintain their venting position. </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 6 OF6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. I </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) The cause analysis for the existing design without supporting PMs are: • the failure of the responsible engineer for the device installation to involve the cognizant individuals in the design phase as well as failure to institute changes to the design documents utilized by later tornado venting engineers which may have identified the error in LOOP protection, and . • the failure of an interdisciplinary group involved in the original installation to identify the required LOOP protection for the system. V. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS On 3/1/2012 at 1913 hours, the battery rooms were restrained and on 3/2/2012 at 1532, the fire impairments were implemented including a roving fire watch to ensure fire protection requirements are maintained. After the cable spread room doors were also identified to utilize the same closure mechanism as the battery room doors on 3/12/12 at 1714 hours, actions were implemented to provide contingencies to secure the CSR doors open and implement a fire impairment during periods of heightened tornado risk. The cause was a design process legacy issue, and current design processes are significantly different from those in place during early operation of CPNPP. The specific conditions have been addressed in the corrective action program and, along with current programs and practices, are adequate to prevent future occurrences. Existing batteries will be replaced as required and PMs will be created to inspect and replace controller panel batteries for fulfillment of tornado venting function. VI. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS There have been no previous similar reportable events at CPNPP in the last three years. </TH></TR></Table></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>