<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-01-08T11:44:34-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-01-08T11:44:34-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-01-08T11:44:34-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:a8b165d7-7f04-4c5d-84b7-fccfeff40940</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:d47556d2-429e-ea4e-a050-7afa59dfed56</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="II "><ImageData src="images/2013_12_09_ML14008A201_img_0.jpg"/>II </Figure>Rafael Flores Luminant Power </P><P>Senior Vice President POBox 1002 &amp; Chief Nuclear Officer 6322 North FM 56 </P><P>Rafael.Flores@Luminant.com Glen Rose, TX 76043 </P><Part><H2>Luminant </H2><P>T 254 897 5590 C 8175590403 F 254 897 6652 </P><P>CP-201301362 Ref. # lOCFR50.73 TXX-13176 </P><P>December 9, 2013 </P><P>u. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
Washington, DC 20555 
</P><P>SUBJECT: 	COMANCHE PEAK NUCLEAR POWER PLANT 
DOCKET NOS. 50-445 AND 50-446 
UNANALYZED CONDITION UNDER 10CFR50 APPENDIX R, 
SECONDARY FIRES FROM UNPROTECTED AMMETER WIRING 
LICENSEE EVENT REPORT 445/13-002-00 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Pursuant to 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B), Lurninant Generation Company LLC (Luminant Power) hereby submits enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) 445/13-002-00, &quot;Unanalyzed Condition Under 10CFR50 Appendix R, Secondary Fires From Unprotected Ammeter Wiring,&quot; for Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Units 1 and 2. </P><P>This communication contains no new commitments regarding Comanche Peak Units 1 and 2. </P><P>Should you have any questions, please contact Mr. Jack Hicks at (254) 897-6725. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>Luminant Generation Company LLC </P><P>Rafael Flores </P><P>By, ~r-{</P><P>ThOffiSP.M~ol Vice President, Station Support </P><P>A member of the STARS Alliance </P><P>Callaway· Comanche Peak· Diablo Canyon· Palo Verde· South Texas Project· Wolf Creek </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission TXX-13176 Page 2 of2 12/09/2013 </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>c -Marc L. Dapas, Region IV </P><P>Balwant K. Singal, NRR </P><P>Resident Inspectors, Comanche Peak </P><P>Enclosure to TXX-131 76 </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_12_09_ML14008A201_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION ~x~!fR:~~1/9M~ NO. 3150-0104(10-2010) Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments re~ardin~ burden LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch ~ -5 F 3), U.S. Nuclear Re?culatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-000 , or by' internet e-mail to in ocollects@nrc.~ov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of In ormation (See reverse for required number of and Regulatory Affairs, NE B-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information digits/characters for each block) collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC r!lY not c~~~~~~t?~nSponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Units 1 &amp; 2 05000445 1 OF 5 4. TITLE UNANALYZED CONDITION UNDER 10CFR50 APPENDIX R, SECONDARY FIRES FROM UNPROTECTED AMMETER WIRING 5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED MONTH DAY YEAR YEAR I SEQUENTIAL REV MONTH DAY YEAR FACILITY NAME DOCUMENT NUMBER NUMBER NO. CPNPP UNIT 2 05000446 10 08 2013 13 002 00 12 09 2013 FACILITY NAME DOCUMENT NUMBER 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) I~ 20.2201 (b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 1 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) @50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)i= 20.2203(a)(1 ) D 20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) B50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8)== 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)-10. POWER LEVEL I§ 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) 100 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) D 73.71(a)(5) IB 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) VOLUNTARY LER 12. IICFN!::I=F CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) TimC'+'lv A Hope, Manaaer, Reaulatorv Affairs 254-897 -6370 13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH ,.UO&lt;O CA'&quot; 'DC DESCRIBED IN THIS &quot;&lt;.U&quot; CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT Kt:t&quot;UK I CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT Kt:~~~~IXFACTURER TO EPIX FACTURER 14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR D GJ NO SUBMISSION YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) DATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 .&quot;. . 'T!&quot;v'&quot; '''v' ' lines) On October 8, 2013, during a review of industry operating experience OE 305419 regarding the impact of non-fused, Direct Current (DC) ammeter circuits in the control room, it was determined that the described condition was applicable to Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant. This resulted in a potentially unanalyzed condition with respect to 10CFR50 Appendix R analysis requirements. The original plant wiring and associated analysis for the Class 1 E batteries control room ampere indications do not include overcurrent protection features to limit the fault current. Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Units 1 and 2 were in Mode 1 operating at 100% power. The cause of this event was the original design of the DC ammeter circuits did not adequately address fire protection program requirements. Immediate corrective actions were to develop and implement compensatory measures to maintain requirements of 1 OCFR50 Appendix R. As a part of the CPNPP Corrective Action Program, a design change to include circuit protection for the cables routed from the Safety Related batteries to the control room DC ammeters will be developed and implemented. All times in this report are approximate and Central Time unless noted otherwise. </Figure><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) PRINTEO ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Units 1 &amp; 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 2 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) I. DESCRIPTION OF THE REPORTABLE EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION: 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B), &quot;The nuclear power plant being in an unanalyzed condition that significantly degraded plant safety.&quot; B. PLANT CONDITION PRIOR TO EVENT: On October 8,2013, CPNPP Units 1 and 2 were in Mode 1 operating at 100% power. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, OR COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE EVENT There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components at the start of the event that contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT, INCLUDING DATES AND APPROXIMATE TIMES: On October 8, 2013, during a review of industry operating experience OE 305419 regarding the impact of non-fused, Direct Current (DC) ammeter circuits [EllS: (EJ)(II)] in the control room of Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP), it was determined that the described condition was applicable to Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant. This resulted in a potentially unanalyzed condition with respect to 10CFR50 Appendix R analysis requirements. The original plant wiring and associated analysis for the Class 1 E batteries control room ampere indications do not include overcurrent protection features to limit the fault current. CPNPP Units 1 and 2 were in Mode 1 operating at 100% power. During the Nuclear Energy Institute Fire Protection Information Forum held on September 15-18,2013, an issue was raised both at the breakout session on Regulatory issues and the breakout session on Inspection Trends by the NRC Region III Branch Chief. The issue of concern was contained in the Davis-Besse, NRC Triennial Fire Protection Inspection Report dated May 10, 2013 and is as follows: Introduction: The following finding that affects 10 CFR 50.48 was identified by the NRC and was a violation of NRC requirements. This finding has been screened and determined to warrant enforcement discretion per the Interim Enforcement Policy Regarding Enforcement Discretion for Certain Fire Protection Issues. The inspectors identified a violation of 10 CFR 50.48(b) and 10 CFR Part 50, Appendix R, Section III.G.3 for the licensee's failure to provide electrical protection for common enclosure associated circuits to ensure that one train of systems and components is free of fire damage during a fire. Specifically, the licensee failed to provide electrical protection (Le., fuses) for the control room ammeter circuits associated with the batteries and battery chargers to prevent secondary fire due to thermal and/or arcing affects from damaged ammeter cables outside the fire area. It was recommended at the Information Forum that all plants should decide if the non-fused DC ammeter issue identified at Davis-Besse was applicable at their plants. The representatives from Comanche Peak at the Information Forum discussed the concern with the Fire Protection Consulting Engineer and Electrical Design Engineering, to confirm if this condition existed at Comanche Peak. The Electrical Design Engineer did confirm that Comanche Peak in fact does have &quot;shunt&quot; driven, DC ammeters that are non-fused; routed to the control room. Based on this information, Condition Report (CR), CR-2013-010297, was initiated and Event Notification (EN) EN# 49419 was submitted on 10/08/13, by Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP), notifying the NRC of a potentially unanalyzed condition with respect to 10CFR50 Appendix R, Section III.G.3 electrical protection requirements. In conjunction with the Event Notification, compensatory measures (fire watches) were implemented for the plant affected areas. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Units 1 &amp; 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 3 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) Additional reviews/evaluations were conducted associated with this Condition Report identifying that the exact condition reported by Davis-Besse does not exist at Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP). The plant design at Comanche Peak is such that the remote reading DC ammeters in the control room are supplied only by the negative (-) battery bus and are &quot;un-fused&quot;, or a non-protected portion of the circuit. The only identified portion of the DC circuit that originates from the positive (+) side of the battery are local shunt driven meters for the battery chargers and DC switchboards. This physical arrangement, which was incorporated as part of the original design received from vendor documentation, prevents the identical scenario of a fire in the control room spreading via the &quot;un-fused&quot; DC cables to a secondary location outside of the control room at Comanche Peak. The Apparent Cause Analysis team looked at the possibility that the condition reported by Davis-Besse might exist in other Fire Areas and concluded the following: The cables of concern from the shunts on the battery feed to each of the train A and train B switchboards of both Unit 1 and Unit 2 are not routed directly from the rooms containing the switchboards to the control room. It can be seen that both units and trains of cables follow similar routes. Both trains of cables have the same fire area routing outside the inverter rooms with the exception of train A is routed through the chiller rooms and train B is not. Review of the loads on the various DC switchboards with remote ammeters indicates that there are either &quot;un-fused&quot; circuits or circuits with&gt; 30 amp protective devices in the following Fire Zones (FZ) 50, 51,52,53,54,57,63,64. Per electrical engineering, low current «30 amp) source cables do not have sufficient energy to jeopardize the cables of concern and allow fire propagation to adjacent fire areas. However there are locations that either have high energy source conductors or &quot;un-fused&quot; source conductors. This confirms that we can potentially have a fire event and the consequential events can potentially spread the fire to unaffected fire areas. E. THE METHOD OF DISCOVERY OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE, OR PROCEDURAL PERSONNEL ERROR The unanalyzed condition was discovered by Engineering (Utility, Non Licensed) personnel during a review of industry operating experience OE 305419 regarding the impact of non-fused, Direct Current (DC) ammeter circuits in the control room. II. COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURES A. CAUSE OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. B. FAILURE MODE, MECHANISM, AND EFFECTS OF EACH FAILED COMPONENT Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. C. SYSTEMS OR SECONDARY FUNCTIONS THAT WERE AFFECTED BY FAILURE OF COMPONENTS WITH MULTIPLE FUNCTIONS Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. D. FAILED COMPONENT INFORMATION Not applicable -No component or system failures were identified during this event. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Units 1 &amp; 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 4 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. I </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required. use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) III. ANALYSIS OF THE EVENT A. SAFETY SYSTEM RESPONSES THAT OCCURRED Not applicable -No safety system responses occurred as a result of this event. B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM TRAIN INOPERABILITY Not applicable -No safety system was rendered inoperable as a result of this event. C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE EVENT Unfused Direct Current (DC) ammeter circuits in the control room is an issue that is reportable in accordance with 10CFR50.72 (b)(3)(ii)(B) as an unanalyzed condition with respect to lOCFR50 Appendix R analysis requirements. The original plant wiring design and associated analysis for the Class 1 E batteries control room ampere indications did not include overcurrent protection features to limit the fault current. In the postulated event, a fire outside the control room could cause one of the ammeter wires to hot short to the ground plane. Simultaneously, the fire causes another DC wire from the opposite polarity on the same battery to also hot short to the ground plane. This could cause a ground loop through the unprotected ammeter wiring. This event could result in excessive current flow (heating) in the ammeter wiring to the point of causing a secondary fire in the raceway system. The secondary fire could adversely affect safe shutdown equipment and potentially cause the loss of the ability to conduct a safe shutdown as required by 10CFR50 Appendix R. The cables of concern run from the shunts on the battery feed to each of the Train A and Train B switchboards to the control room. Both units and trains of cables follow similar routes through the same fire areas routing outside the inverter rooms with the exception of Train A going through the chiller rooms. There are locations in the cable routing where there are either high energy source conductors or unfused source conductors. A fire event and the consequential events could potentially spread the fire to unaffected fire areas. Should this fire propagate from one fire area to another via the cables of concern, Fire Safe Shutdown could be jeopardized. There were no actual safety consequences for this event. This is a postulated event and as such did not result in challenges to fission product barriers, control of radioactive materials, or the health and safety of the public. This event has been evaluated to not meet the definition of a safety system functional failure per 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(v). IV. CAUSE OF THE EVENT The cause of this event was the original design of the DC ammeter circuits did not adequately address fire protection program requirements. The uniqueness of the design application was not apparent and is different from standard design convention. This resulted in &quot;un-fused&quot; DC ammeter circuits being utilized in applications related to Fire Safe Shutdown (Associated Circuits by Common Enclosure) not being identified as needing specific analysis or resolution. The original issue of the Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Fire Protection Report for Units 1 and 2 on September 22, 1987, stated there was compliance with common enclosure circuits based on proper cable protection. The design and use of &quot;unfused&quot; DC ammeter circuits for both local and remote reading are not discussed in this document as they were incorporated as part of the original design documents received from the vendor. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant Units 1 &amp; 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 -445 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE 5 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) The Design Basis was not adequately considered when applying the basis to the DC shunt driven ammeters used in remote locations such as the control room due to assumptions that were made in the Fire Safe Shutdown Analysis that all DC circuits had protective devices that adequately protected the cables in the event of a circuit fault. The design convention to utilize &quot;un-fused&quot; circuits for remote reading DC ammeters is an accepted practice. In the case of the Safety Related and Fire Protection Related DC circuits, the common enclosure associated circuits, if analyzed with the appropriate rigor could have provided enough reason to deviate from standard convention. V. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Immediate corrective actions were to develop and implement compensatory measures to maintain the requirements of 1 OCFR50 Appendix R. Roving fire watch patrols were implemented for the affected fire areas. Lifting the leads on the remote reading ammeters was also identified as an option to the compensatory measures currently in place. This was not considered a viable option due to the fact that plant indication circuits are powered from this circuit as well and would not be functional. As a part of the CPNPP Corrective Action Program, a design change to include circuit protection for the cables routed from the Safety Related batteries to the control room DC ammeters will be developed and implemented. VI. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS There have been no previous similar reportable events at CPNPP in the last three years. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>