<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-11-04T09:10:15-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-11-04T09:10:15-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-11-04T09:10:15-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="II "><ImageData src="images/2014_10_20_ML14308A079_img_0.jpg"/>II </Figure>Rafael Flores Lumlnant Power </P><P>Senior Vice President POBox 1002 </P><P>&amp; Chief Nudear Officer 6322 North FM 56 Rafael.Flores@Luminant.com Glen Rose. TX 76043 </P><Part><H1>Luminant </H1><P>T 254 897 5590 </P><P>C 817 559 0403 </P><P>F 254 897 6652 </P><P>CP~201401175 10 CFR 50.73 TXX~14118 </P><P>October 20, 2014 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATIN: Document Control Desk 
VVashin~on, DC 2055~OOOl 
</P><P>SUBJECT: 	COMANCHE PEAK NUCLEAR POWER PLANT (CPNPP) DOCKEr NO. 50446 UCENSEE EVENT REPORT 446/14~005~OO, CENTRIFUGAL CHARGING PUMP INOPERABLE FOR LONGER THAN ALLOVVED BY TECHNICAL SPECIFICAnONS </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Enclosed is Licensee Event Report (LER) 446/1~005~00, &quot;Centrifugal Charging Pump Inoperable For </P><P>Longer Than Allowed by Technical Specifications,&quot; for Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 2. </P><P>This communication contains the following new licensing basis commitment regarding CPNPP Units 1 and 2. </P><P>Commitment No. 	Description </P><P>4943911 	The Centrifugal Charging Pump Main Lube Oil Pump (MLOP) couplings will be modified to eliminate the possibility of the shaft coupling pushing back on the MLOPshaft. </P><P>The commitment number is used by Luminant Generation Company LLC for the internal tracking of CPNPP commitments. </P><P>If there are any questions regarding this report, please contact Mr. Gary L. Merka at (254) 897~613 or Gary .Merka@luminant.com. </P><P>A member ofthe STARS Alliance 
Callaway. Comanche Peak Diablo Canyon. Palo Verde. WolfCreek 
</P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>u. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><P>TXX-14118 </P><P>Page 2 of2 10/20/2014 </P><P>Sincerely, 
Luminant Generation Company LLC 
</P><P>Rafael Flores 
</P></Part><Part><H1>BYM~ </H1><P>Director, External Affairs </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>c -Marc L. Dapas, NRC Region IV Balwant K. Singal, NRR Resident Inspectors, CPNPP </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02·2014) ~.,~&quot;,&quot; ..-~~ G \, j LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) ...... (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3160-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Eslimated burden per response 10 comply with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated Into the licensing process and fed back 10 Industry. Send comments regarding burden estimale to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (l·5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory CommiSSion, Washington, DC 20555-0001. or by internet e·mail to InfocoUects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, OffICe of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-l0202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budge~ Washington. DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information coUection does not display a currently valid OMB conlrOl number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Comanche Peak </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 446 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4, TITLE Centrifugal Charging Pump Inoperable For Longer Than Allowed by Technical Specifications </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACIUTV NAME </TD><TD>DOCI&lt;£T NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>8 </TH><TD>20 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>14 -005 . 00 </TD><TD>\0 </TD><TD>20 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACIUTY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TH>1 </TH><TD>D 20.2201(b) </TD><TD>D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(viQ </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2201(d) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(1) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(4) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(9) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(9) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(1) </TD><TD>o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) </TD><TD>o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>o 50.36(c)(2) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(4) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) </TD><TD>o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(9) </TD><TD>D 73.71(a)(5) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) </TD><TD>o OTHER </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) </TD><TD>[(] 50.73(a)(2)(i)(9) </TD><TD>[(] 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) </TD><TD>Specify In Abstraci below or In NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSEE CONTACT Timothy A. Hope, Manager, Regulatory Affairs </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) (254) 897-6370 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE CAUSETO EPIX y </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU· FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>B </TH><TD>CB </TD><TD>P </TD><TD>Pacific </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED DYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) [{] NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On August 3, 2014, while starting Centrifugal Charging Pump (CCP) 2-02, the CCP 2-02 Main Lubricating Oil pump (MLOP) decoupled from its drive shaft. On August 20, 2014 an evaluation was completed that determined CCP 2-02 was inoperable from July 6,2014 to August 3,2014, which exceeded the completion times ofTechnical Specification 3.5.2. During this time, CCP 2-01 was also inoperable for 1 hour 44 minutes on July 14,2014, and for I hour 4 minutes on July 18,2014. The cause ofthis event was the design of the CCP MLOP coupling requires blind fitting ofthe drive pins into the drive pin holes and does not definitively allow for postinstallation verification. Corrective actions include replacement of the CCP 2-02 MLOP shaft hub and speed increaser bushings, modification of the MLOP coupling design, procedure revisions, and Maintenance personnel training. All times in this report are approximate and Central Time unless noted otherwise. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULA TORY COMMISSION </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150·0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 </TH></TR><TR><TH>(02·2014) ~...~'&quot; .l¥\. ~ . c'\, l.. ~.... LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TD>Estimated burden per response to comply with !his mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated into !he licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to !he FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections BranCh (T·5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e·mail to Inlocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to !he Desk Officer, OffICe of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOS.l0202, (3150'()104), Offce of Management and Budget Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to Impose an Information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, !he NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, !he information collection. </TD></TR><TR><TH>1, FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Comanche Peak </TH><TD>OSOOO 446 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -OOS -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE I. DESCRIPTION OF THE REPORTABLE EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION IOCFRSO.73(a)(2)(i)(8) &quot;Any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications&quot; and IOCFRSO.73 (a)(2)(v)(D) &quot;Any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident. B. PLANT CONDITION PRIOR TO EVENT On August 3, 2014, Comanche Peak Nuclear Power Plant (CPNPP) Unit 2 was in Mode I operating at 100% power. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, OR COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRJBUTED TO THE EVENT There were no structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start of the event that contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT, INCLUDING DATES AND APPROXIMATE TIMES On August 3, 2014, Centrifugal Charging Pump (CCP) 2·02 [EITS: (CB)(P)] was started per SOP-103, Section S.S.18, &quot;Alternating Centrifugal Charging Pumps&quot;, which provides operating guidance for starting and stopping the CCPs biweekly. Per procedure, prior to startup the CCP 2-02, Auxiliary Lube Oil Pump (ALOP) was started to provide lubrication until the Main Lube Oil Pump (MLOP) generated sufficient pressure to provide lubrication to the CCP, at which time the ALOP would automatically stop. However, following startup ofCCP 2-02, the ALOP remained in operation, indicating either an issue with the ALOP controller or the MLOP. CCP 2-02 was secured for troubleshooting. The CCP MLOP drive coupling is a pin-in-hole (pin type) coupling where pins located in the MLOP side hub (driven hub) are inserted into pin holes located in the CCP side hub (drive hub). The drive hub is located at one end ofthe speed increaser low speed shaft, while the motor coupling is located at the other end of the low speed shaft. The drive hub and speed increaser shaft comprise an integral unit that is replaced as a unit; it is impossible to replace either ofthe two elements without replacing the entire unit. The drive pin holes are bored into the speed increaser shaft. All four CCPs share this design. Troubleshooting discovered that the driven hub had been pushed back onto the MLOP shaft approximately 112 inch, sufficient to allow the drive pins to disengage from the pin holes in the drive hub. Inspection of the driven hub and MLOP shaft revealed that the drive pins exhibited no wear other than at the trailing edge of the tips, the set screw was present and tight, and the shaft key exhibited two distinctly different scoring patterns: a continuous scrape of slightly greater than 1/4 inch in length, and a series of horse shoe shaped skip marks. Inspection of the drive hub revealed that the drive pin bushings exhibited no internal wear and had no grease on their inner surface, the tops of the bushings had been sheared offby the drive pins, the drive pin bushings exhibited no deformation other than the damage sustained to their tops, the drive pin holes exhibited signs of recent wear on the extreme edge of their trailing sides, and the drive hub had a shallow groove worn into it, the width of which matched the diameter of the drive pins. The CCP 2-02 MLOP driven hub and speed increaser bushings were removed and replaced and CCP 2-02 was declared operable. On August 20, 2014, an evaluation was completed that determined CCP 2-02 was inoperable from July 6, 2014 through August 3, 2014 due to the inability to successfully start the pump, or to restart the pump if it had been secured as the result ofload shedding. It was also determined that CCP 2-01 had been inoperable for I hour 44 minutes on July 14, 2014, and for 1 hour 4 minutes on July 18, 2014. Therefore, this event is reportable per IOCFRSO.73(a)(2)(i)(B) &quot;Any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications&quot; and I OCFRSO.73(a)(2)(v)(D) &quot;Any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident.&quot; </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (02.2014) NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1_ FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Comanche Peak </TH><TD>05000 446 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -005 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE E. THE METHOD OF DISCOVERY OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE, OR PROCEDURAL PERSONNEL ERROR During perfonnance ofSOP-\03, Section 5.5.18, &quot;Altemating Centrifugal Charging Pumps,&quot; Maintenance personnel (Utility, NonLicensed) detennined that the driven hub had been pushed back onto the MLOP shaft approximately 112 inch, sufficient to allow the drive pins to disengage from the pin holes in the drive hub. n. COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURES A. CAUSE OF EACH COMPONENT OR SYSTEM FAILURE The design of the CCP MLOP coupling requires blind fitting ofthe drive pins into the drive pin holes and does not definitively allow for post-installation verification. The drive hub ofthe CCP MLOP coupling is located in a recess approximately 5 inches deep. This design does not afford Maintenance personnel a means by which to definitively verify proper reassembly of the coupling. B. FAILURE MODE, MECHANISM, AND EFFECTS OF EACH FAILED COMPONENT The driven hub was pushed back onto the MLOP shaft approximately 112 inch, sufficient to allow the drive pins to disengage from the pin holes in the drive hub. The tops of the bushings had been sheared off by the drive pins, the drive pin bushings exhibited no deformation other than the damage sustained to their tops, the drive pin holes exhibited signs of recent wear on the extreme edge of their trailing sides, and the drive hub had a shallow groove wom into it, the width of which matched the diameter ofthe drive pins. C. SYSTEMS OR SECONDARY FUNCTIONS THAT WERE AFFECTED BY FAILURE OF COMPONENTS WITH MULTIPLE FUNCTIONS Reactor Coolant Pump (RCP) shaft seal cooling is supplied from the CCPs. The CCPs also serve as the high-head pumps for the Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS). In the event of a Loss Of Coolant Accident (LOCA), the CCPs inject borated water into the reactor core. D. FAILED COMPONENT INFORMA TION The CCPs are horizontal, centrifugal type pumps, model RLU, manufactured by Pacific Pumps. Ill. ANALYSIS OF THE EVENT A. SAFETY SYSTEM RESPONSES THAT OCCURRED Not applicable -No safety system responses occurred as a result of this event. B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM TRAIN lNOPERABILlTY CCP 2-02 was inoperable from July 6, 2014 through August 3, 2014 due to the inability to successfully start the pump, or to restart the pump if it had been secured as the result ofload shedding. It was also detennined that CCP 2-01 was inoperable for I hour 44 minutes on July 14, 2014, and for I hour 4 minutes on J lily 18, 2014. C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE EVENT The CCPs are part of the ECCS. The primary function ofthe ECCS is to remove the stored and fission product decay heat from the reactor core during accident conditions. During the time that CCP 2-02 was inoperable, the Residual Heat Removal and Safety Injection systems would have fulfilled their respective ECCS safety functions. Except for 1 hour 4 minutes on July 18, 2014, it was detennined that one CCP train would have been available to perfonn it's ECCS safety function. The potential unavailability of both CCPs for one hour and 4 minutes on July 18,2014 would have most likely resulted in loss of the high-pressure injection ECCS function during that interval. Specifically, had a secondary pipe break occurred inside containment (sufficient in size to generate a phase B isolation signal) concurrent with a loss ofoffsite power, then the 2-0 I CCP would have been the sole source ofRCP seal cooling_ </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Comanche Peak </TH><TD>05000 446 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. 2014 -005 -00 </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE Reactor Coolant System (RCS) pressure 'recovers' after an initial period of decrease (during which CCP 2-01 would have provided seal injection flow). Approximately 1000 seconds into the postulated accident. RCS pressure is predicted to recover to the point where operability of the alternate mini-flow valve would be demanded in order to ensure continued pump operation. As continued pump operation is required to ensure RCP seal integrity, the effective loss of CCP 2-01 under the stated conditions is conservatively considered to constitute a loss of the high-pressure ECCS function during the interval of interest. Therefore, this event is reportable per 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) &quot;Any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident.&quot; A probabilistic risk assessment of the inoperability of the CCPs found a negligible effect on core damage frequency and large early release frequency. In addition, there were no events which required an ECCS actuation during the time that CCP 2-02 was inoperable. Based on these considerations, there was no adverse effect on plant safety or on the health and safety of the public. IV. CAUSE OF THE EVENT The CCP 2-02 speed increaser low speed shaft driven MLOP coupling hub was pushed back approximately 112 inch onto the MLOP shaft, resulting in disengagement of the drive pins from the pin holes. The design of the CCP MLOP coupling requires blind fitting of the drive pins into the drive pin holes and does not allow for postinstallation verification. The drive hub of the CCP MLOP coupling is located in a recess approximately 5 inches deep. This design does not afford Maintenance personnel a means by which to definitively verifY proper reassembly of the coupling. V. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Immediate corrective actions included removing and replacing the CCP 2-02 MLOP driven hub and speed increaser bushings. The CCP MLOP couplings will be modified to eliminate the possibility of the shaft coupling pushing back on the MLOP shaft. Procedure SOP-I03 Section 5.5.18, &quot;Alternating Centrifugal Charging Pumps&quot; will be revised to ensure the ALOP stops automatically upon CCP start and procedure MSM-PO-4703, &quot;Centrifugal Charging Pump Speed Increaser Lube Oil Pump Coupling Inspection&quot; will be revised to include best CCP maintenance practices including use of guide rods, checking for grease in bushing following first fit, and locating the driven hub flush with the end of the MLOP shaft. The MLOPs for CCP 1-01, CCP 1-02 and CCP 2-01 will be inspected to verifY that the coupling hub pins are aligned with the inserts and that the I\1LOP coupling hubs are positioned near the end of the MLOP shafts. Maintenance personnel received just in time training regarding CCP MLOP maintenance prior to CCP I-Oland 1-02 work during the 17th refueling outage on Unit 1. VI. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS There have been no previous similar reportable events at CPNPP in the last three years. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>