<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2010-05-09" id="2852012007">
   <abstract>During inspections to determine the physical integrity of a failed pressurizer heater
      it was determined that the heater sheath (number 26) was cracked. Due to the location of the
      pressurizer heater crack, this is considered a degradation of the reactor coolant system
      boundary. The initial visual inspection of heater 26 in November 2011 did not identify the
      cracking. During efforts to remove the heater, a crack was observed on May 19, 2012. The crack
      is above and below the heater support plate. The crack is an axial crack showing some
      branching. The crack is about an inch above and inch below the heater support plate. These
      inspections were being performed as a result of operating experience. On May 23, 2012, it was
      determined that the pressurizer heater sheath was part of the reactor coolant system boundary.
      A root cause analysis is in progress. The results will be published in a supplement to this
      LER. The heater sheath has been removed and replaced. The other heater sheaths have been
      inspected and none of them had indications of cracking.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion
         Engineering (CE) design. The pressurizer and its associated heaters were replaced in the
         fall of 2006 as part of a plant upgrade project. The pressurizer is designed with 36
         pressurizer heaters. The heaters are 480 VAC immersion heaters with an output of
         approximately 25 (23.6) kilowatts each. Each heater is 1.252 inches in diameter,
         approximately 5 feet long, and protrudes vertically into the pressurizer through sleeves
         welded in the bottom head of the pressurizer. The heaters and sheaths were manufactured by
         Watlow Electric Manufacturing.</background>
      <eventDesc>During inspections to determine the physical integrity of a failed pressurizer
         heater it was determined that the heater sheath (number 26) was cracked. Due to the
         location of the pressurizer heater crack, this is considered a degradation of the RCS
         Barrier. The initial visual inspection of heater 26 in November 2011 did not identify the
         cracking. It appears that the crack expanded during the intervening period. During efforts
         to remove the heater, a crack was observed on May 19, 2012. The crack is above and below
         the heater support plate. The crack is an axial crack showing some branching. The crack is
         about an inch above and inch below the heater support plate. These inspections were being
         performed as a result of operating experience. On May 23, 2012, it was determined that the
         pressurizer sheath was part of the reactor coolant system boundary. However, there were no
         indications of any external RCS leakage. At 1854 Central Daylight Time (CDT) on May 23,
         2012, an 8-hour notification was made to the Headquarters Operations office (HOO), under
         10CFR50.72(b)(3)(ii)(a). This report is being made per 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A). This LER
         reports a condition that was documented in the FCS corrective action program on several
         occasions. A ground on a pressurizer heater on May 9, 2010, was only reviewed with respect
         to the Technical Specification requirements for available pressurizer heaters. When the
         potential challenge to the reactor coolant boundary due to a failed pressurizer heater was
         identified on August 5, 2011, the Operations review focused on the current operating
         conditions, noting that the condition would need to be resolved prior to start up. The
         station paradigm inappropriately concluded that reportability could be evaluated at a later
         date since current operating conditions were not challenged, and that the 60-day reporting
         window commenced when the event was determined to be reportable. In addition, FCS resources
         were focused on flood response and mitigation due to the extensive flooding that occurred
         along the Missouri River beginning in June 2011. FCS had declared an Unusual Event on June
         6, 2011, due to rising river level and river projections, and resources were focused on
         flood response and asset protection. This condition was initially reported in Event
         Notification (EN) 47953 on May 23, 2012, at 1854 CDT. FCS has been systematically
         addressing issues that have been identified since June 2011, in response to the flooding
         conditions, switchgear fire, and increased oversight. This LER is being submitted beyond
         the 60-day regulatory reporting requirement due to non-conservative decisions with respect
         to procedural and regulatory reportability requirements and resource constraints caused by
         the operating challenges which began in June 2011.</eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A root cause analysis is in progress. The conclusions of the analysis will be
         presented in a supplement to this LER. </conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>Actions to Prevent Recurrence The cracked heater has been removed and
         replaced. The other heater sheaths have been very rigorously inspected to ensure any cracks
         would be identified. None of the other heater sheaths had indications of cracking.
         Additional actions will be tracked in the stations corrective action
         system.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>While the heater sheath crack caused the electrical failure of the
         pressurizer heater, the heater design includes a secondary seal (not the RCS pressure
         boundary) that prevented any leakage from the reactor coolant system. This integral safety
         function operated as anticipated and designed. FCS performed a bare metal inspection of the
         pressurizer bottom head and confirmed that there were no indications of any external RCS
         leakage from any of the heaters or their penetrations. Therefore this event had no impact
         on the health and safety of the public.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does not result in a safety system functional
         failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>The station has not had any previous cracking of pressurizer heater
         sheaths.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
