<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-12-07" id="2852012013">
   <abstract>Technical Data Book Procedure (TDB)-III.40, “Technical Specification Required SIRWT
      Levels,” lists the administrative requirements to maintain the Technical Specification (TS)
      required Safety Injection Refueling Water tank (SIRWT) levels. The required SIRWT level for TS
      2.3 accounts for instrument uncertainty, as described in the basis for TS 2.3. However, the
      required SIRWT levels listed in TDB-III.40 for TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 do not account for
      instrument uncertainty. Therefore, the TS described levels in TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 did not
      adequately account for SIRWT instrument level uncertainty. As a result, using the levels
      described in TDB-III.40 for compliance with TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 was non-conservative. The
      analysis concluded that there was inadequate/incomplete procedural guidance for developing
      Administrative Limits used to protect TS Limits. This includes guidance for understanding how
      to evaluate and apply uncertainties when developing TS Administrative Limits. SIRWT level was
      increased to a level that accounted for instrument uncertainty. TDB-III.40 has been modified
      to change the Administrative Limits to account for uncertainty.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Technical Specifications (TS) Limiting Conditions for
         Operation (LCOs) contain requirements to maintain the Safety Injection Refueling Water
         (SIRW) tank as follows: 2.3, Emergency Core Cooling System (1) Minimum Requirements The
         reactor shall not be made critical unless all of the following conditions are met: a. The
         SIRW tank contains not less than 283,000 gallons of water with a boron concentration of at
         least the refueling boron concentration at a temperature not less than 50 degrees F. 2.2.7,
         Borated Water Source - Shutdown Applicable in modes 4 and 5 c. The SIRW tank with 1. A
         minimum useable borated water volume of 10,000 gallons, 2.2.8, Borated Water Sources –
         Operating Applies to the operational status of borated water sources when the reactor
         coolant temperature (T cold) is greater than 210 degrees Fahrenheit (F). b. The SIRW tank
         with: 1. A minimum useable borated water volume of 25,000 gallons, System Description A
         safeguards actuation signal starts two of the three 100 percent capable high-pressure
         safety injection (HPSI) pumps, the two low-pressure safety injection (LPSI) pumps, and
         opens the twelve SI line isolation valves. The third 100 percent capable HPSI pump (SI-2C)
         may be manually aligned to either of the two HPSI injection headers. Pump SI-2C is manually
         actuated as required during plant operations. The SI pumps take suction from two
         independent suction headers which are supplied with borated water from the SIRW tank
         (SIRWT). The pumps discharge into the reactor coolant system through the four SI nozzles.
         For long term core cooling, a continuous source of borated water is provided by
         recirculating containment water.</background>
      <eventDesc>On December 7, 2011, a condition report (CR) (2011-9956) was written to identify a
         concern associated with the TS values contained in the Technical Data Book (TDB) for the
         SIRWT. Specifically, TDB-III.40, “Technical Specification Required SIRWT Levels,” lists the
         administrative requirements for maintaining the TS required SIRWT levels. As stated in the
         TS Basis for TS 2.3, the required SIRWT level for TS 2.3 accounts for instrument
         uncertainty and therefore is not a concern. However, the required SIRWT levels listed in
         TDB-III.40 for TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 do not account for instrument uncertainty. As a result,
         the TS described levels in TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 did not account for SIRWT instrument level
         uncertainty and using the levels described in TDB-III.40 for compliance with TSs 2.2.7 and
         2.2.8 was determined to be non-conservative. The cause analysis identified two times in the
         previous three years when LCO 2.2.7, Borated Water Source – Shutdown requirements were not
         met. During the 2009 refueling outage (RFO), between approximately 1430 on November 1,
         2009, and 0330 on November 12, 2009, and again during the 2011 RFO, between approximately
         0347 on May 29, 2011, and 0300 on May 31, 2011. No instances of LCO 2.2.8, Borated Water
         Sources – Operating, not being met were identified. This condition has been entered in the
         station’s Corrective Action Program (CAP) as CR 2011-9956. This event is being reported
         pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). During the cause analysis, three additional TS
         instrument uncertainties were questioned and entered into the FCS CAP: 1. Pressurizer level
         - uncertainty in initial pressurizer level was not applied appropriately in several of the
         calculations of USAR Chapter 14 analyses performed during the timeframe of the replacement
         steam generator project. However, due to the additional conservatism already employed in
         the initial pressurizer level in those calculations, the initial pressurizer level used is
         still conservative to what was required, and therefore, the calculations themselves remain
         conservative. 2. Refueling cavity level instruments LI-106 and LI-199 – being reviewed. 3.
         CEA position indication – being reviewed. FCS has been systematically addressing issues
         that have been identified since June 2011, in response to the flooding conditions,
         switchgear fire, and increased oversight. This LER is being submitted beyond the 60-day
         regulatory reporting requirement due to non-conservative decisions with respect to
         procedural and regulatory reportability requirements and resource constraints caused by the
         operating challenges which began in June 2011.</eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis was conducted to determine the reason for the failure to account
         for instrument uncertainties. The analysis concluded that there was inadequate/incomplete
         procedural guidance for developing Administrative Limits used to protect Technical
         Specification Limits. This includes guidance for understanding how to evaluate and apply
         uncertainties when developing Technical Specification Administrative Limits.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>Interim Actions SIRWT level was increased to a level that accounted for
         instrument uncertainty. TDB-III.40 (Engineering Change (EC) 56127) has been modified to
         change the Administrative Limits to account for uncertainty. Actions to Prevent Recurrence
         Procedures PED-QP-9, “Setpoint Control,” SO-G-30, “Procedure Changes and Generation,” and
         PED-NEI-4, “Interface Requirements for Reload Analysis Process,” will be revised to include
         guidance on the development of new Technical Specification limits and the associated
         administrative limits. These actions will be tracked in the station’s CAP and will be
         completed prior to December 31, 2012.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>Two instances occurred where TS Limit 2.2.7 was not met as a result of
         this condition. The 10,000-gallon limit for SIRWT volume (credited for a mode 5 boron
         dilution event) is in fact not used in USAR 14.3, Boron Dilution Incident. There is no
         analytical basis for the 10,000-gallon limit associated with SIRWT volume. The
         25,000-gallon limit associated with SIRWT volume is enveloped by a larger required limit of
         283,000 gallons. Although this resulted in a reportable event, it did not represent a
         challenge to nuclear safety as the refueling cavity was filled as required by TS. This
         event did not result in the release of any radiation. Therefore, this event had no impact
         on the health and safety of the public.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does not result in a safety system functional
         failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>No previous events concerning inadequate application of uncertainty have been
         identifed.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
