<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-02-03" id="2852011003" version="2">
   <abstract>During identification and evaluation of flood barriers, unsealed through wall
               penetrations in the outside wall of the intake, auxiliary and chemistry and radiation
               protection buildings were identified that are below the licensing basis flood
               elevation. Additionally a potential flooding issue was identified on the inside of
               the Intake Structure. Holes were noted in the floor at the 1007’6” level, which is
               the ceiling of the Raw Water Vault. A summary of the root causes included: a weak
               procedure revision process; insufficient oversight of work activities associated with
               external flood matters; ineffective identification, evaluation and resolution of
               performance deficiencies related to external flooding; and “safe as is” mindsets
               relative to external flooding events. The penetrations were temporarily sealed and a
               configuration change was developed and implemented whereby permanent seals were
               installed. A one foot sandbag berm was placed around the holes. Comprehensive
               corrective actions to address the root and contributing causes are being addressed
               through the corrective action program.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>As a result of a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)
         inspection conducted from January 1 to June 21, 2010, the NRC determined that Fort Calhoun
         Station (FCS) did not have adequate procedures to protect the intake structure and
         auxiliary building against external flooding events. Specifically, contrary to Technical
         Specification 5.8.1.a, the station failed to maintain procedures for combating a
         significant flood as recommended by Regulatory Guide 1.33, Appendix A, section 6.w, “Acts
         of Nature.” The NRC identified the following violation of NRC requirements associated with
         a yellow significance determination process finding in the mitigating systems cornerstone
         in inspection report 05000285/2010008 dated October 6, 2010: Technical Specification
         5.8.1.a, “Procedures,” states, “Written procedures and administrative policies shall be
         established, implemented, and maintained covering the following activities: (a) The
         applicable procedures recommended in Regulatory Guide 1.33, Revision 2, Appendix A, 1978.”
         NRC Regulatory Guide 1.33, “Quality Assurance Program Requirements (Operation),” Appendix
         A, “Typical Procedures for Pressurized Water Reactors and Boiling Water Reactors,” Section
         6, recommends procedures for combating emergencies and other significant events. Section
         6.w, “Acts of Nature,” includes, in part, procedures for combating floods. Contrary to
         Technical Specification 5.8.1.a, since 1978, written procedures and administrative policies
         were not maintained covering the applicable procedures recommended by NRC Regulatory Guide
         1.33, Revision 2, Appendix A. Specifically, the licensee failed to maintain written
         procedures for combating a significant external flood as recommended by NRC Regulatory
         Guide, Appendix A, Section 6.w, “Acts of Nature.” The licensee’s written procedures did not
         adequately prescribe steps to mitigate external flood conditions in the Auxiliary Building
         and Intake Structure up to 1014 feet mean sea level, as documented in the Updated Final
         Safety Analysis Report [USAR]. The NRC reported that the station’s flood protection
         strategy was not fully effective during worst-case Missouri River flooding scenarios. The
         strategy required workers to install floodgates in front of the doors to the plant’s
         auxiliary building and intake structure, and then stack and drape sandbags over the top of
         the floodgates up to a height of five feet. The procedural guidance was inadequate because
         the cross-section on top of the floodgates would not support a stacked sandbag
         configuration that would retain five feet of moving water.</background>
      <eventDesc>During identification and evaluation of flood
         barriers (condition report (CR) 2010-2387), in response to NRC findings previously noted,
         unsealed through wall penetrations in the intake structure were identified that are below
         the licensing basis flood elevation. These penetrations were installed during the
         installation of upgrades to the plant fire protection system. As a result of the
         penetrations not being sealed, the intake structure was vulnerable to water inflow during
         an extreme flooding event. This inflow had the potential to affect the operability of both
         trains of safety related raw water pumps (ultimate heat sink). On February 4, 2011, an
         eight (8) hour report was made under 10 CFR 50.72 (b)(3)(v)(D) to the NRC Headquarters
         Operation Office (HOO) at 1717 CST (Event Number (EN) 46594). The report should have been
         made on September 9, 2009. (Documented in Condition Report (CR) 2011-0801) During the
         extent of cause analysis for this issue the following penetrations were identified as not
         having been reported. Unsealed penetrations were created during the installation of the
         original plant security system and were abandoned when the security system was replaced
         (approximately 1985). The penetrations for the “new” security system were appropriately
         sealed. The old penetrations were abandoned and not sealed. As a result of the penetrations
         not being sealed, the intake structure was vulnerable to water inflow during an extreme
         flooding event. This inflow had the potential to affect the operability of both trains of
         safety related raw water pumps (ultimate heat sink). On February 27, 2011, an eight (8)
         hour report was made under 10 CFR 50.72 (b)(3)(v)(D) to the NRC Headquarters Operation
         Office (HOO) at 1640 CST (EN 46590). The report should have been made on January 27, 2011.
         (Documented in CR 2011-0609) Two additional conduits have been identified that are not
         sealed. These conduits penetrate the south wall of the auxiliary building near the
         transformers into Room 19 and were created as part of a station modification that was in
         progress at the time. Flooding through the penetrations could have impacted the ability of
         the station's auxiliary feedwater (AFW) pumps to perform their design accident mitigation
         functions. On March 31, 2011, an eight (8) hour report was made under 10 CFR 50.72
         (b)(3)(v)(D) to the NRC Headquarters Operation Office (HOO) at 2232 CDT (EN 46716)
         (Documented in CR 2011-2470) A weakness in the flood protection strategy was discovered
         that would prevent protection of the raw water pumps for floods above 1007 feet-6 inches
         mean sea level (MSL). The flood protection strategy includes control of the intake cell
         level by throttling the sluice gates and running raw water pumps to maintain cell level.
         During the preparation of a calculation to demonstrate the validity of this method it was
         determined that the grid backwash pipe for each grid and the surface sluice penetrate the
         east wall of the intake structure through an unsealed penetration (7 penetrations). The
         grid backwash line is an 18 inch pipe passing through a 24 inch sleeve. Cell in-leakage
         through these penetrations would be beyond the capacity of the raw water pumps resulting in
         flooding of the intake structure and loss of the raw water pump function. On March 22,
         2011, an eight (8) hour report was made under 10 CFR 50.72 (b)(3)(v)(D) to the NRC
         Headquarters Operation Office (HOO) at 1611 CDT (EN 46690). (Documented in CR 2011-2161) An unsealed conduit (location 56E-S-43 in pull box 127) was
         identified that penetrates the auxiliary building into Room 56. Room 56 contains the safety
         related electrical switchgear. In addition, a drain flow path from the Chemistry and
         Radiation Protection (CARP) building into Room 23 which can drain into the rooms holding
         the Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS) Pumps was identified. On April 8, 2011, an eight
         (8) hour report was made under 10 CFR 50.72 (b)(3)(v)(D) to the NRC Headquarters Operation
         Office (HOO) at 1240 CDT (EN 46741). (Documented in CRs 2011-2072 and 2011-2448) Three
         fittings into room 19 (auxiliary feedwater and plant air compressors) and fittings into
         room 56E (electrical switchgear) were found to contain no filling material. One additional
         fitting into room 56E that was thought to be capped was found to be open with a sheet metal
         box covering the inside access thereby obscuring inspections. The stations auxiliary
         feedwater and safety related electrical switch gear could be affected. On October 20, 2011,
         an eight (8) hour report was made under 10 CFR 50.72 (b)(3)(v)(B) and (D) to the NRC
         Headquarters Operation Office (HOO) at 1246 CDT (EN 47359). (Documented in CR 2011-8547)
         Since each of these incidents are events that are related (i.e., they have the same cause
         and consequences) and they were discovered during a single activity (i.e., investigation to
         correct the initial problem) then per NUREG 1022, Revision 2, these are being reported in
         one LER. This report is being made per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) and (D).</eventDesc>
         <conclusion>A root
         cause determination was prepared in connection with CR 2010-2387 which documents the causes
         of the problem. The following four (4) root causes explain why written procedures were
         inadequate to mitigate the external flood conditions prescribed by the Updated Safety
         Analysis Report (USAR). These root causes address the NRC issued yellow finding as well as
         the specific penetrations being addressed in this LER. Historically, when procedures for
         flooding protection were restructured or substantially augmented, a weak procedure revision
         process did not assure FCS met its USAR requirements. Supervisory and management oversight
         of work activities associated with external flood matters was not sufficient to prevent
         this issue from occurring. The FCS organization has not been effective in ensuring that
         performance deficiencies related to external flooding are adequately identified, evaluated,
         and resolved. Mindsets existed that FCS was “safe as is” relative to external flooding
         events. These mindsets collectively led to the incorrect conclusion that regulatory
         requirements were being met.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>Configuration changes were developed as
         needed and the penetrations sealed. Comprehensive corrective actions to address the root
         and contributing causes have been developed and will be addressed through the corrective
         action program.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>The Fort Calhoun Station is required to be
         protected from flooding within the station’s licensing basis. The safety related equipment
         required to mitigate the consequences of an accident were affected by these findings. The
         openings could have jeopardized the ability of the safety related equipment to perform
         their design basis function during an accident. Other methods of removing decay heat and
         mitigating the consequences of a flooding event were available. Therefore, this external
         flooding concern has substantial importance to safety as indicated by the Yellow Finding
         issued for this event.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does result in a safety
         system functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>No licensee event
         report prior to this has identified the flooding issue. LER 2011-001 which had been written
         to report a flooding penetration has been cancelled as indicated in Reference 3 to the
         cover letter to this LER. The penetration is discussed in this LER.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TD>FORT CALHOUN STATION </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD>NOD-QP-9.2 </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD>R0 </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD>LICENSING CORRESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD>LIC-12-00022 </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <P>Date Issued: 2/27/12 Requested Return Date:____2/28/12______ </P>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>Review/Approval </TH>

            <TH>Information </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Dave Bannister </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Lynn Smith </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Susan Baughn </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Brad Blome </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Cory Cameron </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Mike Cooper </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <P>Subject___ Inadequate Flooding Protection Rev 2 </P>

      <P>Please review and approve the attached draft correspondence (referenced above). In order to
         document your review for our records, please sign this form and return it to the Licensing
         Coordinator. If n o notification is received by the requested return date, your concurrence
         with no comment will be assumed. </P>

      <P>E. Matzke 1597____ Technical Coordinator (Ext.) Licensing Coordinator (Ext.) </P>

      <P>[ ] Approved with no comment. [ ] Approved pending resolution of comments as noted. </P>

      <P>Comments:_______________________________________________________________________________ </P>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>___________________________ </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>___ </TH>

            <TD>_________________ </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH> Reviewer's Signature </TH>

            <TD>Date </TD>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>FORT CALHOUN STATION QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TH>

            <TH>NOD-QP-9.2 R0 </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>LICENSING CORRESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM SUMMARY </TH>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>LIC-12-0022 </TH>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Date Issued: </TH>

            <TD>2/27/12 </TD>

            <TD>Requested Return Date: </TD>

            <TD>2/28/12 </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TD>Name </TD>

            <TD>Date Comments Received </TD>

            <TD>No Comments1 </TD>

            <TD>Comments - How Resolved2 </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Dave Bannister </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Susan Baughn </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Cory Cameron </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Mike Cooper </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Lynn Smith </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>Subject: Inadequate Flooding Protection Rev 2 </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>NOTE – This submittal does ____ does not __X__ include documents/files on CD-ROM.3
            </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>NL Comment Coordinator Signature E. Matzke </TH>

            <TD>Date </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Responsible Dept. Manager (if required) </TH>

            <TD>Date </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Review by Nuclear Licensing Supervisor </TH>

            <TD>Date </TD>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <P>1 Attach only signed Licensing Correspondence Review Form. 2 Attach necessary
         documentation. 3 Ensure that the CD-ROM files are formatted properly for electronic
         information exchange (EIE) to the </P>

      <P>NRC. (Reference NL-17) </P>
   </Part>
</TaggedPDF-doc>
