<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-12-13" id="2852012009">
   <abstract>During the review of the current analysis of record for Main Steam Line Break (MSLB)
      inside containment, no analysis or evaluation could be found to address why the original
      Electrical Environmental Qualification (EEQ) evaluation of peak MSLB conditions remain valid.
      The current analysis of record establishes that containment temperatures remain above the Loss
      of Coolant Accident (LOCA) peak temperature for substantially longer (220 seconds versus 60
      seconds) but at a lower temperature (347.9 degrees Fahrenheit vs. 401 degrees Fahrenheit). The
      longer dwell times could result in a more adverse impact on environmentally qualified
      equipment. A cause analysis is being processed and the results will be reported in a
      supplement to this LER. Fort Calhoun Station will perform thermal lag analyses for the
      Electrical Equipment Qualification Program equipment located within containment prior to plant
      startup. The LER will be supplemented with the information from the EEQ and cause
      analysis.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion
         Engineering (CE) design.</background>
      <eventDesc>FCS Condition Report (CR) 2011-10129, described a condition where equipment within
         the 10CFR50.49 (Equipment Qualification Rule) was not analyzed to the conditions defined in
         FCS calculation FC07054 Rev 1, “Containment Response Study of a Main Steam Line Break with
         GOTHIC,” and created an unanalyzed condition. This condition was determined to be
         reportable as an unanalyzed condition which could prevent fulfillment of a safety function.
         During the review of the current analysis of record for Main Steam Line Break (MSLB) inside
         containment, no analysis or evaluation could be found to address why the original
         Electrical Environmental Qualification (EEQ) evaluation of peak MSLB conditions remain
         valid. The current analysis of record in calculation FC07054 Rev 1 establishes that
         containment temperatures remain above the Loss of Coolant Accident (LOCA) peak temperature
         for substantially longer (220 seconds versus 60 seconds) but at a lower temperature (347.9
         degrees Fahrenheit vs. 401 degrees Fahrenheit). The longer dwell time could result in a
         more adverse impact on environmentally qualified equipment. This would impact both trains
         and a majority of the safety related equipment inside containment. At 1513 Central Daylight
         Time (CDT) on May 4, 2012, an 8-hour notification was made to the Headquarters Operations
         office (HOO), under 10CFR50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B). This report is being made per
         10CFR50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A), (B), (C) and (D). This LER reports a
         condition where equipment within 10 CFR 50.49, Equipment Qualification Rule, was not
         properly analyzed when the analysis of record was revised. The initial Operations review
         focused on the current operating conditions, noting that the condition would need to be
         resolved prior to start up. The station paradigm inappropriately concluded that
         reportability could be evaluated at a later date since current operating conditions were
         not challenged, and that the 60-day reporting window commenced when the event was
         determined to be reportable. In addition, FCS resources were focused on flood response and
         mitigation due to the extensive flooding that occurred along the Missouri River beginning
         in June 2011. FCS had declared an Unusual Event on June 6, 2011, due to rising river level
         and river projections, and resources were focused on flood response and asset protection.
         This condition was initially reported in Event Notification (EN) 47900 on May 4, 2012, at
         1513 CDT. FCS has been systematically addressing issues that have been identified since
         June 2011, in response to the flooding conditions, switchgear fire, and increased
         oversight. This LER is being submitted beyond the 60-day regulatory reporting requirement
         due to non-conservative decisions with respect to procedural and regulatory reportability
         requirements and resource constraints caused by the operating challenges which began in
         June 2011.</eventDesc>
      <conslusion>A cause analysis is being processed and the results will be reported in a
         supplement to this LER.</conslusion>
      <correctiveActions>Fort Calhoun Station will perform thermal lag analyses for the Electrical
         Equipment Qualification Program equipment located within containment prior to plant
         startup. The LER will be supplemented with the information from the EEQ and cause analysis.
         Additional actions will be tracked in the stations corrective action
         system.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>The safety significance of this event will be evaluated in the LER
         supplement following completion of the thermal lag analysis.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFuncitonalFailure>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in
         accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFuncitonalFailure>
      <previousEvents>The station has not had any previous LERs for environmental
         qualification.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
