<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-12-06" id="2852012010">
   <abstract>While preparing an engineering package to relocate two transmitters, Fort Calhoun
      Station engineering identified seismic class 1 components in a seismic class 2 instrument
      rack. This appears to be a legacy issue. The instrument racks in the auxiliary building and
      containment were assessed with respect to the Updated Safety Analysis Report (USAR) specified
      class 1 requirements for seismic design. The seismic calculations for two instrument racks
      were over the analyzed weight for the seismic analysis. The instruments on these racks are
      used for reactor coolant system (RCS) pressure transmitters. During a seismic event, the
      excessive weight of these instrument racks could cause the racks to fail, resulting in an
      unisolable leak from the RCS. A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis
      will be published in a supplement to this LER.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion
         Engineering (CE) design.</background>
      <eventDescription>While preparing an engineering package to relocate two transmitters, Fort
         Calhoun Station engineering identified seismic class 1 components in a seismic class 2
         instrument rack. This appears to be a legacy issue. The instrument racks in the auxiliary
         building and containment were assessed with respect to the Updated Safety Analysis Report
         (USAR) specified class 1 requirements for seismic design. The seismic calculations for two
         instrument racks were over the analyzed weight for the seismic analysis. The instruments on
         these racks are used for reactor coolant system (RCS) pressure transmitters. During a
         seismic event, the excessive weight of these instrument racks could cause the racks to
         fail, resulting in an unisolable leak from the RCS. At 2059 Central Daylight Time (CDT) on
         June 4, 2012, an 8-hour notification was made to the Headquarters Operations office (HOO),
         under 10CFR50.72(b)(3)(ii)(A), degraded condition. Subsequent internal review has
         determined that the initial reporting criterion for degraded condition, 10 CFR
         50.72(b)(3)(ii)(A), was incorrect. The 8-hour non-emergency notification should have been
         made under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B), unanalyzed condition. On August 3, 2012, Event
         Notification (EN) 47992 was updated to correct the reporting criterion. This report is
         being submitted in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B). This LER reports a condition
         where components classified as seismic class 1 were installed in instrument racks
         classified as seismic class 2, specifically RCS pressure transmitters that are part of the
         RCS pressure boundary. A failure of these racks during a seismic event could result in an
         unisolable RCS leak. The condition was documented in the FCS corrective action system on
         December 6, 2011. The initial Operations review focused on the current operating
         conditions, noting that the condition would need to be resolved prior to start up. The
         station paradigm inappropriately concluded that reportability could be evaluated at a later
         date since current operating conditions were not challenged, and that the 60-day reporting
         window commenced when the event was determined to be reportable. This condition was
         initially reported in Event Notification (EN) 47992 on June 4, 2012, at 2059 CDT. FCS has
         been systematically addressing issues that have been identified since June 2011, in
         response to the flooding conditions, switchgear fire, and increased oversight. This LER is
         being submitted beyond the 60-day regulatory reporting requirement due to non-conservative
         decisions with respect to procedural and regulatory reportability requirements and resource
         constraints caused by the operating challenges which began in June 2011.</eventDescription>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be published in
         a supplement to this LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>A cause analysis is in progress. The corrective actions will be published
         in a supplement to this LER.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be
         published in a supplement to this LER.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does not result in a safety system functional
         failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents> A cause analysis is in progress. Previous Events will be determined from the
         results of the cause analysis.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
