<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-09-16" id="2852012015">
   <abstract>While reviewing a draft of the Master List Reconstitution for Electrical Equipment
      Qualification (EA-FC-08-011), Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Engineering Department identified
      that some of the listed components may not be qualified for the environments where they are
      located. This was discovered during a comprehensive re-evaluation of potential high energy
      line breaks and radiological impacts outside containment initiated in response to issues
      identified by the station staff. This condition was identified on September 16, 2011, while
      the unit was shutdown. A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be
      published in a supplement to this LER.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion
         Engineering (CE) design.</background>
      <eventDesc>FCS has been conducting a comprehensive re-evaluation of potential high energy line
         breaks and radiological impacts outside containment. On September 16, 2011, while reviewing
         a draft of the Master List Reconstitution for Electrical Equipment Qualification, FCS
         Engineering Department personnel identified that some of the listed components may not be
         qualified for the environments where they are located. Of the 29 items listed, seven were
         identified that may exhibit spurious operation when exposed to a post-accident harsh
         environment. Those items are: PCS-2937, Low Pressure Safety Injection (LPSI) Pump Suction
         Valve SI-1B Pressure Control Switch PCS-2947, LPSI Pump Suction Valve SI-1A Pressure
         Control Switch Failure of these pressure switches in a post-accident harsh environment may
         result in spurious operation of the low pressure safety injection (LPSI) suction valves. A
         spurious closure of these valves will result in a loss of LPSI pump suction from the Safety
         Injection Refueling Water tank (SIRWT) and a spurious opening with the SIRWT below the
         minimum level may result in air intrusion into the pump. VA-40A-M, Contaminated Area
         Exhaust Unit Fan A Motor VA-40B-M, Contaminated Area Exhaust Unit Fan B Motor VA-40C-M,
         Contaminated Area Exhaust Unit Fan C Motor These fans are required to provide cooling to
         the safety injection (SI) pump rooms in a post-accident scenario. All trains of SI will
         become inoperable due to room heat-up after a loss of these fans. HCZ-1105, Feedwater
         Bypass Valve Positioner HCZ-1106, Feedwater Bypass Valve Positioner The failure of the
         positioners will not affect the ability of the feedwater bypass valves HCV-1105 and
         HCV-1106 to open and provide auxiliary feedwater as this function can be accomplished by
         operation of the hand controller. However, the hand controller does not have the ability to
         close the valves. Therefore, the safety function of the valves closing on a Steam Generator
         Isolation Signal will be lost. This condition is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR
         50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), Any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the
         safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an
         accident, The condition described in this LER was identified in September 2011, but not
         promptly investigated as a reportable condition. The station paradigm inappropriately
         concluded that reportability could be evaluated at a later date since current operating
         conditions were not challenged, and that the 60-day reporting window commenced when the
         event was determined to be reportable. FCS has been systematically addressing issues that
         have been identified since June 2011, in response to the flooding conditions, switchgear
         fire, and increased oversight. This LER is being submitted beyond the 60-day regulatory
         reporting requirement due to non-conservative decisions with respect to procedural and
         regulatory reportability requirements and resource constraints caused by the operating
         challenges which began in June 2011.</eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be published in
         a supplement to this LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>A cause analysis is in progress. The corrective actions will be published
         in a supplement to this LER.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be
         published in a supplement to this LER.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFuncitonalFailure>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in
         accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFuncitonalFailure>
      <previousEvents>A cause analysis is in progress. Previous Events will be determined from the
         results of the cause analysis.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
