<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler when="2011-09-28" id="2852012008">
   <abstract>A review of previously completed cause analyses has identified that Fort Calhoun
      Station (FCS) has moved fuel while the Spent Fuel Pool Area ventilation charcoal filter
      (VA-66) was inoperable due to failing the methyliodide penetration surveillance. FCS Technical
      Specification 2.8.3(4) requires the Spent Fuel Pool Area ventilation system to be in service
      prior to fuel movement. The Spent Fuel Pool Area ventilation system includes a charcoal filter
      which prevents the release of radioactive material to the outside atmosphere in the event of a
      fuel handling accident. However, the fuel handling accident analysis does not credit removal
      of any radioiodine through operation of the Spent Fuel Pool charcoal filter (VA-66); offsite
      radiological consequences are well within the 10 CFR 50.67 requirements without the charcoal
      filtration. There have been repeated charcoal efficiency test failures since 2005. There was
      evidence that the charcoal filters were not capable of meeting the 18-month surveillance
      frequency. Fuel movement was conducted while the Spent Fuel Pool Area charcoal filter was in
      service, yet potentially not able to meet the adsorption criteria, hence inoperable which is a
      violation of TS requirements. A cause analysis is in progress. The results will be published
      in a supplement to this LER. Corrective actions included a revision of the applicable
      procedure to ensure that charcoal life is predicted and charcoal filter change out is
      performed before the charcoal expires. This event is being reported under 10 CFR
      50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), operation or condition prohibited by TS.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>The Auxiliary Building Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning (HVAC) system is
         designed and operated to protect station personnel and the public from airborne
         radioactivity, and to provide environmental control for safety-related instrumentation,
         controls, and equipment. There are several charcoal filters in the Auxiliary Building HVAC
         system, including the Spent Fuel Pool (SFP) area charcoal filter (VA-66). The filters are
         made of activated charcoal and have one-inch thick adsorber beds. The charcoal filter
         (VA-66) is installed in a normally bypassed section of the exhaust ductwork which draws air
         from the SFP area. The exhaust from the SFP area is monitored for radioactive
         contamination. If radiation is detected, the charcoal filter (VA-66) can be placed on line
         from the Control Room. The system does not automatically realign and therefore must be in
         operation prior to refueling operations in the SFP. Technical Specification (TS) 2.8.3(4)
         requires the Spent Fuel Pool Area Ventilation to be in service during refueling operations
         in the SFP to minimize the consequences of a fuel handling accident in the SFP that could
         affect public health and safety. The charcoal filter in the SFP ventilation system prevents
         the release of significant radionuclides to the outside atmosphere. When the SFP area
         ventilation is not in operation, refueling operations in the SFP must be immediately
         suspended. TS Section 3.2, Table 3-5, Item 10b.2, requires testing of the SFP area charcoal
         filter on a refueling frequency or every 720 hours of operation, or following significant
         painting, fire, or chemical release in any ventilation zone communicating with the system
         to ensure the methyliodide penetration is less than 10 percent when tested in accordance
         with ASTM D3803-1989 at a temperature of 30 degrees C (86 degrees F) and a relative
         humidity of 95 percent. Laboratory testing must be completed within 31 days after removal
         of a sample of the charcoal adsorber. The fuel handling accident analysis does not credit
         removal of any radioiodine through operation of the SFP charcoal filter (VA-66); offsite
         radiological consequences are well within the 10 CFR 50.67 requirements without the
         charcoal filtration.</background>
      <eventDesc>A review of previously completed cause analyses has identified that Fort Calhoun
         Station (FCS) has moved fuel while the Spent Fuel Pool Area ventilation charcoal filter
         (VA-66) was likely below the required adsorption capability, hence inoperable due to
         failing the methyliodide penetration surveillance. FCS TS 2.8.3(4) requires the Spent Fuel
         Pool Area ventilation system to be in service prior to fuel movement. There have been
         repeated charcoal efficiency test failures since 2005. There was evidence that the charcoal
         filters were not capable of meeting the 18-month surveillance frequency. Fuel movement was
         conducted while the SFP Area charcoal filter was inoperable in violation of TS
         requirements. This LER documents a condition that was prohibited by TS. Fuel was moved in
         the SFP when the SFP area ventilation (VA-66) was considered inoperable. After the ASTM
         standard for methyliodide testing was revised, the one-inch thick charcoal adsorber beds
         routinely failed the penetration surveillance test. FCS documented the most recent
         methyliodide penetration failure in September 2011. FCS had previously concluded (December
         2009) that the methyliodide penetration failure of the charcoal adsorber in VA-66 was not
         reportable since VA-66 was no longer credited in the fuel handling accident analysis. The
         evaluation did not recognize the TS non-compliance. When the condition was questioned as ‘a
         condition prohibited by TS’ in May 2012, the engineering review agreed with the December
         2009 station position, and a new reportability evaluation was not promptly completed. The
         station paradigm inappropriately concluded that reportability could be evaluated at a later
         date since current operating conditions were not challenged, and that the 60-day reporting
         window commenced when the event was determined to be reportable. FCS has been
         systematically addressing issues that have been identified since June 2011, in response to
         the flooding conditions, switchgear fire, and increased oversight. This LER is being
         submitted beyond the 60-day regulatory reporting requirement due to non-conservative
         decisions with respect to procedural and regulatory reportability requirements and resource
         constraints caused by the operating challenges which began in June 2011.</eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is in progress. The conclusions of the analysis will be presented
         in a supplement to this LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>Corrective actions included a revision of the applicable procedure to
         ensure that charcoal life is predicted and charcoal filter change out is performed before
         the charcoal expires. Additional actions will be tracked in the station’s corrective action
         system.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>FCS TS require the SFP area ventilation to be in operation during
         operations in the SFP to mitigate the consequences of a fuel handling accident. However,
         the FCS accident analysis for a fuel handling accident in the SFP assumes the activity is
         collected by the SFP area ventilation system and released, unfiltered, to the environment,
         via the auxiliary building vent stack. Since there is no means of isolating the SFP area,
         all of the airborne activity resulting from the fuel handling accident is assumed to be
         exhausted out of the auxiliary building in a period of two hours. The SFP area ventilation
         has no safety function as it is not credited for mitigating the radiological consequences
         of a fuel handling accident even though actual tests have demonstrated the effectiveness of
         VA-66 in reducing radiation doses. Therefore, there is no safety significance associated
         with fuel movement when VA-66 is inoperable and this event had no impact on the health and
         safety of the public.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does not result in a safety system functional
         failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>The station has had two similar events (movement of fuel with VA-66
         inoperable) as documented in LER 90-05 and LER 94-006.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
