<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-07-11" id="2852012014">
   <abstract> On July 11, 2012, while performing the Extent of
      Condition for an existing Condition Report (CR) it was determined that Beam B-22, a structural
      member of the containment internal structure at the 1013 foot elevation, loading conditions
      were outside the allowable limits for both Working Stress and No Loss of Function load
      combinations as noted in the USAR Section 5.11. This condition was identified on July 11,
      2011, while the unit was shutdown and reported to the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)
      Headquarters Operations Center the same day at approximately 1603 CDT under Event Notification
      Number 48094. A cause analysis is being evaluated and will be published in a supplement to
      this LER.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion
         Engineering (CE) design. Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 2.6 Containment System This
         LCO does not contain a specification stating the requirements related to the containment
         internal support structures. However, system such as the containment and safety injection
         rely on the containment support structures integrity to be maintained under accident
         conditions for each individual system to be OPEARABLE. Operable – Operability is defined in
         the Technical Specifications (TS) as: A system, subsystem, train, component or device shall
         be OPERABLE or have OPERABILITY when it is capable of performing its specified safety
         function(s) and when all necessary attendant instrumentation, controls, normal or emergency
         electrical power sources, cooling and seal water, lubrication, and other auxiliary
         equipment that are required for the system, subsystem, train, component or device to
         perform its specified safety functions(s) are also capable of performing their related
         support function(s). The FCS Updated Safety Analysis Report (USAR), Section 5.11.3 Design
         Criteria - Class I Structures, Sub-section, a. Loadings states in part: Class I structures
         were designed on the basis of working stress for the following load combinations: S = D + L
         S = D + L + W or E S = D + F where: S = Required section capacity D = Dead load L = Live
         load, including hydrostatic load W = Wind load E = Design earthquake F = Hydrostatic load
         to elevation 1007 feet The ACI Code 318-63 and the AISC Code for Structural Steel, 1963
         edition, design methods and allowable stresses were used for reinforced concrete and steel
         structures, respectively. The concrete structure within the containment was considered as a
         Class I structure and was subject to the loads and analysis noted above with the exception
         of wind and tornado loads. In addition, a transient analysis was made to determine the
         maximum differential pressure across the interior shielding and structural walls and
         floors. Openings in the interior concrete walls and floors are provided and grating floors
         are used wherever possible, without reducing the necessary shielding, to allow
         pressurization of all compartments with the minimal differential pressure across walls and
         floors.</background>
      <eventDesc>On July 11, 2012, while performing the Extent of Condition for an existing
         Condition Report (CR) it was determined that Beam B-22, a structural member of the
         containment internal structure at the 1013 foot elevation, loading conditions were outside
         the allowable limits for both Working Stress and No Loss of Function load combinations as
         noted in the USAR Section 5.11. This condition was identified on July 11, 2011, while the
         unit was shutdown and reported to the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) Operations
         Center the same day at approximately 1603 CDT under Event Notification Number 48094. This
         condition is being submitted pursuant to: 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B), Any event or
         condition that resulted in the nuclear power plant being in an unanalyzed condition that
         significantly degraded plant safety. 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), Any operation or condition
         which was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications. 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D),
         &quot;Any event or condition that alone could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety
         function of structures or systems that are needed to: (D) Mitigate the consequences of an
         accident.&quot; The condition described in this LER was identified in July 2012, but not
         promptly investigated as a reportable condition. The station paradigm inappropriately
         concluded that reportability could be evaluated at a later date since current operating
         conditions were not challenged, and that the 60-day reporting window commenced when the
         event was determined to be reportable. FCS has been systematically addressing issues that
         have been identified since June 2011, in response to the flooding conditions, switchgear
         fire, and increased oversight. This LER is being submitted beyond the 60-day regulatory
         reporting requirement due to non-conservative decisions with respect to procedural and
         regulatory reportability requirements and resource constraints caused by the operating
         challenges which began in June 2011. This issue was placed in the stations corrective
         action system.</eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is being evaluated and will be published in a supplement to this
         LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>Compensatory measures were taken to ensure the loading on beam 22 was
         within calculated limits. Additional corrective actions will be determined following
         completion of the cause evaluation.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>A cause analysis is being evaluated the safety significance will be
         published following the completion of the investigation.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in
         accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>A cause analysis is being evaluated and previous events will be determined
         following the completion of the evaluation.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
