<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-03-12" id="2852012003">
   <abstract>A non-conservative error was identified in the input calculation for post-LOCA
               cooling flow (post-RAS (recirculation actuation signal)). The calculation used an
               incorrect (non-conservative) input for LPSI pump performance. The associated
               procedure (EOP/AOP Attachment 11) as written does not provide adequate direction
               during the Alternate Hot Leg Injection mode of operation. Therefore, the procedural
               guidance may not ensure the completion of the safety function of providing adequate
               core cooling during the Alternate Hot Leg Injection mode of operation under a worst
               case scenario. A cause analysis is in progress and the results will be included in a
               supplement to this LER. Corrective actions to address the causes of this condition
               will be documented in a supplement to this LER.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two loop Combustion
         Engineering, pressurized water reactor. The FCS Safety Injection (SI) system consists of
         three High Pressure Safety Injection (HPSI) pumps, associated piping and valves; three
         Containment Spray (CS) pumps, associated piping and valves; and two Low Pressure Safety
         Injection (LPSI) pumps, associated piping and valves. During accident conditions Emergency
         Operating Procedures (EOPs) and Abnormal Operating Procedures (AOPs) are used to ensure
         safe operation of the plant. The primary function of the LPSI system is to provide
         emergency core cooling following a loss-of-coolant-accident (LOCA). The LPSI system is
         designed to achieve this in conjunction with the operation of one HPSI pump and one
         emergency diesel generator during worst case accident conditions. Long-term cooling and
         recirculation are mainly accomplished by the HPSI system. However, the LPSI pumps can be
         used to obtain increased recirculation cooling flow once the reactor coolant system
         pressure is reduced to approximately the same as the containment building pressure. The
         LPSI pumps may be used to inject uncooled water, or a portion of their discharge may be
         diverted through the shutdown cooling heat exchanges before being injected back into the
         Reactor Coolant System (RCS). If only one HPSI pump is available, one LPSI pump in
         conjunction with the available HPSI pump will be used for simultaneous hot and cold leg
         injection in accordance with EOP/AOP Attachment 11, “Alternate Hot Leg Injection,” via the
         shutdown cooling flow path. Hot leg injection is normally accomplished with two HPSI pumps
         via a cross tie to the Chemical Volume and Control System (CVCS).</background>
      <eventDesc>The
         minimum analyzed flow for a LPSI pump is 150 gpm. The calculation does not clearly
         demonstrate that this flow is maintained during some accident conditions. The associated
         procedure (EOP/AOP Attachment 11) as written does not provide adequate direction during the
         Alternate Hot Leg Injection mode of operation to ensure this requirement is met. EOP/AOP
         Attachment 11 requires that RCS pressure be less than 140 pounds per square inch absolute
         (psia) as the entry point for the procedure. The LPSI pumps may not be able to meet minimum
         flow requirements for long term pump operation at this pressure, which could result in pump
         damage. The minimum required RCS hot leg injection flow is 134 gpm may not be met with
         current procedural guidance and instrument accuracy limitations. Therefore, procedural
         guidance may not ensure completion of the safety function of providing adequate core
         cooling during the Alternate Hot Leg Injection mode of operation under a worst case
         scenario. On April 25, 2012, at 1622 Central Daylight Time (CDT) an eight-hour notification
         per 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B) was made to the Headquarters Operation Office (HOO) (Event
         Number 478620). This report is being made per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B).
         </eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is in progress and the results will be
         included in a supplement to this LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>The station is currently in a
         refueling mode. Corrective actions to address the causes of this condition will be
         documented in a supplement to this LER. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE An evaluation of the safety
         significance of this issue will be completed following the completion of the cause
         analysis.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does not result in a safety system
         functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>No previous qualifications
         issues with hot leg injection have been identified.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TD>FORT CALHOUN STATION </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD>NOD-QP-9.2 </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD>R0 </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD>LICENSING CORRESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD>LIC-12-0065 </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <P>Date Issued: 5/9/12 Requested Return Date:____5/10/12______ </P>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>Review/Approval </TH>

            <TH>Information </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Dave Bannister </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Lynn Smith </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Susan Baughn </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Woody Goodell </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>J. Herman </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>S. Miller </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>C. Cameron </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>M. Cooper </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>M. Friedman </TH>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <P>Subject LER 2012-003 “Non-Conservative Error in Calculation for Alternate Hot Leg Injection
         Results in Unanalyzed </P>

      <P>Condition” </P>

      <P>Please review and approve the attached draft correspondence (referenced above). In order to
         document your review for our records, please sign this form and return it to the Licensing
         Coordinator. If n o notification is received by the requested return date, your concurrence
         with no comment will be assumed. </P>

      <P>E. Matzke 6855____ Technical Coordinator (Ext.) Licensing Coordinator (Ext.) </P>

      <P>[ ] Approved with no comment. [ ] Approved pending resolution of comments as noted. </P>

      <P>Comments:_______________________________________________________________________________ </P>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>___________________________ </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>___ </TH>

            <TD>_________________ </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH> Reviewer's Signature </TH>

            <TD>Date </TD>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>FORT CALHOUN STATION QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TH>

            <TH>NOD-QP-9.2 R0 </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>LICENSING CORRESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM SUMMARY </TH>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>LIC-12-0065 </TH>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Date Issued: </TH>

            <TD>5/9/12 </TD>

            <TD>Requested Return Date: </TD>

            <TD>5/10/12 </TD>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TD>Name </TD>

            <TD>Date Comments Received </TD>

            <TD>No Comments1 </TD>

            <TD>Comments - How Resolved2 </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Dave Bannister </TD>

            <TD>5/10/12 </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Corrected discussed and resolved </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>J. Herman </TD>

            <TD>none </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Woody Goodell </TD>

            <TD>none </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>S. Miller </TD>

            <TD>none </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Susan Baughn </TD>

            <TD>5/10/12 </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Discussed and corrected </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>C. Cameron </TD>

            <TD>5/10/12 </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Discussed and corrected </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>M. Friedman </TD>

            <TD>5/10/12 </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Discussed and corrected </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Lynn Smith </TD>

            <TD>none </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD>Mike Cooper </TD>

            <TD>5/10/12 </TD>

            <TD/>

            <TD>Discussed and corrected </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>

            <TD/>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <Table>
         <TR>
            <TH>Subject: LER 2012-003 “Non-Conservative Error in Calculation for Alternate Hot Leg
               Injection Results in Unanalyzed Condition” </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>NOTE – This submittal does ____ does not __X__ include documents/files on CD-ROM.3
            </TH>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>NL Comment Coordinator Signature E. Matzke </TH>

            <TD>Date 5/10/12 </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Responsible Dept. Manager (if required) </TH>

            <TD>Date </TD>
         </TR>

         <TR>
            <TH>Review by Nuclear Licensing Supervisor </TH>

            <TD>Date </TD>
         </TR>
      </Table>

      <P>1 Attach only signed Licensing Correspondence Review Form. 2 Attach necessary
         documentation. 3 Ensure that the CD-ROM files are formatted properly for electronic
         information exchange (EIE) to the </P>

      <P>NRC. (Reference NL-17) </P>
   </Part>
</TaggedPDF-doc>
