<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-04-24" id="2852012006">
   <abstract>The station identified that the CCW pumps were operating beyond their pump curves with
      the motor running into the service factor, runout conditions were not observed as there were
      no fluctuations in pressure, no fluctuations in motor amps, no visible signs of pitting or
      damage on impeller vain trailing, no damage to internal pump casing surfaces, no abnormal
      vibration, and no abnormal noise. A review of this condition determined that operation in this
      condition is a violation of plant technical specification for CCW operation A cause analysis
      is in progress. The results of the analysis will be published in a supplement to this
      LER.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>The Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Component Cooling Water (CCW) system is a closed
         loop system consisting of three motor driven circulating pumps, four heat exchangers (HX),
         a surge tank, valves, piping, instrumentation and controls. Cooling water flows from the
         cooled components to the HXs from a single header. From the four HXs, the flow goes to the
         three pumps through a single header and back to the cooled components. The surge tank is
         connected at the suction header of the pumps. Heat is transferred from the CCW system to
         the Raw Water (RW) system via the CCW HXs. CCW flows through the shell side and RW flows
         through the tube side of the HXs. The rejected heat is then discharged by the RW system to
         the Missouri River. FCS Technical Specification (TS) 2.4 requires that “The reactor shall
         not be made critical, except for low-temperature physics tests, unless all the following
         are met:” and includes all three CCW pumps. </background>
      <eventDesc>Condition Report (CR) 2012-03254 identified issues related to the CCW pumps
         operating outside of the manufacturer's recommendations. As a result a team was assembled
         to evaluate the condition. The team reviewed historical documentation and operating data.
         The evaluation concluded that the CCW pumps have been operating past the end of their pump
         curves for periods of time beginning in late 1996. This was due to the actions FCS
         implemented in response to NRC Generic Letter (GL) 96-06. The action was to increase the
         overpressure on the CCW surge tank AC-2 and, as a result, the CCW system pressure also
         increased. This action resulted in increasing the pump flows past the manufactures
         recommendations. Although the CCW pumps were operating beyond their pump curves with the
         motor running into the service factor, runout conditions were not observed as there were no
         fluctuations in pressure, no fluctuations in motor amps, no visible signs of pitting or
         damage on impeller vain trailing, no damage to internal pump casing surfaces, no abnormal
         vibration, and no abnormal noise. A review of this condition determined that operation in
         this condition is a violation of FCS TS 2.4 for CCW operation due to the flow being outside
         of the manufactures recommendations. This report is being submitted in accordance with 10
         CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be published in
         a supplement to this LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>Interim action: On 05/07/2012 the CCW System Engineer, after discussion of
         the issue with the Shift Manager, issued the following recommendation: The CCW System
         Engineer has recommended limiting CCW System single pump flow to 5300 to ensure CCW Pump
         operation below the end of the pump curve. If greater CCW system flow is required to meet
         CCW system heat load requirements, it is recommended that the Control Room start and run a
         second CCW Pump. This recommendation will remain in effect until actions associated with CR
         2012-03254 are complete and any subsequent procedure changes have been issued. This
         recommendation applies to normal operations only and is not intended to change or affect
         Operator response to any accident or off normal plant event. This recommendation placed the
         CCW single pump operations back into the region defined by the manufacturer's certified
         curve for normal operations. A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis
         will be published in a supplement to this LER.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be
         published in a supplement to this LER.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does not result in a safety system functional
         failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>A cause analysis is in progress. Previous Events will be determined from the
         results of the cause analysis.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
