<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-02-21" id="2852012005" version="2">
   <abstract>On February 21, 2012, during a review of Fort Calhoun Station surveillance
               procedures, it was identified that the Emergency Diesel Generator (EDG) fuel oil
               transfer pumps have not been tested in accordance with the requirements of Technical
               Specifications (TSs). The inadequate testing was caused by a procedure change made in
               1990 that removed the required monthly test of the automatic low level start feature
               of the fuel oil transfer pumps. There is reasonable assurance that the EDGs and fuel
               transfer pumps would function as required as the low level switches are calibrated on
               a refueling frequency. The apparent cause of this event is a lack of technical rigor
               in the procedure change process employed in 1990s. Corrective actions have been
               developed to revise the EDG surveillances to include fuel oil transfer pump
               surveillance testing.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>The Emergency Diesel Generators (EDGs) fuel oil
         transfer pumps are skid mounted electric pumps located next to each of the EDGs. There are
         two pumps for each EDG. Each EDG has a suction pipe from the diesel generator fuel oil
         storage tank (FO-1). The fuel oil transfer pumps for each EDG draw fuel from the suction
         pipe for the respective EDG. Each EDG has a wall mounted fuel oil day tank that is supplied
         by the fuel transfer pumps. The day tanks have level indication on the outside of the tank,
         a manual drain valve on the bottom of the tank, a vent, and an overflow line that goes back
         to F0-1. Each day tank also has four level switches, high and high-high level switches, and
         low and low-low level switches. The fuel oil transfer pumps have three control switches.
         Each pump has a three-position switch with positions HAND, OFF, and AUTO. There is also a
         two-position selector switch with positions labeled NO 1 and NO 2. During normal operation,
         the control switches for each fuel oil transfer pump are placed in AUTO and the selector
         switch is placed in the NO 1 position. In this arrangement, when the day tank low level
         switch actuates, the number 1 fuel oil transfer pump energizes to fill the tank. In the
         event that the number 1 fuel oil transfer pump fails to operate, the low-low level switch
         will start the number 2 fuel oil transfer pump. With the selector switch in the NO 2
         position, the number 2 fuel oil transfer pump would start on low level and the number 1
         pump would start on low-low level. The original Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Technical
         Specifications (TSs) issued May 24, 1973, included a requirement to test the diesel
         generator fuel oil transfer pumps monthly. Monthly fuel oil transfer pump testing is
         currently required by TS 3.7(1)e. and Table 3-2, Item 12.</background>
      <eventDesc>During a review
         of surveillance procedures, a failure to perform complete surveillance testing of the full
         automatic functions of the EDG fuel oil transfer pumps was identified (Condition Report
         (CR) 2012-01324). However, procedure changes made in 1990 removed the test of the automatic
         start of the fuel oil transfer pumps on low level in the fuel oil day tank. Consequently,
         the EDGs cannot be considered operable because all auxiliary equipment to support
         operability has not demonstrated that it is fully capable of performing its safety
         function. This report is being made per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B),
         50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) and (D), and 50.73(a)(2)(vii). 
      </eventDesc>
         <conclusion>Prior to 1989, fuel oil transfer pump testing
         was included in the EDG surveillance procedures. The cause evaluation identified that the
         specific procedure steps to test the automatic start of the fuel oil transfer pumps on low
         level was removed by a procedure revision made in May 1990. Fuel oil transfer pump trip on
         high level remained in the procedure. The procedure change was prompted by a modification
         that replaced the fuel transfer pumps and added pressure gauges and flow rate meters. Other
         procedure changes not pertinent to the modification were made at the same time. The
         additional changes included fully removing steps to place the fuel oil transfer pump
         transfer switches in AUTO for the purpose of testing. By operating the fuel oil transfer
         pumps in HAND, the length of the monthly EDG run would be shortened. The procedure revision
         summary did not provide discussion on the changes made beyond the scope of the
         modification. The FCS EDG configuration results in unavailability hours under the
         maintenance rule during surveillance testing, so reducing EDG run time would reduce
         unavailability time. The change was made 22 years ago, making it very difficult to
         reconstruct thoughts and discussions surrounding the procedure change. Clearly, there was a
         lack of understanding surrounding the purpose of the testing of the auto start feature of
         the fuel oil transfer pump, but there is no indication that the change was made to violate
         or circumvent TS requirements. Several historical organizational and/or programmatic
         defenses may have failed. The procedure revision process used in the 1990s did not have the
         technical rigor that is currently employed at FCS. In addition, the surveillance test
         program does not clearly link surveillance requirements to specific surveillance tests.
         Furthermore, the design basis document for the EDGs does not currently contain sufficient
         information on fuel oil transfer pump testing and verification. The procedure changes made
         in 1990 removed the test of the automatic start of the fuel oil transfer pumps on low level
         in the EDG day tank. Without full testing of the automatic functions of the fuel oil
         transfer pumps, they cannot be considered operable. Consequently, the EDGs cannot be
         considered operable because all auxiliary equipment to support operability has not
         demonstrated that it is fully capable of performing its safety function. The apparent cause
         of this event is a lack of technical rigor in the procedure change process employed in the
         1990s. Contributing causes are a lack of documentation indicating which surveillance tests
         satisfy specific technical specification surveillance requirements, and a lack of design
         basis information on verification methods for the fuel oil transfer pumps. </conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>1. Prior to plant restart, the Emergency
         Diesel Generator (EDG) surveillance tests will be revised to perform a test of the fuel oil
         transfer pumps ensuring auto operation is verified on a monthly basis. This is an ongoing
         commitment. 2. Prior to plant restart, the EDG design basis document will be updated to
         include verification information for the diesel generator fuel oil transfer pumps. This is
         a one-time commitment.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>Failure to fully test the automatic functions of
         the fuel oil transfer pumps renders the pumps inoperable. Therefore, consistent with the
         definition of OPERABLE, the EDGs cannot be considered operable as they rely upon the fuel
         oil transfer pumps to ensure an adequate fuel supply when the EDGs are performing their
         safety function. The EDGs have been technically inoperable in excess of TS allowed times.
         However, there is reasonable assurance that the EDGs and fuel transfer pumps would function
         as required as the low level switches are calibrated on a refueling frequency.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in
         accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>No previous events of a similar nature have been
         identified.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>