<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-03-19" id="2852012012">
   <abstract>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) operating procedures allow filling and sluicing multiple
      safety injection tanks (SITs) while at power, rendering the SITs inoperable during the
      evolution. The use of this procedure allowed multiple safety injection tanks to be
      concurrently filled while FCS was at power. FCS Technical Specifications (TS) and accident
      analysis do not allow more than one SIT to be inoperable. This condition was identified on
      March 19, 2012, while the unit was in Mode 5, by the NRC during initial license examination
      preparation. A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be published in
      a supplement to this LER.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion
         Engineering (CE) design. The FCS Updated Safety Analysis Report (USAR) Section 6.2.2,
         System Description, states that the safety injection system [BP] for this plant consists of
         both passive and active components. The four pressurized safety injection tanks (SITs) [6A,
         6B, 6C, 6D] are of the passive type and require no outside power or safety injection
         actuation signal to operate. The SITs inject large quantities of borated water into the
         reactor coolant system (RCS) [AB] following a large pipe break. The water rapidly covers
         and cools the core, thereby limiting clad melting and metal water reaction. The separate
         and independent tanks are each connected to one of the four safety injection nozzles [NZL];
         one nozzle is located on each of the four RCS cold legs. The driving head for water
         injection is provided by a nitrogen cover gas at a pressure of 240 pounds per square inch
         (psig) minimum. As the RCS pressure falls below tank pressure, check valves [V] open in the
         line connecting each tank to the system. Thus, these tanks will initiate their discharge
         when the RCS pressure drops below approximately 240 psig minimum. The figure below is
         provided to aid in understanding the event. SI-6A, 6B, 6C, 6D HCV-2916, 2936, 2956, 2976
         HCV-2914, 2934, 2954, 2974 FCS USAR Section 6.2.1, Design Bases, states that the system
         requirements during a Design Basis large break loss of coolant accident (LBLOCA) are met
         with the assumption of three of the four SITs delivering borated water to the core and with
         one high pressure safety injection (HPSI) pump [BQ] delivering approximately 75 percent of
         its rated flow to the core and one low-pressure safety injection (LPSI) pump delivering
         approximately 75 percent of its rated flow to the core. Technical Specification (TS)
         Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 2.3, Emergency Core Cooling, Minimum Requirement
         (1)(c) requires that all four SITs are operable and pressurized to at least 240 psig and a
         maximum of 275 psig with tank level of at least 116.2 inches (67 percent) and a maximum
         level of 128.1 inches (74 percent) with refueling boron concentration. Minimum Requirement
         1(ii) states that all valves, piping and interlocks associated with the above components
         and required to function during accident conditions are operable. Valves HCV-2914, 2934,
         2974, and 2954 (SIT 6A, 6B, 6C and 6D outlet valves) shall have power removed from the
         motor operators by locking open the circuit breakers in the power supply lines to the valve
         motor operators. Valve FCV-326 (Shutdown Cooling Heat Exchangers AC-4A &amp; 4B LPSI Bypass
         Flow Control Valve) shall be locked open. TS LCO 2.3 Modification of Minimum Requirements
         (2)f. states that one safety injection tank may be inoperable for reasons other than g.
         [temperature/pressure] or h. [born concentration] for a period of no more than 24 hours.
         The normal at-power line-up for SIT-6A, 6B, 6C, and 6D is to have HCV-2914 [ISV], 2934,
         2954, and 2974 locked open with power removed and to have HCV-2916, 2936, 2956, and 2976
         (SIT 6A, 6B, 6C and 6D fill/drain valve) closed. Valves HCV-2916, 2936, 2956, and 2976 all
         receive an accident signal to automatically close.</background>
      <eventDesc>FCS operating procedures allow filling and sluicing multiple safety injection tanks
         (SITs) while at power. Since the filling operation requires opening the valves (which
         receive a signal to close post accident), these valves would be required to close via
         electrical signals, which is not a passive feature. Since the tanks are credited as a
         passive feature, the opening of the valves could impact the tanks’ passive design feature,
         hence rendering the SITs inoperable during the evolution. The use of this procedure allowed
         multiple SITs to be concurrently inoperable while FCS was at power. FCS TS and accident
         analysis do not allow more than one SIT to be inoperable. This condition was identified on
         March 19, 2012, while the unit was in Mode 5, by the NRC during initial license examination
         preparation. This report is being submitted in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), 10
         CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(vii)(D). This LER reports a condition where
         multiple SITs could be filled, hence potentially rendering them inoperable using approved
         plant procedures. The initial Operation’s review focused on the current operating
         conditions, noting that the condition would need to be resolved prior to start up. The
         station paradigm inappropriately concluded that reportability could be evaluated at a later
         date since current operating conditions were not challenged, and that the 60-day reporting
         window commenced when the event was determined to be reportable. FCS has been
         systematically addressing issues that have been identified since June 2011, in response to
         the flooding conditions, switchgear fire, and increased oversight. This LER is being
         submitted beyond the 60-day regulatory reporting requirement due to non-conservative
         decisions with respect to procedural and regulatory reportability requirements and resource
         constraints caused by the operating challenges which began in June 2011.</eventDesc>

      <conclusion>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be published in
         a supplement to this LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>A cause analysis is in progress. The corrective actions will be published
         in a supplement to this LER.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>A cause analysis is in progress. The results of the analysis will be
         published in a supplement to this LER.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in
         accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>A cause analysis is in progress. Previous events will be determined from the
         results of the cause analysis.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
