<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-03-02" id="2852012002">
   <abstract>During a review of environmental qualification records for reactor containment building
      electrical penetrations, six penetrations were identified that may not provide an adequate
      seal during worst case (Design Basis Accident (DBA)) conditions as required. These
      penetrations are through wall from the containment into the auxiliary building. A cause
      analysis is in progress and the results will be included in a supplement to this LER. The
      station is currently in a refueling mode. Corrective actions to address the causes of this
      condition will be documented in the supplement to this LER. The subject penetrations will be
      restored to full environmental qualifications prior to plant startup.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station Technical Specification (TS) 2.6(1)a. states: Containment
         integrity shall not be violated unless the reactor is in a cold or refueling shutdown
         condition. Without containment integrity, restore containment integrity within one hour or
         be in at least hot shutdown within the next 6 hours, in at least subcritical and greater
         than 300 degrees Fahrenheit within the next 6 hours and in cold shutdown within the
         following 30 hours. Normally locked or sealed-closed valves (except for PCV-742A/B/C/D) may
         be opened intermittently under administrative control without constituting a violation of
         containment integrity.</background>
      <eventDesc>During research into the qualification of electrical penetrations in reactor
         containment building, discrepancies in the qualification basis of six sealing mechanisms
         (penetration feedthrough assemblies) have been identified. RE-091A and RE-091B (Containment
         Hi Range Monitors) signal cables are affected. HCV-240 (Pressurizer RC-4 Auxiliary Spray
         Inlet Valve), TCV-202 (Reactor Coolant System Loop 2A Letdown Temperature Control Valve),
         HCV-248 (Reactor Coolant System Loop 2A Charging Line Stop Valve) and HCV-249 (Pressurizer
         RC-4 Aux Spray Inlet Valve HCV-240 bypass valve) cables are affected. The affected
         penetrations are original plant equipment. The condition of these penetrations violates TS
         2.6(1)a. This report is being made per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) and 10 CFR
         50.73(a)(2)(i)(B).</eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is in progress and the results will be included in a supplement
         to this LER.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>The station is currently in a refueling mode. Corrective actions to address
         the causes of this condition will be documented in a supplement to this LER. The subject
         electrical penetrations will be restored to full qualification prior to plant
         startup.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>An evaluation of the safety significance of this issue will be completed
         following the completion of the cause analysis.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does not result in a safety system functional
         failure in accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>No previous qualifications issues with containment penetrations have been
         identified.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
