<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-02-21" id="2852012005">
   <abstract>During a QA review of surveillance procedures, an apparent failure to perform
      surveillance testing of the full automatic functions of the fuel oil transfer pumps was
      identified. Technical Specifications require monthly testing of the fuel oil transfer pumps.
      However, procedure changes made in 1990 removed the test of the automatic start of the fuel
      oil transfer pumps on low level in the Emergency Diesel Generator (EDG) day tank. Without full
      testing of the automatic functions of the fuel oil transfer pumps, they cannot be considered
      operable. Consequently, the EDGs cannot be considered operable because all auxiliary equipment
      to support operability has not demonstrated that it is fully capable of performing its safety
      function. There is reasonable assurance that the EDGs and fuel transfer pumps would function
      as required as the low level switches are calibrated on a refueling frequency and have
      functioned correctly during extended EDG surveillances. This report is being made in
      accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B), 50.73(a)(2)(vii), and
      50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) and (D). Corrective actions have been developed to revise the Emergency
      Diesel Generator surveillances to include fuel oil transfer pump surveillance
      testing.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Technical Specifications (TS) require monthly testing
         of the fuel oil transfer pumps. However, procedure changes made in 1990 removed the test of
         the automatic start of the fuel oil transfer pumps on low level in the Emergency Diesel
         Generator (EDG) day tank. Without full testing of the automatic functions of the fuel oil
         transfer pumps, they cannot be considered operable. Consequently, the EDGs cannot be
         considered operable because all auxiliary equipment to support operability has not
         demonstrated that it is fully capable of performing its safety function. “A system,
         subsystem, train, component or device shall be OPERABLE or have OPERABILITY when it is
         capable of performing its specified safety function(s) and when all necessary attendant
         instrumentation, controls, normal or emergency electrical power sources, cooling and seal
         water, lubrication, and other auxiliary equipment that are required for the system,
         subsystem, train, component or device to perform its specified safety function(s) are also
         capable of performing their related support function(s).” Monthly fuel oil transfer pump
         testing is required by TS 3.7(1) e. and Table 3-2, Item 12.</background>
      <eventDesc>During a Quality Assurance (QA) review of surveillance procedures, an apparent
         failure to perform surveillance testing of the full automatic functions of the EDG fuel oil
         transfer pumps was identified. Technical Specifications require monthly testing of the fuel
         oil transfer pumps. However, procedure changes made in 1990 removed the test of the
         automatic start of the fuel oil transfer pumps on low level in the EDG day tank. Without
         full testing of the automatic functions of the fuel oil transfer pumps, they cannot be
         considered operable. Consequently, the EDGs cannot be considered operable because all
         auxiliary equipment to support operability has not demonstrated that it is fully capable of
         performing its safety function.</eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause determination is in progress. The results of the evaluation will be
         published in a revision to this LER. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Corrective actions have been
         developed to revise the EDG surveillance tests to include fuel oil transfer pump
         surveillance testing. Additional corrective actions may be developed based on the
         conclusions of the cause analysis.</conclusion>
      <safetySignificance>Failure to fully test the automatic functions of the fuel oil transfer
         pumps renders the pumps inoperable. Therefore, consistent with the definition of OPERABLE,
         the EDGs cannot be considered operable as they rely upon the fuel oil transfer pumps to
         ensure an adequate fuel supply when the EDGs are performing their safety function. The EDGs
         have been technically inoperable in excess of TS allowed times. However, there is
         reasonable assurance that the EDGs and fuel transfer pumps would function as required as
         the low level switches are calibrated on a refueling frequency and have functioned
         correctly during extended EDG surveillances. FCS TS do not contain electrical system
         requirements for shutdown conditions. The inoperability of the EDGs in the current
         operating MODE does not violate TS. The EDGs will be fully operable prior to plant restart
         and modes of applicability.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in
         accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>Previous events will be identified by the cause analysis and included in the
         supplement to this LER.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
