<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-03-29" id="2852012004">
   <abstract>While investigating operating experience from another station concerning potential
      instrument drift it was determined that Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is subject to similar
      conditions. It was determined that pressure switches that provide safety related signals for
      high containment pressure to the reactor protection system (RPS) and engineered safeguards
      actuation circuitry may be similarly affected at FCS. The impact of the potential drift was
      evaluated and it was determined that neither RPS nor the engineered safeguard circuitry may
      actuate at the required containment pressure of 5 psig. An evaluation determined that the
      actuation may not occur until slightly higher than the required pressure. Other systems are
      currently being evaluated for this condition. A cause analysis is being performed and will be
      provided in a supplement to this report. Corrective actions will be determined following the
      completion of the cause analysis.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <eventDesc>While investigating operating experience from another station it was determined
         that Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is subject to similar conditions. The operating experience
         involved setpoint drift of safety-related pressure switches beyond what had been accounted
         for in the station’s safety analyses. Following investigation and evaluation, it was
         determined that pressure switches that provide safety-related signals for high containment
         pressure to the reactor protection system (RPS) and engineered safeguards actuation
         circuitry may be similarly affected at FCS. The impact of the potential drift was evaluated
         and it was determined that neither RPS nor the engineered safeguard circuitry may actuate
         at the required containment pressure of 5 psig. An evaluation determined that the actuation
         may occur at a slightly higher value than the required pressure. Other systems are
         currently being evaluated for the condition. On May 2, 2012, an eight (8) hour report was
         made per 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B) to the NRC Headquarters Operation Office (HOO) at 1802
         CDT (Event Number (EN) 47892). After further evaluation this report is being made per 10
         CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) and (a)(2)(v)(A,B,C,D). </eventDesc>
      <conclusion>A cause analysis is being performed and the results will be provided in a
         supplement to this report.</conclusion>
      <correctiveActions>Corrective actions will be determined following the completion of the cause
         analysis.</correctiveActions>
      <safetySignificance>A cause analysis is in progress. The safety significance of this event
         will be provided in a supplement to this LER following completion of the
         analysis.</safetySignificance>
      <safetySystemFunctionalFailure>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in
         accordance with NEI-99-02.</safetySystemFunctionalFailure>
      <previousEvents>No events of a similar nature have been identified.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
