<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-07-12T13:59:09-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Böwe Bell+Howell 1400u TWAIN</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-07-12T13:59:50-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-07-12T13:59:50-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:979d8caf-1e70-454e-8b9f-a8ed0c197d97</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:cdb709ee-fc77-8044-934e-e687ecb8447a</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>~?* </P><Part><H1>&amp;;;;;B
</H1><P>-
</P><P>~-~ </P><P>Omaha Public Power District </P><P>444 South 16th Street Mall Omaha NE 68102-2247 </P><P>July 12, 2010 LlC-10-0052 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555 </P><P>Reference: 	Docket \\lo. 50-285 </P><P>Subject: 	Special Report on Inoperability of Main Steam Line Radiation Monitor RM-064 for Post Accident Monitoring </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>The Omaha Public Power District (OPPD), holder of Renewed Operating License DPR-40, submits this report pursuant to the requirements of Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Technical Specification (TS) 2.21, &quot;Post Accident Monitoring Instrumentation.&quot; Technical Specification 2.21', Table 2-10, specifies the minimum operable channels for several post accident monitoring instruments. If the required instrumentation is not operable, then the appropriate actions specified in Table 2-10 are to be taken . </P><P>Technical Specification 2.21, Table 2-10, item 3, specifies a minimum of one operable channel for the Main Steam Line Radiation Monitor, RM-064. </P><P>Footnote (a) of Table 2-10 states: </P><P>(a) With the number of OPERABLE channels less than required by the minimum channels operabl'e requirements, initiate the pre-planned alternate method of monitoring the appropriate parameter(s) within 72 hours, and </P><L><LI><LI_Label>1. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>either restore the inoperable channel(s) to OPERABLE status within 7 days of the event, or </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>2. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>prepare and submit a special report to the Commission pursuant to specification 5.9.3 within 14 days following the event outlining the action taken, the cause of the inoperability, and the plans and schedules for restoring the system to OPERABLE status. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission L1C-10-0052 Page 2 </P><P>Radiation Monitor RM-064, Accident Range Main Steam Line Radiation Monitor, did not successfully pass its surveillance test (ST) after removal from service at 0402 COT on June 28, 2010. The rate display started trending up at approximately 2130 COT on June 28, 2010. Background and checksource counts increased approximately 200 percent, outside the acceptance criteria for the ST. RM-064 was declared inoperable as of 0402 COT on June 28, 2010. The counts returned to normal, at 1600 COT on June 30, 2010. The cause of the unexpected upward count-rate trend of RM-064 has yet to be determined. No work was being performed on the monitor when it trended up or when it trended back to normal. RM-064 remains inoperable. </P><P>Since the duration of the inoperability of RM-064 has exceeded seven days, this special report is required . </P><P>Radiation Monitor RM-064 is an accident range, main steam line radiation monitor, so the alternate sampling is described in EPIP-EOF-6, &quot;Dose Assessment&quot; Attachment 6.5, Section 3 &quot;Determining Actual Release From Field Team Data.&quot; </P><P>It is expected that RM-064 will be returned to service no later than July 30, 2010. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact me. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Je r y A. Reinhart Sit ice President </P><P>JAR/rda </P><P>c: E. E. Collins, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland , NRC Senior Resident Inspector </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>