<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-10-08T11:21:02-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Böwe Bell+Howell 1400u TWAIN</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-10-08T11:24:20-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-10-08T11:24:20-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:e9aa0459-d45b-421b-9e2d-a27972c16877</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:2175f5a2-7ab8-4f4b-95a7-961f0f543de3</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>-
</P><P>Omah6 Public Puwe,District 444 South 161h Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>October 8, 2010 LIC-1 0-0090 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Wash.ington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Reference: 	Docket No. 50-285 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2010·005, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2010-005, Revision 0, dated October 8, 2010. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </P><P>No regulatory commitments are contained in this submittal. If you should have any questions, please contact me. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Je, rey A. Reinhart Site Vice President </P><P>JAR/rmc </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: E. E. Collins, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector I N PO Records Center </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORYCOMMISSION (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT R~PORT (LER) I (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH><Link>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 08/31/2010 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hrs. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAlPnvacy Service Branch (T-5 F52), U.S Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001 . or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer. Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. NEOB-10202. (3150-0104). Office of Management and Budget. Washington. DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to. the information collection. </Link></TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER , 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Inoperability of the Emergency Diesel Generator Fuel Oil Transfer System </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>REVYEAR AL NONUMBER ISEQUENTI I </TD><TD>MONT H </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME D0</TD><TD>OCKET NUMBER 5000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>I 1 </TH><TD>6 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>2010 -00500 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>8 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME 0</TD><TD>5000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. ntis REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check al/ that apply) 0 20.2201 (b) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 0 20.2201(d) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) 0 20.2203(a)(1 ) 0 20.2203(a)(4 ) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(9) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(9) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(i) 0 5O.36(c){1I)(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 0 50.36(c)( 1 )(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(x) I 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.36(c)(2) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) 0 73.71(a)(4) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 0 50.46(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(9) 0 73.71 (a)(5) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50. 73(a )(2)(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) 0 OTHER 0 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) X 5O .73(a)(2)(i)(9) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100, I </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Erick Matzke 402-533-6855 ITELEPHONE NUMBER (include Area Code) </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONEN T </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD/><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE ITO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>I 14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED XX Yes (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>1 </TD><TD>28 </TD><TD>2011 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces. i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) Diesel Fuel Oil Transfer Pump FO-37 and its credited portable back-up pump were inoperable on January 6-7, 2010. On January 6, 2010, FO-37 was rendered inoperable due to local area flooding caused by the rupture of FP-772, &quot;Service Building Fire Sprinkler Isolation Valve&quot;. The function of FO-37 is to transfer diesel fuel between &quot;Diesel Fuel Oil Storage Tanks&quot; FO10 and Fa-I. On June 24, 2010, an engineering evaluation determined that the credited portable back up pump to FO-37 was not the correct pump for the application and would not transfer diesel fuel oil from FO-l 0 to FO-I as intended. Since both pumps (FO-37 and the credited portable back-up pump) were inoperable this is reportable in accordance with 10 CFR 50. 73(a)(2)( i)(B). The root cause of the event is still under investigation and will be reported in a supplement to this LER The originally credited portable back-up pump was replaced with a new portable pump that has the capability to transfer diesel fuel oil between tanks FO-10 and FO-l. The appropriate procedures were revised to address the pump replacement. I I , </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (9-2007) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><P>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </P><P>(9-2007) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</P><Table><TR><TD>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TD><TD>2. DOCKET 05000285 </TD><TD>6. LER NUM,BER YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER r 2010 -005 </TD><TD>REV NO. 00 </TD><TD>2 </TD><TD>3. PAGE OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>BACKGROUND </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>On March 29, 1994, Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) received approval (Teclmical Specification (TS) amendment 162) to revise TS 2.7( I)m that enabled the configuration of the fuel oil system for the emergency diesel generators to meet Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) 308, &quot;Standard Criteria for Class 1 E Power Systems for Nuclear Power Generating Stations.&quot; This provides FCS the capability to provide diesel fuel oil for seven days of diesel generator operation following the most limiting accident condition. The revised TS 2.7( I )m, &quot;Limiting Condition for Operation, Electrical Systems, Applicability, Minimum Requirements (plant greater than 300 degrees F)&quot; states, &quot;One diesel fuel oil storage system containing a minimum volume of 16,000 gallons of diesel fuel in FO-I and a minimum volume of 10,000 gallons of diesel fuel in FO-IO.&quot; </P><P>The FCS diesel fuel oil system is defined in part as, FO-I, FO-I 0, FO-37, the credited portable back-up pump, associated </P><P>piping, other pumps, valves, portable hoses and instmmentation. </P><P>The original ficensed configuration was to solely use the fuel oil inventory in FO-I, which contains approximately four days </P><P>supply for the emergency diesel generators. The TS amendment changes included combining the fuel oil inventories of FO-I </P><P>and FO-I 0, &quot;Auxiliary Boiler (AS-I) Fuel Oil Tank&quot; which would extend the operation of the emergency diesel generators to </P><P>seven days. FO-I and FO-I 0 are separate tanks and are not physically connected. </P><P>The TS amendment 162 &quot;Discussion, Justification and No Significant Hazards Consideration&quot; section stated that fuel oil </P><P>make-up to FO-I could be achieved by manually connecting FO-37 from FO-lO to FO-I through mbber hose connections. </P><P>Additionally, a portable pump and hoses were dedicated and stored in an appropriate place as a back-up to FO-37. A </P><P>preventative maintenance task was developed to periodically verify the pump and hoses are available for use . Since the </P><P>portable pump is a credited back-up to FO-37, then FO-37 can be out-of-service without violating the TS requirement of </P><P>having an operable &quot;fuel oil storage system.&quot; </P><P>FO-37 is a non-Critical Quality Element (CQE) positive displacement pump capable of transferring fuel oil from FO-IO to FOI, through rubber hose cOimectiolls, at a rate of 5.8 gpm. The credited portable back-up pump was a non-CQE manual double diaphragm Munster Simms Whale Gusher 30 bilge pump with a nominal rating of 29 gpm. </P><P>FCS Procedure EPIP-RR-17A, &quot;TSC Administrative Logistics Coordinator Actions&quot; contains instmctions on the use ofFO-37 and the portable back-up pump to transfer diesel fuel from FO-l 0 to FO-I. This procedure also addresses the contingency to have diesel fuel oil delivered via truck from a local vendor. This helps to ensure that there is sufficient diesel fuel oil on site should an accident requiring sustained emergency diesel generator operation. </P><P>EVENT DESCRlPTION </P><P>On January 6-7, 20 I 0, due to local area flooding FO-37 was rendered inoperable for approximately 24 hours. In response to NRC Resident Inspector questions an engineering review was performed on June 24, 2010, on the capability of the portable back-up pump. This review revealed that the portable back-up pump was not the correct pump for the application and it could not perform its intended function of transferring diesel fuel oil from FO-I 0 to FO-I in the event that FO-37 was inoperable. Additionally, on August 30,2010, the portable back-up pump failed a functional test when the pump diaphragm ruptured. </P><P>Since FO-37 was inoperable on January 6-7, 20 I 0, and an engineering evaluation determined the portable back-up pump was not capable of transferring diesel fuel oil from FO-I 0 to FO-J, then these two components, that are part of the diesel fuel oil system required by TS 2.7(1)m were inoperable concurrently, then this condition is reportable in accordance with 10 CFR 73(a)(2)(i)(B). </P><P>NKl,; ~UKM J66. (9-2UUf) t-'KIN I t:w ON RECYCLED PAPER NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY-COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6_ LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>05000285 </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 I </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 -005 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE CONCLUSION The root cause is currently under investigation and will be repOlied in a supplement to this LER. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS The non-CQE manual double diaphragm Munster Simms Whale Gusher 30 bilge pump was replaced with a Filterdyne Portable filtration System, Model 757.10.1 and procedure EPIP-RR-17 A was revised to address the use of the Filterdyne Portable Filtration System for use as the credited back-up to FO-37. Other actions will be addressed by the FCS corrective action program. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The transfer of diesel fuel oil from FO-l 0 to FO-l can be accomplished by FO-37, or other portable back-up pumps. FCS procedures also address the delivery of diesel fuel oil on site from a local vendor. Since there are several methods to transfer diesel fuel oil to FO-I , this event has no effect on the health and safety of the public. SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This event does not result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEl-99-02. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS Previous similar events are currently being researched and will be provided in a supplement to this LER. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>