<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">Microsoft Word - LIC-12-0003.docx</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
         <dc:creator>
            <rdf:Seq>
               <rdf:li>x13568</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Seq>
         </dc:creator>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-01-17T13:53:34-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-01-17T14:44:20-06:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-01-17T14:44:20-06:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:51a41585-344c-4c43-8450-69d6f00786e8</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:ebcf6a9d-9845-9147-be6f-ee8a868873d5</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>~~
</P><Part><H1>DjjjjD 
</H1><P>~.... -</P><P>Omaha Publlt: PDwrn IJIBIIfct 444 South 16th Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LlC-12-0003 January 16, 2012 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><Table><TR><TD>Reference: </TD><TD>Docket No. 50-285 </TD></TR><TR><TD>Subject: </TD><TD>Licensee Event Report 2011-010, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>Station </TD></TR></Table><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2011-010, Revision 0, dated, January 16, 2012. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A), (B), (C) and (D). If you should have any questions, please contact me. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>»-~ 
</P><P>D. J. Bannister Vice President and Chief Nuclear Officer Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>DJB /epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: E. E. Collins, Jr., NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector INPO Records Center </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are inco rporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Priv acy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulator y Commission, Washington, DC 205 55-0001, or b y internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informationand Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management andBudget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an informationcollection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC maynot conduct or sp onsor, and a person is not required to respond to, th e information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Fire Causes a Circuit Breaker to Open Outside Design Assumptions </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>6 </TH><TD>7 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>2011 -010 -0 </TD><TD>1 </TD><TD>16 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply)  20.2201(b)  20.2203(a)(3)(i) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 50.73(a)(2)(vii)   20.2201(d)  20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)   20.2203(a)(1)  20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)   20.2203(a)(2)(i)  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)   20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(x) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii)   50.36(c)(2) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)  73.71(a)(4)  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)  50.46(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)  73.71(a)(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(v)  50.73(a)(2)(i)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) OTHER  20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below  or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 0 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Erick Matzke </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 402-533-6855 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>6 </TD><TD>29 </TD><TD>2012 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 7, 2011, a bus fault in load center 1B4A initiated a switch gear fire that resulted in the opening of a circuit breaker which supplies power to load center 1B3A, associated with the opposite train. A fire in one fire area that resulted in a loss of power to a load center associated with the opposite train is not in compliance with 10 CFR 50, Appendix R. The analysis assumes that a fire in a fire area affecting one train of power will be isolated such that power associated with the redundant train will be maintained. A root cause analysis is being performed to determine the cause of the failure. The affected bus was de-energized and the Halon system extinguished the fire. The Halon system was recharged and restored to service. Inspections and testing of the unaffected 480 V buses, the supply circuit breakers to the 480 V buses, and the 480 V bus tie circuit breakers were performed. Appropriate 480 V supply circuit breakers and bus tie circuit breakers passed their inspections and testing. The fire damaged switchgear (1B4A), which contains two 480V supply circuit breakers, 1B4A and BT-1B4A (supply circuit breaker to the associated “island” bus), is being replaced. Additional corrective actions will be specified following the completion of the root cause analysis. </TH></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12018A044_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 2 OF 3 2011 -010 -0 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET BACKGROUND Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering (CE) design. The plant has six safety-related 480 VAC (V) buses and three 480 V safety related “island” cross-tie buses.  The island buses are fed from one side or the other of the main 480 V buses.  Load center 1B3A and 1B3C normally feed island buses in the east switchgear room, and 1B4C normally feeds an island bus in the west switchgear room.  Non-segregated bus work connects each island bus to its alternate power supply on the opposite switchgear side.  The 480 V bus feeder circuit breakers are NLI/Square D Masterpact circuit breakers with Micrologic trip units. EVENT DESCRIPTION On June 7, 2011, a bus fault in load center 1B4A initiated a switch gear fire that resulted in the opening of a circuit breaker which supplies power to load center 1B3A, associated with the opposite train. The fact that a fire in one fire area resulted in a loss of power to a load center associated with the opposite train is inconsistent with assumptions made in the 10 CFR 50, Appendix R Safe Shutdown analysis. This compliance analysis assumes that a fire in a fire area affecting one train of power will be isolated such that power associated with the redundant train will be maintained. Although there was local indication at the circuit breaker that the 1B3A main feeder circuit breaker opened due to an overcurrent condition, other available information does not conclusively indicate that a fault that should have opened the 1B3A main feeder circuit breaker actually occurred. Investigation is continuing into the cause of the trip of the 1B3A main feeder circuit breaker. On November 15, 2011, this event was determined to be reportable per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v).  This event is being reported per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A), (B), (C) and (D). CONCLUSION During normal plant operation, 480V load center and bus tie circuit breakers are expected to remain closed to provide 480V, three phase power to their associated buses. In the event of a fault on the associated bus, a load center circuit breaker or bus tie circuit breaker should open to isolate the fault without opening the next circuit breaker upstream, i.e., the circuit breakers should coordinate to isolate the fault by preserving power to loads not directly impacted by the fault. The FCS 10 CFR 50, Appendix R, Safe Shutdown Analysis credits coordination of the 480 V load center and bus tie circuit breakers for a fire in either switchgear room by assuming that a fault resulting from the fire damaged switchgear will be isolated by bus tie circuit breakers associated with the opposite train. Isolation of the fault by the bus tie circuit breakers will result in one train of AC power remaining in operation during a worst case fire event. The 10 CFR 50, Appendix R, Safe Shutdown Analysis demonstrates that the plant can be safely brought to hot shutdown from an operating mode and subsequently to cold shutdown with a worst case fire in any fire area in the plant. Coordination of plant circuit breakers is analyzed in the FCS, “Breaker/Fuse Coordination Study.” The two analyses referenced in this discussion support the FCS Updated Safety Analysis Report (USAR) requirement that “Design provisions were made to limit fire damage to one train of the electrical systems…” 480 V load center and bus tie circuit breakers are expected to remain closed under normal conditions to provide power to buses to which they are aligned within the loading limitations as established in operating procedures. In the event of a fault on a main bus or island bus, the circuit breaker supplying </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12018A044_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 3 OF 3 2011 -010 -0 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET that bus should open to isolate the fault without tripping upstream circuit breakers. Load center circuit breakers should not open due to a fault or fire in the opposite train. 10 CFR 50, Appendix R design assumptions are that a fire in either the east or west switchgear room will result in the loss of switchgear in the affected room, but will not impact the operability of the switchgear in the opposite room. During the fire in 1B4A, the formation of fire residue (soot) on the non-segregated bus stabs within 1B4A switchgear bus tie circuit breaker cubicle created fault currents that were sensed by circuit breaker 1B3A.  At the time of the event, circuit breaker BT-1B4A was open and circuit breaker BT-1B3A was closed supplying island bus 1B3A-4A. An NRC Part 21 (2005-039) addressed spurious tripping of the Micrologic trip devices, and the supplier Nuclear Logistics Incorporated (NLI) added a filter capacitor to the trip module.  Additionally, a subsequent industry spurious trip of NLI/Square D Masterpact circuit breakers in 2008 (OE 21873) resulted in a design change to the trip module.  The NLI/Square D Masterpact circuit breakers replaced in 2009, contained the industry operating experience of the Micrologic trip units, and the vendor confirmed the FCS trip units contained the upgrades driven by the NRC Part 21 (2005-039). CORRECTIVE ACTIONS As documented in LER 2011-008 (Fire in Bus 1B4A) the following actions have been or are being taken: The affected bus was de-energized and the Halon system extinguished the fire.  The Halon system was recharged and restored to service. FCS conducted inspections and testing of the unaffected 480 V buses, the supply circuit breakers to the 480 V buses, and the 480 V bus tie circuit breakers.  The tested 480 V supply circuit breakers and bus tie circuit breakers passed their inspections and testing. FCS is replacing the affected bus (1B4A), which contains two 480 V supply circuit breakers, 1B4A and BT-1B4A (supply circuit breaker to the associated “island” bus). Additional corrective actions will be determined following completion of the root cause for this event. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The safety significance will be fully evaluated following completion of the root cause analysis for this event. SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This event does result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02. PREVIOUS EVENTS LER 2011-008 documents the fire associate with this event. </Figure><Table><TR><TD>FORT CALHOUN STATION </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>NOD-QP-9.2 </TD></TR><TR><TD>QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TD><TD/><TD>R0 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>LICENSING CORRESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>LIC-12-0003 </TD><TD/></TR></Table><P>Date Issued:  1/6/12 Requested Return Date:____1/11/12______ 
</P><Table><TR><TH>Review/Approval </TH><TH>Information </TH></TR><TR><TH>Dave Bannister </TH><TD/><TD>Brad Blome </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TH>John Herman </TH><TD/><TD>Woody Goodell </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Steve Miller </TH><TD/><TD>Tim Nellenbach </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Susan Baughn </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Chris Sterba </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Dave Digiacinto </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>John Adams </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Fred Fork </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>C. Cameron </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Mike Cooper </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>Subject: ___ LER 2011-010 “Fire Creates Fault Currents Outside Design Assumptions.” </P><P>Please review and approve the attached draft correspondence (referenced above).  In order to document your review for our records, please sign this form and return it to the Licensing Coordinator.  If n o notification is received by the requested return date, your concurrence with no comment will be assumed.   </P><P>E. Matzke 6855_ 
Technical Coordinator   (Ext.) Licensing Coordinator   (Ext.) 
</P><P>[ ] Approved with no comment.        [ ] Approved pending resolution of comments as          noted. </P><P>Comments:_______________________________________________________________________________ </P><Table><TR><TH>___________________________ </TH></TR><TR><TH>___ </TH><TD>_________________ </TD></TR><TR><TH>       Reviewer's Signature </TH><TD>Date </TD></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>FORT CALHOUN STATION QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TH><TH>NOD-QP-9.2 R0 </TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSING CORRESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM SUMMARY </TH><TD/></TR><TR><TH>LIC-12-0003 </TH><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Date Issued:  </TH><TD>1/6/12 </TD><TD>Requested Return Date: </TD><TD>1/11/12 </TD><TD/></TR></Table><Table><TR><TD>Name </TD><TD>Date Comments Received </TD><TD>No Comments1 </TD><TD>Comments - How Resolved2 </TD></TR><TR><TD>Dave Bannister </TD><TD>1/7/*12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected </TD></TR><TR><TD>J. Herman </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Woody Goodell </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Tim Nellenbach </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Susan Baughn </TD><TD>1/11/12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected </TD></TR><TR><TD>Mike Cooper </TD><TD>1/11/12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected </TD></TR><TR><TD>Steve Miller </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Chris Sterba </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Brad Blome </TD><TD>1/10/12 </TD><TD>X </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Dave Digiacinto </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>John Adams </TD><TD>1/9/12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected </TD></TR><TR><TD>Fred Fork </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>C. Cameron </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>Subject: ___ LER 2011-010 “Fire Creates Fault Currents Outside Design Assumptions.” </TH></TR><TR><TH>NOTE – This submittal does  ____  does not __X__ include documents/files on CD-ROM.3 </TH></TR><TR><TH>NL Comment Coordinator Signature E. Matzke </TH><TD>Date 1/16/12 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Responsible Dept. Manager (if required) </TH><TD>Date </TD></TR><TR><TH>Review by Nuclear Licensing Supervisor </TH><TD>Date 1/16/12 </TD></TR></Table><P>1  Attach only signed Licensing Correspondence Review Form. 
2  Attach necessary documentation. 
3 Ensure that the CD-ROM files are formatted properly for electronic information exchange (EIE) to the 
</P><P>NRC. (Reference NL-17) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>