<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:creator>
            <rdf:Seq>
               <rdf:li>x13568</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Seq>
         </dc:creator>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">Microsoft Word - LIC-12-0160.docx</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-10-27T10:22:49-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-10-31T09:41:11-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-10-31T09:41:11-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:4ebeb15e-2411-4b5e-8a21-68bad10efb3f</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:9a3f9bf7-2334-e849-b4b3-612d261a779c</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/>-&quot;11Omaha Public Powtlr DI$IdcI </Figure><P>-~</P><P>444 South 16th Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LlC-12-0160 October 27, 2012 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><Table><TR><TD>Reference: </TD><TD>Docket No. 50-285 </TD></TR><TR><TD>Subject: </TD><TD>Licensee Event Report 2012-004, Revision 2, for the Fort Calhoun </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>Station </TD></TR></Table><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2012-004, Revision 2, dated 
October 27,2012. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8). 
No commitments are being made in this letter. 
If you should have any questions, please contact me. 
</P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Louis P. Cortopassi Vice President and CNO </P><P>LPC/rjr </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: E. E. Collins, Jr., NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector INPO Records Center </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are inco rporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Priv acy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulator y Commission, Washington, DC 205 55-0001, or b y internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informationand Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management andBudget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an informationcollection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC maynot conduct or sp onsor, and a person is not required to respond to, th e information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Inadequate Analysis of Drift Affects Safety Related Equipment </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>03 </TH><TD>29 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 -004 -2 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>27 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply)  20.2201(b)  20.2203(a)(3)(i) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 50.73(a)(2)(vii)   20.2201(d)  20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)   20.2203(a)(1)  20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)   20.2203(a)(2)(i)  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)   20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(x) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii)   50.36(c)(2) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)  73.71(a)(4)  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)  50.46(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)  73.71(a)(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(v)  50.73(a)(2)(i)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) OTHER  20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract belowor in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 0 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Erick Matzke </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 402-533-6855 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) While investigating industry operating experience, it was determined that Fort Calhoun Station is subject to similar conditions where Static &quot;0&quot; Ring pressure switches with certain housing styles exhibit a setpoint shift when exposed to a change in temperature if the switch body is not vented. Fort Calhoun Station pressure switches that provide signals for high containment pressure to the reactor protection system and engineered safeguards actuation circuitry may have this configuration. The impact of the potential drift was evaluated and it was initially determined that neither reactor protection system nor the engineered safeguard circuitry may actuate at the required containment pressure of 5 psig. A subsequent evaluation of actual data concluded that safety analysis limits were not exceeded. However, two Technical Specification limits were not protected by the calibration procedure nominal trip setpoint when applying the additional uncertainty. The Apparent Cause was determined to be poor vendor documentation which led to Engineering personnel to improperly interpret and apply the information contained in the Static “O” Ring vendor manual. Corrective actions were initiated to remove the vent caps, revise the affected calculations to the temperature correction factor and drift. Additional actions to revise and re-perform surveillance testing were initiated. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12305A319_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 2 OF 4 2012 -004 -2 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET EVENT DESCRIPTION While investigating industry operating experience, it was determined that Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is subject to similar conditions.  The operating experience documented a condition where Static &quot;0&quot; Ring (SOR) pressure switches with housing styles N6 or RT and conduit seal option JJ, exhibit a setpoint shift when exposed to a change in temperature if the switch body is not vented. Engineering performed an equipment database search to determine where the switches in question were installed at FCS.  Several switches that input into specific Reactor Protection System (RPS) and Engineered Safeguards Actuation Circuitry (ESF) loops were in the affected population.  Specifically these pressure switches provide safety-related signals for high containment pressure to the RPS and ESF. Field inspection revealed that the vent plugs were installed on the subject SOR switches and therefore the temperature effect is applicable.  No other interim actions were required at the time of discovery as the affected switches are not required in the current plant mode. The impact of the potential drift was evaluated and it was determined that neither RPS nor the engineered safeguard circuitry may actuate at the required containment pressure of 5 psig.  A preliminary evaluation determined that the actuation may occur at a slightly higher value than the required pressure. A subsequent analysis of actual data concluded that safety analysis limits were not exceeded and that only two TS Limits were not protected by the calibration procedure nominal trip setpoint when applying the additional uncertainty. On May 2, 2012, an eight (8)-hour report was made per 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B) to the NRC Headquarters Operation Office (HOO) at 1802 CDT (Event Number (EN) 47892) as an unanalyzed condition, which was retracted on October 16, 2012.  As a result of the analysis discussed above, this LER is amending the previous reporting criteria. This report is being made in accordance with the requirements of 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). The reporting requirements of 10 CRF 50.73(a)(2)(v) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) have been deleted. CONCLUSION The condition was initially determined to be reportable under 10 CFR50 72(b )(3)(ii)(B), Unanalyzed Condition, based on a conservative assumption that the error introduced violated not only the Technical Specification (TS) limits on Tables 2-1 and 2-11 (5.0 psig) but also the safety analysis limit of 5.4 psig, Updates Safety Analysis Repot (FSAR) Table 14.1-1.  A subsequent evaluation of actual data concluded that safety analysis limits were not exceeded and that two TS Limits were not protected by the calibration procedure nominal trip setpoint when applying the additional uncertainty. The cause was determined to be poor vendor documentation which led Engineering personnel to improperly interpret and apply the information contained in the SOR vendor manual. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS FCS is currently conducting a Causal Analysis as part of the Restart Checklist Item 3.d.1.  The results of this analysis will be provided separately to the NRC as part of the Confirmatory Action Letter (CAL) closure process. Corrective actions specific to this condition were initiated which include the following: </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12305A319_img_3.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 3 OF 4 2012 -004 -2 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET 1. For SOR switches used in safety related applications for which Uncertainty Calculations exist, a. Revise the associated calculations to include the temperature correction factor and drift as specified in the vendor manual, b. Revise the associated surveillance tests based on the updated Uncertainty Calculations, and c. Update the Equipment Database information as needed. 2. For SOR switches used in safety related applications for which Uncertainty Calculations do not exist and the evaluation was indeterminate, perform an analysis to evaluate the impact of temperature and drift on the setpoints and implement recommendations from the analysis. 3. For the non-safety related switches, revise the affected calculation or modify the switches to install breather drains, revise and perform the affected surveillance tests, and update the Equipment Database information as necessary. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE Both the actual nuclear safety impact and the potential nuclear safety impact for this event are low based on the following considerations. The affected pressure switches provide safety related signals for high containment pressure to the reactor protection system (RPS) and engineered safeguards actuation system (ESFAS) circuitry.  Specifically, the switches perform the following functions as specified in the FCS Technical Specifications: • Technical Specification Table 2-11, RPS Limiting Safety System Settings, item 7, High Containment Pressure s 5 psig; Reactor Trip • Technical Specification Table 2-1, Engineered Safety Features System Initiation Instrument Setting Limits Item 1, High Containment Pressure s 5 psig; Safety Injection, Containment Spray, Containment Isolation, Containment Air Cooler- DBA Mode, and Steam Generator Isolation While the Technical Specification limit is 5 psig, a review of the FCS USAR shows that the setpoint value used in the accident analysis is 5.4 psig. This is shown in Table 14.1-1- Reactor Protective System Trips and Safety Injection for Safety Analyses Setpoints which identifies a Containment Pressure High Setpoint of 5.0 psig and a Safety Analysis Setpoint 5.4 psig.  This specific actuation feature is credited only in USAR 14.6, &quot;Containment Pressure Analysis&quot;, which credits the switches for initiation of Engineered Safety Features at a setpoint of 5.4 psig. Further analysis was performed to determine the worst case installed setpoint value when the temperature effect is included.  This was done by adding the temperature effect associated with a 30°F temperature shift to the worst case &quot;as found&quot; value from the historical calibration data and verifying that value is less than the value used in the accident analysis.  From this it was determined that the worst case installed setpoint was less than the value of 5.4 psig used in the safety analysis.  This demonstrates that while the trip setpoint used in the calibration procedure may not be adequate to protect the Technical Specification limits, the safety limit used in the accident analysis was not exceeded and therefore this condition did not impact Nuclear Safety. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12305A319_img_4.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 4 OF 4 2012 -004 -2 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This event does result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02. PREVIOUS EVENTS No events of a similar nature have been identified. </Figure></TaggedPDF-doc>