<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:creator>
            <rdf:Seq>
               <rdf:li>x7002</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Seq>
         </dc:creator>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">Microsoft Word - LIC-12-0043.docx</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-05-01T17:32:21-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-07-26T08:41:53-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-07-26T08:41:53-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:bb457663-8120-41e6-909b-63ecf1671562</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:28f18f97-00db-3c44-a67d-94b95155e2d9</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>r?~ </P><Part><H1>nlllln</H1><P>---</P><P>Omaha Public Power Distriel </P><P>444 South 1611/ Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LlC-12-0043 May 1, 2012 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Reference: 	Docket No. 50-285 </P><Sect><H4>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2012-002, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station </H4><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2012-002, Revision 0, dated May 1, 2012. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact me. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>~~~ </P><P>D. J. Bannister Site Vice President and CNO </P><P>DJB /epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: E. E. Collins, Jr., NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector 
INPO Records Center 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)(See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB:  NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Privacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informationand Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management andBudget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC maynot conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Inadequate Qualifications for Containment  Penetrations Renders Containment Inoperable </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>3 </TH><TD>2 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 -002 -0 </TD><TD>5 </TD><TD>1 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply)  20.2201(b)  20.2203(a)(3)(i)  50.73(a)(2)(i)(C)  50.73(a)(2)(vii)   20.2201(d)  20.2203(a)(3)(ii)  50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)   50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)   20.2203(a)(1)  20.2203(a)(4)  50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)   50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)   20.2203(a)(2)(i)  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(iii)  50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)   20.2203(a)(2)(ii)  50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A)   50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)   50.73(a)(2)(x) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii)   50.36(c)(2)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)   73.71(a)(4)  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)  50.46(a)(3)(ii)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)   73.71(a)(5)  20.2203(a)(2)(v)   50.73(a)(2)(i)(A)   50.73(a)(2)(v)(C)  OTHER  20.2203(a)(2)(vi)  50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)   50.73(a)(2)(v)(D)  Specify in Abstract below   or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Erick Matzke </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 402-533-6855 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>7 </TD><TD>18 </TD><TD>2012 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) During a review of environmental qualification records for reactor containment building electrical penetrations, six penetrations were identified that may not provide an adequate seal during worst case (Design Basis Accident (DBA)) conditions as required. These penetrations are through wall from the containment into the auxiliary building. A cause analysis is in progress and the results will be included in a supplement to this LER. The station is currently in a refueling mode.  Corrective actions to address the causes of this condition will be documented in the supplement to this LER. The subject penetrations will be restored to full environmental qualifications prior to plant startup. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12208A313_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 2 OF 3 2012 -002 -0 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET BACKGROUND Fort Calhoun Station Technical Specification (TS) 2.6(1)a. states: Containment integrity shall not be violated unless the reactor is in a cold or refueling shutdown condition. Without containment integrity, restore containment integrity within one hour or be in at least hot shutdown within the next 6 hours, in at least subcritical and greater than 300 degrees Fahrenheit within the next 6 hours and in cold shutdown within the following 30 hours. Normally locked or sealed-closed valves (except for PCV-742A/B/C/D) may be opened intermittently under administrative control without constituting a violation of containment integrity. EVENT DESCRIPTION During research into the qualification of electrical penetrations in reactor containment building, discrepancies in the qualification basis of six sealing mechanisms (penetration feedthrough assemblies) have been identified. RE-091A and RE-091B (Containment Hi Range Monitors) signal cables are affected. HCV-240 (Pressurizer RC-4 Auxiliary Spray Inlet Valve), TCV-202 (Reactor Coolant System Loop 2A Letdown Temperature Control Valve), HCV-248 (Reactor Coolant System Loop 2A Charging Line Stop Valve) and HCV-249 (Pressurizer RC-4 Aux Spray Inlet Valve HCV-240 bypass valve) cables are affected.  The affected penetrations are original plant equipment.  The condition of these penetrations violates TS 2.6(1)a.  This report is being made per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). CONCLUSION A cause analysis is in progress and the results will be included in a supplement to this LER. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS The station is currently in a refueling mode.  Corrective actions to address the causes of this condition will be documented in a supplement to this LER. The subject electrical penetrations will be restored to full qualification prior to plant startup. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE An evaluation of the safety significance of this issue will be completed following the completion of the cause analysis. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12208A313_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 3 OF 3 2012 -002 -0 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This event does not result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02. PREVIOUS EVENTS No previous qualifications issues with containment penetrations have been identified. </Figure></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>