<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">Microsoft Word - LIC-12-0121.docx</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
         <dc:creator>
            <rdf:Seq>
               <rdf:li>x13568</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Seq>
         </dc:creator>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-08-17T15:22:44-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-08-17T15:25:25-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-08-17T15:25:25-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:bbbeae38-3334-4068-a5b4-55365f12c82c</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:87a6c889-7f89-0c43-81bb-72957120e9c2</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/>--~==ii </Figure><P>~~e 
</P><P>-
</P><P>Omaha Public Power Oistrict </P><P>444 South 16111 Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LlC-12-0121 August 17, 2012 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Reference: 	Docket No. 50-285 </P><Part><H4>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2012-013, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station </H4><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2012-013, Revision 0, dated August 17, 2012. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </P><P>The following commitment is being made in this letter: </P><P>Procedures PED-QP-9, &quot;Setpoint Control,&quot; SO-G-30, &quot;Procedure Changes and Generation,&quot; and PED-NEI-4, &quot;Interface Requirements for Reload Analysis Process,&quot; will be revised to include guidance on the development of new Technical Specification limits and the associated administrative limits. These actions will be tracked in the station's CAP and will be completed prior to December 31,2012. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact me. </P><P>Sincerely, </P></Part><Part><H3>j).~ </H3><P>D. f-B~nnister Vice President and CNO </P><P>DJB /epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: E. E. Collins, Jr., NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector 
INPO Records Center 
</P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are inco rporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Priv acy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulator y Commission, Washington, DC 205 55-0001, or b y internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informationand Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management andBudget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an informationcollection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC maynot conduct or sp onsor, and a person is not required to respond to, th e information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Inadequate Calculation of Uncertainty Results a Technical Specification Violation </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>12 </TH><TD>7 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>2012 -013 -0 </TD><TD>8 </TD><TD>17 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply)  20.2201(b)  20.2203(a)(3)(i) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 50.73(a)(2)(vii)   20.2201(d)  20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)   20.2203(a)(1)  20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)   20.2203(a)(2)(i)  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)   20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(x) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii)   50.36(c)(2) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)  73.71(a)(4)  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)  50.46(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)  73.71(a)(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(v)  50.73(a)(2)(i)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) OTHER  20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below  or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 0 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Erick Matzke </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 402-533-6855 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) Technical Data Book Procedure (TDB)-III.40, “Technical Specification Required SIRWT Levels,” lists the administrative requirements to maintain the Technical Specification (TS) required Safety Injection Refueling Water tank (SIRWT) levels. The required SIRWT level for TS 2.3 accounts for instrument uncertainty, as described in the basis for TS 2.3. However, the required SIRWT levels listed in TDB-III.40 for TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 do not account for instrument uncertainty. Therefore, the TS described levels in TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 did not adequately account for SIRWT instrument level uncertainty. As a result, using the levels described in TDB-III.40 for compliance with TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 was non-conservative. The analysis concluded that there was inadequate/incomplete procedural guidance for developing Administrative Limits used to protect TS Limits. This includes guidance for understanding how to evaluate and apply uncertainties when developing TS Administrative Limits. SIRWT level was increased to a level that accounted for instrument uncertainty. TDB-III.40 has been modified to change the Administrative Limits to account for uncertainty. </TH></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12233A178_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 2 OF 4 2012 -013 -0 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET BACKGROUND Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Technical Specifications (TS) Limiting Conditions for Operation (LCOs) contain requirements to maintain the Safety Injection Refueling Water (SIRW) tank as follows: 2.3, Emergency Core Cooling System (1) Minimum Requirements The reactor shall not be made critical unless all of the following conditions are met:   a. The SIRW tank contains not less than 283,000 gallons of water with a boron concentration of at least the refueling boron concentration at a temperature not less than 50 degrees F. 2.2.7, Borated Water Source - Shutdown Applicable in modes 4 and 5 c. The SIRW tank with 1. A minimum useable borated water volume of 10,000 gallons, 2.2.8, Borated Water Sources – Operating Applies to the operational status of borated water sources when the reactor coolant temperature (T cold) is greater than 210 degrees Fahrenheit (F). b. The SIRW tank with: 1. A minimum useable borated water volume of 25,000 gallons, System Description A safeguards actuation signal starts two of the three 100 percent capable high-pressure safety injection (HPSI) pumps, the two low-pressure safety injection (LPSI) pumps, and opens the twelve SI line isolation valves.  The third 100 percent capable HPSI pump (SI-2C) may be manually aligned to either of the two HPSI injection headers. Pump SI-2C is manually actuated as required during plant operations. The SI pumps take suction from two independent suction headers which are supplied with borated water from the SIRW tank (SIRWT). The pumps discharge into the reactor coolant system through the four SI nozzles.  For long term core cooling, a continuous source of borated water is provided by recirculating containment water. EVENT DESCRIPTION On December 7, 2011, a condition report (CR) (2011-9956) was written to identify a concern associated with the TS values contained in the Technical Data Book (TDB) for the SIRWT.  Specifically, TDB-III.40, “Technical Specification Required SIRWT Levels,” lists the administrative requirements for maintaining the TS required SIRWT levels. As stated in the TS Basis for TS 2.3, the required SIRWT level for TS 2.3 accounts for instrument uncertainty and therefore is not a concern.  However, the required SIRWT levels listed in TDB-III.40 for TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 do not account for instrument uncertainty. As a result, the TS described levels in TS 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 did not account for SIRWT instrument level uncertainty and using the levels described in TDB-III.40 for compliance with TSs 2.2.7 and 2.2.8 was determined to be non-conservative. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12233A178_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 3 OF 4 2012 -013 -0 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET The cause analysis identified two times in the previous three years when LCO 2.2.7, Borated Water Source – Shutdown requirements were not met. During the 2009 refueling outage (RFO), between approximately 1430 on November 1, 2009, and 0330 on November 12, 2009, and again during the 2011 RFO, between approximately 0347 on May 29, 2011, and 0300 on May 31, 2011.  No instances of LCO 2.2.8, Borated Water Sources – Operating, not being met were identified. This condition has been entered in the station’s Corrective Action Program (CAP) as CR 2011-9956.  This event is being reported pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). During the cause analysis, three additional TS instrument uncertainties were questioned and entered into the FCS CAP: 1. Pressurizer level - uncertainty in initial pressurizer level was not applied appropriately in several of the calculations of USAR Chapter 14 analyses performed during the timeframe of the replacement steam generator project. However, due to the additional conservatism already employed in the initial pressurizer level in those calculations, the initial pressurizer level used is still conservative to what was required, and therefore, the calculations themselves remain conservative. 2. Refueling cavity level instruments LI-106 and LI-199 – being reviewed. 3. CEA position indication – being reviewed. FCS has been systematically addressing issues that have been identified since June 2011, in response to the flooding conditions, switchgear fire, and increased oversight.  This LER is being submitted beyond the 60-day regulatory reporting requirement due to non-conservative decisions with respect to procedural and regulatory reportability requirements and resource constraints caused by the operating challenges which began in June 2011. CONCLUSION A cause analysis was conducted to determine the reason for the failure to account for instrument uncertainties.  The analysis concluded that there was inadequate/incomplete procedural guidance for developing Administrative Limits used to protect Technical Specification Limits.  This includes guidance for understanding how to evaluate and apply uncertainties when developing Technical Specification Administrative Limits. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Interim Actions SIRWT level was increased to a level that accounted for instrument uncertainty.  TDB-III.40 (Engineering Change (EC) 56127) has been modified to change the Administrative Limits to account for uncertainty. Actions to Prevent Recurrence Procedures PED-QP-9, “Setpoint Control,” SO-G-30, “Procedure Changes and Generation,” and PED-NEI-4, “Interface Requirements for Reload Analysis Process,” will be revised to include guidance on the development of new Technical Specification limits and the associated administrative limits.  These actions will be tracked in the station’s CAP and will be completed prior to December 31, 2012. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12233A178_img_3.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 4 OF 4 2012 -013 -0 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE Two instances occurred where TS Limit 2.2.7 was not met as a result of this condition.  The 10,000-gallon limit for SIRWT volume (credited for a mode 5 boron dilution event) is in fact not used in USAR 14.3, Boron Dilution Incident.  There is no analytical basis for the 10,000-gallon limit associated with SIRWT volume.  The 25,000-gallon limit associated with SIRWT volume is enveloped by a larger required limit of 283,000 gallons.  Although this resulted in a reportable event, it did not represent a challenge to nuclear safety as the refueling cavity was filled as required by TS.  This event did not result in the release of any radiation.  Therefore, this event had no impact on the health and safety of the public. SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This event does not result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02. PREVIOUS EVENTS No previous events concerning inadequate application of uncertainty have been identifed. </Figure><Table><TR><TD>FORT CALHOUN STATION </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>NOD-QP-9.2 </TD></TR><TR><TD>QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TD><TD/><TD>R0 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>LICENSING CORRESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>LIC-12-0121 </TD><TD/></TR></Table><P>Date Issued:  8/14/12 Requested Return Date:____8/15/12______ 
</P><Table><TR><TH>Review/Approval </TH><TH>Information </TH></TR><TR><TH>Dave Bannister </TH><TD/><TD>Lynn Smith </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Susan Baughn </TH><TD/><TD>Woody Goodell </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TH>S. Miller </TH><TD/><TD>Brad Blome </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Mike Cooper </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>C. Sterba </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>C. Cameron </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>J. Steinke </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>S. Simpson </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>Subject__ Inadequate Calculation of Uncertainty Results a Technical Specification Violation _ </P><P>Please review and approve the attached draft correspondence (referenced above).  In order to document your review for our records, please sign this form and return it to the Licensing Coordinator.  If n o notification is received by the requested return date, your concurrence with no comment will be assumed.   </P><P>E. Matzke 6855____ 
Technical Coordinator   (Ext.) Licensing Coordinator   (Ext.) 
</P><P>[ ] Approved with no comment.        [ ] Approved pending resolution of comments as          noted. </P><P>Comments:_______________________________________________________________________________ </P><Table><TR><TH>___________________________ </TH></TR><TR><TH>___ </TH><TD>_________________ </TD></TR><TR><TH>       Reviewer's Signature </TH><TD>Date </TD></TR></Table><Table><TR><TD>FORT CALHOUN STATION QUALITY PROCEDURE FORM </TD><TD/><TD>NOD-QP-9.2 R0 </TD></TR><TR><TD>LICENSING CORR</TD><TD>ESPONDENCE REVIEW FORM SUMMARY </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>LIC-12-0121 </TD><TD/></TR></Table><P>Date Issued:  8/14/2012 Requested Return Date: 8/15/2012 
</P><Table><TR><TD>Name </TD><TD>Date Comments Received </TD><TD>No Comments1 </TD><TD>Comments - How Resolved2 </TD></TR><TR><TD>Dave Bannister </TD><TD>8/14/12 </TD><TD>X </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Susan Baughn </TD><TD>8/15/12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected </TD></TR><TR><TD>S. Miller </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Mike Cooper </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>John Goodell </TD><TD>8/15/12 </TD><TD>X </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD>C. Sterba </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>C. Cameron </TD><TD>8/15/12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected or explained </TD></TR><TR><TD>Lynn Smith </TD><TD>none </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>J. Steinke </TD><TD>8/15/12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected </TD></TR><TR><TD>S. Simpson </TD><TD>8/15/12 </TD><TD/><TD>Corrected </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>Subject: Inadequate Calculation of Uncertainty Results a Technical Specification Violation </TH></TR><TR><TH>NOTE – This submittal does  ____  does not __X__ include documents/files on CD-ROM.3 </TH></TR><TR><TH>NL Comment Coordinator Signature E. Matzke </TH><TD>Date 8/17/12 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Responsible Dept. Manager (if required) </TH><TD>Date </TD></TR><TR><TH>Review by Nuclear Licensing Supervisor </TH><TD>Date </TD></TR></Table><P>1  Attach only signed Licensing Correspondence Review Form. 
2  Attach necessary documentation. 
3 Ensure that the CD-ROM files are formatted properly for electronic information exchange (EIE) to the 
</P><P>NRC. (Reference NL-17) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>