<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-12-04T09:35:35-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Xerox ColorQube 9201</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-12-06T14:35:53-06:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-12-06T14:35:53-06:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:56906d3b-fb9a-42f5-8d50-1dccea230d2c</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:4b6c983a-aae7-374e-a168-0a95c1fea30e</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>-~
</P><Part><H1>ujjjju 
</H1><P>Omaha Public PowerDIsbtt:I </P><P>444 South 1 (/h Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LlC-13-0163 </P><P>December 6, 2013 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>References: 	1. Docket No. 50-285 </P><L><LI><LI_Label>2. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Letter from the OPPD (Louis P. Cortopassi) to NRC (Document Control Desk), Licensee Event Report 2012-017, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station, dated September 24,2012 (LlC-12-0142) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>3. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Letter from the OPPD (Louis P. Cortopassi) to NRC (Document Control Desk), Licensee Event Report 2012-017, Revision 1, for the Fort Calhoun Station, dated January 31,2013 (LlC-13-0008) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2012-017, Revision 2, for the Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2012-017, Revision 2. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(2)a)(i)(B), 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B), 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) and (D), 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(vii), and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A). </P><P>There are no new commitments being made in this letter: </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site Regulatory Assur nce, at (402) 533-6263. </P><P>ouis P. Cortopassi Vice President and CNO </P><P>LPClrjr </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: M. L. Dapas, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>J. M. Sebrosky, NRC Senior Project Manager </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><P>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industo: Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAIPrivacy Section -5 F53), U.S. Nuclear RegulatoryCommission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of InformationLICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) and Regulatory Affairs, NE B-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information(See reverse for required number of collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the</P><P>digits/characters for each block) 	information collection. </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 	2, DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 	05000285 1 OF 5 </P><P>4. TITLE </P><P>Containment Valve Actuators Design Temperature Ratings Below those Required for Design Basis Accidents </P><Table><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBER </TH><TH>7. REPORT DATE </TH><TH/><TH>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TH></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL IREV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>07 </TH><TD>26 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>017 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>2 </TD><TD>12 </TD><TD>6 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD/><TD>05000 </TD></TR></Table><P>9. OPERATING MODE 11 . THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check al/ that apply) </P><P>D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(vii) </P><P>5 	D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </P><P>10. POWER LEVEL D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71(a)(5) </P><P>0 </P><P>D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract belOW or in NRC Form 366A </P><P>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) </P><P>Erick Matzke 	402-533-6855 </P><P>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </P><P>MANU-REPORTABLE 	MANU-REPORTABLE</P><P>CAUSE 	SYSTEM COMPONENT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT</P><P>FACTURER TO EPIX 	FACTURER TO EPIX </P><P>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 	15. EXPECTED </P><P>MONTH DAY YEAR SUBMISSION DYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ~NO </P><P>DATE </P><P>~BSTRACT(Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </P><P>On July 26, 2012, while performing an extent of condition review associated with air operated valves (AOV) , it was discovered that several valves had nitrile based elastomers used in the air filter regulator and actuator that may not be acceptable for harsh environment conditions. On September 6, 2012, it was also identified that due to a lack of documentation, the States terminal blocks associated with the AOV's control circuit may not be acceptable for harsh environment conditions. These were entered into the station's corrective action program as Condition Reports 2012-08621 and 2012-12739. </P><P>During design basis accidents, the limiting analysis temperature inside Containment is 374.2 degrees Fahrenheit (F). The design service temperature for the nitrile elastomers is 180 degrees F and the testing performed on the States terminal blocks did not bound the required accident conditions. Since these valves have both open and/or close functions, failure of the nitrile based elastomers or the States terminal blocks could prevent the valves from fulfilling their intended safety function. </P><P>A causal analysis was conducted and found that the station did not fully implement and or maintain the electrical equipment qualification program. This resulted in a lack of qualification documentation and equipment not qualified for expected design basis accident conditions. </P><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH/><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIALNUMBER </TH><TH>J REV NO. </TH><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD/><TD>Fort Calhoun Station </TD><TD>05000285 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>2 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>5 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>2012 </TD><TD>017 </TD><TD>2 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>EVENT DESCRIPTION </P><P>On July 26, 2012, while performing an extent of condition review associated with air operated valves (AOV) , it was discovered that several valves had nitrile based elastomers used in the air filter regulator and actuator that may not be acceptable for harsh environment conditions. On September 6, 2012, it was also identified that due to a lack of documentation, the States terminal blocks associated with AOV's control circuit may not be acceptable for harsh environment conditions. These were entered into the station's corrective action program as Condition Reports 2012-08621 and 201212739. </P><P>During design basis accidents, the limiting analysis temperature inside Containment is 374.2 degrees Fahrenheit (F). The design service temperature for the nitrile elastomers is 180 degrees F and the testing performed on the States terminal blocks did not bound the required' accident conditions. Since these valves have both open and/or close functions, failure of the nitrile based elastomers or the States terminal blocks could prevent the valves from fulfilling their intended safety function. </P><P>Event Notification (EN) No. 47900 reported on May 4,2012, contained two issues. One being an analysis issue of temperature dwell time reported in LER 2012-009 and a second of equipment not analyzed for the conditions which they may be subjected to during a design basis accident, the subject of this LER. </P><P>This condition was initially submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D): any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident. Additional reporting criteria of 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications, 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii) any event or condition that resulted in: (8) the nuclear power plant being in an unanalyzed condition that significantly degraded plant safety, 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8): any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to remove residual heat, 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(vii) any event where a single cause or condition caused at least one independent train or channel to become inoperable in multiple systems or two independent trains or channels to become inoperable in a single system designed to: (8) remove residual heat; (C) control the release of radioactive material; or (D) mitigate the consequences of an accident, and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) any event or condition that as a result of a single cause could have prevented the fulfillment of a safety function for two or more trains or channels in different systems that are needed to: (1) shut down the reactor and maintain it in a safe shutdown condition; (2) remove residual heat; (3) control the release of radioactive material; or (4) mitigate the consequences of an accident have been added. This was identified during FCS' review of the condition. The failure to identify all reporting criteria in LERs has been entered into the station's corrective action program as Condition Report 2013-12863. </P><P>CONCLUSION </P><P>A causal analysis reviewing the requirements of 10 CFR 50.49 was conducted and found that the station did not fully implement and or maintain the electrical equipment qualification program. This resulted in a lack of qualification documentation, unidentified impacted equipment, and expanded the plant areas to be considered as affected by an event. </P><P>The EEQ issues with the States terminal blocks and elastomers are associated with much of the same the same equipment. Either condition could have impacted the equipment's ability to function during an event. See Table 1 for a listing of equipment affected by these issues. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>{10·2010} </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE </P><P>I SEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR </P><P>NUMBER NO. Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 3 OF 2012 017 2 </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>The causal analysis found that Fort Calhoun Station's (FCS) responses to IE Bulletin 79-01 B made </P><P>inaccurate and simplifying assumptions, without supporting documentation, that compromised the </P><P>validity and scope of the electrical equipment qualification (EEQ) program, ultimately resulting in the </P><P>program being non-compliant with 10 CFR 50.49. This resulted in a lack of qualification </P><P>documentation and equipment not qualified for expected design basis accident conditions. The </P><P>causal analysis also found that the engineering change process created an unnecessary burden on </P><P>the EEQ coordinator affecting the sustainability of the EEQ program. </P><P>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>The equipment conditions were entered into the station's corrective action program and the States terminal blocks and elastomers that do not meet the EEQ program requirements are being replaced. </P><P>Fully implement the Engineering Analyses that forms the basis of the EEQ Program including the 
affected documents. 
</P><P>Revise all EEQ procedures such that all EEQ engineering activities are performed under the PEDQP-2, Configuration Change Control process. </P><P>SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE </P><P>The lack of a complete analysis and various EEQ hardware issues could have prevented safety related equipment from performing their safety function in the event of a design basis accident inside containment or a high energy line break outside of containment. </P><P>SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE </P><P>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02. </P><P>PREVIOUS EVENTS </P><P>Although the root or apparent causes identified in the following LERs are not identical, the condition identified in this report is closely related as it also resulted in components not being qualified for the expected accident environment. These were latent conditions that were recently identified and any corrective action from the previous events would not have prevented the reported condition. </P><P>LER 2012-002, Inadequate Qualifications for Containment Penetrations Renders Containment </P><P>Inoperable, documents component qualification issues. </P><P>These two reports identify events that post-date the current event and are listed for completeness. </P><P>LER 2012-015, Electrical Equipment Impacted by High Energy Line Break Outside of Containment. Some components not included in EQ program resulting in some identified components not being qualified when required. </P><P>LER 2013-011, Inadequate Design for High Energy Line Break in Rooms 13 and 19 of the Auxiliary Building, documents piping in Rooms 13 and 19 either not previously considered in the high energy line break analysis or the analysis used an incorrect terminal end point. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A {10·2010} </P><P>NRC FORM 366A 	LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 	2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE YEAR </P><P>I SEQUENTIAL I REV </P><P>NUMBER NO. </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 	4 OF </P><P>2012 -017 -2 </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>Table 1 </P><P>Equipment Description</P><P>Tag HCV-238 REACTOR COOLANT SYSTEM LOOP 1A CHARGING LINE STOP VALVE HCV-239 REACTOR COOLANT SYSTEM LOOP 2A CHARGING LINE STOP VALVE HCV-864 CONTAINMENT SPRAY HEADER TO CHARCOAL FILTER INLET VALVE HCV-240 PRESSURIZER RC-4 AUXILIARY SPRAY INLET VALVE HCV-865 CONTAINMENT SPRAY HEADER TO CHARCOAL FILTER INLET VALVE HCV-883A CNTMT HYDROGEN ANALYZER VA-81 B INLET INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE HCV-1387A STEAM GENERATOR RC-2B BLWD ISOLATION VALVE HCV-1388A STEAM GENERATOR RC-2A BLWD ISOLATION VALVE HCV-241 RC PUMPS RC-3A,B,C&amp;D CONTROLLED BLEEDOFF INBOARD ISOLATION VLV HCV-438A RCP RC-3A-D LUBE OIL &amp; SEAL CLRS CCW INLET INBOARD ISOLATION VLV HCV-438B RCP RC-3A-D LUBE OIL &amp; SEAL CLRS CCW INLET OUTBOARD ISOLATION VLV HCV-438C RCP RC-3A-D LUBE OIL &amp; SEAL CLRS CCW OUTLET INBOARD ISO VALVE HCV-438D RCP RC-3A-D LUBE OIL &amp; SEAL CLRS CCW OUTLET OUTBOARD ISO VALVE HCV-467A DET WELL CLNG CLS VA-14A&amp;B COMBINED CCW INLET HDR INBD ISOL VLV HCV-467C DET WELL CLNG CLS VA-14A&amp;B COMBIND CCW OUTLET HDR INBD ISOL VLV HCV-545 SAFETY INJECTION LEAKAGE TO WASTE DISPOSAL SYS ISOLATION VALVE HCV-2916 SAFETY INJECTION TANK SI-6A FILUDRAIN VALVE HCV-2936 SAFETY INJECTION TANK SI-6B FILUDRAIN VALVE </P><P>. </P><P>HCV-2956 SAFETY INJECTION TANK SI-6C FILUDRAIN VALVE HCV-2976 SAFETY INJECTION TANK SI-6D FILUDRAIN VALVE PCV-2909 SI LEAKAGE COOLER SI-4A OUTLET PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE PCV-2929 SI LEAKAGE COOLER SI-4B OUTLET PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE PCV-2949 SI LEAKAGE COOLER SI-4C OUTLET PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE PCV-2969 SI LEAKAGE COOLER SI-4D OUTLET PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE HCV-2603B SI TANKS SI-6A-6D SUPPLY INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE HCV-2604B RCDT WD-I/PQT RC-S SUPPLY INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE HCV-42SA SI LKG CLRS SI-4A-D COMBINED CCW INLET HDR INBOARD ISOL VALVE HCV-42SC SI LKG CLRS SI-4A-D COMBINED CCW OUTLET HDR INBOARD ISOL VALVE HCV-746A CONTAINMENT PRESSURE RELIEF INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE HCV-881 CONTAINMENT HYDROGEN PURGE INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 	2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE YEAR </P><P>I SEQUENTIAL I REV </P><P>NUMBER NO. </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 	5 OF 5 </P><P>2012 -017 -2 </P><P>NARRATIVE HCV-882 CONTAINMENT HYDROGEN PURGE INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE PCV-742A CONTAINMENT PURGE AIR OUTLET INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE PCV-742C CONTAINMENT PURGE AIR INLET INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE TCV-202 REACTOR COOLANT SYSTEM LOOP 2A LETDOWN TEMPERATURE CONTROL VLV HCV-2S04A RC SAMPLE LINE CONTAINMENT ISOL VALVE (INSIDE) HCV-2S06A SG RC-2A SAMPLE CONTAINMENT ISOL VALVE (INSIDE) HCV-2S07A SG RC-2B SAMPLE CONTAINMENT ISOL VALVE (INSIDE) PCV-742E RADIATION MONITORING CABINET OUTLET INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE PCV-742G RADIATION MONITORING CABINET INLET INBOARD ISOLATION VALVE HCV-1107A STEAM GENERATOR RC-2A AUXILIARY FEEDWATER INLET VALVE HCV-1107B STEAM GENERATOR RC-2A AUXILIARY FEEDWATER INLET VALVE HCV-1108A STEAM GENERATOR RC-2B AUXILIARY FEEDWATER INLET VALVE HCV-1108B STEAM GENERATOR RC-2B AUXILIARY FEEDWATER INLET VALVE HCV-2898A CONTROL ROOM VENTILATION VA-46A CCW INLET VALVE HCV-2898B CONTROL ROOM VENTILATION VA-46A CCW OUTLET VALVE HCV-2899A CONTROL ROOM VENTILATION VA-46B CCW INLET VALVE HCV-2899B CONTROL ROOM VENTILATION VA-46B CCW OUTLET VALVE HCV-2987 HPSI ALTERNATE HEADER ISOLATION VALVE PCV-6680A-1 CONTROL ROOM FAN VA-63A SUCTION PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE PCV-6680A-2 CONTROL ROOM FAN VA-64A DISCHARGE PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE PCV-6680B-1 CONTROL ROOM FAN VA-63B SUCTION PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE PCV-6680B-2* CONTROL ROOM FAN VA-64B DISCHARGE PRESSURE CONTROL VALVE YCV-1045A MAIN STEAM LINE A AUXILIARY FEEDWATER PUMP FW-10 SUPPLY VALVE YCV-1045B MAIN STEAM LINE B AUXILIARY FEEDWATER PUMP FW-10 SUPPLY VALVE </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>