<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-09-30T11:46:36-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Xerox ColorQube 9201</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-09-30T15:29:39-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-09-30T15:29:39-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:9d86c49d-9be6-4185-873c-b23388361ede</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:b5a4e5a7-a27d-7a45-be8f-6f7b069f057f</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>-~
</P><Part><H1>jjjjjjjj </H1><P>~.... -</P><P>Omaha Public PowetDlsIItcl </P><P>444 South ](lh Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LlC-13-0127 September 30, 2013 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><Table><TR><TD>Reference: </TD><TD>Docket No. 50-285 </TD></TR><TR><TD>Subject: </TD><TD>Licensee Event Report 2012-015, Revision 1, for the Fort Calhoun </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>Station </TD></TR></Table><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2012-015, Revision 1. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a){2)(i){8), 10 CFR 50.73(a){2)(v)(A), (8), (C) and (D), and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </P><P>No commitments are being made in this letter. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site Regulatory Assurance, at (402) 533-6263. </P><P>Louis P. Cortopassi Site Vice President and CNO LPC/rjr/epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: S. A. Reynolds, Acting NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>J. M. Sebrosky, NRC Sr. Project Manager </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>., </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><P>NRC FORM 366 	U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORV COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to indust?f Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOINPrivacy Section -5 F53), U.S. Nuclear RegulatoryCommission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information</P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-O104), Office of Management and </P><P>Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information </P><P>(See reverse for required number of collection does not display acurrently valid OMB control number, the NRC may </P><P>not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to the</P><P>digits/characters for each block) 	information collection. </P><P>' </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 	2. DOCKET NUMBER </P><P><Figure ActualText="e· "><ImageData src="images/ML13274A635_img_0.jpg"/>e· </Figure>PAGE</P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 	05000285 1 OF 5 </P><P>4. TITLE Electrical Equipment Impacted by High Energy Line Break Outside of Containment </P><P>5. EVENT DATE 	6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </P><P>FACILITY NAME 	DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV</P><P>MONTH DAY YEAR 	MONTH DAY YEAR</P><P>NUMBER NO. 	05000 </P><P>FACILITY NAME 	DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>09 16 2011 2012 -015 -1 10 02 2013 	05000 </P><P>9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check aI/ that apply) </P><P>D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii)</P><P>5 	D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </P><P>10. POWER LEVEL 	D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71(a)(5)</P><P>0 </P><P>D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </P><P>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </P><P>FACILITY NAME 	rELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) </P><P>Erick Matzke 	402-533-6855 </P><P>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </P><P>MANU-REPORTABLE 	MANU-REPORTABLE</P><P>CAUSE 	SYSTEM COMPONENT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT</P><P>FACTURER TO EPIX 	FACTURER TO EPIX </P><P>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR SUBMISSION </P><P>DVES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ~NO </P><P>DATE </P><P>~BSTRACT(Umit to 1400 spaces, i. e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </P><P>On September 16, 2011, while reviewing a draft of the Master List Reconstitution for Electrical </P><P>Equipment Qualification (EEQ) (EA-FC-OB-011), Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Engineering Department </P><P>identified that some of the listed components located outside of containment may not be qualified for </P><P>the environments where they are located. This was discovered during a comprehensive re-evaluation </P><P>of potential high energy line breaks and radiological impacts outside containment initiated in response </P><P>to issues identified by the station staff. This condition was identified when Fort Calhoun Station was </P><P>shutdown and defueled. </P><P>The causal analYSis identified a number of components located in auxiliary building rooms 4,13,21, </P><P>22, and 81 that should have been included in the EEQ program. This omission was determined to be </P><P>the result of insufficient engineering rigor by the preparer and reviewer of the EEQ Program Basis </P><P>Document. </P><P>The identified components are being qualified by additional analysis, replacement with qualified components, providing shielding or electrical isolation capabilities, or moving to the component to a location where EEQ is not required. </P><P>(10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIALJ NUMBER </TH><TH>I REV NO. </TH><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Fort Calhoun Station </TD><TD>05000285 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>2 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>5 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2012 </TD><TD>015 </TD><TD>1 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>BACKGROUND </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering (CE) design. </P><P>EVENT DESCRIPTION </P><P>On September 16, 2011, while reviewing a draft of the Master List Reconstitution for Electrical Equipment Qualification (EEQ) (EA-FC-08-011), FCS Engineering Department identified that some of the listed components located outside of containment may not be qualified for the environments where they are located. This was discovered during a comprehensive re-evaluation of potential high energy line breaks and radiological impacts outside containment initiated in response to issues identified by the station staff. The condition was identified when FCS was shutdown and defueled. </P><P>This condition was initially submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D): any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident. Additional reporting criteria of </P><P>10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B): any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications, 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v) any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to: (A) shut down the reactor and maintain it in a safe shutdown condition; (B) remove residual heat; (C) control the release of radioactive material, and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) any event or condition that as a result of a single cause could have prevented the fulfillment of a safety function for two or more trains or channels in different systems that are needed to: (1) shut down the reactor and maintain it in a safe shutdown condition; (2) remove residual heat; (3) control the release of radioactive material; or (4) mitigate the consequences of an accident have been added. This was identified during FCS' review of the condition. The failure to identify all reporting criteria in LERs has been entered into the station's corrective action program as Condition Report 2013-12863. </P><P>Although the condition described in this LER was identified on September 16, 2011, it was not promptly investigated as a reportable condition. The station inappropriately concluded that reportability could be evaluated at a later date since current operating conditions were not challenged. The station also inappropriately concluded that the 60-day reporting criteria commenced when the event was determined to be reportable. A performance gap has been identified in performing reportability determinations, including late reportability determinations, and has been entered into the station's corrective action program as Condition Report 2012-03796. </P><P>CONCLUSION </P><P>The causal analysiS identified a number of components that should have been included in the EEQ program. This omission was determined to be the result of insufficient engineering rigor by the preparer and reviewer of the EEQ Program Basis Document. </P><P>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>The identified components are being qualified by additional analYSiS, replacement with qualified components, provided shielding or electrical isolation capabilities, or moving the component to a location where EEQ is not required. This will be completed prior to entering plant conditions requiring the equipment. </P><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIALNUMBER </TH><TH>I REV NO. </TH><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Fort Calhoun Station </TD><TD>05000285 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>3 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>5 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2012 </TD><TD>015 </TD><TD>1 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>The causal analysis concluded that non-compliant components potentially impacted the closure of the main steam isolation valves (MSIV). The applicable severe accident sequence is a main steam line break in Room 81, downstream of the MSIVs, with both MSIVs failing to close. Additionally, the causal analysis concluded that non-compliant components potentially impacted operation of the low pressure safety injection (LPSI) pumps by loss of suction or air intrusion, limiting the ability to supply borated water to the reactor coolant system during an accident. See Table 1 for affected equipment. </P><P>SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE </P><P>This event does result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with Nuclear Energy Institute, NEI-99-02, Regulatory Assessment Performance Indicator Guideline, Revision 6. </P><P>PREVIOUS EVENTS </P><P>Although the root or apparent causes identified in the following four LERs are not identical, the condition identified in this report is closely related as it also resulted in components not being qualified for the expected accident environment. These were latent conditions that were recently identified and any corrective action from the previous events would not have prevented the reported condition. </P><P>LER 2012-002, Inadequate Qualifications for Containment Penetrations Renders Containment Inoperable, documents component qualification issues. </P><P>LER 2012-009, Inoperable Equipment due to Lack of Environmental Qualifications, documents an analysis issue in containment. </P><P>These two reports identify events that post-date the current event and are listed for completeness. </P><P>LER 2012-017, Containment Valve Actuators DeSign Temperature Ratings Below those required for DeSign Basis Accidents, documents elastomer qualification issues inside and outside of containment. </P><P>LER 2013-011, Inadequate Design for High Energy Line Break in Rooms 13 and 19 of the Auxiliary Building, documents piping in Rooms 13 and 19 either not previously considered in the HELB analysis or analysis that used an incorrect terminal end point. </P><P>(10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2.00CKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIALNUMBER </TH><TH>I REV NO. </TH><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Fort Calhoun Station </TD><TD>05000285 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>4 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>5 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2012 </TD><TD>015 </TD><TD>1 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>NARRATIVE Table 1 -Potentially Affected Functions due to the Unqualified Equipment </P><P>-(I) .... Input from EEQ MASTER LIST FOR ELECTRICAL EQUIPMENT QUALIFICATION </P><P>-
</P><P>C C CoO </P><P>.... (I) 0 (I) E .0 E ::l</P><P>ffi'c.E &quot;'&quot; 0 .9-z</P><P>:2: .-C</P><P>::l ::l ::lCl Function</P><P>C-cu</P><P>~u. </P><P>wI</P><P>() Slow Opening DC SOV -is only energized when 0 the MSIV is closed and until the MSIV reaches 74 </P><P>N </P><P>degrees open. With the MSIV more than 74 </P><P>ct: </P><P>..... </P><P>degrees open, (HCV-1041A-20 is deenergized . </P><P>~ </P><P>0 </P><P>..... </P><P>:&gt; </P><P>() </P><P>J: </P><P>Failure Mode Bases and Possible Effect on 
Safety Related Function 
</P><P>Its failure may jeopardize the MSIV function </P><P>1---/--:0-:---=---:---=-::-:::,-:::-:-..,...,---:------:----:---:-----1 or position indication since its circuitry is part </P><P>Slow Opening DC SOV is only energized when </P><P>() </P><P>the MSIV is closed and until the MSIV reaches 74 </P><P>0 </P><P>N I degrees open. With the MSIV more than 74 </P><P>« </P><P>N degrees open, HCV-1042A-20 is deenergized. </P><P>~ </P><P>0 </P><P>..... </P><P>:&gt; </P><P>() </P><P>~ J: </P><P>U5 2 This local test pushbutton is part of the DC </P><P>!Xl </P><P>0-circuitry for the test SOV (HCV-1 041 A-20B). ct: However, its failure may jeopardize the MSIV </P><P>..... </P><P>~ function or position indication. </P><P>0 </P><P>..... </P><P>:&gt; </P><P>() </P><P>J: </P><P>of the 125 VDC control circuitry that supplies EEQ MSIV indication and solenoid valves with no electrical (fuse) isolation. </P><P>Its failure may jeopardize the MSIV function or position indication since its circuitry is part </P><P>1-------1I-=,---:---:-----:-=---:------:--:---=-::c------I of the 125 VDC control Circuitry that supplies </P><Table><TR><TD>!Xl </TD><TD>The local test pushbutton is part of the DC </TD><TD>EEQ MSIV indication and solenoid valves </TD></TR><TR><TD>0-I « N </TD><TD>circuitry for the test SOV (HCV-1042A-20B). However, its failure may jeopardize the MSIV </TD><TD>with no electrical (fuse) isolation. </TD></TR><TR><TD>~ 0 </TD><TD>function or position indication. </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD>..... </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>:&gt; </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>() </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>J: </TD><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>MSLB = Main Steam Line Break, FWLB = Feedwater Line Break, 
MSIV =Main Steam Isolation Valve, SOV =Solenoid Operated Valve, 
EEQ = Electrical Equipment Qualification, USAR = Updated Safety Analysis Report, CQE = Critical Quality 
Element, 
</P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE</P><P>I SEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR </P><P>NUMBER NO. Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 5 OF 5 2012 015 1 </P><P>NARRATIVE Table 1 -Potentially Affected Functions due to the Unqualified Equipment (continued) </P><P>-Q) ... Input from EEQ MASTER LIST FOR ELECTRICAL EQUIPMENT QUALIFICATION </P><P>Cc CoO </P><P>... Q) 0 Q) E </P><P>o</P><P>.CO' E'0.. ts .§.~</P><P>000:::: .-C Failure Mode Bases and Possible Effect on </P><P>..::::::J::J ::JC) Function </P><P>C&quot;(II</P><P>~u.. Safety Related Function </P><P>wI</P><P>c </P><P>o </P><P>U </P><P>::J </P><P>(J) </P><P>1Il &quot;OUJ </P><P>This pressure control switch is part of the DC control circuitry for HCV-2937. It must not fail to prevent spurious actuation to dose the parent HCV when LPSI is required and must function to permit closing the parent valve, if required, for </P><P>C Q) 1-__l-lo_n_g-_te_r_m_c_o_re_co_o_r_In_9_(E_O_p_A_tt_a_ch_m_e_nt_4_)__-I Failure of the may result in spurious</P><P>(II &gt; </P><P>«Cij </P><P>operation of the LPSI suction valves </P><P>This pressure control switch is part of the DC</P><P>~&gt; </P><P>......</P><P>E control circuitry for HCV-2947. It must not fail to </P><P>::J ~ </P><Sect><H5>0.. N, prevent spurious actuation to close the parent </H5><P>(J) HCV when LPSI is required and must function to</P><P>Ci5 </P><P>()</P></Sect><Sect><H5>0.. 0.. permit closing the parent valve, if required, for </H5><P>...J </P><P>long-term core cooling (EOP Attachment 4) </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>