<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-11-12T15:29:26-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Xerox ColorQube 9201</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-11-12T15:34:24-06:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-11-12T15:34:24-06:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:c41c7a0e-75b6-4e60-8ef6-99ac4ff0a198</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:64553a2e-25bf-4143-8931-8f3ba7ae6d53</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>-~</P><Part><H1>nlllln </H1><P>Omaha Pub/It: PowerDlsltlcI </P><P>444 South 16th Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LIC-13-0 166 November 12,2013 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Reference: 	Docket No. 50-285 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2013-015, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2013-015, Revision O. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8): No commitments are being made in this letter. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site Regulatory Assurance, at (402) 533-6263. </P><P>ouis P. Cortopassi Site Vice President and CND </P><P>LPClrjr </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: M. L. Dapas, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>J. M. Sebrosky, NRC Sr. Project Manager </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><P>(10-2010) Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOINPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail toLICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150·0104), Office of Management and</P><P>(See reverse for required number of </P><P>Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information </P><P>digits/characters for each block) 	collection does not display a currenUy valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 1 OF 3 </P><P>4. TITLE Unqualified Coating used as a Water Tight Barrier in Rooms 81 and 82 </P><P>5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV 	05000</P><P>MONTH DAY YEAR 	MONTH DAY YEAR</P><P>NUMBER NO. </P><P>FACILITY NAME 	DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>09 13 2013 2013 -015 -0 11 12 2013 	05000 </P><P>9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check al/ that apply) </P><P>o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii)5 o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) 181 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>10. POWER LEVEL o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) </P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5)</LI_Title></LI></L><P>0 </P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </LI_Title></LI></L><P>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) </P><P>Erick Matzke 	402-533-6855 </P><P>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </P><P>MANU-REPORTABLE 	MANU-REPORTABLE</P><P>CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT 	CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT</P><P>FACTURER TO EPIX 	FACTURER TO EPIX </P><P>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 	15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR </P><P>SUBMISSION I8IYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ONO DATE 02 03 2014 </P><P>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </P><P>On September 13,2013, it was identified that the floor coatings in Rooms 81 and 82 may not maintain </P><P>its integrity during a high energy line break environment allowing water to migrate into the rooms below </P><P>which contain the diesel generators and safety related switchgear. This was reported on September 23, </P><P>2013, under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(8), Unanalyzed Condition (Event Notification 49378). Fort Calhoun </P><P>Station was shutdown in MODE 5 when the condition was identified and entered into the station's </P><P>corrective action program as Condition Report 2013-17605. </P><P>Engineering is reviewing this condition and the evaluation performed in 2009 for a previous condition. 
The completed results of this review will be used to update this report. 
</P><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) (10·2010) </P><Sect><H5>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</H5><P>1. FACILITY NAME 	2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE I SEQUENTIAL I REV</P><P>YEAR </P><P>1 </P><P>NUMBER NO. </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 2 OF 2013 015 o </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>BACKGROUND </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering (CE) design. </P><P>EVENT DESCRIPTION </P><P>On September 13,2013, it was identified that the floor coatings in Rooms 81 and 82 may not </P><P>maintain its integrity during a high energy line break environment allowing water to migrate into the </P><P>rooms below which contain the diesel generators and safety related switchgear-This was reported </P><P>on September 23,2013, under 10 CFR 50.72(b}(3}(ii}(B}, Unanalyzed Condition (Event Notification </P><P>49378). Fort Calhoun Station was shutdown in MODE 5 when the condition was identified and </P><P>entered into the station's corrective action program as Condition Report 2013-17605. </P><P>The FCS Updated Safety Analysis Report, Appendix M, Postulated High Energy Line Rupture, states, in part, that the evaluations of Room 81 flooding assume that leakage through cracks in the concrete is minimal. A number of cracks in the floor of Room 81 and Room 82 were identified and subsequently repaired prior to any significant leakage occurring. </P><P>Engineering is reviewing this condition and the evaluation performed in 2009 for a previous condition. The completed results will be used to update this report. </P><P>This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a}(2)(ii}(B}, any event or condition that resulted in: the nuclear power plant being in an unanalyzed condition that significantly degraded plant safety. </P><P>CONCLUSION </P><P>Engineering is reviewing this condition and the evaluation performed in 2009 for a previous condition. The completed results of this review will be used to update this report. </P><P>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>Actions Completed to Address Floor Leaks: </P><P>The floor in Room 82 was recoated. </P><P>The seismic gap between containment and the auxiliary building was sealed. </P><P>All penetrations that had openings below 2 feet above the floor were coated and the area </P><P>around the impingement plate was sealed. </P><P>Cracks in the ceilings of the switchgear and upper electrical penetration rooms were repaired. </P><P>Actions Remaining to Address Floor Leaks: </P><P>The floor in Room 81, the hallway between Room 82 and the filter area, and the filter area </P><P>floor will be recoated. </P><P>Update USAR Appendix M to reflect calculation FC08313, Fort Calhoun Room 81 Flooring </P><P>Analysis. </P><P>Develop and implement a quarterly preventive maintenance task to inspect the floor coatings </P><P>in Rooms 81 and 82. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</P><Table><TR><TH/><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIALNUMBER </TH><TH>I </TH><TH>REV NO. </TH><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD/><TD>Fort Calhoun Station </TD><TD>05000285 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>3 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>3 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>2013 </TD><TD>015 </TD><TD/><TD>o </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE </P><P>Engineering is reviewing this condition and the evaluation performed in 2009 for a previous condition. The completed results of this review will be used to update this report. </P><P>SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE </P><P>Engineering is reviewing this condition and the evaluation performed in 2009 for a previous condition. The completed results of this review will be used to update this report. </P><P>PREVIOUS EVENTS </P><P>Engineering is reviewing this condition and the evaluation performed in 2009 for a previous condition. The completed results of this review will be used to update this report. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>