<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-09-30T11:46:55-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Xerox ColorQube 9201</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-09-30T15:30:02-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-09-30T15:30:02-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:454075d3-ce33-4854-97ce-5df9c35dc785</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:381f2467-3b80-2c42-af3f-9285bb97b679</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>-~
</P><Part><H1>a&quot;IIa 
</H1><P>lJIuha Publlt:Po1flii'DIsIrit:I 444 South 1(/h Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>L1C-13-0132 September 30,2013 </P><P>u.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Reference: 	1. Docket No. 50-285 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2013-012, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2013-012, Revision O. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A). There are no new commitments being made in this letter. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site Regulatory Assurance, at (402) 533-6263. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>Louis P. Cortopassi Site Vice President and CNO </P><P>LPC/epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: S. A. Reynolds, Acting NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>J. M. Sebrosky, NRC Senior Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><P>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licenSing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAIPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear RegulatoryCommission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of InformationLICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information(See reverse for required number of collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the</P><P>digits/characters for each block) 	information collection. </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 	2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 	05000285 1 OF 3 </P><P>4. TITLE </P><P>Intake Structure Crane Seismic Qualification </P><P>5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV</P><P>MONTH DAY YEAR MONTH DAY YEAR 	05000</P><P>NUMBER NO. </P><P>FACILITY NAME 	DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>8 2 2013 2013 012 -0 9 30 2013 	05000 </P><P>9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check aI/ that apply) </P><P>D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii)</P><P>5 	D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2){iii) IZI 50.73{a)(2){ix)(A} </P><P>10. POWER LEVEL D 20.2203{a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c){1 )(ii){A) D 50.73(a){2)(iv)(A) D 50.73{a)(2){x) D 20.2203{a){2){iii) D 50.36{c){2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) D 20.2203{a){2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3){ii) IZI 50.73{a){2)(v){8} D 73.71{a)(5)</P><P>0 </P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a){2)(v) D 50.73{a)(2)(i){A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a){2)(i)(8) D SO.73{a)(2)(v){D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </LI_Title></LI></L><P>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME rELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) </P><P>Erick Matzke 	402-533-6855 </P><P>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </P><P>MANU-REPORTABLE 	MANU-REPORTABLE</P><P>CAUSE 	SYSTEM COMPONENT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT</P><P>FACTURER TO EPIX 	FACTURER TO EPIX </P><P>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR </P><P>SUBMISSION 
DYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) IZI NO 
</P><P>DATE </P><P>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </P><P>On August 2,2013, Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Engineering identified that the intake structure crane (HE-5) seismic analysis assumes that the crane is not in operation with the hood retracted and in the parked position. The seismic analysis does not evaluate the crane's ability to withstand a seismic event when in use and an investigation identified that HE-5 was used when the raw water pumps were required to be operable. When discovered, FCS was shutdown in MODE 5. </P><P>The crane was not in use when the condition was identified and was verified in the parked position. Compensatory actions were identified to which would allow the use of the intake crane. The condition was entered in to the station's corrective action program as Condition Report 2013-15474. A new seismic analysis to address crane use will be developed. </P><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) (10·2010) </P><Sect><H5>CONTINUATION SHEET </H5><P>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE </P><P>I SEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 2 OF 2013 012 o </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>BACKGROUND </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering (CE) 
design. 
</P><P>EVENT DESCRIPTION </P><P>On August 2, 2013, Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) Engineering identified that the intake structure crane (HE-5) seismic analysis assumes that the crane is not in operation with the hood retracted and in the parked position. The seismic analysis does not evaluate the crane's ability to withstand a seismic event when in use and an investigation identified that HE-S was used when the raw water pumps were required to be operable. When discovered, FCS was shutdown in MODE S. </P><P>Heavy loads analysis FC06338, Load Drop Analysis for Intake Structure Operating Floor, had previously evaluated the potential damage of a dropped load event that could be caused by a seismic or tornado initiating condition. The analysis shows that the crane will not cause damage to the intake structure if used. However, damage to the unprotected fire protection headers that exist in the intake structure are not considered the in load drop analysis. Therefore, this piping may be damaged during a seismic event if HE-S is in use during a seismic event. The volume of this flooding that could be produced by this event is outside of the assumptions of the intake structure internal flooding analysis and could result in all four raw water pumps becoming inoperable. </P><P>Technical Specification 2.4 states that only two Raw Water Pumps may be out of service at power </P><P>operation. HE-S is known to have been used during power operation in the last 3 years. Therefore, </P><P>there could have been a condition that resulted in inoperability of all Raw Water Pumps. </P><P>This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR SO.73(a)(2)(v): any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are designed to (A) shut down the reactor and maintain it in a safe shutdown condition; (B) remove residual heat; (C) control the release of radioactive material; or (D) mitigate the consequences of an accident and 10 CFR SO.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) any event or condition that as a result of a single cause could have prevented the fulfillment of a safety function for two or more trains or channels in different systems that are needed to: (1) shut down the reactor and maintain it in a safe shutdown condition; (2) remove residual heat; (3) control the release of radioactive material; or (4) mitigate the consequences of an accident. </P><P>CONCLUSION </P><P>Heavy loads analysis FC06338 did not consider damage to unprotected fire protection headers that exist in the intake structure and only was valid when the crane was parked. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) </P><P>I </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</P><Table><TR><TH/><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIALNUMBER </TH><TH>I </TH><TH>REV NO. </TH><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD/><TD>Fort Calhoun Station </TD><TD>05000285 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>3 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>3 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>2013 </TD><TD>012 </TD><TD/><TD>o </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>The crane was verified not in use and in the parked position at the time of discovery. Compensatory actions were identified which would allow the use of the intake crane. The condition was entered in to the station's corrective action program as Condition Report 2013-15474 and a new seismic analysis to address crane use will be developed. </P><P>SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE </P><P>Technical Specification 2.4 states that only two Raw Water Pumps may be out of service at power operation. The postulated flooding event is outside of the assumptions of the intake structure internal flooding analysis and could lead to an internal flooding event that renders all four raw water pumps inoperable. However, FCS Abnormal Operating Procedure (AOP) 18, Loss of Raw Water, is written to specifically address a total loss of raw water. </P><P>SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE 
This does represent a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI 99-02, Revision 6. 
</P><P>PREVIOUS EVENTS 
</P><P>Eight LERs referencing the raw water pumps were identified. However, none of the LERs reviewed contained the same reason of this event, failure, or sequence of events. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>