<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:creator>
            <rdf:Seq>
               <rdf:li>x13568</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Seq>
         </dc:creator>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">Microsoft Word - LIC-13-0089.docx</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-06-28T14:15:59-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-06-28T14:17:26-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-06-28T14:17:26-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:4b59d9c8-d20c-4fb3-b54d-96943ddec82f</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:5b9bd35e-2b0d-1f4d-a030-2a195ca2e023</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>.-~~ </P><Part><H1>nlllln </H1><P>Omaha Public Power District </P><P>444 South 16'h Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>LlC-13-0089 June 28, 2013 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn : Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Reference: 	Docket No. 50-285 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2013-002, Revision 1, for the Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2013-002, Revision 1. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C). There are no new commitments being made in this letter. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site Regulatory Assurance, at (402) 533-6263. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/>ouis P. Cortopassi </Figure><P>Site Vice President and CNO LPC/rjr/epm Attachment </P><P>c: A. T. Howell, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>J. M. Sebrosky, NRC Sr. Project Manager </P><P>L. E. Wilkins, NRC Project Manager </P><P>J. C. Kirkland , NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are inco rporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Priv acy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulator y Commission, Washington, DC 205 55-0001, or b y internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informationand Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management andBudget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an informationcollection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC maynot conduct or sp onsor, and a person is not required to respond to, th e information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE CVCS Class 1 &amp; 2 Charging Supports are Unanalyzed </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>1 </TH><TD>25 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>2013 002 -1 </TD><TD>06 </TD><TD>28 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply)  20.2201(b)  20.2203(a)(3)(i) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 50.73(a)(2)(vii)   20.2201(d)  20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)   20.2203(a)(1)  20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)   20.2203(a)(2)(i)  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)   20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(x) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii)   50.36(c)(2) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)  73.71(a)(4)  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)  50.46(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)  73.71(a)(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(v)  50.73(a)(2)(i)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) OTHER  20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below  or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 0 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Erick Matzke </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 402-533-6855 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On January 25, 2013, while developing the modification to replace a portion of the Chemical and Volume Control System (CVCS) piping in containment, it was identified that the original piping supports had no calculations of record. When the calculations for the replacement piping were completed using the original support configuration, an overstress condition of the new piping was identified that directly related to the old piping. This condition would have made the original piping susceptible to failure during a seismic event. Portions of the Class 1 charging and letdown lines were affected. The plant was shutdown and defueled at the time of discovery. The causal analysis determined that station construction project management failed to ensure that initial construction procedures for design and installation of small bore piping systems and supports were in compliance with USA Standard B31.7, Nuclear Power Piping. Fort Calhoun Station will analyze and modify the supports as required to conform to the piping load requirements of the various operational Modes prior to entering that Mode. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13182A689_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 2 OF 3 2013 -002 -1 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET BACKGROUND Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering (CE) design. The FCS Chemical and Volume Control System (CVCS) consists in part of three charging pumps that take suction from the volume control tank and return the coolant to the reactor coolant system by way of the shell side of the regenerative heat exchanger.  The heat exchanger transfers heat from the letdown coolant to the charging coolant before the charging coolant is returned to the reactor coolant system. Although the three charging pumps start upon receipt of an Engineered Safeguards signal, no credit is taken for charging pump operation in the Updated Safety Analysis Report (USAR) safety analyses and as such these pumps are not classified as engineered safeguards equipment.  CVCS is classified as a reactor coolant exposed system.  The CVCS charging line enters containment through penetration M-3.  The valve configuration on this penetration is acceptable because the pressure in the direction of flow toward containment is greater than the maximum containment pressure. EVENT DESCRIPTION On January 25, 2013, while developing the modification to replace a portion of the Chemical and Volume Control System (CVCS) piping in containment, it was identified that the original piping supports had no calculations of record.  When the calculations for the replacement piping were completed using the original support configuration, an overstress condition of the new piping was identified that directly related to the old piping. This condition would have made the original piping susceptible to failure during a seismic event. Portions of the Class 1 charging and letdown lines were affected. CVCS is classified as a reactor coolant exposed system and charging line replaced is credited for maintaining pressure at containment penetration M-3, where CVCS enters containment, above containment pressure for a minimum of 30 minutes after a loss of coolant accident.  The letdown line replaced contains TCV-202 which closes on a containment isolation actuation signal.  The plant was shutdown and defueled at the time of discovery. This report is being submitted in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant’s Technical Specifications and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C), any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to control the release of radioactive material. CONCLUSION The causal analysis determined that station construction project management failed to ensure that initial construction procedures for design and installation of small bore piping systems and supports were in compliance with USA Standard B31.7, Nuclear Power Piping.  The RCA team determined that the procedure for installing small bore piping and supports used a generic methodology consisting of a seismic spacing nomograph and qualitative walkdowns to address thermal expansion concerns. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Fort Calhoun Station will: 1. Analyze and modify the supports as required to conform to the piping load requirements of the various operational Modes prior to entering that Mode, and </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13182A689_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 3 OF 3 2013 -002 -1 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET 2. Revise and implement procedures to specify the detailed piping stress analyses and support qualification to be performed to demonstrate full code compliance for small bore piping systems and supports designed to USAS B31.7. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE A CVCS piping failure event is enveloped by the small break LOCA as described in FCS USAR Section 14.5.5.  This type of event at power operations would cause automatic or manual shutdown of the plant per design and operating procedures. Operations would then control RCS volume per applicable emergency procedures. SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This event does result in a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI-99-02. PREVIOUS EVENTS Seventeen LERs with event dates between January 1, 2010, and January 25, 2013, were identified with the same reporting criteria.  However, the condition identified in this LER is a latent condition that could not have been prevented by the corrective actions taken as a result of the LERs reviewed. </Figure></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>