<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-04-14T12:45:36-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Xerox ColorQube 9201</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-04-14T13:15:24-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-04-14T13:15:24-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:278697ef-f0ac-4821-8bb8-1dd357372075</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:72c5d08a-1bfc-8142-a741-664e2c8dd4be</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>~~ </P><Part><H1>iI;;;;u </H1><P>Omaha Public PowerOlslricl </P><P>444 South 16th Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>LIC-14-0045 April 14, 2014 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station, Unit No.1 
Renewed Facility Operating License No. DPR-40 
NRC Docket No. 50-285 
</P><P>Reference: 	Letter from OPPD (L. Cortopassi) to US NRC (Document Control Desk) dated January 31,2014. (LlC-14-0006) </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2013-019, Revision 1, for the Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2013-019, Revision 1. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8). There are no new commitments being made in this letter. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site </P><P>Regulatory Assurance, at (402) 533-6263. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><Sect><H2>&quot;hJJ) I)p~ </H2><P>Louis P. Cortopassi FI1Il </P><P>Site Vice President and CNO </P><P>LPC/epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: J. M. Sebrosky, NRC Senior Project Manager </P><P>M. L. Dapas, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>J. C. Kirkland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector </P><P>Employment with Equal Opportunity </P><P>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAlPrivacy Section (T·5 F53), U.S. Nuclear RegulatoryCommission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of InformationLICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information (See reverse for required number of collection does not display acurrently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the</P><P>digits/characters for each block) </P><P>information collection. </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME 	2. DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>13. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 1 OF 3 </P><P>4. TITLE Non-Seismic Circulating Water Pipe Could Disable Raw Water Pumps </P><P>5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>MONTH DAY YEAR YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV MONTH DAY YEAR 	05000</P><P>NUMBER NO. FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>12 2 2013 2013 019 -1 4 14 2014 	05000 </P><P>9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </P><P>o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 3 o 20.2201 (d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 	50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 	50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>10. POWER LEVEL o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) </P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) 181 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5)</LI_Title></LI></L><P>0 </P><P>o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D 	OTHER </P><P>D 	20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </P><P>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) </P><P>Erick Matzke 	402-533-6855 </P><P>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT MANU-REPORTABLE MANU-REPORTABLE</P><P>CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT 	CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT</P><P>FACTURER TO EPIX 	FACTURER TO EPIX </P><P>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR SUBMISSION </P><P>DYES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 181 NO </P><P>DATE </P><P>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On December 2, 2013, NRC inspectors questioned the validity of an operability determination performed by the station on a non-safety grade pipe in the Raw Water (RW) pump vaults. The concern was determined to be valid and on December 3, 2013 at 0038 CST, an operability evaluation for Condition Report (CR) 2013-22090 confirmed operability of the RW pumps with interim actions to prevent Circulating water (CW) flow from the affected 12&quot; pipe into the RW vault during a hypothetical seismic event. An interim compensatory action to maintain operability of the raw water pumps was to disabled the screen wash pumps thereby preventing flow to the RW vault due to a pipe break caused by a hypothetical seismic event. </P><P>A cause analysis determined that the station had misapplied design information to a non-safety class system due to design engineering personnel failing to use expected human performance tools for validating assumptions, procedure use and adherence, during modification activities in the early 1970's. </P><P>A design change was completed to eliminate the adverse interaction noted above. </P><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><P>(10-2010) </P><Sect><H5>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</H5><P>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE </P><P>SEQUENTIAL REV</P><P>I</P><P>YEAR </P><P>I </P><P>NUMBER NO. </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 2 OF 3 2013 -019 -01 </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>BACKGROUND </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering (CE) 
design. 
</P><P>EVENT DESCRI PTION </P><P>On December 2, 2013, NRC inspectors questioned the validity of an operability determination 
performed by the station on a non-safety grade pipe in the Raw Water (RW) pump vaults. The 
concern was determined to be valid and on December 3,2013, at 0038 CST, an operability 
evaluation for Condition Report (CR) 2013-22090 confirmed operability of the RW pumps with 
interim actions to prevent dates from the region for the Phase 2 Buried Piping inspection flow from 
the affected 12 inch pipe into the RW vault during a hypothetical seismic event. An interim 
compensatory action to maintain operability of the raw water pumps was to disabled the screen 
wash pumps thereby preventing flow to the RW vault due to a pipe break caused by a 
hypothetical seismic event. 
</P><P>This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B), Any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to: (B) Remove residual heat. </P><P>CONCLUSION </P><P>The vulnerability described in this report has existed since the original design and installation of the 
spray wash system at FCS. 
</P><P>A cause analysis determined that the station had misapplied design information to a non-safety </P><P>system due to design engineering personnel failing to use expected human performance tools for </P><P>validating assumptions, procedure use and adherence, during modification activities in the early 
1970's. 
</P><P>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS 
A design change was issued to the station and installed that eliminated the adverse interaction 
</P><P>I </P><P>noted above. </P><P>SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE </P><P>While the design issue noted above resulted in the system being inoperable as defined in RIS </P><P>2005-20, the CW piping is quality industrial piping. Wall thickness of the pipe was measured in </P><P>three critical areas with only minor thinning of the piping. FCS has performed an analysis that </P><P>demonstrates that the existing piping would not fail during a seismic event. </P><P>SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE </P><P>This does not represent a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI 99-02, 
revision 7. FCS has performed an analysis that demonstrates that the existing piping would not 
fail during a seismic event. Therefore, this is not a safety system functional failure in accordance 
with the latest frequently asked questions (FAQs) for NEI 99-02. 
</P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) (10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000285 </TD><TD>YEAR 2013 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER I SEQUENTIALNUMBER -019 -</TD><TD>I REV NO. 01 </TD><TD>3 </TD><TD>3. PAGE OF </TD><TD>3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE PREVIOUS EVENTS </TH><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>The following LERs report inoperability of the stations RW system due to seismic concerns: LER 2013-012, Intake Structure Crane Seismic Qualification LER 2012-020, Raw Water Pump Anchors </TH><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P></Sect></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>