<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool>PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-11-13T11:10:15-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-11-12T12:23:01-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-11-13T11:10:15-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">Microsoft Word - LIC-14-0123</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
         <dc:creator>
            <rdf:Seq>
               <rdf:li>x7002</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Seq>
         </dc:creator>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:f69a8f32-9d6a-4b7d-bedc-f61f11e7248a</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:cae531e8-8a3e-5f42-8905-cfca45bb51e1</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>-~</P><Part><H1>jjjjjjjj</H1><P>---</P><P>Omaha Public PowerOislrlct </P><P>444 South 161h Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>LlC-14-0123 </P><P>November 12, 2014 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station, Unit No. 1 
Renewed Facility Operating License No. DPR-40 
NRC Docket No. 50-285 
</P><Sect><H5>Subject: Licensee Event Report 2014-006, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station </H5><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2014-006, Revision O. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). There are no new commitments being made in this letter. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site Regulatory Assurance, at (402) 533-6263. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>d </P></Sect></Part><Part><H1>L~paSSi</H1><P>Site Vice President and CNO </P><P>LPC/epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: M. L. Dapas, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>C. F. Lyon, NRC Senior Project Manager </P><P>S.M. Schneider, NRC Senior Resident Inspector </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hou rs. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and f ed back t o industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy a nd Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Re gulatory Commission, Washington, DC 205 55-0001, or by internet e-mail to Infocollects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Inoperability of Radiation Monitors Due to an Error in Technical Specifications </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9 </TH><TD>16 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 006 -00 </TD><TD>11 </TD><TD>12 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TH>1 </TH><TD>  20.2201(b)</TD><TD>  20.2203(a)(3)(i)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(vii)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2201(d)</TD><TD>  20.2203(a)(3)(ii)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(1)</TD><TD>  20.2203(a)(4)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(i)</TD><TD>  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(iii)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100</TH><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(ii)</TD><TD>  50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>20.2203(a)(2)(iii)</TD><TD>  50.36(c)(2)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)</TD><TD> 73.71(a)(4)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)</TD><TD>  50.46(a)(3)(ii)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)</TD><TD> 73.71(a)(5)</TD></TR><TR><TD> 20.2203(a)(2)(v)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C)</TD><TD> OTHER</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(vi)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)</TD><TD> 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) </TD><TD>Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSEE CONTACT Erick Matzke </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 402-533-6855 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14316A452_img_0.jpg"/></Figure></TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION       DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) During an NRC inspection on September 16, 2014, it was discovered that the calibration procedure for Radiation Monitor (RM) - 091A/B uses a source that is above 1 Roentgen per hour (R/hr). This does not meet the technical specification requirement for calibration at least one decade below 1 R/hr. 1 R/hr is the lower limit of detection of the high range detector for the RM-091 instruments. Calibration at least one decade below 1 R/hr is not possible. The most likely cause of the event is that a typographical error was introduced into license amendment request (LAR) during review process in 1993 and was not corrected prior to submittal to NRC. A LAR (LIC-14-0122) was submitted to the NRC to correct the technical specification error. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (02-2014) NRC FORM 366 (02-2014) NRC FORM 366 (02-2014) </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14316A452_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply w ith this mandatory collection request: 80 ho urs. Reported lessons learned are inc orporated into the licensing process and fed back t o industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 2055 5-0001, or b yinternet e-mail to Infocollects.Resource@nrc.gov, and t o the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is notrequired to respond to, the information collection. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 2 OF 3 2014 -006 -00 NARRATIVE BACKGROUND Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering design. The Containment Wide Range Radiation Monitors (RM) are RM-091A &amp; B. Technical Specification (TS) 2.21, Post-Accident Monitoring Instrumentation, requires that for RM-091 A/B inoperability Table 2-10, Post-Accident Monitoring Instrumentation Operating Limits, 1. Containment Wide Range Radiation Monitors (RM-091A &amp; B) minimum operating channels is 2 and With the number of OPERABLE channels less than required by the minimum channels operable requirements, initiate the pre-planned alternate method of monitoring the appropriate parameter(s) within 72 hours, and 1. either restore the inoperable channel(s) to OPERABLE status within 7 days of the event, or 2. prepare and submit a special report to the Commission pursuant to specification 5.9.3 within 14 days following the event outlining the action taken, the cause of the inoperability, and the plans and schedules for restoring the system to OPERABLE status. TS Table 3-3, Minimum Frequencies for Checks, Calibrations and Testing of Miscellaneous Instrumentation and Controls, for Area and Post-Accident Radiation Monitors states: “Secondary and Electronic calibration performed at refueling frequency. Primary calibration with exposure to radioactive sources only when required by the secondary and electronic calibration. RM-091 A/B - Calibration by electronic signal substitution is acceptable for all range decades above        10 R/hr. Calibration for at least one decade below 1-R/hr shall be by means of calibrated radiation source.” R/hr (Roentgen per hour) EVENT DESCRIPTION During an NRC inspection on September 16, 2014, it was discovered that: The calibration procedure (IC-ST-RM-0048) for RM-091A/B uses a source that is above 1 R/hr. This does not meet the TS requirement for calibration at least one decade below 1 R/hr. 1 R/hr is the lower limit of detection of the high range detector for the RM-091 instruments.  Calibration at least one decade below 1R/hr is not possible. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14316A452_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply w ith this mandatory collection request: 80 ho urs. Reported lessons learned are inc orporated into the licensing process and fed back t o industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 2055 5-0001, or b yinternet e-mail to Infocollects.Resource@nrc.gov, and t o the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is notrequired to respond to, the information collection. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Fort Calhoun Station 05000285 YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REV NO. 3 OF 3 2014 -006 -00 NARRATIVE Per TS 2.21 Table 2-10 pre-planned alternate methods (compensatory measures if RM-091A/B fail) of analysis are established per EP-FC-121-AD-F-01, Fort Calhoun Equipment Matrix. Compensatory measures are to perform periodic radiation surveys or use adjacent monitors or portable monitors as needed. Additionally, it is recognized that RM-091A and RM-091B have been successfully calibrated within their full available operating range, and despite not meeting the requirements of the Technical Specifications as it is currently written, are fully functional and available for use to monitor containment conditions post-accident. This event is reportable per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), Operation or Condition Prohibited by TS. CONCLUSION An investigation determined that the most likely cause of the event is that a typographical error was introduced into license amendment request (LAR) during review process for amendment number 152 in 1993 and was not corrected prior to submittal to NRC.  The NRC approved the TS as submitted.  CORRECTIVE ACTIONS A LAR (LIC-14-0122) was submitted to the NRC on November 7, 2014, to correct this error. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE Although the instruments have been declared inoperable due to not meeting the technical specification requirements, the instruments are properly calibrated and fully capable on monitoring radiation levels as intended. SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This does not represent a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI 99-02, revision 7. PREVIOUS EVENTS None </Figure></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>