<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2015-02-19T11:20:58-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2015-02-19T11:20:58-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2015-02-19T11:20:58-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>-~</P><Part><H1>jjjjjjjj</H1><P>---......</P><P>Omaha Public PowerOistrlcl </P><P>444 South 161h Street Mall Omaha, NE 68102-2247 </P><P>10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>LlC-15-000 1 February 13, 2015 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Fort Calhoun Station, Unit No. 1 
Renewed Facility Operating License No. DPR-40 
NRC Docket No. 50-285 
</P><P>Subject: Licensee Event Report 2014~007, Revision 0, for the Fort Calhoun Station </P><P>Please find attached Licensee Event Report 2014-007, Revision O. This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A), Specified System Actuation (RPS). There are no new commitments being made in this letter. </P><P>If you should have any questions, please contact Terrence W. Simpkin, Manager, Site Regulatory Assurance, at (4 2) 533-6263. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/>Sincerely, </Figure><P>Lo s P. Cortopassi Site Vice President and CNO </P><P>LPC/epm </P><P>Attachment </P><P>c: M. L. Dapas, NRC Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>C. F. Lyon, NRC Senior Project Manager </P><P>S.M. Schneider, NRC Senior Resident Inspector </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION 102·2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3160'()104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lassons learned rue im:orporaled into \he licensing process and led back to industry. Send comments regruding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53), u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informalion and Regulelory Affairs, NEOB--l0202. (315().l}104), Office 01 Management and Budget, Washington. DC 20503. II a means used to impose an information coUdon does nol display acurrently vatid OMB conlrol number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to, the Information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000285 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Plant Trip Due to Moisture Intrusion into a Transformer Control Cabinet </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>12 </TH><TD>17 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 007 . 00 </TD><TD>02 </TD><TD>13 </TD><TD>2015 </TD><TD>FACILITV NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TH>1 </TH><TD>o 20.2201(b) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(i)(C) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(vii) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2201 (d) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(1) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(4) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) </TD><TD>o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) </TD><TD>o SO.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) </TD><TD>181 SO.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>o SO.36(c)(2) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(4) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) </TD><TD>D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(5) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(i)(A) </TD><TD>o 50. 73(a)(2)(v)(C) </TD><TD>o OTHER </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) </TD><TD>Specify in Abstracl be/ow or In NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER r</TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSEE CONTACT ELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Erick Matzke 402-533-6855 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>B </TH><TD>EA </TD><TD>63 </TD><TD>GE </TD><TD>y </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 181 NO </TH><TD>1S. E)CPECTEDSUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Umitto 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewrillen lines) On December 17, 2014, at 1014 Central Standard Time (CSn, the Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) reactor tripped due to a loss of load Signal from the main turbine. The loss of load signal actuates the reactor protective system (RPS) which tripped the plant. The trip of the turbine was caused by a spurious actuation of a relay on the station unit auxiliary transformer that normally provides power to 4160 VAC bus 1A2. The root cause was that FCS had not ensured that an identified single point vulnerability for T1 A-2 transformer was eliminated or had an adequate mitigating strategy. The control cabinet sealing was improved to reduce moisture from the interior of the cabinet. The relay that caused the trip was removed from the trip circuit. The station will modify the control circuits to eliminate the single point vulnerability in the transformer control cabinets. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (02-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01131/2017 </TH></TR><TR><TH>02·2014) r··....'· </TH><TD>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons learned me incorporated into the licensing process and led back to industry.</TD></TR><TR><TH>l~) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH><TD>Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA. Pnvacy and Information Collections Branch (l-5 F53). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washington. DC 20555-{)OOl. or by internet e-mail to InlocoIlects.Resource@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer. Office of Inlormation and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-l0202, (3150-0104). Office 01 Management and Budget. </TD></TR><TR><TH>CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TD>Washington. DC 20503. II a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to. the information collection. </TD></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>05000285 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 • 007 • 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE BACKGROUND Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) is a two-loop reactor coolant system of Combustion Engineering deSign. EVENT DESCRIPTION On December 17, 2014, at 1014 Central Standard Time (CST), the Fort Calhoun Station (FCS) reactor tripped due to a loss of load signal from the main turbine. The loss of load signal actuates the reactor protective system (RPS) which tripped the plant. The trip of the turbine was caused by a spurious actuation of the 63FPXAlT1 A-2, &quot;63FP Seal-in relay A&quot; on transformer T1 A-2. This transformer is the station unit auxiliary transformer that normally provides power to 4160 VAC bus 1 A2. This transformer is a 22kV to 4160 VAC transformer. The transformer is protected from overpressure events internally by a 63FPIT1 A-2 sudden pressure relay. This relay actuates downstream auxiliary relays that cause annunciation in the control room and a plant trip by tripping the turbine generator and isolating 345kV to the site. Upon discovery, the auxiliary relay 63FPXAlT1A-2 was found picked up and sealed in, and the 63FPXBIT1A-2 was found de-energized with no target flags actuated. The circuit is designed so that the &quot;B&quot; relay must actuate in order for the &quot;A&quot; relay to actuate. However, the circuit is designed in such a way that the actuation of the &quot;A&quot; relay without the &quot;B&quot; relay actuating will trip the plant. Additionally, moisture was found on the internals of the cabinet, and signs of water intrusion were found on the 63FPXAlT1 A-2 relay. Immediate response by operations personnel included implementing emergency operating procedure (EOP)-OO, Standard Post Trip Actions, and subsequent entry into EOP-01, Reactor Trip Recovery. Based on plant system response this is considered an uncomplicated trip. At 1156 CST, the NRC Headquarter Operations Officer (HOO) was notified of the event per 10 CFR 50.72(b)(2)(iv)(8) (RPS Actuation) and 50.72(b)(3)(iv)(A) (Specified System Actuation (RPS». This report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A), Specified System Actuation (RPS). CONCLUSION The auxiliary relays were functionally tested and were acceptable. Troubleshooting has revealed that the direct cause of the reactor trip is moisture intrusion into the T1 A-2 transformer control cabinet causing a spurious actuation of 63FPXAlT1A-2 relay. A root cause evaluation was conducted and determined that the plant trip occurred because FCS had not ensured that an identified single point vulnerability for T1 A-2 transformer was eliminated or had an adequate mitigating strategy. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (02·2014) </P><P>.' </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150.()104 EXPIRES: 0113112017 </TH></TR><TR><TH>02-2014) ,........ </TH><TD>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory coflection request 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry.</TD></TR><TR><TH>\~) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH><TD>Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA. Pnvacy and fnfotmation Collections Branch (T-5 F53). U.S, Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washinglon, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to Inlocollects.Resource@nrc,gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-l0202. (3150-0104). Office of ManaQernenl and Budget.</TD></TR><TR><TH>CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TD>Washington. DC 20503. It a means used to impose an information coRacfion does not display a currently valid OMS controf number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond 10, the information collection. </TD></TR><TR><TH>1_ FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Fort Calhoun Station </TH><TD>05000285 </TD><TD>YEAR J SEQUENTIAL lNUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 • 007 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Immediate Corrective Actions Inspections were conducted of the control cabinets for transformers T1, T1 A-1 and T1 A·2. The control cabinets for T1 and T1 A-1 were found to be acceptable. The T1 A-2 unit auxiliary control cabinet sealing was improved to reduce moisture from the interior of the cabinet. The panel contained a terminal block which had signs of corrosion, and has since been replaced. 63FPXAff1 A-2 was removed from the trip circuit. Long Term Corrective Actions Install a modification to transformers T1, T1A-1, and T1A-2 that aligns with the industry standard for the sudden pressure relay scheme. This includes installation of a relay containing logic redundancy, and the installation of a solid state relaying scheme. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The plant responded normally as designed to a failure of a protective relay that resulted with the isolation of transformers supplying power to the station. Plant systems responded as deSigned in response to the spurious transformer fault signal. There were no failures of safety equipment in the automatic reactor shutdown. The loss power from the transformers did not result in the unavailability of other plant equipment. SAFETY SYSTEM FUNCTIONAL FAILURE This does not represent a safety system functional failure in accordance with NEI 99-02, revision 7. PREVIOUS EVENTS None </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FOAM 366 (02-2014) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>