<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-03-29T09:38:57-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-03-29T09:38:57-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-03-29T09:38:57-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>..Pacific Gas and </P><P>~~~ Electric Company® 	James R. Becker Diablo Canyon Power Plant Site Vice President Mail Code 104/5/601 </P><P>p. O. Box 56 Avila Beach, CA 93424 </P><P>805.545.3462March 17,2010 Intemal: 691.3462 Fax: 805.545.6445 </P><P>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-1 0-027 </P><P>U.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
Washington, DC 20555-0001 
</P><P>Docket No. 50-275, OL-DPR-80 Docket No. 50-323, OL-DPR-82 Diablo Canyons Unit 1 &amp; Unit 2 Licensee Event Report 2-2010-001-00 2008 Diablo Canyon Power Plant Unit 2 Loss of Auxiliary Building Ventilation System Exhaust Fans </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff: </P><P>Pacific Gas and Electric Company submits the enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) regarding an event that occurred in July 2008 when the Diablo Canyon Power Plant Unit 2 auxiliary building ventilation system exhaust fans where simultaneously turned off for a brief period of time (less than 1 hour). This LER is submitted in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). </P><P>There are no new or reyised regulatory commitments in this report. </P><P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>swh/2246/50295954 </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc/enc: 	Elmo E. Collins, NRC Region IV Michael S. Peck, NRC Senior Resident Inspector Alan B. Wang, NRR Project Manager INPO Diablo DistribUtion </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance </P><P>Callaway. Comanche Peak. Diablo Canyon. Palo Verde. San Onofre. South Texas Project. WolfCreek , </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML100880112_img_1.jpg"/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (9-2007) .-LICENSEE EVENT REPO'RT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/cha'racters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 08/31/2010 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch ·(T-5 F52), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Unit 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000323 1 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE 2008 Diablo Canyon Unit 2 Loss of Auxiliary Building Ventilation System Exhaust Fans </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>'YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>7 </TH><TD>21 </TD><TD>2008 </TD><TD>2010 -001 -00 </TD><TD>03 </TD><TD>17 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME . </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Ch\eck al/ that apply) o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201 (d) o ·20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) . 0 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.7.3(a)(2)(i)(A) [8J 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) t8I 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or inNRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME lTELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Steven W. Hamilton -Senior Regulatory Services Supervisor . (805) 545-3449 . </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>A </TH><TD>VF </TD><TD>FAN </TD><TD>R165 </TD><TD>N </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED D YES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) t8I NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) , On July 21,2008,05:04 PDT, Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Unit 2 entered Technical Specification (TS) 3.0.3 when operators secured auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1 with auxiliary building exhaust fan E-2 cleared for maintenance. The securing. of auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1, resulted in a loss of all DCPP Unit.2 auxiliary building ventilation system exhaust. On July 21,2008,0534 PDT, DCPP Unit 2, TS 3.0.3 was exited when auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1 was restarted. , &quot; On January 28,2010, PG&amp;E conducted a review of-past events for safety system functional failures. Past events included entries into TS 3.0.3. This review was conducted utilizing recently published U.S. NRC training material on this subject. This review concluded that the simultaneous inoperability of the DCPP Unit 2 auxiliary building exhaust fans constituted a safety system functional failure and as such was reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). &quot; I </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (9-2007) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><Table><TR><TH>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) TEXT CONTINUATION </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) LER NUMBER (6) PAGE (3) YEAR SEQUENTIAL NUMBER REVISION NUMBER </TH></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Unit 2 0 151 0 I 0 I 0 13 121 3 2010 -I 0 I 0 I 1 I 0 I 0 2 I OF 15 TEXT I. Plant Conditions / At the time of the event Unit 2 was in Mode 1 (Power Operation) at approximately· 100 percent reactor power with normal operating reactor coolant temperature and pressure. II. Description of Problem A. Background The DCPP Auxiliary Building Ventilation System (ABVS) exhaust fans provide a constant exhaust air flow from the DCPP auxiliary building. The DCPP ABVS exhaust fans also: • Maintain a negative pressure in the DCPP auxiliary building. • Limit the maximum design engineered safety feature (ESF) equipment room temperature to 104°F in the auxiliary building. • Ensure radioactivity is filtered during accident conditions and released through the exhaust system and monitored at the plant vent. The ABVS has several modes of operation: Building Only operation, Safeguards operation, and Building and Safeguards operation. A safety injection signal ('S' signal) will cause a nonoperating, stand-by ABVS exhaust fan to start and align to the plant vent. An operating ABVS exhaust fan experiencing low inlet flow will shutdown down automatically. Should a low flow event occur, a system reset is required for the ABVS prior to manually restarting or auto-restart via an'S' signal. B. Event Description On July 21,2008,05:04 PDT, DCPP Unit 2 entered Technical Specification (TS) 3.0.3 when plant operators closed the suction dampers of the running exhaust fan E-1 prior to placing an'S' signal into the system. This action resulted in tripping auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1 with auxiliary building exhaust fan E-2 cleared for· maintenance. Placing a'S' signal into the system would have opened an alternate flow path and would have prevented the trip of the running fan. Failure to select the'S' signal caused the only available exhaust fan to trip off on low flow, placing the plant in a one-hour TS action statement. This resulted in a loss of all DCPP Unit 2 ABVS exhaust. On July 21,2008,0534 PDT, DCPP Unit 2 exited TS 3.0.3 when plant operators restarted auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1 by resetting the ABVS and inserting a 'S'signal. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) TEXT CONTINUATION </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET NUMBER (2) </TD><TD>LERNUMBER~ </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REVISION NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Unit 2 </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>01 0 </TD><TD>3 I OF I 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>TEXT On January 28, 2010, PG&amp;E conducted a review of past events for safety system functional failures. This review was conducted utilizing recently published U.S. NRC training material on this subject. This review concluded that the simultaneous inoperability of the DCPP Unit 2 auxiliary building exhaust fans constituted a safety system functional failure and as such was reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). C. Status of Inoperable Structures, Systems, or Components that Contributed to the Event None. D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected No additional safety systems were adversely affected by this event. E. Method of Discovery PG&amp;E conducted a review of past events for safety system functional failures. This review was conducted utilizing recently published U.S. NRC training material on this subject. This review ,concluded that the simultaneous inoperability of the DCPP Unit 2 auxiliary building exhaust fans constituted a safety system functional failure. F. Operator Actions None. G. Safety System Responses Plant operators restarted DCPP Unit 2 auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1 in safeguards mode by initiating a system reset and inserting a'S' signal. III. Cause of the Problem A. Immediate Cause Plant operators incorrectly caused the operating auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1 to secure on low flow with auxiliary building exhaust fan E-2 cleared for maintenance. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) TEXT CONTINUATION </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET NUMBER (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER 6 </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REVISION NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Unit 2 </TH><TD>015101010131213</TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>-1010111</TD><TD>01 0 </TD><TD>4 1 OF 1 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>TEXT B. Cause Operations personnel performing the work were using a partially marked up procedure and a clearance to take the E-2 Fan out of service to allow maintenance work on the system. The operators did not recognize the sequence of the process required the'S' signal be selected prior to closing the dampers isolating flow to the fan. IV. Assessment of Safety Consequences Under 10 CFR 50. 73(a)(2)(v), &quot;Any event or condition that alone could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are or systems that are needed to: (A) Shut down the reactor and maintain it in a safe shutdown condition; (B) Remove residual heat; (C) Control the release of radioactive material; or (D) Mitigate the consequences of an accident.&quot; This event was reviewed to determine if it meets the criteria for a safety system functional failure. Based on a review of the event, equipment in the same system, ABVS exhaust fans E-1 and E-2, were not operable and available to perform the required safety function. The design of these fans impacts subsections (C) and (D), . regarding control the release ofradioactivity by filtering the exhaust stream and mitigate the consequences of an accident by maintaining the ESF room temperatures below the design limits, as cited above. Although both DCPP Unit 2 ABVS exhaust fans were not operating, placing the unit into TS 3.0.3, the allowed outage time for this specification was not exceeded and the ESF features for this system were fully capable of performing their design safety functions. Based on the foregoing, this event is not considered risk significant and did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) TEXT CONTINUATION </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET NUMBER (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER 6 </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REVISION NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Unit 2 </TH><TD>o 151 0 I0 I0 I3 I2 I3 </TD><TD>201 0 </TD><TD>-I0 I0 I 1 I -</TD><TD>01 0 </TD><TD>5 IOF I 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>TEXT V.Corrective Actions A. Immediate Corrective Actions 1. DCPP Unit 2 exited TS 3.0.3 when plant operators restarted auxiliary building exhaust fan E-1 by initiating a'S' signal. B.Corrective Actions to Prevent Recurrence (CAPR) 1. ABVS exhaust fan clearances have been updated to clearly show that a'S' signal must be initiated prior to removing, the associated ABVS exhaust fan from service. VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components None B. Previous Similar Events None. C. Industry Reports None. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>