<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-10-28T11:42:12-07:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-10-28T11:51:05-07:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-10-28T11:51:05-07:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:bdfc0d96-de54-4a27-9eef-5a037a40f974</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:4364a657-c201-3a42-b0ee-6708f7982447</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>Pacific Gas and </TH></TR><TR><TH>Electric Company® </TH><TD>James R. Becker Site Vice President </TD><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant Mail Code 104/ 5/ 601 p. O. Box 56 Avil a Beach, CA 93424 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>805.545.3462 </TD></TR><TR><TH>October 28, 2011 </TH><TD/><TD>Inte rn al: 691.3462 Fax: 805.545.6445 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-11 -113 </TH><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 10 CFR 50.73 ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Docket No. 50-275, OL-DPR-80 Docket No. 50-323, OL-DPR-82 Diablo Canyon Units 1 &amp; 2 Licensee Event Report 1-2011-006-00 Diablo Canyon Power Plant -Loss of Control Room Envelope Integrity </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff: </P><P>Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) submits the enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) regarding loss of control room envelope integrity. Both units are impacted by this issue. PG&amp;E is submitting this LER in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) and 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D). </P><P>There are no new or revised regulatory commitments in this report. </P><P>This event resulted in an insignificant increase in risk to the control room operators. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><Part><H3>~Av...1.4 L l.,-</H3><P>James R. Becker </P><P>mlpy/50424481 Enclosure cc/enc: Elmo E. Collins, NRC Region IV </P><P>Michael S. Peck, NRC Senior Resident Inspector Alan Wang, NRR Project Manager Jim Polickoski, NRR Project Manager INPO Diablo Distribution </P><P>A member of the STA~S (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance 
Callaway . Comanche Peak . Diablo Canyon. Palo Verde . San Onofre . South Texas Project . Wolf Creek 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 (10-2010) Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Privacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information (See reverse for required number of collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may digits/characters for each block) not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 275 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Loss of Control Room Envelope Due to the Work Control Shift Foreman Incorrectly Authorizing Removal of a Blank Flange </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIALI REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Unit 2 </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 323 </TD></TR><TR><TH>08 </TH><TD>29 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>2011 -6 -0 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>28 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) o 20.2201 (b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8)o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x)o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) L. Mark Padovan -Regulatory Services Supervisor (805) 545-4540 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) DNa </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>01 </TD><TD>15 </TD><TD>2012 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i. e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On August 29, 2011, at 1724 PDT, an operator attempted to reposition Unit 2 control room ventilation system (CRVS) dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A using the CRVS mode switch in the control room, but was unable to do so. During a follow-up investigation, at about 2230 PST, plant operators discovered that the integrity of the Units 1 and 2 common control room envelope boundary was lost due to maintenance personnel removing a blank flange on the inlet duct to dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A with the dampers still inoperable (in mid-position). This condition is contrary to the requirements of Technical Specification (TS) 3.7.10 &quot;Control Room Ventilation System (CRVS).&quot; Maintenance personnel reinstalled the blank flange on August 30, 2011, at 0110 PDT. PG&amp;E will provide the cause in a supplemental report following completion of its apparent cause evaluation of this issue. On August 30, 2011, at 1404 PDT, Pacific Gas &amp; Electric made a late 8-hour non-emergency report (Reference NRC Event Notification 47223) under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B) and (b)(3)(v)(D). Plant personnel entered this late notification into the Diablo Canyon Nuclear Power Plant corrective action system. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000 275 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 006 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE I. Plant Conditions At the time of discovery, Units 1 and 2 were in Mode 1 (Power Operation) at approximately 100 percent power. II. Description of Problem A. Background The Control Room Ventilation System (CRVS) provides a protected environment from which operators can control the units from the common control room following an uncontrolled release of radioactivity, hazardous chemicals, or smoke. The CRVS consists of two independent, redundant trains that recirculate and filter the air in the common control room envelope (CRE), and a CRE boundary that limits the inleakage of unfiltered air (one CRVS train from each unit). The CRVS is an emergency system, parts of which may also operate during normal unit operations. Upon receipt of an actuating signal, the normal air supply to the CRE is isolated, and the stream of outside ventilation air from the pressurization system and recirculated control room air is passed through a system filter. The pressurization system draws outside air from either the north end or the south end of the turbine building based upon the wind direction or the absence of releases at the inlet. The prefilters remove any large particles in the air, to prevent excessive loading of the high-efficiency particulate air filters and charcoal adsorbers [ADS). The CRVS is designed to maintain a habitable environment in the Units 1 and 2 common CRE for the duration of the most severe Design Basis Accident without exceeding a 5 rem whole body dose or its equivalent to any part of the body. This basis is consistent with General Design Criteria 19, dated 1971. B. Event Description On August 29, 2011, at about 1130 PDT, prior to reporting off a clearance to perform maintenance on Unit 2 control room dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A, maintenance personnel received permission from the Work Control Shift Foreman (WCSF) to remove the blank flange from the inlet duct [DUCT) to the dampers [CDMP). This blank flange was maintaining the integrity of the CRE boundary while dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A were inoperable during maintenance. At about 1400 PDT, plant personnel completed maintenance on Unit 2 control room dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A and planned on performing static testing of the CRE the next morning. At about 1724 PDT, an operator attempted to reposition the dampers from the control room, but was unable to do so. During a follow-up investigation, at about 2230 PST, operators determined that the flange had been removed prematurely and dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A were still inoperable awaiting stroke testing by electrical maintenance. Maintenance personnel reinstalled the flange on August 30, 2011, at 0110 PDT to meet the required actions associated with Technical Specification (TS) 3.7.10.B. The loss of CRE boundary created an unanalyzed condition that could have prevented the CRVS from mitigating the exposure of control room personnel to the consequences of an accident. On August 30, 2011, at 1404 PDT, Pacific Gas &amp; Electric made a late 8-hour nonemergency report (Reference NRC Event Notification 47223) under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B) and (b)(3)(v)(D). Plant personnel entered this late notification into its corrective action system. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000 275 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 006 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE C. Status of Inoperable Structure, Systems, or Components That Contributed to the Event CRVS dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A were inoperable in mid-position. D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected Inoperability ofthe CRE rendered both Units 1 and 2 CRVS trains inoperable. However, the CRVS trains remained capable of performing their normal ventilation functions. E. Method of Discovery An operator attempted to reposition the dampers from the control room, but was unable to do so. F. Operator Actions Operators took required actions associated with TS 3.7.10.B and re-installed the blank flange on August 30, 2011, at 0110 PDT. G. Safety System Responses None. III. Cause of the Problem A. Immediate Cause Control room boundary integrity was lost due to maintenance personnel removing a blank flange on the inlet duct to the Unit 2 CRVS dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A with the dampers still inoperable and in mid-position. B. Cause PG&amp;E will provide the cause in a supplemental report following completion of its apparent cause evaluation (ACE) of this issue. IV. Assessment of Safety Consequences Maintenance personnel removed the blank flange from the upstream side of dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A for about 12 hours. During this time, the ability of the CRVS to protect operators from a post-accident release of airborne radiation was compromised. However, the probability that a core-damaging accident could occur and require actuation of the pressurization mode of control room ventilation during this period of time was extremely low (less than lE-07 during the 12-hour window). Therefore, this event resulted in an insignificant increase in risk to the control room operators. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)U,S, NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000 275 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 006 .. 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE V. Corrective Actions A. Immediate Correction Actions A clearance was created for CRVS dampers MOD-2 and MOD-2A to track the removal of the blank flange. B. Corrective Actions To Prevent Recurrence (CAPRs) PG&amp;E will provide corrective actions in the supplemental report following completion of the ACE. VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components All components functioned as designed. B. Previous Similar Events There are no examples of previous similar events at DCPP. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>