<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-10-16T11:53:02-07:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-10-16T11:55:53-07:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-10-16T11:55:53-07:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:7d28262e-b3bf-46e5-9b27-f6031023e393</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:680bb354-ff5a-f840-b96c-3d628e0b1b00</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>__ Pacific Gas and ~&amp;~ Electric Company </P><P>Diablo Canyon Power Plant PO. Box 56 Avila Beach, CA 93424 </P><P>800.545.6000 </P><P>October 16, 2012 </P><P>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-12-096 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 10 CFR 50.73 ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Docket No. 50-323, OL-DPR-82 Diablo Canyon Unit 2 Licensee Event Report 2-2012-001-00, Failure to Meet Emergency Diesel Generator Technical Specifications </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff: </P><P>Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) is submitting the enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) regarding the discovery of a broken emergency diesel generator fuel oil booster pump drive belt and subsequent failure to meet plant technical specifications. PG&amp;E is submitting this LER in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D). </P><P>PG&amp;E makes no new or revised regulatory commitments (as defined by NEI 99-04) in this report. </P><P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Barry S. Allen </P><P>Site Vice President </P><P>wrl8/6980/50507816 </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc/enc: 	Elmo E. Collins, NRC Region IV Laura H. Micewski, Acting NRC Senior Resident Inspector Joseph M. Sebrosky, NRR Senior Project Manager INPO Diablo Distribution </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAlPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000-323 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Failure to Meet Emergency Diesel Generator Technical Specifications </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIALI REVI NUMBER I NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>08 </TH><TD>18 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 -001 -00 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>16 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii)D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8)D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) D 73;71(a)(5)D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Sp~cify in Abstract below or In NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME /TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Wilbert R. Landreth, Regulatory Services Engineer (805) 545-6980 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED D YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 0 NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On August 18,2012, Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Unit 2 Operations personnel discovered that the belt connecting Emergency Diesel Generator (EDG) 2-3 to its fuel oil booster pump (FOBP) was broken. DCPP operators declared EDG 2-3 inoperable, entering Technical Specification (TS) 3.8.1. On August 21,2012, at 0330, operators declared EDG 2-3 operable after replacing both the FOBP and its drive belt. The cause analysis concluded that the belt and FOBP had failed following satisfactory performance of a surveillance test on August 3,2012, at 13.04 PDT. EDG 2-3 was therefore inoperable longer than allowed by TS 3.8.1.B.4, and is thus reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). During the time between August 3, 2012, at 1304 PDT, and August 21,2012, at 0330 PDT, EDG 2-2 was declared inoperable twice for testing, but was still available. When EDG 2-2 was inoperable, DCPP Unit 2 only had one operable EDG, since the broken belt rendered EDG 2-3 inoperable. Two EDGs are required to be operable to mitigate the consequences of a design basis accident, making this situation reportable under 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(v)(D). PG&amp;E will reduce the EDG 2-3 drive belt tension specification in plant procedures pending vendor approval. PG&amp;E will establish a periodic replacement strategy for the FOBP in lieu ofthe present condition-monitored replacement strategy. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><Part><H5>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</H5><P>3. PAGE</P><P>2. DOCKET </P><P>6. LER NUMBER </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME </P><P>SEQUENTIAL T REV</P><P>YEAR I </P><P>NUMBER NO.</P><P>I </P><P>2 OF</P><P>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </P><P>05000-323 </P><P>2012 -001 00 </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>I. Plant Conditions </P><P>On August 18, 2012, Unit 2 was in Mode 1 (Power Operation) at 100 percent power. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>II. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Problem Description </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>A. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Background </LI_Title></LI></L><P>Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Unit 2 has three emergency diesel generators (EDGs) [DG] that provide vital </P><P>backup power to three electrical buses [BU] to mitigate the consequences of a design basis accident (DBA) </P><P>whenever normal or off-site power sources are unavailable. DCPP EDGs are designed to function so that a single </P><P>failure of any EDG will not jeopardize the capability ofthe remaining EDGs to start and provide power to operate </P><P>the shutdown systems required to mitigate any DBA condition. </P><P>Each EDG has a single fuel oil booster pump (FOBP) [P] driven by a belt connected to the EDG crankshaft </P><P>extension shaft. The FOBP supplies fuel oil from the diesel engine's day tank [TK] to each cylinder's fuel oil </P><P>injection pump. The engine fuel oil system [DC] and FOBP are required for diesel operation. However, because </P><P>ofthe independence of each diesel and its associated powered bus, a single failure involving one diesel will not </P><P>cause a failure of any other EDG to perform its designed safetY functions. </P><P>B. Event Description </P><P>On August 18, 2012, the DCPP Unit 2 Operations turbine building (TB) watch discovered a broken EDG 2-3 FOBP belt. Operators declared EDG 2-3 inoperable, entering Technical Specification (TS) 3.8.1, &quot;AC Sources -Operating,&quot; Condition B, &quot;One DG inoperable.&quot; TS 3.8.1 and its associated TS Bases required EDG 2-3 to be returned to operable within 7 days for unplanned maintenance. Security personnel evaluated the as-found condition ofthe EDG 2-3 drive belt and concluded that the belt had not been broken due to sabotage. The other five EDGs have different FOBP belts, which cause lower side loading on the pumps. Plant engineers and operators walked down all five other EDGs and found no visible damage ofthe belts or FOBPs. </P><P>Plant personnel evaluated the pump's internal material condition. Normally, the FOBP easily rotates by hand with </P><P>no drive belt attached. The FOBP would not rotate. Plant staff disassembled the pump and identified significant </P><P>and uneven wear within the shaft bushing, significant and uneven scoring wear on the pump case faces, and galling </P><P>on the internal gear [GR] faces, indicative of side loading on the pump. With normal side loading and adequate </P><P>lubrication, the bushing would not be expected to wear unevenly and lead to shaft skewing. However, with </P><P>excessive side loading, this would be expected to occur. </P><P>DCPP Engineering performed a thorough evaluation ofplausible causes ofthe broken belt and seized FOBP that </P><P>included discussions with the EDG vendor and FOBP vendor. Based upon the inspection results and vendor </P><P>discussions, DCPP Engineering concluded that the FOBP drive belt failed because the FOBP seized. The FOBP </P><P>seized because the excessive drive belt tension caused uneven side loading, bushing wear, and shaft skewing. This </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000-323 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE prevented pump sheave rotation that resulted in the belt snapping during coast-down on August 3, 2012, at l304 PDT, following EDG 2-3's satisfactory performance ofDCPP Surveillance Test Procedure (STP) M-9A, &quot;Diesel Engine Generator Routine Surveillance Test.&quot; On August 20,2012, DCPP Maintenance personnel replaced the FOBP and its drive belt. On August 21,2012, at 0330 PDT, PG&amp;E declared EDG 2-3 operable. PG&amp;E failed to meet TS 3.8.1, Condition B, &quot;One DG inoperable,&quot; because EDG 2-3 was not returned to operable status within the required 7-day completion time for unplanned maintenance after EDG 2-3 belt and FOBP failure following the test run on August 3,2012, at l304 PDT. During the time between August 3,2012, at l304 PDT, and August 21,2012, at 0330 PDT, EDG 2-2 was taken out of service and declared inoperable twice to perform surveillance testing. However, EDG 2-2 was still available for use via manual operator action. For those periods that EDG 2-2 was declared inoperable, DCPP Unit 2 only had one operable EDG, when two are required to be operable to perform the designed safety function of providing vital emergency power. This condition would have prevented the fulfillment ofthe EDG's designed safety function of mitigating the consequences of a DBA. C. Status of Inoperable Structure, Systems, or Components That Contributed to the Event None. D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected None. E. Method of Discovery The DCPP Unit 2 Operations turbine building watch discovered the broken EDG 2-3 FOBP belt. F. Operator Actions DCPP Operators entered TS 3.8.1, &quot;AC Sources -Operating;&quot; declaring EDG 2-3 inoperable. G. Safety System Responses None. III. Cause ofthe Problem The EDG 2-3 FOBP seized because the vendor-recommended drive belt tension caused excessive side loading and shaft skewing. The drive belt broke because the FOBP seized, preventing sheave rotation, resulting in the drive belt snapping during coast-down ofEDG 2-3 following surveillance testing. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000-323 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 • 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE IV. Assessment of Safety Consequences PG&amp;E's quantitative risk analysis for the 18 days between the time EDG 2-3 was last successfully run on August 3,2012, and the time when EDG 2-3 was declared operable on August 21,2012, after replacing the FOBP and its drive belt, concluded that the incremental conditional core damage probability was less than the 1.0E-06 risk significance threshold. This event was a Safety System Functional Failure, but it is not considered risk significant and did not adversely affect the health and safety ofthe pUblic. V. Corrective Actions A. Immediate Corrective Actions On August 20,2012, DCPP Maintenance personnel replaced the FOBP and its drive belt. B. Other Corrective Actions 1) DCPP will reduce the EDG 2-3 drive belt tension specification in procedure MP M-21.7B, &quot;Diesel Engine 2-3 Fuel Oil Booster Pump,&quot; to a lower vendor-approved deflection force value. 2) DCPP will establish a periodic replacement strategy for the FOBP. VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components 1) The EDG 2-3 FOBP. 2) The EDG 2-3 FOBP drive belt. B. Previous Similar Events None. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>