<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-08-06T15:09:12-07:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-08-06T15:14:14-07:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-08-06T15:14:14-07:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:dde0b5cb-b902-4f3e-8f02-0217a144f240</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:82cb1e1f-badf-8c41-b35b-501d0393b5f7</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>Pacific Gas and </TH></TR><TR><TH>Electric Company® </TH><TD>James M. Welsch </TD><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>Station Director </TD><TD>Ma il Code 104/5/ 502 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>P. O. Box 56 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>Avila Beach, CA 93424 </TD></TR><TR><TH>August 6, 2012 </TH><TD/><TD>805 .545.3242 Internal: 691.3242 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>Fax: 805.545.4234 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-12-072 </TH><TD/><TD>Internet: JMW1@pge .com </TD></TR></Table><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 10 CFR 50.73 ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Docket No. 50-275, OL-DPR-80 Diablo Canyon Unit 1 Licensee Event Report 1-2012-003, &quot;Low Temperature Overpressure Protection System Inoperable due to Human Performance Error&quot; </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff; </P><P>Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) is submitting the enclosed Licensee Event Report in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), for a human performance event that rendered the low temperature overpressure protection (LTOP) system inoperable. On June 7, 2012, at 0129 PDT, PG&amp;E declared both trains of the L TOP system inoperable when the vital 120 VAC Distribution Panel (PY) PY13 was de-energized due to an electrical maintenance technician inadvertently opening the incorrect breaker. Plant staff immediately recognized the error and the technician closed the PY13 supply breaker, thereby re-energizing Panel PY13, returning one train of L TOP to service. </P><P>PG&amp;E makes no new or revised regulatory commitments (as defined by NEI 99-04) in this report. </P><P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>~~LJA..~ 
</P><P>James M. Welsch </P><P>Interim Site Vice President </P><P>wrl8/50488907 </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: 	Diablo Distribution </P><P>cc/enc: 	Elmo E. Collins, NRC Region IV Michael S. Peck, NRC Senior Resident Inspector Joseph M. Sebrosky, NRR Senior Project Manager INPO </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Shari ng) Alliance </P><P>Callaway. Comanche Peak. Diablo Canyon. Palo Verde . San Onofre. South Texas Project. Wolf Creek </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Privacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503~ If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000-275 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Low Temperature Overpressure Protection System Inoperable due to Human Performance Error </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED YEAR ISEQUENTIALI REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER NUMBER NO. MONTH DAY YEAR FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 2012 -003 -00 08 06 2012 </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TH>06 </TH><TD>07 </TD><TD>2012 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D SO.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D SO.73(a)(2)(vii)D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D SO.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D SO.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D SO.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) D SO.73(a)(2)(viii)(8)D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D SO.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D SO.73(a)(2)(iii) D SO.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D SO.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) D SO.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D ·SO.73(a)(2)(x)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) BSO.36(c)(2) D SO.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) S0.46(a)(3)(ii) D SO.73(a)(2)(v)(8) D 73.71(a)(5)D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) [(] SO. 73(a)(2)(v)(D) Sp~cify in Abstract below or In NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL o </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME iTELEPHONE NUMBER (Indude Area Code) Wilbert R. Landreth, Regulatory Services Engineer (805) 545-6980 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED DYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) [{] NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 7, 2012, at 0129 PDT, Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) declared both trains of the Low Temperature Overpressure Protection (LTOP) system inoperable when the vital 120 VAC Panel PY13 was de-energized due to a human performance error. Unit 1 was in Mode 5 and the reactor coolant system (RCS) loops were not filled. Plant technicians were troubleshooting a de-energized vital 120 VAC Panel PY14 that had resulted from the supply breaker inadvertently tripping open. During troubleshooting, a plant technician incorrectly opened the supply breaker to Panel PY13 instead ofPY14. With PY14 de-energized, one train ofLTOP was inoperable due to loss of signal from RCS Wide Range Pressure Transmitter PT-405A. With PY13 de-energized, the second train ofLTOP was rendered inoperable due to loss of signal from RCS Wide Range Pressure Transmitter PT -403A. Plant staff immediately recognized the error and the technician closed the PY13 supply breaker, thereby re-energizing Panel PY13, returning one train of L TOP to service. On June 7, 2012, at 0856 PDT, PG&amp;E made an 8-hour non-emergency report (Reference NRC Event Notification 48002) under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(v)(D). As corrective actions, PG&amp;E will conduct human performance skills assessments for Electrical Maintenance (EM) personnel, reinforce human performance expectations with EM supervisors, and revise troubleshooting standards. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR REV NO.I SEQUENTIAL 1 NUMBER I </TD><TD>2 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE I. Plant Conditions At the time of discovery, Unit 1 was in Mode S (Cold Shutdown) at 0 percent power with the reactor coolant system (RCS) [AB] loops not filled. II. Description ofProblem A. Background The Low Temperature Overpressure Protection (LTOP) system is designed to prevent the reactor [RCT] vessel [VSL] from experiencing brittle fracture due to overpressure transients at low RCS temperatures (e.g., during startup and shutdown). The LTOP system uses two Class 1 Power Operated Relief Valves [PORVs], PCV-4SSC and PCV-4S6, that are activated by RCS Wide Range Pressure Transmitters [PT] PT-403A and PT-40SA, respectively. Vital 120 VAC Power Distribution Panel PY14 powers PT-40SA, and vital 120 VAC Power Distribution Panel PY13 powers PT-403A. Although these two PORVs are required to be operable for LTOP, only one PORV is credited in the LTOP analyses to allow for a single failure. B. Event Description On June 6, 2012, at 2111 PDT, the Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) control room received multiple alarms related to the loss ofPY14. The IY14 output breaker [BKR] tripped unexpectedly, de-energizing PY14 and PT-40SA, causing the associated alarms. Plant operators declared vital 120 VAC Panel PY14 inoperable. On June 7, 2012, a plant technician was performing troubleshooting activities associated with the above-mentioned IY14 output breaker trip in accordance with plant procedures. The plant technician placed a correct component verification (CCV) label on the upper section ofIY14 and began troubleshooting. The troubleshooting plan directed the opening and closing ofthe output breaker on IY14 five times. The technician removed all loads from PY14 and verified that IY14 and PY14 had no fuse [FU] or equipment problems. The troubleshooting team reconvened and determined maintenance should perform testing on the circuit to verifY cable integrity before returning IY14 to service. This step required opening the output breaker on IY14. The IY14 output breaker manipulations were coordinated between the technician performing the work in the field and control room using the plant telephone system. During the phone call to the control room, the three other individuals moved from IY14 to IY13 to give the technician more room to perform his task. After the phone call, the technician went to the panel where the individuals were located and opened the output breaker on Inverter IY13 instead ofIY14. This condition resulted in loss ofAC power to Safety-Related Distribution Panel PY13 and resultant Solid-State Protection System Train B error alarm. On June 7, 2012, at 0129 PDT, DCPP operators declared both trains ofthe LTOP system inoperable when the vital 120 VAC Panel PY13 was de-energized due to the plant technician's inadvertent opening ofthe IY13 output breaker during the PY14 troubleshooting activities. With PY13 momentarily de-energized, the second train ofLTOP was rendered inoperable due to loss of signal from PT-403A placing the plant in Technical Specification (TS) Condition 3.4.12.0 with &quot;two required RCS Class 1 PORVs inoperable in Mode S or 6, with the vessel head closure bolts not fully de-tensioned.&quot; The technician immediately closed the PY13 supply breaker after recognizing his error, thereby re-energizing panel PY13 less than S seconds after de-energizing it. Operations completed the necessary paper </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</P><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH/><TH>6. LER NUMBER </TH><TH/><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TD><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>3 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>5 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2012 </TD><TD>at </TD><TD>003 </TD><TD>.. </TD><TD>00 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>closure and returned one train ofLTOP back to operable within nine minutes. This condition resulted in a Safety System Functional Failure for Unit 1LTOP. </P><P>On June 7, 2012, at 0856 PDT, PG&amp;E made an 8-hour non-emergency report ofthe event (Reference NRC Event Notification 48002) under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(v)(D). </P><P>C. Status ofInoperable Structures, Systems, or Components That Contributed to the Event None. </P><P>D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected </P><P>The control room ventilation system (CRVS) and the fuel handling building [BLDG] ventilation system (FHBVS) realigned to their safeguards alignments, as expected, due to the de-energization of associated radiation monitors [MON] (RM) RM-26 and RM-59. </P><P>E. Method of Discovery 
The control room received multiple alarms related to the loss ofPY13. 
</P><P>F. Operator Actions 
</P><P>Operators declared both trains ofthe L TOP system inoperable when the technician inadvertently de-energized vital 120 VAC panel PY13. Plant staff immediately recognized the error and the technician closed the PY13 supply breaker, thereby re-energizing Panel PY13, restoring the functionality of one train ofLTOP. </P><P>G. Safety System Responses </P><P>The CRVS swapped to its safeguards alignment after RM-26 alarmed due to loss ofPY13. The FHBVS swapped to its safeguards alignment after RM-59 lost power due to loss ofPY13. Both the CRVS and FHBVS responded appropriately. DCPP operators reset the associated RM after verifying that it responded solely because power to PY13 was lost. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>III. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Cause ofthe problem </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>A. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Apparent Cause 
Electrical Maintenance (EM) supervisors have not consistently reinforced self-checking standards. 
</LI_Title></LI></L><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 3GGA (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>G. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER 2012 -003 REV NO. 00 </TD><TD>4 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE B. Contributing Cause (l) EM allowed use of a troubleshooting plan which did not meet work instruction quality standards as described in DCPP Procedure, AD7.DC8, &quot;Work Planning,&quot; in that specific component identifiers and sign-offs for each step were not provided. (2) EM allowed use of a troubleshooting plan without establishing robust barriers on adjacent equipment to prevent mis-operation. IV. Assessment of Safety Consequences The potential for over pressurizing the reactor vessel is greatest when the RCS is water solid. During this event, the RCS loops were not filled and the RCS was thus not water solid. During Mode 5 (Cold Shutdown with all reactor vessel head closure bolts fully tensioned), TS Limiting Condition for Operation 3.4.12, &quot;Low Temperature Overpressure Prote,ction System,&quot; provides RCS overpressure protection by limiting coolant input capability to the RCS andhaving adequate pressure relief capacity. The LCO specifies that no safety injection pumps, and only one centrifugal charging pump, are capable of injecting into the RCS, and all ofthe accumulator discharge isolation valves are deactivated in the closed position. Considering the plant conditions at the time ofthis occurrence, it is not credible that enough mass or heat energy could be injected into the RCS to cause a low temperature overpressure event while the LTOP system was incapable of actuating for less than 5 seconds. V. Corrective Actions DCPP performed an Apparent Cause Evaluation ofthis occurrence and developed the corrective actions described below. A. Corrective Actions (l) Perform a &quot;Skills Assessment&quot; for EM personnel to ensure human performance verification standards and the use of robust barriers are clearly understood and can be successfully demonstrated. A remediation plan will be developed for </TH></TR></Table><P>those workers that cannot demonstrate the knowledge and proficiency ofthe standard. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>(2) </LI_Label><LI_Title>Counsel EM supervisors on expectations for reinforcement of self checking, correct component verification (CCV), and the use of robust barriers and establish supervisor commitment and accountability. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>(3) </LI_Label><LI_Title>Revise DCPP Procedure MAl.DC10, &quot;Troubleshooting,&quot; Revision 12, to provide direction that troubleshooting plans will comply with station work instruction and documentation quality standards as described in DCPP Procedure AD7.DC8, &quot;Work Planning,&quot; and to specify the use of robust barriers. </LI_Title></LI></L><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6: LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR REV NO.ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>5 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components None. B. Previous Similar Events On February 28, 200S, maintenance workers began work on Unit 2 Main Steam (MS) Lead Check Valve MS-2-2066 in error. Workers were assigned to perform a check valve inspection on Valve MS-2-106S. As workers completed work on MS-2-42, the workers were then ready to work on Valve 2-MS-1068, which was said to be adjacent to MS-2-42. There were two valves in the area, MS-2-106S, and MS-2-2066, both with insulation removed. All the valves in the area no longer have any operator valve identification (OVID) tags. The workers assumed which valve to work on by deducing that the removed insulation and staged rigging over Valve MS-2-2066 identified the correct valve. Subsequently, the workers began disassembling the wrong valve. On February 29, 200S, a worker obtained the OVID drawings, and identified that the valve in progress was MS-2-2066, not MS-2-106S. The worker immediately notified the supervisor. On May 16,2011, as part ofthe 230kV Startup System Reliability Upgrade Project, PG&amp;E was making a physical modification to the 12kV startup relay board panel (RU). During cutting ofthe RU with a reciprocating saw, the 230kV Line Differential Relay 287 actuated and sent a trip signal to the Unit 1 Startup Transformer 11 output breaker to the Unit I Startup bus and to the Unit 2 startup Transformer 21 output breaker (cleared at the time) to the Unit 2 startup bus. On May 27, 2011, while performing function testing ofUnit 2 Relay 87UT2I, technicians inadvertently began testing on Unit 1 Relay 51187 UTI I , initiating a trip signal for the Unit 1 Startup Transformer 11 hi-side circuit interrupter and output supply breaker to the Unit I startup bus. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>