<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-08-31T12:21:19-07:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-08-31T12:25:40-07:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-08-31T12:25:40-07:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:f8802b21-4477-4ca7-85a1-eff1ca2cdc0f</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:a49ca6a5-318e-1f4a-85ca-0206266133b0</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>Pacific Gas and </TH></TR><TR><TH>Electric Company® </TH><TD>James M. Welsch </TD><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>Station Director </TD><TD>Mail Code 104/ 5/502 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>P. O. Box 56 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>Avila Beach, CA 93424 </TD></TR><TR><TH>August 31, 201 2 </TH><TD/><TD>805.545.3242 Internal: 691. 3242 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>Fax: 805.545.4234 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-12-082 </TH><TD/><TD>Internet: JMW1@pge.com </TD></TR></Table><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 10 CFR 50.73 ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Docket No. 50-275, OL-DPR-80 Docket No. 50-323, OL-DPR-82 Diablo Canyon Units 1 and 2 Licensee Event Report 1-2012-005-00, Unanalyzed Condition due to Nonconservative Change in Atmospheric Dispersion Factor </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff: </P><P>Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) submits the enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) regarding the discovery of a nonconservative historical change in the control room ventilation system atmospheric dispersion factor methodology on July 5, 2012. PG&amp;E is submitting this LER in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B), 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(vii). PG&amp;E will submit a supplemental LER explaining the safety consequences of this issue following completion of our assessment. </P><P>This LER also mentions a related issue identified on August 28, 2012 (Event Notification 48246), that PG&amp;E is still investigating. PG&amp;E will either withdraw that notification or submit a separate LER to the NRC for the August 28,2012, issue based on the outcome of its investigation. </P><P>PG&amp;E makes no new or revised regulatory commitments (as defined by NEI 99-04) in this report. </P><P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>~~ 
</P><P>James M. Welsch </P><P>Interim Site Vice President </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance 
Callaway . Comanche Peak . Di ablo Canyon . Palo Verde . San Onofre . South Texas Project . Wolf Creek 
</P><Part><H4>wrl8/6980/50497328 </H4><Sect><H5>Enclosure </H5><P>cc/enc: 	Elmo E. Collins, NRC Region IV Dean H. Overland, NRC Senior Resident Inspector Michael S. Peck, NRC Senior Resident Inspector Joseph M. Sebrosky, NRR Senior Project Manager INPO Diablo Distribution </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance 
Callaway. Comanche Peak. Diablo Canyon. Palo Verde. San Onofre. South Texas Project. Wolf Creek 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industc;' Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAlPrivacy Section T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13 . PAGEl 05000-275 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Unanalyzed Condition due to Nonconservative Change in Atmospheric Dispersion Factor </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon, Unit 2 </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000-323 </TD></TR><TR><TH>07 </TH><TD>05 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 • 005 • 00 </TD><TD>08 </TD><TD>31 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) D 20.2201 (b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) [(] 50.73(a)(2)(vii) D 20.2201 (d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) [(] 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) B50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71(a)(5) D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) [(] 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) [(] 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONT ACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME jTELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Wilbert R. Landreth, Regulatory Services Engineer (805) 545-6980 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED [{] YES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) DNO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>04 </TD><TD>01 </TD><TD>2013 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On July 5, 2012, Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) identified a nonconservative change in the Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Updated Final Safety Analysis Report (UFSAR) Chapter 15, &quot;Accident Analyses,&quot; control room (CR) atmospheric dispersion factor (XlQ) methodology, made in Revision 2 ofthe DCPP UFSAR in 1986. The change in methodology under-predicted the overall radiological dose received by the CR operators in the event of various design basis accidents. On July 26, 2012, PG&amp;E completed a Prompt Operability Assessment that concluded the CR operator dose limit of 30 Rem thyroid following a large-break loss-of-coolant accident (LBLOCA) would not be exceeded using compensatory actions to restrict allowable emergency core cooling system leakage and containment leakage. PG&amp;E also established a compensatory measure prohibiting fuel movement inside the fuel handling building and inside the containment. On August 28,2012, PG&amp;E identified additional release pathways that could affect the CR operator dose following a LBLOCA (see Event Notification 48246). Consequently, PG&amp;E declared the control room envelope inoperable and established mitigative actions in accordance with Technical Specification 3.7.l0, Actions B.1 andB.2. PG&amp;E will revise the XlQs and incorporate them into the DCPP licensing basis. PG&amp;E will submit a supplemental report on the July 5, 2012, issue following completion of its safety consequences assessment. PG&amp;E will either retract the notification or submit a separate report for the August 28,2012, issue mentioned in this report. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR REV NO.ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>2 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -005 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE I. Plant Conditions On July 11,2012, Units 1 and 2 were in Mode 1 (Power Operation) at 100 percent power. The Unit 1 control room envelope (eRE) was inoperable due to preplanned maintenance on a Unit 1 control room ventilation system (CRVS) subtrain. II. Problem Description A. Background Units 1 and 2 CRVS provides a protected environment from which operators can control the units from the common control room (CR) following an uncontrolled release of radioactivity, hazardous chemicals, or smoke. The CRVS consists of two trains (one CRVS train from each unit) that recirculate and filter the air in the common CRE, and a CRE boundary that limits the in-leakage ofunfiltered air. Each train is comprised oftwo redundant, full-capacity, active components such that each train is composed of two subtrains. The CRVS is an emergency system, parts of which may also operate during normal unit operations. Upon receipt of an actuating signal, the normal air supply to the CRE is isolated, and the stream ofoutside ventilation air from the pressurization system and recirculated CR air is passed through a system filter [FL T]. The pressurization system draws outside air from either the north end or the south end ofthe turbine building [NM]. The prefilters remove any large particles in the air to prevent excessive loading ofthe. charcoal adsorbers [ADS]. The CRVS is designed to maintain a habitable environment in the Units 1 and 2 common CRE for the duration ofthe most severe design basis accident (DBA) without exceeding 5 Rem whole-body dose or its equivalent to any part ofthe body (calculated over 30 days) to assure compliance with General Design Criteria (GDC) 19. Updated Final Safety Analysis Report (UFSAR) Chapter 15 dose analyses use atmospheric dispersion factors (XlQs) to determine the dose CR operators receive after an accident. B. Event Description On July 5, 2012, Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) identified a nonconservative change in the Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) UFSAR Chapter 15, &quot;Accident Analyses,&quot; CR X/Q values made in Revision 2 in 1986. Before Revision 2 ofthe DCPP UFSAR, the CR X/Q calculation used the Murphy-Campe (MC) methodology. Revision 2 ofthe DCPP UFSAR replaced the MC methodology with a modified-Halitsky (MH) methodology for determining X/Qs. PG&amp;E did not evaluate the UFSAR Revision 2 change in accordance with 10 CFR 50.59 to determine whether or not NRC review and approval ofthe change was required prior to implementation. The UFSAR change request did identify that the change increased the radiological dose the CR operators would receive in the event of an accident, but that dose would not exceed GDC 19 limits. On July 11,2012, at 0345 PDT, CR operators declared the CRE inoperable because the CR dose calculations used a X/Q value that was neither evaluated per 10 CFR 50.59 nor reviewed and approved by the NRC for use at DCPP, and thus constituted an unanalyzed condition. The NRC Resident Inspector identified PG&amp;E's delay in reviewing operability </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET </P><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH/><TH>6. LER NUMBER </TH><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TD><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>. </TD><TD>005 </TD><TD>-00 </TD><TD>3 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>5 </TD></TR></Table><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>between July 5 and July 11,20.12. The delay was due to personnel errors in communicating the concern to control room licensed operators for evaluation. Preliminary dose calculations, using the originally-licensed methods, concluded the CR operator dose limit of 30 Rem thyroid would be exceeded following a large-break loss-of-coolant accident (LBLOCA). Plant operators had already entered Technical Specification (TS) 3.7.10, &quot;Control Room Ventilation System (CRVS),&quot; Condition B, which states: &quot;One or more CRVS trains inoperable due to inoperable CRE boundary in MODE 1,2,3, or 4,&quot; due to preplanned maintenance on a Unit 1 CRVS subtrain. Since plant operators had already completed Action B.1, &quot;Initiate action to implement mitigating actions immediately,&quot; and Action B.2, &quot;Verify mitigating actions ensure CRE occupant exposures to radiological hazards will not exceed limits, and CRE occupants are protected from smoke and chemical hazards within 24 hours,&quot; because ofthe preplanned maintenance, operators reevaluated the mitigating actions (i.e., availability of self-contained breathing apparatus and staging of potassium iodide) that were already in place and found them to be adequate. However, Action B.3, &quot;Restore CRE boundary to OPERABLE status,&quot; had not yet been completed. </P><P>On July 26, 2012, at 1152 PDT, PG&amp;E established new compensatory actions to restrict allowable emergency core </P><P>cooling system (ECCS) leakage, and containment [NH] leakage, and declared the CRE operable after completing a </P><P>Prompt Operability Assessment (POA) that concluded the CR operator dose limit of 30 Rem thyroid following a </P><P>LBLOCA would not be exceeded under accident conditions with the compensatory actions in place. The POA </P><P>additionally identified the fuel handling accident analyses also used the MH methodology XlQs. Compensatory actions </P><P>were established to prohibit fuel movement until the issue was resolved. </P><P>Emergency planning models and offsite dose analyses do not rely on the XlQs derived from MH methodology and are not impacted by this incorrect analysis change. Therefore, this condition is limited to the CR post-accident dose for both Units 1 and 2. </P><P>As a result of further investigation into this issue, on August 28, 2012, PG&amp;E identified additional release pathways that could affect the CR operator dose following a LBLOCA (see Event Notification 48246). Consequently, PG&amp;E declared the CRE inoperable and established mitigative actions in accordance with TS 3.7.10, Actions B.l and B.2. Accordingly, PG&amp;E has concluded that, pending reanalysis, the CRVS would not have been capable of performing its safety function of mitigating the CR operator dose consequences of a LBLOCA. PG&amp;E will either withdraw that notification or submit a separate licensee event report (LER) on the August 28,2012, issue based on the outcome of its investigation. </P><P>PG&amp;E has not completed reanalysis ofthe fuel handling accidents. PG&amp;E conservatively assumed that the CR operator </P><P>dose limits would be exceeded, pending reanalysis ofthe fuel handling accidents. Therefore, PG&amp;E has concluded that, </P><P>pending reanalysis, the CRVS would not have been capable of performing its safety function of mitigating the </P><P>consequences of a fuel handling accident for past fuel handling activities. PG&amp;E has implemented a compensatory </P><P>measure prohibiting fuel movement inside the fuel handling building (FHB) [ND] and inside the containment until this issue is resolved. </P><P>C. Status ofInoperable Structure, Systems, or Components That Contributed to the Event </P><P>None. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</P><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH/><TH>6. LER NUMBER </TH><TH/><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TD><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>4 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>5 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2012 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>005 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>00 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected None. </P><P>E. Method ofDiscovery </P><P>PG&amp;E discovered this incorrect change to the XlQs during a licensing basis review ofUFSAR Chapter 15, Section 15.5, &quot;Environmental Consequences ofPlant Accidents.&quot; </P><P>F. Operator Actions </P><P>On July 11 and August 28,2012, plant operators entered TS 3.7.10, &quot;Control Room Ventilation System (CRVS),&quot; Condition B, and implemented mitigative actions as directed by TS Actions B.l and B.2, as previously discussed in Section B, &quot;Event Description.&quot; </P><P>G. Safety System Responses None. </P><P>III. Cause ofthe Problem </P><P>The incorrect change ofthe XlQs was determined to have been caused by inadequate design control processes in 1986, whereby the analysis change was made without evaluating the change in accordance with 10 CFR 50.59 to determine whether prior NRC review and approval was required. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>IV. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Assessment of Safety Consequences To be provided in a supplemental LER. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>V. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Corrective Actions </LI_Title></LI></L><P>1) PG&amp;E will revise the accident analyses which used the MH X/Qs and incorporate the revised analyses into the DCPP licensing basis. </P><P>2) PG&amp;E will complete its licensing basis verification project that is reviewing, validating, and revising the current DCPP licensing basis where found to be necessary. This project was initiated in 2010. This project identified the problem described in this LER. </P><P>3) Additional corrective actions will be addressed and reported in a supplemental LER as necessary. </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR REV NO.ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>5 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -005 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE A. Immediate Corrective Actions Operators reviewed the mitigating actions in place for adequacy to assure that CR operator dose would remain acceptable following a LBLOCA. PG&amp;E has implemented' a compensatory measure prohibiting fuel movement inside the FHB and inside the containment and revised operational restrictions on ECCS leakage and containment leakage. VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components None. B. Previous Similar Events On September 12,2011, at 1745 PDT, operators declared the Units 1 and 2 CRE boundary inoperable and entered TS 3.7.10, &quot;Control Room Ventilation System (CRVS).&quot; This was due to discovery of inadequately-documented CRE in-leakage test data. At 2257 PDT on September 12,2011, PG&amp;E made an 8-hour nonemergency report under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B). Human error affected the interpretation oftest results and led to the nonconservative determination of zero in-leakage in 2005. Plant staff verified that administrative controls were in place to maintain post-LOCA ECCS leakage at arate that would ensure that CR operator doses would not exceed GDC 19 limits. PG&amp;E performed an assessment ofthe testing and revised procedures to specify separate acceptance criteria for each ofthe tested CRVS configurations in accordance with RG 1.197. (Reference LER 1-2011-007-01) On November 3, 2011, at 1550 PDT, PG&amp;E determined that the DCPP CRVS had a design vulnerability; whereby, unfiltered air supplied to the control room could exceed the flow rates used in the licensing-basis analysis of design basis accident consequences. PG&amp;E discovered this vulnerability during performance of control room in-leakage testing required by TS Surveillance Requirement 3.7.10.5. On November 3, 2011, at 2051 PDT, PG&amp;E made an 8-hour nonemergency report under 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(ii)(B). (Reference LER 1-2011-008-00) C. Industry Reports None. </TH></TR></Table></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>