<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-06-26T08:20:20-07:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-06-26T08:32:15-07:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-06-26T08:32:15-07:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:3143096c-df94-477f-b057-9cadb6f6e3cf</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:c86a45f2-716b-d945-9be2-65b063af892b</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>Pacific Gas and </TH></TR><TR><TH>Electric Company® </TH></TR><TR><TH>Barry S. Allen </TH><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TD></TR><TR><TH>Site Vice President </TH><TD>Mail Code 104/6 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>P. O. Box 56 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>Avila Beach. CA 93424 </TD></TR><TR><TH>June 26, 2013 </TH><TD/><TD>805.545.4888 Internal: 691.4888 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>Fax: 805.545.6445 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-13-068 </TH><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 10 CFR 50.73 ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Docket No. 50-323, OL-DPR-82 Diablo Canyon Unit 2 Licensee Event Report 2-2012-002-01 ! Coupling Capacitor Voltage Transformer Bushing Failure Causes Reactor Trip </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff: </P><P>Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) is submitting the enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) supplement identifying a reactor trip and an auxiliary feedwater pump auto-start as a result of a flashover of a 500kV insulator. PG&amp;E is submitting this supplement to provide updated cause and corrective action information, following completion of a formal root cause analysis and a vendor material analysis. This LER supplement is submitted in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A). </P><P>PG&amp;E makes no new or revised regulatory commitments (as defined by NEI 99-04) in this report. </P><P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>~2Ie! M-</P><P>dh06/50518473 </P><P>Enclosure cc/enc: Thomas R. Hipschman, NRC Senior Resident Inspector </P><P>Arthur T. Howell III, NRC Region IV </P><P>James T. Polickoski, NRR Project Manager </P><P>INPO </P><P>Diablo Distribution </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industc,' Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Privacy Section T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocoilects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000-323 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 6 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Coupling Capacitor Voltage Transformer Bushing Failure Causes Reactor Trip </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIALI REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>10 </TH><TD>11 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 • 002 • 01 </TD><TD>06 </TD><TD>26 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii)D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8)D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A)D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) B50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) D 73.71(a)(5)D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Dean Overland, Sr. Engineer, Regulatory Services (805) 545-6038 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>B </TH><TD>EL </TD><TD>XFMR </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>y </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED D YES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) [ZINO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On October 11,2012, at 12:08 PDT, the Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Unit 2 500kV line differential relay actuated, resulting in a unit trip. The 500kV coupling capacitor voltage transformer (CCVT) bushing experienced a flashover to ground, resulting in a unit trip and turbine trip. With the turbine tripped and Unit 2 operating above the 50 percent power permissive, the reactor protection system initiated a reactor trip as designed. All plant equipment, including the auto-start ofthe auxiliary feedwater (AFW) system, responded as designed. DCPP determined that the bushing failed because the insulator minimum creepage distance was not consistent with industry codes and standards for its operating environment. When the bushing was replaced in 2011, DCPP staff made unvalidated assumptions, and over-relied on industry experts. DCPP will move CCVT metering to an area with lower contamination levels, and reinforce expectations to review current industry codes and standards. Additionally, an unintended AFW pump restart occurred following this event as a result of a human performance error that resulted in a procedure not being revised following a plant modification. DCPP will revise procedure supporting documents and train procedure writing staff on use ofthe supporting documents to identify all changes required by a plant modification. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000-323 </TD><TD>REV NO. YEAR ISEQUENTIAL T NUMBER I </TD><TD>2 OF 6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -002 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE I. Plant Conditions Just prior to the event, Unit 2 was operating in Mode I (Power Operation) at approximately 100 percent reactor [RCT] power with normal operating reactor coolant temperature and pressure. II. Problem Description A. Background The Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) is equipped with a Class IE alternating current electrical power distribution system [EB] that is divided into three load groups. The power sources for this system consist oftwo physically-independent offsite sources and multiple onsite standby power sources (three engine-driven diesel generators (DGs)[DG] for each unit). These systems have independent controls, independent protection, and separate switchyards, transmission lines, and tie-lines to the plant. In the normal alignment, the power produced at DCPP is transmitted offsite via the 500kV system [EL] and also feeds normal onsite loads via the auxiliary transformer [XFMR]. Backup power is available immediately via the 230kV system [EK] and startup transformer and in a delayed manner (for vital loads) from on site DGs. The alternating current electrical power sources provide sufficient capacity, capability, redundancy, and reliability to ensure the availability of necessary power to engineered safety systems so that the fuel, reactor coolant system [AB], and containment design limits are not exceeded. DCPP's 500kV system has metering hardware that provides real-time generation and consumption data to the Independent System Operator (ISO). Independent bushing current transformers (CTs) and 500kV coupling capacitor voltage transformers (CCVTs) are the sensors used for this application. The CCVTs and CTs are connected to each unit's Main Bank Transformer (MBT). A catastrophic failure ofthe Unit 2 &quot;C&quot; phase high-voltage (HV) bushing (insulator) in 2008 led to a 2009 replacement oftwo ofthe six ceramic HV insulator bushings with a silicone polymer design that had less potential for collateral damage upon failure. All ofthe DCPP lightning arresters (LAs) and CCVTs have also been replaced with this same silicone polymer design. There are three key factors to consider for an insulating system to be able to adequately withstand the applied system voltage: insulator material properties, creepage distance, and environmental conditions (contaminants, such as salt, dust, industrial pollutants, etc.). A contaminated insulator without adequate creepage margin will suffer arcing and eventually flashover. Silicone polymer provides exceptional performance as an insulator material, especially in adverse environmental conditions. By continuously extruding a layer of silicone, it encapsulates contaminants on the surface ofthe insulator. This prevents the buildup of a conductive film when the insulator is exposed to moisture. The silicone layer performs the same&quot; function as the silicone grease some plants apply to porcelain insulators. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(10-2010) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET 
</P><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH/><TH>6. LER NUMBER </TH><TH/><TH/><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>NUMBER ISEQUENTIAL I </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TD><TD>05000-323 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>3 </TD><TD>OF </TD><TD>6 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2012 </TD><TD>. </TD><TD>002 </TD><TD>. </TD><TD>01 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD>NARRATIVE </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>Creepage distance is the shortest path between two conductive parts. The Institute ofElectrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) standard C57.19.100, &quot;IEEE Guide for Application of Power Apparatus Bushings,&quot; provides recommendations for various environmental conditions. DCPP's location exposes these systems and components to environmental contaminants such as salt, dust, industrial pollutants, etc. Per IEEE C57.19.100, DCPP's environment is classified as a heavy or very heavy contamination area, which establishes the recommended minimum creepage distance as 502 or 616 inches, respectively. Pacific Gas and Electric (PG&amp;E) corporate transmission line design standard indicates a minimum creepage distance of400 inches, but does not refer to environmental classifications. The installed polymer CCVT bushings have a vendor stated guaranteed minimum of400 inches ofcreepage distance. A DCPP generic vendor document described a porcelain CCVT creepage distance of435 inches. A separate, model-specific vendor document detailed a porcelain CCVT creepage distance of 521 inches. DCPP later determined that the previously installed CCVTs had the longer creepage distance. </P><P>Relative to the auxiliary feedwater pump, PG&amp;E had implemented a temporary setpoint change in March 2012 to address a deficiency related to Rosemount transmitter uncertainty error increase. This resulted in a setpoint change for each ofthe steam generator (SG) low-low level setpoints from 15 percent to 17 percent for the auxiliary feedwater (AFW) pump autostarts. Procedures were reviewed to identify necessary changes due to the level setpoint changes, particularly reviewing all 15 percent level values in the procedures to implement necessary changes. </P><P>The Emergency Operating Procedure EOP E-0.1, &quot;Reactor Trip Response,&quot; Response Not Obtained, Step 6.c, checks whether the turbine-driven (TD) AFW pump should be secured by verifying SG level greater than </P><P>16 percent in at least 3 SGs. The 16 percent value is derivative ofthe 15 percent AFW start setpoint, but is not explained as such in the setpoint basis documents or in the text ofthe procedures. Without a clear link between the 15 percent and the 16 percent value provided in the procedure or setpoint bases documents, procedure writers failed to identify the need to increase the 16 percent procedure requirement. </P><P>B. Event Description </P><P>On October 11, 2012, during a light rain, plant personnel identified visible arcing on the Unit 2 &quot;A&quot; and &quot;B&quot; Phase MBT CCVTs. At 1208 PDT, the &quot;A&quot; Phase MBT CCVT flashed over to ground, causing a single-line-to-ground fault. This caused the 500kV tie-line differential relay to actuate, resulting in a Unit 2 trip. The Unit 2 trip actuated a turbine trip and, because Unit 2 was operating above the 50 percent power permissive, the reactor protection system initiated a Unit 2 reactor trip. All plant equipment, including the auto start ofthe AFW system, responded as designed. </P><P>About 18 minutes after the reactor trip, plant operators manually closed the steam supply valve to the TD AFW pump to secure the pump. Operators performed this action in accordance with plant operating procedures after they verified that the indicated SG levels were greater than the procedural requirement of 16 percent narrow range span. However, because the SG low-level bistables associated with the AFW actuation circuits had not yet cleared, the emergency safeguards actuation signal drove the steam-supply valve back open, restarting the TD AFW pump. Operators increased steam generator levels to clear the bistables and successfully reclosed the steam-supply valve. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000-323 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -002 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE C. Status ofInoperable Structure, Systems, or Components That Contributed to the Event None. D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected None. E. Method ofDiscovery Annunciators in the control room alerted licensed control room operators ofthe 500kV system problem. F. Operator Actions Plant operators verified appropriate plant trip response using Emergency Operating Procedure (EOP) E-O, &quot;Reactor Trip or Safety Injection&quot; and EOP E-O.1, &quot;Reactor Trip Response.&quot; G. Safety System Responses Vital buses transferred from auxiliary power to startup power as designed. III. Cause ofthe Problem DCPP determined that the CCVT bushing failed because the insulator minimum creepage distance was not consistent with industry codes and standards for the contaminant levels in its operating environment. When the bushing was replaced in 2011, DCPP staff performing the design change referenced a design document that was not updated to reflect current industry codes and standards. When the design document provided unclear and conflicting information, DCPP staff made unvalidated assumptions, and over-relied on PG&amp;E and industry experts. This resulted in selection of an insulator with a creepage distance that was less than the minimum creepage distance recommended by current industry codes and standards. The cause ofthe AFW pump setpoint procedure issue was a human knowledge based error. IV. Assessment of Safety Consequences There were no safety consequences as a result ofthis event. The transfer of plant loads to startup occurred as designed. Equipment necessary decay heat removal was available and operated as required by plant procedures. The unexpected restart ofthe AFW pump did not challenge operator restoration actions or operational limits. Unit 1 remained at full power and all vital buses remained powered by auxiliary power. Therefore, the event is not considered risk significant and did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)U,S, NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000-323 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>5 OF 6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 • 002 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE V. Corrective Actions A. Immediate Corrective Actions The following immediate corrective actions relative to the CCVTs were taken following the CCVT failure: (1) Replace the Unit 2 &quot;A&quot; Phase CCVT and perform Power Factor (PF) testing. (2) Replace the Unit 2 &quot;A&quot; Phase LA and perform PF testing. (3) Perform PF testing ofthe Unit 2 &quot;B&quot; and &quot;C&quot; Phase CCVT and LA. (4) Clean the HV Polymer Bushings on the Unit 2 MBT &quot;A&quot; and &quot;B&quot; Phases (&quot;C&quot; Phase is ceramic) and clean the insulators on the Unit 2 &quot;A,&quot; &quot;B,&quot; and &quot;C&quot; Phases CCVTs and LAs. (5) Megger the secondary circuits ofthe Unit 2 &quot;A&quot; Phase CCVT (between the CCVT and CAL-ISO metering relays). (6) Establish monthly corona-camera monitoring and weekly infrared monitoring to identify trends. (7) Establish visible light camera to monitor Unit 1 CCVTs with real time video. B. Corrective Actions to Prevent Recurrence PG&amp;E implemented the following actions to prevent recurrence: (1) Incorporated lessons learned in a newsletter targeted for the entire Engineering Support Personnel group to inform personnel ofthe event and emphasize the expectation / procedural requirements to review industry standards and codes when performing design work / evaluations. (2) Revised Design Criteria Memorandum (DCM) S-61B to reflect: (a) IEEE C57.19.100 and C57.19.01, &quot;IEEE Standard Performance Characteristics and Dimensions for Outdoor Apparatus Bushings,&quot; guidance for creepage distance for all high voltage insulators including determination of contamination classifications; and (b) IEEE 693, &quot;Nonlinear Structural Dynamics And Coritrol Research,&quot; guidance for seismic criteria. Additionally, PG&amp;E will implement the following actions to prevent recurrence: (1) Revise design procedures and process to incorporate an expectation to review current industry codes and standards for information relevant to the design work being performed and to use and understand the standard's guidance as appropriate to ensure a correct use ofthe guidance. (2) Relocate the CCVTs from the MBT to the 500kV switchyard, which has lower environmental contamination levels. Unit 2 CCVTs were relocated during the Unit 2 Seventeenth Refueling Outage. Unit 1 CCVTs are scheduled to be relocated in July 2013. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)U,S, NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000-323 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL 1 NUMBER I REV NO. </TD><TD>6 OF 6 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 .. 002 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE C. AFW Pump Setpoint Corrective Actions (1) Update setpoint document to identify the relationship between the SG setpoint and the TD AFW pump actions. (2) Tailboard Operations procedure writer staff on the event and the expectation to consult supporting documents when performing Emergency Operating Procedure modification scoping. VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components The DCPP Unit 2 MBT &quot;A&quot; phase CCVT bushing failed due to an insulator flashover. B. Previous Similar Events On August 16,2008, Diablo Canyon Unit 2 MBT &quot;C&quot; Phase experienced a catastrophic failure ofthe HV bushing. A significant amount of porcelain shrapnel resulted from the failure. The debris damaged adjacent equipment and penetrated the northeast side ofthe administration building in multiple locations. Debris was also found in the parking lot several hundred feet away. The event occurred at 23:56 on a Saturday. The potential for injury was very high ifthe catastrophic failure ofthat HV bushing had occurred on a normal workday. A root cause evaluation performed as a result ofthe MBT &quot;C&quot; Phase HV bushing failure found that catastrophic failure ofbushings was not an uncommon occurrence. To improve personnel safety, a recommendation was made to replace the MBT porcelain bushings, the CCVTs, and the LAs with models made with a safer insulator material. Design changes were developed and components were replaced with models made of a silicone polymer insulator rather than porcelain. Bushings ofUnit 2 MBT &quot;A&quot; and &quot;B&quot; phases were replaced with polymer in 2009. The Unit 2 MBT &quot;C&quot; phase bushing remains of porcelain design. In Unit 2 Refueling Outage Sixteen, the CCVTs and LAs were replaced with polymer. In Unit 1 Refueling Outage 17, the CCVTs and LAs were replaced with polymer. All three Unit 1 MBTs continue to have porcelain bushings. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>