<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-12-12T13:58:59-08:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-12-12T14:05:47-08:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-12-12T14:05:47-08:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:4f705e38-900d-4326-9e18-cc4006d3e7bf</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:b3bef1b5-7ae4-464d-bc80-b6d72b5c4356</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>Pacific Gas and </TH></TR><TR><TH>Electric Company® </TH></TR><TR><TH>Barry S. Allen </TH><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plant </TD></TR><TR><TH>Site Vice President </TH><TD>Mail Code 104/6 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>P. O. Box 56 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>Avila Beach, CA 93424 </TD></TR><TR><TH>December 12,2013 </TH><TD/><TD>805.545.4888 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>Internal: 691.4888 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-13-117 </TH><TD/><TD>Fax: 805.545.6445 </TD></TR></Table><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 10 CFR 50.73 ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Docket No. 50-275, OL-DPR-80 Diablo Canyon Unit 1 Licensee Event Report 1-2013-007-00, Auxiliary Feedwater Actuation Due to a Main Feedwater Pump Trip </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff; </P><P>Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) submits the enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) for a valid manual actuation of the auxiliary feedwater system when a main feedwater pump tripped. PG&amp;E is submitting this LER in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A). </P><P>PG&amp;E makes no new or revised regulatory commitments (as defined by NEI 99-04) in this report. PG&amp;E will implement corrective actions in accordance with the Diablo Canyon Power Plant Corrective Action Program. </P><P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>d~-A-Z Lj~J;..</P><P>Barry S. Allen </P><P>ssz1/4040/5058801 0/5058811 0/50588799 </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc\enc: 	Brian J. Benney, NRR Project Manager Marc L. Dapas, NRC Region IV Thomas R. Hipschman, NRC Senior Resident Inspector INPO Diablo Distribution </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance 
Callaway. Comanche Peak. Diablo Canyon. Palo Verde. San Onofre. South Texas Project. Wolf Creek 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 30 hours. Re!orted lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fe back to indust~ Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAlPrivacy Section -5 F53). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.~ov. and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NE B-10202, (3150-0104), Office of ManaQement and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an Information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Power Plant Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000-275 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Licensee Event Report 1-2013-007-00, Auxiliary Feedwater Actuation Due to a Main Feedwater Pump Trip </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACiLITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR _I SEQUENTIALI REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>10 </TH><TD>14 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>2013 . 007 -00 </TD><TD>12 </TD><TD>12 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) o 20.2201 (b) D 20.2203(a)(3}(i) o 50.73(a}(2}(i)(C} D 50.73(a}(2)(vii)D 20.2201 (d) D 20.2203(a}(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii}(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A}D 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii}(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)o 20.2203(a)(2}(i} o 50.36(c)(1}(i)(A} o 50.73(a}(2)(iii) o 50.73(a}(2)(ix}(A)D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii} D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv}(A} D 50.73(a}(2)(x)D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) B50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4}o 20.2203(a}(2}(iv) 50.46(a)(3}(ii) o 50.73(a}(2)(v)(B) D 73.71(a)(5)o 20.2203(a}(2)(v} o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C} D OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a}(2}(i)(B) D 50.73(a)(2}(v)(O) Specify In Abstract below er in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Steven Zawalick, Diablo Canyon Power Plant (805) 545-4040 I </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU:' FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>B </TH><TD>JK </TD><TD>ACC </TD><TD>D-1400 </TD><TD>Y </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 0 NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On October 14,2013, at 15:11 PDT, with Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Unit 1 in Mode 1 at 100 percent power, Main Feedwater Pump 1-1 tripped. This event began when a 480 V bus overcurrent relay tripped during relay maintenance and caused a loss of control oil pressure which resulted in a main feedwater pump trip. In response, plant operators controlled a ramp from 100 percent to 50 percent power and manually started the auxiliary feedwater pumps per plant procedures and conditions. The auxiliary feedwater system actuation was reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(iv)(a) in NRC Event Notification 49442. DCPP determined that the cause ofthe relay trip was failure to incorporate operating experience in the relay maintenance procedure. Similar inservice relay testing was halted until the procedure is updated. DCPP determined that the main feedwater pump trip occurred due to loss of power to the in-service control pump (caused by the 480 V bus deenergization) and the inability ofthe backup control oil system to respond quickly enough due to nitrogen pre-charge leakage from an accumulator bladder. The bladder was replaced and the system tested. Other corrective actions are also being implemented. This event did not adversely affect the health or safety ofthe public. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULAT~~Y,COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET . </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL r NUMBER I REV NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 -007 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE 1. Plant Conditions Prior to the event, Unit 1 was operating in Mode 1 (Power Operation) at approximately 100 percent reactor [RCT] power with normal operating reactor coolant temperature and pressure. Following the event, plant operators stabilized the reactor at approximately 50 percent reactor power. II. Problem Description A. Background The main feedwater pump [P] delivers high-temperature, high-pressure feedwater to the steam generators (SGs) as required by the secondary plant steam load. Both turbine-driven [TRB] main feedwater pumps are controlled by governor valves [65] and a control system. The control system uses oil pressure to hydraulically open and close the valves on the turbine as needed. Upon a loss ofoil pressure, the turbine will automatically shut down. The Auxiliary Feedwater (AFW) System [BA] supplies feedwater to the SGs when the main feedwater system [SJ] is unavailable. It provides an engineered safety feature of removing decay heat from the reactor coolant system [AB]. B. Event Description On October 14,2013, at 15:11 PDT, the overcurrent relay [50] for the Bus [BU] feeder to 480 V Bus 15D tripped during relay maintenance. At the time ofthe trip, the Main Feedwater Pump 1-1 alternating current (AC) Lube Oil Pump 1 (T1MOP1) was in service and fed from Bus 15D. Main Feedwater Pump 1-1 AC Lube Oil Pump 2 (T1MOP2) was in standby, fed from Bus 15E. The loss ofBus 15D resulted in a loss of power to T1MOP1, which triggered an automatic start ofT1MOP2. T1MOP2 started after the loss ofBus 15D, but the control oil pressure dropped rapidly and Main Feedwater Pump 1-1 tripped on low control oil pressure before T1MOP2 could recover the pressure. The low pressure transient in the control oil header during an AC oil pump swap was recognized as a threat to reliable feedwater pump operation and a design change in 1992 installed hydraulic accumulators [ACC] in the system for each pump. The purpose ofthe accumulator is to maintain oil pressure during an AC oil pump swap which would occur during the loss ofthe running pump. The accumulator consists ofa vertical steel tank [TK] with an internal nitrile bladder precharged with nitrogen. This oil accumulator system failed to maintain pressure during the pump swap due to a nitrogen leak from its bladder assembly. Following the trip ofthe Main Feedwater Pump 1-1, the turbine control system [JJ] initiated an automatic ramp from 100 percent to 50 percent turbine load. Operators entered Abnormal Operating Procedure (OP) AP-15, &quot;Loss ofFeedwater Flow,&quot; and started both motor-driven AFW Pumps 1-2 and 1-3, based on procedural guidance and existing plant conditions. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)U,S, NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 -007 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE The AFW system actuation was reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(iv)(a) in NRC Event Notification 49442. The valid actuation is reportable as a Licensee Event Report in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv) (A). C. Status ofInoperable Structure, Systems, or Components That Contributed to the Event The main feedwater pump control oil system accumulator bladder system failed to maintain its nitrogen precharge, which resulted in a low pressure transient and main feedwater pump trip. D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected The turbine control system automatic ramp from 100 percent to 50 percent power was successful. Both motor driven AFW pumps operated as expected. E. Method ofDiscovery Alarms [ALM] and indications received in the control room alerted licensed plant operators to the event. F. Operator Actions Operators entered Abnormal Operating Procedure (OP) AP-15, &quot;Loss ofFeedwater Flow,&quot; and started both motor-driven AFW Pumps 1-2 and 1-3, based on procedural guidance and existing plant conditions. G. Safety System Responses All safety systems responded as designed. III. Cause ofthe Problem DCPP determined that the cause ofthe Bus 15D trip was an organizational weakness and failure to incorporate operating experience in the relay maintenance procedure. DCPP determined that the main feedwater pump trip occurred due to loss ofpower to the in-service control pump (caused by the 480 V bus deenergization) and the inability ofthe backup control oil system to respond quickly enough due to nitrogen precharge leakage from an accumulator bladder. Several contributory causes were related to not monitoring the bladder pressure, not checking for leaks at operating pressure, and not providing guidance on bladder replacement. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 • 007 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE IV. Assessment of Safety Consequences The protective features that shutdown the Main Feedwater Pump 1-1 operated as designed. The plant response involved the turbine control system, operations staff and the AFW system. All safety systems responded as expected and designed. Overall, this was an uncomplicated event and there were no resulting personnel, off-site radiological, or environmental safety issues caused by this event. The safety significance of this event is very low. This event did not adversely affect the health or safety ofthe public. V. Corrective Actions A. Immediate Corrective Actions Similar inservice relay testing was halted until plant procedures incorporate the lessons learned and external operating experience. Specifically, a 1997 event (OE 161841) involved an inadvertent relay actuation on the General Electric model 12IAC53A101A relay at Fort Calhoun station. The accumulator bladder was replaced and tested prior to operation. B. Other Corrective Actions Operators will record the accumulator pressure daily. Accumulator bladder maintenance and testing processes will also be enhanced. VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components The main turbine control oil system accumulator failed to maintain its precharge pressure. B. Previous Similar Events Following a 1999 kelp overload at the intake, oil was found in this accumulator's pressure indicator, suggesting a bladder tear. The bladder was replaced at that time. It was replaced again in 2012 as part of a preventative maintenance activity. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>