<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-08-22T12:53:14-07:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-08-22T13:33:28-07:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-08-22T13:33:28-07:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:4a45b07a-7108-4a17-ae2b-8e691fff3fb8</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:f4acc9f3-87c1-d24a-9c2f-b4ff3bf04cab</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>Pacific Gas and </TH></TR><TR><TH>Electric Company® </TH></TR><TR><TH>Barry S. Allen </TH><TD>Diablo Canyon Power Plan t </TD></TR><TR><TH>Site Vice President </TH><TD>Mail Code 104/6 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>P. O. Box 56 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>Avil a Beach, CA 93 424 </TD></TR><TR><TH>August22,2013 </TH><TD/><TD>805 .545.4888 In tern al: 691 .4888 </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD>Fax : 805.545.6445 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PG&amp;E Letter DCL-13-084 </TH><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 10 CFR 50.73 ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Docket No. 50-275, OL-DPR-80 Diablo Canyon Unit 1 Licensee Event Report 1-2013-004-00, All Three Unit 1 Emergency Diesel Generators Momentarily Inoperable </P><P>Dear Commissioners and Staff; </P><P>In accordance with1 0 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) submits the enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER). This LER describes Unit 1 being in an unanalyzed condition and a condition that could have prevented fulfillment of a safety function due to huma'n error. </P><P>PG&amp;E makes no new or revised regulatory commitments (as defined by NEI 99-04) in this report. </P><P>All of the corrective actions identified in this letter will be implemented in accordance with the Diablo Canyon Power Plant corrective action program. </P><P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Barry S. Allen </P><P>SSZ1/4040/50570582 Enclosure </P><P>cc: 	Thomas R. Hipschman, NRC Senior Resident Inspector Jennivine K. Rankin, NRR Project Manager Steven A. Reynolds, NRC Region IV Diablo Distribution INPO </P><P>A membe r of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance 
Callaway . Comanche Peak . Diablo Canyon . Palo Verde . San Onofre . South Texas Project . Wol f Creek 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO, 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industc,' Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Privacy Section T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc'bov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NE B-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 130 PAGEl 05000-275 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE All Three Unit 1 Emergency Diesel Generators Momentarily Inoperable </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>06 </TH><TD>23 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>2013 . 004 . 00 </TD><TD>08 </TD><TD>22 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) D 20.2201 (b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) [(] 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) B50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71(a)(5) D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) [(] 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER I</TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Steven Zawalick, Senior Engineer, Regulatory Services (805) 545-4040 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE ,,; TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>&quot; </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED DYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) [{]NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 23, 20l3, at 22:01 PDT, Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Unit 1 control room operators used an annunciator response procedure to address the loss ofstartup power. Contrary to Technical Specification, 3.8.1, plant operators made all three Unit 1 emergency diesel generators inoperable when they simultaneously placed all three emergency diesel generator control switches into manual control. On June 24, 20l3, at 22:07 PDT, PG&amp;E made an 8-hour, non-emergency report to the NRC (reference NRC Event Notification Number 49147). DCPP determined that this was the result of inattention by control room operators, lack ofoversight by the Shift Foreman, and an absence of cautionary instructions in the annunciator response procedure. Plant management issued an Operations Shift Order that reinforces guidance and expectations for oversight, processed personnel accountability as appropriate, and will revise plant procedures for oversight and annunciator response. All actions are scheduled to be complete by September 26, 20l3. This event did not adversely affect the health or safety ofthe public. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10.2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR REV NO.I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 -004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE I. Plant Conditions Unit 1 operated in Mode 1 (Power Operation) at approximately 100 percent reactor power with normal operating reactor coolant temperature and pressure throughout the event. II. Problem Description A. Background Diablo Canyon Power Plant (DCPP) Unit 1 has three emergency diesel generators (EDGs) [DG] that provide vital backup power to three electrical buses [BU] to mitigate the consequences of a design basis accident (DBA) whenever normal or offsite power sources [EK] are unavailable. DCPP EDGs are designed to function so that a single failure of any EDG will not jeopardize the capability ofthe remaining EDGs to start and provide power to operate the shutdown systems required to mitigate any DBA condition. Each EDG is supplied with a control room selector switch [HS] for auto or manual mode control. When the selector switch for an EDG is taken to manual, the EDG is inoperable as it will not start in response to normal autostart signals or load onto the vital electrical buses. B. Event Description On June 24, 20l3, at 16:15 PDT, an operator reviewing EDG performance data (related to the loss of230 kV startup power [EK] event reported in NRC Event Notification (EN) Number 49143) identified that during the previous night operators had simultaneously disabled all three Unit 1 EDGs, prior to restoring them to their automatic standby control alignment. DCPP was in this condition for 1 minute and 44 seconds (between 22:01:10 PDT and 22:02:54 PDT, on June 23, 20l3). During this time, less than the required minimum oftwo EDGs were available to automatically respond to a DBA. Due to the event reported in NRC EN Number 49143, the startup 230 kV power source was also inoperable at this time. As reported in NRC EN Number 49143, DCPP lost startup power due to an offsite transmission system relay actuation. This resulted in a valid, anticipatory start of all six EDGs. During the restoration activities, operators were in the procedurally-guided process of placing each ofthe running EDG's controls to manual and shutting them down. Once this was complete, the EDGs were returned to the automatic standby control alignment. However, the operators placed all three EDGs in manual and shut them down before returning them to automatic control. During this time, the operators would have responded to a plant event by returning the affected EDGs to auto, whereupon the normal starting and loading sequence would have resumed in accordance with existing accident analyses. At the time of discovery all offsite and onsite power sources were operable. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 -004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE C. Status ofInoperable Structure, Systems, or Components That Contributed to the Event Due to the event reported in NRC EN Number 49143, the startup 230 kV power source was also inoperable during the restoration activities. On June 24, 2013, at 02:00 PDT, operators restored the 230 kV system to operable status. I D. Other Systems or Secondary Functions Affected None. E. Method ofDiscovery An operator reviewing EDG performance data discovered the reportable condition caused by the error. F. Operator Actions At the time ofdiscovery, all offsite and onsite power sources were operable. No actions were required G. Safety System Responses None. III. Cause ofthe Problem Pacific Gas and Electric Company (PG&amp;E) determined the cause ofthis event was an inattentive error by control room operators who placed all EDGs in manual before returning the selector switch to auto. Additionally, the Shift Foreman did not provide oversight as required by plant procedures and the annunciator response procedure did not contain any caution or note to prevent operators from using manual control to shut down all three EDGs concurrently. IV. Assessment of Safety Consequences DCPP performed a probabilistic risk assessment and documented the results in a formal calculation for the exposure period. The exposure timeframe started when the second EDG was stopped and ended when the second EDG was placed in auto. DCPP was in this condition for 1 minute and 44 seconds (between 22:01:10 PDT and 22:02:54 PDT, on June 23, 2013). During this time, less than the required minimum two EDGs were available to automatically respond to a DBA. The calculation showed that both incremental core damage and large early release probabilities were well below their respective acceptance criteria. Therefore, the event is not considered risk significant and did not adversely affect the health and safety ofthe public. This event was a safety system functional failure. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Diablo Canyon Power Plant, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-275 </TD><TD>YEAR REV NO.ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 .. 004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE V. Corrective Actions A. Immediate Corrective Actions Plant management issued an operations shift order that reinforces guidance and expectations for oversight as stated in plant procedures. B. Other Corrective Actions PG&amp;E reviewed the personnel performance ofthe Shift Foreman, Work Control Lead, Balance ofPlant Control Operator, and the Control Operator using the accountability process to assess their response. In accordance with plant processes, an action plan will be maintained in the crew notebook as required. DCPP will revise Departmental Administrative Procedure OPl.DClO, &quot;Conduct of Operations,&quot; to enhance Shift Foreman oversight expectations to provide direct supervision and oversight ofthe control room operators for equipment manipulations on the front control board panels. The revision will also ensure that an adequate prejob brief is performed for similar evolutions. DCPP will revise Annunciator Response Procedure PK19-04, &quot;12KV SU BUS UV,&quot; (startup bus undervoltage) to have sequential steps for placing EDGs in manual and securing them, one at a time, with specific notes or cautions highlighting EDG inoperability when in manual. VI. Additional Information A. Failed Components None. B. Previous Similar Events None. C. Industry Reports None. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>