<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-06-26T07:42:50-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-06-26T07:42:50-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-06-26T07:42:50-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:26cf743e-9f0e-4134-9b8c-7057675a7b64</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:fdd5c622-7277-bc4a-bd4f-47f30cba4354</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>\~.-:: </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>South Texas Project Electric Generating Station P.D. Bar 289 Wadsworth. Texas 77-18J </P><P>----------------------~~ </P><P>May 31,2012 NOC-AE-12002857 File No.: G25 10 CFR 50.73 STI: 33550063 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attention: Document Control Desk One White Flint North 11555 Rockville Pike Rockville, MD 20852-2738 </P><P>South Texas Project 
Unit 1 
Docket No. STN 50-498 
Licensee Event Report 1-2012-001 
Nuclear Instrumentation Channel NI-45A Failed Channel Check 
</P><P>Pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73, STP Nuclear Operating Company (STPNOC) submits the attached Unit 1 Licensee Event Report (LER) 1-2012-001 to address the inoperability of Extended Range (E/R) Flux Lower Range Nuclear Instrument (NI-45A) based on failure to meet procedural acceptance criteria and Technical Specifications Limiting Condition of 9peration. </P><P>This event is considered reportable pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8), as any operation or condition that was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications. </P><P>This event did not have an adverse effect on the health and safety of the public. </P><P>This is this initial LER submittal. A planned supplement will be submitted no later than August 1,2012. </P><P>There are no commitments contained in this LER. Corrective actions will be implemented in accordance with the STP Corrective Action Program. </P><P>If there are any questions on this submittal, please contact either Joe Loya at (361) 972-8005 or me at (361) 972-7566. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH/><TH>G. T. Powell </TH></TR><TR><TH/><TD>Vice-President, Generation </TD></TR><TR><TH>JAL </TH><TD/></TR><TR><TH>Attachment: </TH><TD>LER 1-2012-001 </TD><TD/></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>cc: (paper copy) </P><P>Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 1600 East Lamar Blvd Arlington, Texas 76011-4511 </P><P>Balwant K. Singal Senior Project Manager </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission One White Flint North (MS 8B1) 11555 Rockville Pike Rockville, MD 20852 </P><P>Senior Resident Inspector </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><Table><TR><TD>P. O. Box 289, Mail Code: Wadsworth, TX 77483 </TD><TD>MN116 ' </TD></TR><TR><TD>C. M. Canady City of Austin Electric Utility Department 721 Barton Springs Road Austin, TX 78704 </TD><TD/></TR></Table><P>-..</P><P>NOC-AE-12002857 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>(electronic copy) </P><P>A. H. Gutterman, Esquire Morgan, Lewis &amp; Bockius LLP </P><P>Peter Nemeth 
Crain Caton &amp; James, P.C. 
</P><P>John Ragan 
</P><P>Chris O'Hara 
</P><P>Jim von Suski I 
NRG South Texas LP 
</P><P>Kevin Polio 
</P><P>Richard Pena 
</P><P>City Public Service 
</P><P>C, Mele 
City of Austin 
</P><P>Richard A. Ratliff </P><P>Texas Department of State Health </P><P>Services </P><P>Alice Rogers Texas Department of State Health Services </P><P>Balwant K. Singal </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><P>&quot;~.. </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12178A064_img_3.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) 1. FACILITY NAME South Texas Unit 1 4. TITLE APPROVED BY OMB: NO, 3150·0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Repor·ted lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Prtvacy Section (T-5 F53). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington. DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to 1111&quot;..,(;,,1 J I'n~': rt'!;Otl!':;&lt;'~IJ n·, g,'\', and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. NEOB-10202. (3150-1104), Office of Management and Budget. Washington. DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMS.control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to the information collection. 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE 05000498 1 OF 3 Unit 1 Nuclear Instrumentation Channel NI-45A Failed Channel Check 5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER I 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED MONTH I DAY i YEAR I YEAR , SEQUENTIAL I REV I MONTH DAY ! YEAR ! FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER, !i I NUMBER NO. Ii I I i : I i N/A N/A 03 127 ! 2012 2012 001 0 1 05 31 2012 ! N/A N/A i , i 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10CFR§: (Check al/ that apply) 1 D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) 10. POWER LEOVEL D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 100% D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50. 36(c)(1)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) D 20. 2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71(a)(5) D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) I:8J 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A 12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME : TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Joe Loya, Licensing Engineer i 361-972-8005 13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE TO FACTURER EPIX X IG RI Thermo-YES Fisher 14. SUPPLEMENTAL RESPONSE EXPECTED ~ YES (if yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) r NO CAUSE ABSTRACT (Limit tei 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) SYSTEM COMPONENT 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE MANUFACTURER MONTH 08 REPORTABLE TO EPIX DAY I YEAR 01 I 2012 On March 27, 2012, Operations declared the Extended Range (E/R) Flux Lower Range Nuclear Instrument (NI-45A) inoperable based on failure to meet channel check acceptance criteria per the &quot;Remote Shutdown Monitoring AND Accident Monitoring Instrumentation Channel Checks&quot; Procedure. Subsequent troubleshooting discovered an issue with the channel's isolation circuit card, AT1. The AT1 card was found with a degraded condition which affected the output range of NI-45A. With this degraded condition, Extended Range (E/R) Flux Lower Range Nuclear Instrument (NI-45A) would not have been able to perform its design function. Subsequent review determined that NI 45A had been inoperable since February 29, 2012. After replacement of the AT1 card, the surveillance procedure was completed satisfactory on March 30, 2012 and the instrument was restored to operable. Since NI-45 had been inoperable for longer than the applicable Technical Specification 7 day Allowed Outage Time, this event is reportable under 1 OCFR50.73(a)(2)(i)(6), as an Operation or Condition Prohibited by Technical SpeCifications. This is the initial LER for this event. A planned Supplemental LER will be submitted as indicated above. There were no personnel injuries, no offsite radiological releases, and no damage to safety-related equipment associated with this condition. This condition did not have an adverse effect on the health and safety of the public. ~ </Figure><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM366A LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME ---------------------------------South Texas Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET ---------05000498 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER ----I---------~-----YEAR !SEQUENTIAL I REV. NO 2012 i NUMBER ! I 001 -r--oo---I , </TD><TD>3. PAGE --------------2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>I. DESCRIPTION OF EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION This event is reportable pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), as any operation or condition that was prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications. B. PLANT OPERATING CONDITIONS PRIOR TO EVENT South Texas Project (STP) Unit 1 was in Mode 1, with Reactor Power at approximately 100%. I C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, AND COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE EVENT No structures, systems, or components were inoperable at the start of the event that contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE' EVENT On March 27,2012, Operations declared the Extended Range (E/R) Flux Lower Range Nuclear Instrument·(NI-45A) inoperable based on the failure to meet Technical Specifications (TS) channel check acceptance criteria per the &quot;Remote Shutdown Monitoring AND Accident Monitoring Instrumentation Channel Checks&quot; Procedure. Subsequent troubleshooting discovered an issue with the channel's isolation circuit card, AT1. The AT1 card was found with a degraded condition which affected the indication of NI-45A Lower Range. With this degraded condition, Extended Range (E/R) Flux Lower Range Nuclear Instrument (NI-45A) would not have been able to perform its design function. After replacement of the AT1 card, the surveillance procedure was completed satisfactory on March 30, 2012 and the instrument was returned to an operable condition. Each E/R channel has a Lower Range (which provides indication in shutdown conditions (counts per second)) and an Upper Range (which provides indication at power). For the time period under evaluation, Unit 1 was operating at power and the E/R Lower Range indication was saturated and considered unreliable. The E/R Lower Range indication is considered unreliable above approximately 1 E-4% Power (100,000 CPS). At 100,000 CPS, saturation occurs in the Extended Range Lower Range Nuclear Instrumentation circuitry and a channel may indicate less than 100,000 CPS. A review of channel data indicated that starting in December 2011; the NI-45 E/R Lower Range indication began a downward trend. Subsequent Channel Checks performed in January and February (monthly surveillance) were completed satisfactorily. These Channel Checks are performed with an acceptance criterion that notes the Lower Range indications may be unreliable, and that other indications such as E/R Upper Range output may be used to determine problems with the detector. During this time period, there were no issues found with the detectors E/R Upper' Range output indication. As stated previously, a degraded condition (downward trend) involving the E/R Lower Range indication had been evident since December 2011. Even though this indication is considered unreliable, there is reasonable confidence that in this instance, the indication showed the degrading performance of the AT1 card. Based on how the Surveillance procedure is performed, the Channel Check between N 1-45A and N 1-46A would have failed to meet the &quot;factor of 10&quot; acceptance criteria on February 29,2012, (NI-045A =10,527 cps, NI-046A =106,057 cps). Therefore, it was concluded that the E/R Lower Range indication was inoperable from February 29, 2012 until the </TH></TR></Table><P>.-
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>South Texas Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000498 </TD><TD>_~~~__l~_~~~~~T~.~_.J_~~~'.~.~_.__ 2012 ! 001 I 00 </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>channel was restored to operable on March 30, 2012. The TS 3.3.3.6 Allowed Outage Time for an inoperable Extended Range nuclear instrumentation channel is 7 days. Because Extended Range channel NI-45 was inoperable longer than the TS allowed outage time and associated shutdown time, this event is considered REPORTABLE under 1 OCFR50. 73(a)(2)(i)(B), Operations or Conditions Prohibited by Technical Specifications. E. METHOD OF DISCOVERY This event was discovered by Operations during the performance of the &quot;Remote Shutdown Monitoring AND Accident Monitoring Instrumentation Channel Checks&quot; surveillance procedure. II. EVENT-DRIVEN INFORMATION A SAFETY SYSTEMS THAT RESPONDED N/A B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM INOPERABILITY As discussed above, the Extended Range (E/R) Flux Lower Range Nuclear Instrument (NI-45A) was inoperable from February 29, 2012 until March 30, 2012 (approximately 31 days). C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OFTHE EVENT Nuclear or radiological safety was not affected. This event had no impact to the safety of the public or station personnel. This event did not impact the reliability of plant operation or production capacity. There was no impact to the Core Damage Frequency or Large Early Release Frequency associated with this event. III. GAUSE OF THE EVENT The Root Cause is under investigation and will be submitted in the planned LER supplement. IV. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS The Root Cause of the event, including the resulting corrective actions, is under investigation and will be submitted in the planned LER supplement. V. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS There have been no similar reportable events at STP within the last three years. VI. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION N/A </TH></TR><Caption><P>FORM 366 (10-2010) </P></Caption></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>