<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2003-08-25T16:16:38-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2003-08-25T16:16:38-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2003-08-25T16:16:38-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>EMERGY 
</H1><Sect><H5>NORTHWEST </H5><P>----~-------------.-----•..--------:-~--~~~~--~-</P><P>P.O. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>August 14, 2003 </P><P>G02-03-129 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 
</P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397 
LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2003-005-00 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2003-005-00 for the Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B). The enclosed report discusses items of reportabiJity and corrective actions taken. </P><P>If you have any questions or require additional information, please contact Ms. CL Perino at </P><P>(509) 377-2075. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><P>tt~ </P><P>Vice President, Nuclear Generation 
Mail Drop PE04 
</P><P>Enclosure: Licensee Event Report 2003-005-00 </P><P>cc: 	TP Gwynn -NRC RIV 
BJ Benney -NRC-NRR 
INPO Records Center 
NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) 
RN Sherman -BPA/1399 
TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn 
WB Jones -NRC RIVlfax 
</P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>--. </P><P>, . ';..&quot; </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_08_17_ML032370515_img_1.jpg"/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_08_17_ML032370515_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3160-0104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 (1-2001) COMMISSION estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory Information collection request 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated Into the licensing process and fed back to Industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T-8 Ee). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington DC LICENSEE EVENT REPORt(LER) 20555-0001, or by Internet 8&quot;1&quot;811 to bls1«1!nrc goY. and to the Desk Officer. Office of Information and Regulato,yAffalrs. NEOB-10202 (3150-0104). Office of Management and (See reyerse for required number of Budget. Washington. DC 20503.' If a means used to Impose Information collection does digits/characters for each block) not display a currenUy vafld OMB control number, the NRC may not condud or sponsor. and a person Is not reQuired to respond to. the information coI1edlon. FACfUTY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) Columbia Generating Station 05000397 10F4 nTLE(4) Shutdown Cooling Isolation Caused by Procedure Deficiency EVENT DATE (6) LER NUMBER (6 REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED (8) MO DAY YEAR ISEQUENTIAl REV FACIUTY NAME DOCKET NUMBER YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 6 16 2003 2003 OOS 0 8 14 2003 FACIUTY NAME DOCKET NUMBER OPERAnNG 4 THIS REPORT IS SUBMmED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: Check all that apply (11) MODE (e) 20.2201 (b) 20.2203 a 31(1i) 50.73 a 2)(ii)(B) 50.73 a), 2 ix)(A) POWER 00 20.2201 (d) 20.2203 a 4 50.73 a 2)(iii) 50.73 all 2 x) LEVEL (10) 20.2203 (8)(1) 50.36(c)1 1 (1)1 A) 50.73 a :2.)(iv)(A) 73.71 8)14 20.2203 a)(2)(0 50.36 c 1 U)(A) 50.73 a 2 vA 73.71 a)(5) 20.2203 a 2 il 50.36 c 2 X 50.73 a 2 v B Other 20.2203 a 2 ill) 50.46 a 3 ii 50.73 a 2 v C Specify iI AbsIracI below or 20.2203 a 2 iv) 50.73 a 2 i A) 50.73 a 2 v D In NRC Fonn 366A 20.220~a 2 v 50.73 a 2 i B) 50.73 a 2)(vli) 20.22(!3(a 2 vi) 50.73 a)(2 I C) 5O.73(a 2)(viii)(A) 20.2203(a (3)(i) 60.73 8)(2) 1i)(A) 5O.73(a 2)(vlii)(B) LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER ti2) NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Craig Sly 509-377-8616 COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT (13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TOEPIX FACTURER TOEPIX SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEARIYES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). SUBMISSION X NO DATE(15) ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces. I.e.• approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) On June 16, 2003, Columbia Generating Station was in Mode 4 (cold shutdown) with reactor coolant temperature at approximately 112 degrees Fahrenheit. At approximately 1330 PDT, an isolation of the Residual Heat Removal (RHR) Shutdown Cooling (SDC) common suction header occurred when the outboard containment isolation valve RHR-V-8 closed. The RHR SDC isolation occurred while performing a containment isolation logic functional surveillance test. Surveillance Procedure TSP-CONTIISOL-BS01, section 7.6. requires depressing the manual Nuclear Steam Supply Shutoff System (NSSSS) initiation logic B pushbutton. Depressing this pushbutton causes an isolation signal to 16 NSSSS isolation valves, including RHR-V-S. The primary cause of this event was an inadequate surveillance procedure. A contributing cause was inadequate preparation by operators performing the test. The surveillance procedure has been modified to specify the isolations that will occur when performing section 7.6. The pre-job briefing sheet for TSP-CONTIISOL-B50l, section 7.6 has been modified to list the NSSSS isolations that will occur when Section 7.6 is performed. </Figure></Sect><Sect><H3>;\~~'~i t:~~;'yt~ </H3><P>, </P><P>...-~ ... ' .... ,. </P><P>-. -~-~ ..... .</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAl. REVISION LErR NUMBER (6) I :~UMBER NUMBERYEAR </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>~~ . 05000397 </TD><TD>20F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-005-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (ffmote space Is tequited, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) Event Description On June 16, 2003, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) was in Mode 4 (cold shutdown) with the reactor coolant temperature at approximately 112 degrees Fahrenheit. At approximately 1330 PDT. an isolation of Residual Heat Removal (RHR) Shutdown Cooling (SDC) common suction header occurred when the outboard primary containment isolation valve, RHR-V-8 closed. The RHR SOC isolation occurred while performing surveillance procedure TSP-CONTIISOL-B501, &quot;Containment Isolation LSFf,&quot; [Logic System Functional Test] section 7.6; Manual Initiation. Step 7 .6.42 of this surveillance procedure required depressing the manual Nuclear Steam Supply Shutoff System (NSSSS) initiation logic B pushbutton (MS-RMS-S25B). Depressing this pushbutton causes an isolation signal to 16 NSSSS isolation valves, including RHR-V-8. At the time of the event, RHR SDC subsystem A was operating in the shutdown cooling mode and RHR SDC subsystem B was available for SDC service, but not in operation. Reactor Recirculation Pump IB (RRC-P-IB) was running to support reactor core circulation and was unaffected by the RHR SDC isolation. The condensate system was available as an alternate means of decay heat removal by injection into the RPV with heat rejection to the main condenser. -The SDC isolation was caused by closure ofRHR-V-8, the outboard primary containment isolation valve in the common. suction line for both RHR SDC subsystems. ClOsure of RHR-V-8 subsequently tripped RHR SDC pump 2A (RHR-P-2A). Operators entered abnormal condition procedure ABNRHR-SDC-LOSS, &quot;Loss of Shutdown Cooling,&quot; and the appropriate Technical Specification (TS) Required Action (TS 3.4.tO.A). Technical Specification Required Action 3.4. to.A. t requires verifICation that an alternate source of decay heat removal is available for each inoperable RHR SDC subsystem within one hour. All isolation sigDats were reset and RHR SOC was restored approximately 12 minutes after RHR-V-8 closed. During the time that RHR SDC was out of service, reactor coolant temperature increased from approximately 112 to 113 degrees Fahrenheit. Cause of Event The primary cause of this event was an inadequate procedure. Surveillance procedure TSPCONTIISOL-B501, section 7.6, should have contained a description of the expected valve isolations that would occur when the manual pushbutton forNSSSS initiation logic B was depressed. Other sections of this procedure do contain descriptions ofexpected isolations, while section 7.6 does not. A contributing cause was inadequate preparation by the operators performing the test. Even though the surveillance procedure was weak in describing the impact on the plant.when performing section 7.6, a more thorough review to understand the impact of the test being performed may have prevented this event. </TH></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_08_17_ML032370515_img_3.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) r(-' ; U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET (2) LER NUMBER (6) PAGE (3) YEAR Columbia Generating Station JSEQUENTIAL 1REVISION -NUMBER, NUMBER 2003'()()5'()() 30F4 '.\ , Safety Significance This event posed no threat to the health and safety of the public or plant personnel. The RHR SOC system was restored to service in approximately 12 minutes with an increase in reactor coolant temperature of approximately one degree Fahrenheit. A reactor recirculation pump was in operation throughout the event (RRC-P-IB) to provide reactor coolant circulation. Alternate methods for removal of residual heat were available from condensate injection with heat removal via the main condenser and through abnormal condition procedure, ABN-RHR-SOC.;LOSS, &quot;Loss of Shutdown Cooling, &quot; which provides instructions to restore (manually) RHR shutdown cooling. This event is reportable in accordance with 10 CPR 50.73 (a)(2)(v)(B). Immediate Corrective Actions Control Room Operators entered abnormal condition procedure ABN-RHR-SOC-LOSS and reviewed TSP-CONTIISOL-B50l to determine what step was being performed at the time the SDC isolation occurred. In addition, the Shift Manager verified that the operator performing the surveillance test had depressed the correct pushbutton. The NSSSS isolation signal was reset, and RHR SOC subsystem A was placed in service. The applicable drawings were reviewed to confirm that the actuations/isolations that occurred should have been expected. Further Corrective Actions Surveillance procedure TSP-CONT/ISOL-B501 has been modified to specify the isolations that will occur when performing section 7.6. All valves that isolate are listed prior to the steps requiring the manual depressing of an NSSSS initiation logic pushbutton. The pre-job briefing sheet for surveillance procedure TSP-CONT/ISOL-B501, section 7.6, has been modified to reflect that an NSSSS isolation will occur when section 7.6 is performed. Previous Similar Events A review of the Problem Evaluation Request database from 1997 to present found the following similar events: LER 2003-003 reported an RHR SOC isolation due to the-closure of the inboard RHR SOC primary containment isolation valve RHR-V-9. This event occurred during a planned maintenance activity and was caused by maintenance personnel performing work on the wrong relay when replacing a relay wire lug. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>'. </P><P>&quot;;:'~. </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET(2) , </TD><TD>YEAR SEQUENTIAL REVISIONr LER NUMBER (6) I NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>40F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD></TR><TR><TH>An isolation of shutdown cooling occured on June 8.2001 when the RHR suction outboard isolation valve closed during planned maintenance. However. this event was determined not to be reportable under 10 CFR 50.72 or 73 reporting requirements. EllS Information Text Reference RHR SDC Isolation Valve, RHR-V-8 RHR SDC Pump RHR-P-2A Reactor Recirculation Pump (RRC-P-IB) Nuclear Steam Supply Shutoff System System BO BO AD BD Component ISV P P </TH></TR></Table></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>