<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2004-08-18T14:24:59-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2004-08-18T14:24:59-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2004-08-18T14:24:59-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>.... ... l </P><Part><H1>EMERGY </H1><P>NORTHWEST </P><P>P.O. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>August 12, 2004 002-04-142 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: 	COLmmIA GENERATING STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397, LICENSE NO. NPF-21; 60-DAY FOLLOW-UP REPORT REGARDING EVENT NOTIFICATION 40829 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is the 6O-day follow-up report for the subject event notification pursuant to 10 CFR § 73.71(a)(4). </P><P>Should you have any questions or desire additional information regarding this matter, please call Mr. JR Fisher at (509) 377-8599. </P><P>Respectfully, </P></Part><Part><H1>tu4l&amp;F~ </H1><P>DWColeman Manager, Regulatory Programs Mail Drop PE20 </P><P>Attachment: 6O-day Follow-up Report </P><P>BS Mallet -NRC -RN WA Macon -NRC -NRR TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C RN Sherman -BPAl1399 </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2004_08_12_ML042310582_img_1.jpg"/>NRCi'FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 6-30·2001 (1A!'J01) • COMMISSION Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory Information collection request: 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated Into the Ucenslng process and fed back to Industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T-8 Ee), u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington DC 20555-0001, or by Internet e-mail to bis1«11nrc.goy. and to the Desk Officer, Office of LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Budget. Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to Impose Information collection does digits/characters for each block) not display a currenUy valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person Is not required to respond to, the information collection. FACIUTY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) Columbia Generating Station 50-397 10F4 nTLE (4) Detection of Contraband at Protected Area Access Control Checkpoint EVENT DATE 5) LER NUMBER (6) REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED (8) YEAR ISEQUENTIAL 1 REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MO DAY YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 06 18 2004 2004 -003 -00 08 12 2004 FACIUTY NAME DOCKET NUMBER OPERAnNG 1 THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR I: Check aU that apply) (11) MODE(9} 20.2201 (b) 20,2203 a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) 50.73(a)(21(ix)(A) POWER 100% 20.2201 (d) 20.2203 a)(4 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2I(x) LEVEL (10) 20.2203 (a)(1 50,36 c 1 :i)(A) 50.73 a)(2 iv A) X 73.71 (a)(4 20.2203 a 2 i) 50.36(c)(1 ii)(A) 50.73 a 2 v A 73.71 (a)(5 20.2203 a 2 ii 50.36 c 2 50.73 a 2 v B Other 20.2203 a 2 Iii) 50.46 a 3 ii 50.73 a 2 v C Specify i1 Abstract below or 20.2203 a 2 iv) 50.73 a 2 i)IA) 50.73 a 2 v D In NRC Fonn 366A 20.2203 a 2 v 50.73 a 2 i)IB) 50.73 a 2 vii 20.2203 a 2)(vi) 50.73 a 2 i)IC) 50.73 a 2)(viii){A) 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 50.73 a (2)(ii)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER (12 NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Fred A. Schill (509) 377-2269 COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORTj13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TOEPIX FACTURER TOEPIX SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEARIYES (If yes. complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). ~ SUBMISSION NO DATE (1S) ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 Single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) At 1822 on June 18, 2004, with Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) in mode 1, an Energy Northwest security x-ray machine operator detected a loaded handgun in the backpack of an Energy Northwest employee at Columbia's Protected Area (PA) access control point (ref: Event Report 40829). In response to this event, the individual's access to the PA was terminated and he left the owner controlled area after he was determined to be fit for duty. Local law enforcement (Benton County Sheriff) responded and took possession of the firearm. This event meets the criteria specified in 10 CPR § 73, Appendix G, paragraph I(d), as this was an attempted introduction of contraband into Columbia's PA. This report is made pursuant to the requirement of 10 CFR § 73.71(a)(4) for a 6O-day follow-up written report. </Figure><Table><TR><TH>N~FORM366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>OOCKETi21 </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) IREVISION </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 20F4</TD></TR><TR><TH>. Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-003-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space Is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) DESCRIPTION OF EVENT At 1822 on June 18, 2004, with Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) in mode 1, an Energy Northwest security x-ray machine operator detected a loaded handgun in the backpack of an Energy Northwest employee at Columbia's Protected Area (PA) access control point (ref: Event Report 40829). In response to this event, the individual's access to the PA was terminated and he left the owner controlled area after he was determined to be fit for duty. Local law enforcement (Benton County Sheriff) responded and took possession of the firearm. This event meets the criteria specified in 10 CFR § 73, Appendix G, paragraph I(d), as this was an attempted introduction of contraband into Columbia's PA. This report is made pursuant to the requirement of 10 CFR § 73.71(a)(4) for a 6O-day follow-up written report. Regulatory Guide 5.62, revision 1, section 3.2 instructs licensees to use NRC Form 366 when submitting these reports and describes the report content that is sufficient for NRC analysis and evaluation. Because this event does not involve a security system failure or a threat related incident, only items 1 through 14 in section 3.2 of the Regulatory Guide are germane to this issue and are addressed below: Date and Time of Event June 18,2003 at 1822 PDT. Location of Actual or Threatened Event The event occurred in the search area of Columbia's Protected Area (PA) access control point. Plant Operating Phase At the time of this event, Columbia was in mode 1 operating at full power. Safety Systems Threatened, directly or indirectly Because the event did not result in an actual introduction of contraband into th~ protected area, no safety systems were threatened. Type of Security Force onsite Energy Northwest maintains a proprietary security force. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORr:LI 366A (~&quot;tt&gt;01) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) IREVISION </TD><TD>. PAGE(3) 30F4</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-003&quot;()() </TD></TR><TR><TH>Number and type of personnel involved One Energy Northwest employee and two Energy Northwest nuclear security officers were involved with this event. Method of discovery of incident The contraband was detected as the employee's backpack was processed through the x-ray machine in the protected area access control point. Procedural errors involved Although this action was a violation of an Energy Northwest policy. there were no procedural errors involved. Immediate actions taken in response to event Upon discovery of the contraband, the handgun was left in the x-ray machine while the employee was segregated and searched. A local law enforcement official was summoned to the scene and took possession of the firearm. The individual's access to the PA was terminated and he left the owner controlled area after he was determined to be fit for duty. Corrective actions taken or planned The fundamental cause is personnel error due to lack of attention to detail and lack of focus. Therefore, the corrective actions are centered on the individual involved. The individual's unescorted access to the PA has been restored based upon a favorable psychological evaluation and fitness for duty test. Local, State, or Federal law enforcement agencies contacted The local law enforcement agency (Benton County Sheriff) was contacted and took possession of the firearm. . Description of media interest and press release A press release was not issued regarding this condition and there has been no media interest. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRCFO~366A (~1~ u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 40F4</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER IREVISION </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-003-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Indication of previous similar events There have been no previous similar events. Knowledgeable contact For questions or additional information the point of contact is Lieutenant Jim Fisher in the Columbia Resource Protection department, who may be reached by telephone at 509-377-8599. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158 Rl </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>