<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler>
   <abstract>
      <P>On February 8, 2009 at 1125 hours, an automatic reactor scram occurred while Columbia was
         operating in Mode 1 at 75% power. The Digital Electro-Hydraulic (DEH) Control System
         emergency trip header momentarily depressurized during testing following on-line quadvoter
         valve assembly replacement. A Turbine Governor Valve Fast Closure trip signal was generated
         and a reactor scram occurred. </P>
      <P>The direct cause of the event was the introduction of air into the DEH system during
         quadvoter valve replacement and subsequent compression of the unvented, entrapped air
         during post maintenance testing. The compression resulted in backflow and excursion of the
         trip header pressure below the trip setpoint. The root cause is design deficiencies in the
         on-line serviceable quadvoter assembly which allowed system conditions that resulted in a
         reactor trip following performance of on-line maintenance activities. </P>
      <P>Both quadvoter valve assemblies in the affected channelwere replaced. Prior to reactor
         startup, the DEH system was vented and tested to ensure removal of all air. Corrective
         actions to address quadvoter design deficiencies and to improve quadvoter performance have
         been pursued. </P>
      <P>This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. Since the
         installation of a new DEH system at Columbia in 2007, one similar event was reported by
         Energy Northwest in LER 2008-001-00. </P>
   </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>The plant was operating in Mode 1 at 75% power at the time of this
         event.</plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On January 29,2009, Quadvoter &quot;8&quot; (DEH-SV-TRIP/8) failed during
         performance of weekly surveillance testing of the solenoid valves in the DEH system [JJ]
         quadvoter hydraulic trip block [HCU]. The quadvoter valve assemblies are designed for
         on-line repair and Columbia Licensee Controlled Specifications Surveillance Requirements
         require a failed channel be returned to operable status within 14 days. On February 8,
         2009, Ouadvoter &quot;8&quot; Was isolated, replaced, vented, and unisolated in accordance
         with maintenance work instructions. Weekly surveillance testing was performed as the
         prescribed post maintenance testing prior to returning the quadvoter channel to operable
         status. During this testing, the DEH system experienced pressure transients and the trip
         header of the quadvoter valves momentarily depressurized below the Turbine Governor Valve
         Fast Closure trip setpoint. 80th Reactor Protection System (RPS) [JC] trip systems received
         reactor trip signals and, at 1125 PST, a full scram of the reactor [RCT] occurred. All rods
         fully inserted as expected in response to the RPS actuation and heat removal through the
         main condenser [SG] was maintained. A reactor water level 3 isolation occurred with the
         minimum level attained being zero inches. Post trip reactor vessel water level was
         maintained in the normal band using the feedwater [SJ] and condensate systems [SD] and
         pressure was controlled in the normal band using the bypass valves and main steam line
         drains. No other safety systems actuated or were required to actuate. There was no
         inoperable equipment at the start olthe event that contributed to the event. Off-site power
         was available and three emergency diesel generators [EK] were operable and available. Crew
         recognition, response, and decision making enabled effective management of the transient. .
         At 1808 EST (1508 PST), the NRC was notified of the RPS actuation per 10 CFR
         50.72(b}(2}(iv}(8} (reference event notification number 44839). This LER is submitted
         pursuant to 50.73(a)(2}(iv}(A} as an event or condition that resulted in automatic
         actuation of the reactor protection system. </eventDesc>
      <correctiveActions>Following the event, testing was performed to determine the cause of the
         scram. With the reactor shutdown in . Mode 4, Ouadvoter &quot;8&quot; was again replaced,
         vented per instructions provided for on-line replacement, and the weekly surveillance
         testing re-performed. During the testing, pressure measurements of the trip header were
         conducted. The weekly surveillance testing independently de-energizes and re-energizes the
         solenoid valves to demonstrate proper operation. A pressure transient occurred when
         Quadvoter &quot;8&quot; was re-energized causing the trip header pressure to momentarily
         drop below trip point limits. The testing illustrated that the DEH system was not
         completely vented of air.</correctiveActions>
      <eventCause> The direct cause of the scram was the compression of unvented, entrapped air in
         the DEH system following maintenance which momentarily depressurized the trip header. Air
         introduced into the inter-valve cavity line between Ouadvoter &quot;A&quot; (DEH-SV-TRIP/A)
         and Ouadvoter &quot;8&quot; serial pair during the replacement was incapable of being
         vented due to system design. When Ouadvoter &quot;8&quot; was re-energized, the air was
         aligned with the trip header which resulted in backflow and momentary depressurization. The
         root cause of the event was design deficiencies in the on-line serviceable quadvoter valve
         assembly which allowed system conditions that resulted in a reactor trip following
         performance of on-line maintenance activities. Several contributing causes were identified:
         1) Lack of rigor in making risk decisions and risk being managed at inappropriate levels
         within the organization led to the DEH modification causing two inadvertent reador scrams.
         2) Less than adequate application 'of methods for the Corrective Action Program problem
         resolution process following the DEH scram on August 21, 2008, led to overlooking the
         possibility that a latent design deficiency existed. 3) Less than adequate application of
         resources, processes, and procedures for completing implementation of the DEH modification
         error-free in R-18. Further Corrective Action Ouadvoter &quot;A&quot; was replaced to
         ensure both valves In at least one DEH trip channel were new. With the reactor shutdown in
         Mode 4, the system was operated and vented until testing verified no air remained entrapped
         and no significant pressure transients resulted from solenoid valve operation. To permit
         future on-line replacement of quadvoter valve assemblies, design modifications to the DEH
         system were implemented during the R-19 outage. The modifications allow venting of the DEH
         system following maintenance, prevent depressurization of the trip header during pressure
         transients, provide quadvoter solenoids that operate within the normal temperature range of
         the DEH hydraulic fluid, and provide a pressure monitoring system for the trip header. hi
         addition, a number of corrective actions have been identified that address Senior
         Management decision I making, communication, and resource management. </eventCause>
      <safetyConsequences> Assessment of Safety Consequences For this event, High-Pressure Core
         Spray (HPCS) [8G], Reactor Core Isolation Cooling (RCIC) [8N], and both trains of emergency
         AC power [EA, E8 &amp; EK] and Residual Heat Removal (RHR) [80] systems were capable of
         performing their intended safety function. This event did not involve an event or condition
         that could have prevented the fulfillment of any safety function described in 10 CFR
         50.73(a)(2)(v). This event posed no threat to the health and safety of the public or plant
         personnel and was therefore, not safety significant.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>Similar Events Since installation of the new DEH system at Columbia in 2007,
         one similar event was reported by Energy Northwest in LER 2008-001-00. On August 21, 2008,
         during performance of post maintenance testing of the DEH system following the planned
         replacement of the Channel B DEH Solenoid Trip Valve (DEH-SV-TRIP/B), the Digital
         Electrohydraulic Control (DEH) trip header momentarily depressurized. Coincident with this
         event . was the failure of a DEH compression fitting and the subsequent loss of DEH fluid.
         The failure of the compression fitting was previously believed to be the cause of the
         event. However, the re-evaluation of the event occurring on February 8,2009 determined that
         both events were caused by the same mechanism (a design deficiency in the on-line
         serviceable Quadvoter assembly). Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) Information
         codes from IEEE Standards 805-1984 and . 803-1983: EllS information denoted as [XX] or
         [XXX] throughout the narrative.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
