<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>On August 21,2008, an automatic reactor scram occurred at 1606, while the plantwas
      operating at 65% power due to the Digital Electrohydraulic Control (DEH) trip header
      momentarily depressurizing I during post maintenance testing (PMT). All safety systems were
      available during the event and operated as designed. Plant operators effectively managed the
      transient. This event did not pose a threat to the health and safety of the public. The direct
      cause of the reactor scram was instantaneous recompression of an air bubble trapped in the
      intervalve cavity between the A and B Quadvoter valves during post-maintenance testing ,(PMT).
      This allowed backflow of DEH fluid from the emergency trip header into the intervalve cavity
      during PMT, causing a momentary depressurization of the DEH trip header that resulted in the
      reactor scram. The root cause of the scram was determined to be a design deficiency in the
      on-line serviceable Quadvoter assembly which allowed an air bubble to remain in the intervalve
      cavity following performance of on-line maintenance activities. </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>At the time of the event, the plant was operating in Mode 1 at 65% power for
         planned maintenance on Reactor Feedwater [SJ] Pump 1 B (RFW-P-1 B) coupling. Maintenance on
         RFW-P-1 B was ongoing and the pump was out of service. </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On August 21 , 2008, during performance of post maintenance testing of the DEH
         system following the planned replacement of the Channel B DEH Solenoid Trip Valve
         (DEH-SV-TRIP/B), the Digital Electrohydraulic Control (DEH) trip header momentarily
         depressurized because of the instantaneous recompression an air bubble trapped in the
         intervalve cavity between the A and B Ouadvoter valves. Coincident with this event was the
         failure of a DEH compression fitting and the subsequent loss of DEH fluid. The failure of
         the compression fitting was previously believed to be the cause of the event However, the
         evaluation of a subsequent and similar event in February 2009 (Reference Columbia· LER
         2009-001-01) determined that both events were caused by the same mechanism (a design
         deficiency in the on-line serviceable Ouadvoter assembly). Per design, the low trip header
         pressure actuated the RPS system, scramming the reactor [RCT], via the Turbine Governor
         Valve Fast Closure, Trip Oil Pressure -Low signal. A recirculation [AD] pump trip was also
         associated with the scram. The scram occurred at 1606 hours and was followed by a main
         turbine [T A] trip about 23 seconds later. The control room received a low DEH tank level
         alarm at about 1608 and dispatched an equipment operator to investigate. The equipment
         operator confirmed a DEH system leak that was not directly related to the maintenance
         previously performed on the DEH system. The control room operators secured the DEH pumps to
         limit the leak. To prevent stratification, a reactor recirculation pump was restarted at
         about 1623, and the control room staff continued to monitor stable pressure decay and
         cooldown. By 1719, the DEH tank level had stabilized at 16.25 inches. As a result of the
         event, the DEH tank level dropped about 18 inches indicating a loss of approximately 90
         gallons of Fyrquel hydraulic fluid. At 1930, the NRC Operations Center was notified in
         accordance with 10 CFR 50.72(b)(2)(iv)(B) via Event Notification #44432. </eventDesc>
      <correctiveActions> Immediate Corrective Actions The turbine building [NM] sump pumps were
         stopped, and plant staff was dispatched to isolate, monitor and clean up the spill. The
         hydraulic line was reworked by reinstalling the existing tubing with a new, properly
         assembled compression fitting. </correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>This event did not pose a threat to the health and safety of the public.
         All safety systems operated as designed and there were no conditions that prevented the
         fulfillment of any safety function described in 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). There was no
         resultant loss of mitigating equipment or I functions, nor would such a loss be anticipated
         under any credible alternate conditions. Following the scram, reactor pressure was
         controlled initially via bypass valves while DEH pressure was adequate, and subsequently
         with main steam line drains. Reactor level was controlled to within the normal band with
         the feedwater and condensate systems [SD]. By keeping reactor water level within the normal
         band, and avoiding controlling pressure through safety relief valves, the challenge to the
         reactor pressure vessel posed by the scram was reduced. The consequences of a similar event
         at full power instead of the lower power level of this event would not have been
         considerably more serious. The sequencing of the turbine trip lagging the scram by
         approximately 23 seconds did result in a water level swell that almost reached the level 8
         (L8) trip setpoint. The timing of the turbine trip relative to the scram is not assumed to
         be constant and as such, exact response is difficult to ascertain. Under certain scenarios
         the L8 trip would be reached and might result in the need to restart a feedwater pump
         during the scram recovery, presenting a potential complication to the operators. Actual
         plant response during an event causing a L8 trip would still be bounded by the Final Safety
         Analysis Report (FSAR) Chapter 15 -Feedwater Controller Failure -Maximum Demand analysiS.
         Improvements to the feedwater level control logic will be evaluated to determine if system
         design changes are necessary to further minimize the potential for a L8 trip during similar
         conditions in the future. </safetyConsequences>
      <eventCause> Cause of Event The direct cause of the reactor scram was instantaneous
         recompression of an air bubble trapped in the intervalve cavity between the A and B
         Ouadvoter valves during post-maintenance testing (PMT). This allowed backflow of DEH fluid
         from the emergency trip header into the intervalve cavity during PMT, causing a momentary
         depressurization of the DEH trip header that resulted in the reactor scram. The root cause
         of the scram was determined to be a design deficiency in the on-line serviceable Ouadvoter
         assembly which allowed an air bubble to remain in the intervalve cavity following
         performance of on-line maintenance activities. </eventCause>
      <previousEvents>There were no similar events prior to this event occurring. The Ouadvoter
         assembly was installed in 2007 (R-18) as part of the Digital Electrohydraulic Control (DEH)
         system upgrades and is part of the Main Turbine Trip subsystem. This event was related to
         the design of the new system. However, it should be noted that during the re-evaluation of
         a subsequent event occurring in February 2009 (Reference Columbia LER 2009-001-01), it was
         determined that both events were related and caused by the same design deficiency. </previousEvents>
      <correctiveActions>Corrective actions taken to address the event described in LER 2009-001-01
         also address the root cause of this event. They include: Quadvoter &quot;A&quot; was
         replaced to ensure both valves in at least one DEH trip channel were new. With the reactor
         shutdown in Mode 4, the system was operated and vented until testing verified no air
         remained entrapped and no significant pressure transients resulted from solenoid valve
         operation. To permit future on-line replacement of quadvoter valve assemblies, design
         modifications to the DEH system were implemented during the R-19 outage. The modifications
         allow venting of the DEH system following maintenance, prevent depressurization of the trip
         header during pressure transients, provide quadvoter solenoids that operate within the
         normal temperature range of the DEH hydraulic fluid, and provide a pressure monitoring
         system for the trip header. In addition, a number of corrective actions have been
         identified that address Senior Management decision making, communication, and resource
         management. Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) Information codes from IEEE
         Standards 805-1984 and 803-1983 EllS codes are represented in brackets as [XX] and [XXX]
         throughout the body of the narrative.</correctiveActions>
   </narrative>
</ler>
