<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>
         <P>On June 30, 2010, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) discovered a condition
            prohibited by Technical Specifications (TS). An Air Operated Valve (AOV) diagnostic test
            was performed on Secondary Containment Isolation Valve (SCIV) FDR-V-219, contained in
            the Floor Drain Radioactive (FDR) system. Results showed that the valve was not fully
            closing. This valve must be capable of closing and staying closed to be considered
            operable. Unknowingly, Columbia has operated with this valve inoperable since 1994, a
            condition prohibited by LCO 3.6.4.2, Conditions A and C. Upon discovery of the
            inoperable status, the TS required actions for this condition were completed.
            Subsequently, the valve stroke has been adjusted and the valve has been declared
            operable. </P>

         <P>The direct cause occurred on July 4, 1994. During the replacement of the valve actuator
            for SCIV FDR-V-219, the actuator stroke was set with the valve not fully closed and
            seated. Position limit switches were set based on the incorrect stroke length and did
            not provide any indication of the problem to the control room operators. The root cause
            of the event was inadequate work instructions that failed to verify that the valve was
            fully closed and seated prior to setting the actuator stroke. </P>

         <P>No similar events have been reported by Columbia. </P>

   </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantCond>The plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. 
         </plantCond>
      <eventDesc>On June 30, 2010, diagnostic testing of FDR-V-219 [WK] was completed
                  and a condition prohibited by LCO 3.6.4.2, Conditions A and C, was discovered.
                  Results of the testing showed that the valve close stroke was approximately 1 inch
                  from being fully closed and seated. This valve is an SCIV and must be capable of
                  closing and staying closed to be considered operable. Upon discovery of the
                  inoperable status, the TS required actions for this condition were completed by
                  closing FDR-V-220 and isolating the flow path. Subsequently, the actuator was
                  replaced, the valve stroke was adjusted, and the valve was declared operable. The
                  discrepant condition occurred on July 4, 1994 when the valve actuator was
                  replaced. The work instructions directed that the valve packing be tightened to
                  hold the valve disk in place without verifying that the valve was closed and
                  seated. The valve actuator was installed and the valve stroke was set with the
                  valve disk unseated and partially open. Subsequently, the position limit switches
                  were set based on the incorrect stroke length. This did not allow indication of
                  the problem to be observed by control room operators. Routine maintenance also
                  failed to identify this condition. The required two-year visual verification and
                  the quarterly surveillance on FDR-V-219 do not provide positive verification of
                  the valve's ability to stop flow. Immediate Corrective Actions Upon discovery, the
                  affected penetration flow path was isolated by closing FDR-V-220 (the valve in
                  series with FDR-V-219), and a once per 31 day action was established to verify
                  isolation of the affected penetration flow path. This met the TS 3.6.4.2
                  (Condition A) required actions for an inoperable SCIV. FDR-V-220 was verified
                  closed through AOV diagnostic testing. Causes The direct cause of the valve not
                  being able to fully close automatically was due to incorrectly setting the
                  actuator. The root cause of the event was inadequate work instructions to verify
                  that the valve was fully closed and seated prior to setting the actuator stroke.
                  Further Corrective Actions On July 9,2010, AOV diagnostic testing was performed
                  after the repair of FDR-V-219, to ensure that&quot;' the valve was fully closing.
                  Additional corrective actions to address contributing causes, extent of cause, and
                  recurrence prevention include: (1) improved testing using AOV diagnostics, (2)
                  procedure revisions to the post maintenance testing process, and (3) preventative
                  maintenance clarifications</eventDesc>
      <safetyConsequences>
         <P>A review was conducted of work orders concerning FDR-V-219 and FDR-V-220 during the time
            period when FDR-V-219 was discrepant. This review concluded that FDR-V-220 was either
            closed and deactivated or operable. Consequontly, the affected penetration flow path was
            either isolated or capable of being isolated. Therefore, this event did not involve an
            event or condition that alone could have prevented the fulfillment of any safety
            function described in 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). </P>
      </safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>
         <P>No similar events have been reported by Columbia Generating Station. </P>
      </previousEvents></narrative></ler>