<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler>
   <abstract>At 0750 on August 5, 2009, while Columbia was operating at 100% power, an electrical
      fault on a 6.9 kilovolt (kV) non-segregated bus resulted in a turbine trip and automatic
      reactor scram. During the scram recovery, the turbine bypass valves remained. in the full open
      position and did not automatically modulate to maintain reactor pressure as expected. The most
      probably cause of the bus failure is a relaxation of bolted connections on the center phase
      flexible link(s) caused by repeated thermal cycles over time. The root cause identified for
      this event was the nonperformance of preventive maintenance (PM) tasks for torque checks of
      the non-segregated bus links. The damaged bus has been repaired, and changes to the controls
      for PMs will be made 'to ensure proper performance to prevent this type of failure from
      recurring. The failure of the bypass valves to control pressure resulted from an error
      introduced during a design change of the Digital Electric Hydraulic (DEH) system implemented
      in 2007. As a result, the bypass valves transferred to manual pressure control mode when the
      pressure transient exceeded the main steam throttle inlet pressure input signal limit for all
      three channels. The DEH system has been modified to correct the erroneous signal limit, and to
      retain automatic control of the bypass valves during similar high throttle pressure events. No
      previous similar events have been reported by Columbia.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>The plant was in Mode 1 operating at 100% when this event occurred. Event
         Description On August 5, 2009, at approximately 0750 the plant experienced an automatic
         actuation of the Reactor Protection System [JC] due to a main turbine trip. The turbine
         trip occurred immediately following a main generator [EL] differential lockout due to an
         electrical fault in the 6.9 kV electrical distribution system [EA]. The electrical fault
         was determined to have been caused by a failure in the non-segregated electrical bus [NSBU]
         which generated enough smoke in the turbine building to require declaration of an unusual
         event at 0812 due to toxic gases in amounts that could affect the health of plant personnel
         or safe plant operation. The plant response to the disturbance in the electrical system and
         subsequent turbine trip and scram (RPS actuation) was as expected with the following
         exceptions: 1) The DEH system [JI] unexpectedly transferred to manual pressure control mode
         with the bypass valves remaining in the full open position. Consequently, reactor pressure
         dropped from a post turbine trip maximum of approximately 1081 psig to an approximate
         minimum of 396 psig in just over 3.5 minutes. Plant Operators terminated the reactor
         pressure decrease by manually closing the inboard Main Steam Isolation Valves. 2) After the
         scram, the reactor coolant temperature dropped 106 degrees over a period of approximately
         six minutes, exceeding the Technical Specification (TS) allowable cool down rate of 100
         degrees in an hour. 3) The feedwater [SJ] pumps tripped on low suction pressure within a
         few seconds of the scram. Water from the feed system was re-established when reactor
         pressure decreased to less than the shutoff head of the condensate booster pumps
         approximately two minutes after the scram. There was no inoperable equipment at the start
         of the event that contributed to the event. This LER is submitted pursuant to
         50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) as an event or condition that resulted in automatic actuation of the
         Reactor Protection System. Causes The most probable cause of the electrical bus failure was
         a loosening or relaxation of bolted connections on the center phase flexible link(s) due to
         repeated thermal cycles over time. The looseness resulted in increased heating of the
         joint, which degraded the joint. It is postulated that heating occurred in the joint to the
         point that insulation degraded, resulting in the formation of a high energy arc fault which
         shorted between phase conductors. The loose connections were not detected prior to the
         event due to a failure to perform PMs for bus torque checks as well as a lack of adequate
         temperature monitoring of the nonsegregated buses. Because the bus was destroyed, little
         forensic evidence exists to support these conclusions. Subsequently, it was discovered that
         the bus had been improperly uprated in 1994 to support a modification that added the
         adjustable speed drive (AS D) loads to the bus. The increased bus loading resulted in
         reduced margin between the bus loading and the actual bus rating, leading to increased bus
         link temperatures. In addition, it was discovered that the ASD modification resulted in the
         addition of non-linear loads to the bus. This modification was installed in 1996. The
         non-linear loads caused an increase in total harmonic distortion (THD), which also results
         in increased heating on the bus. The impact of this increase in THD was not addressed as
         part of the design change. In both instances, less than adequate engineering rigor was used
         to analyze the impact of a plant design change on the electrical bus. As such, this lack of
         engineering rigor has been identified as a contributing cause to the electrical bus
         failure. The unexpected transfer of the DEH system to manual pressure control was due to a
         design error introduced during the DEH system modification that was installed in 2007. The
         failure threshold in the DEH software code for the main steam throttle inlet pressure
         transmitters was set too low to accommodate the pressure spike that occurred when the
         turbine tripped from full power. Design changes that were made to the feedpump suction trip
         setpoints and the digital feedwater reactor level control system in R18 (2007) contributed
         to the feedpumps tripping on low suction pressure. Following the scram, the feedpump
         turbines ramped up speed to respond to the RPV low level signal, which caused an
         unanticipated drop in suction pressure below the trip limit. The change that staggered the
         feedpump suction trip setpoints did not achieve the desired result of preventing both
         feedpumps from tripping off in this event.</plantConds>
      <correctiveActions>The following actions have been taken or are planned to address the issues
         identified above, prevent recurrence, and address the extent of condition/cause: 1) The
         damage to the 6.9 kV bus has been repaired, and windows have been installed in the bus duct
         covers to allow for more direct thermography monitoring of the links. 2) An appropriate
         frequency for thermography checks will be established in conjunction with performing torque
         checks for the other non-segregated buses during the next refueling outage to prevent
         recurrence of this type of event. The content and controls for PMs will be strengthened to
         ensure proper completion of critical steps, and appropriate levels of review and approval
         are applied to any changes. 3) The DEH system software has been modified to increase the
         failure threshold setpoint for the main steam throttle inlet pressure signal and to ensure
         the system will remain in automatic pressure control upon failure high of the main steam
         throttle inlet pressure signal. 4) Because the TS allowed cool down rate of the reactor
         pressure vessel (RPV) was exceeded, a fatigue analysis was performed on the RPV and
         concluded that this event is bounded by transients evaluated in the original RPV fatigue
         analysis. 5) The other non-segregated buses were visually inspected and had insulators
         torque checked. Additional infrared thermography windows were installed in the bus housing
         covers at all flexible and rigid link locations with the exception of the two buses that
         are only normally energized during startups up to 23% power, in which only some of the
         thermography windows were installed. The remainder of the windows for the two startup buses
         are scheduled for installation during the next refueling outage in 2011. 6) The logic for
         the Digital Feedwater level control system has been modified to limit feedwater pump
         turbine speed in response to a reactor scram. A staggered time delay for feedwater pump low
         suction pressure trips has also been added to allow suction pressure to recover before a
         second pump trips. 7) The non-segregated electrical bus is being upgraded to replace the
         existing bus bar with a larger busbar with welded bus connections to increase the bus
         ampacity rating and regain margin between the bus loading and bus
         rating.</correctiveActions>

      <safetyAssessment>For this event, all Emergency Core Cooling Systems (ECCS) were available to
         perform their intended safety functions. Both off-site power circuits were available and
         all three of the emergency diesel generators [EB and EK] were operable and available. This
         event did not involve an event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of
         any safety function described in 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). Therefore, this event posed no
         threat to the health and safety of the public or plant personnel and was of low safety
         significance.</safetyAssessment>
      <previousEvents>No previous similar bus failures have been reported by Columbia. A review of
         the Corrective Action Program condition report database found one other occurrence of an
         event with similar characteristics. In May 2007 evidence of electrical connection heating
         was discovered during performance of a PM on one of the non-segregated buses (not the bus
         that failed in this event). The connection was reworked and retaped. Visual inspections
         conducted to address the extent of condition on the other non-segregated buses identified
         and repaired instances of potential overheating on one bus (not the bus that failed in this
         event) and identified no major concerns for the bus that failed in this event. Energy
         Industry Identification System (EllS) Information EllS codes are bracketed [ ] where
         applicable in the narrative. </previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
