<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-12-10" ler="3972011004">
   <abstract>On 12110/11, secondary containment was declared inoperable due to differential pressure
      exceeding technical specification allowable limits for a period of approximately two minutes.
      While technical specification limits were exceeded the resulting excursion was bounded by
      analytical results and thus there were no safety consequences for this event. The cause for
      the event was determined to be ice buildup and subsequent release on exterior air filters
      supplying the reactor building HVAC system. Corrective actions will enhance standard operating
      procedures for cold weather operations to lower the threshold at which positive steps are
      taken to mitigate potential for icing on filters.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>At the time of the event, the plant was in Mode 1 and 100 percent power.
         Therewere.no structures, systems, or components thatwere inoperable at the start of the
         event that contributed to the event. Reactor building exhaust [VL] was in a normal
         alignment with REA-FN-1A, one of two 100 percent·capacity exhaust fans [FAN], running with
         REA-FN-1 B in standby condition. Reactor building exhaust filters [FL T] had been observed
         to be icing over due to adverse environmental conditions (the area had been under a deep
         freeze since 12/8/11 and humidity was approximately 90 percent for this same time period)
         and steps had been taken to monitor the filters and advance roll filters on a more frequent
         basis.</plantConds>
      <eventDesc>The control room received a high secondary containmentdifferential pressure alarm
         on 12110/11 at 04:43. The pressure excursion resulted in a peak pressure of approximately.
         0.03 inches water gauge and an unplanned entry into LCO 3.6.4.1 A. In response to the
         alarm, Operations swapped from REA-FN-1 A and ROA-FN-1 A to REA-FN-1 Band ROA-FN-1 B.
         Reactor Exhaust Air (REA) Differential Pressure (DP) controller [VA], READPIC-1A was then
         able to maintain Reactor Building pressure below the Technical Specification (TS) limit
         of0.25 inches water gauge after two minutes, as designed. This event is reportable as an
         event that could have prevented fulfillment of a safety function needed to control the
         release of radiation and mitigate the consequences of an accident per 10 CFR
         50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) &amp; 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D). A 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(v)(C) and 10 CFR
         50.72(b)(3)(v)(D) notification was made via Event Number 47516. Note that the original
         Event Notification incorrectly listed the event time as 04:56, review of plant data after
         the fact confirmed the actual time the TS limit was exceeded was 04:43.</eventDesc>
      <correctiveActions>The shift manager authorized a verbal procedure change to
         SOP-COLDWEATHER-OPS to allow for cutting of the roll filter of Reactor Building Outside Air
         (ROA) during extreme cold conditions when it was recognized that existing guidance in the
         procedure was insufficient to counter the ongoing conditions.</correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>This event resulted in an unplanned entry into LCO 3.6.4.1 A. Containment
         pressure was above -0.25 inches water gauge for approximately two minutes. The actual
         pressure response of secondary containment [NH] during this event was bounded by existing
         drawdown and dose analyses and thus there are no actual safety consequences to this
         event.</safetyConsequences>
      <eventCause>The DP decrease was caused by buildup and subsequent release of ice on the ROA
         filter and bird screen allowing an increased amount of air to be pulled into the Reactor
         Building [NG] in a short amount of time. The resulting rapid pressure transient was on a
         time scale shorter than that which the flow controllers [TC] could respond.</eventCause>
      <previousEvents>A search of corrective action documents back to 2004 revealed only two
         instances of noted icing on outside air filters. Both events occurred in December 2008, but
         neither resulted in exceeding TS allowable differential pressure on secondary
         containment.</previousEvents>
      <correctiveActions>Additional corrective actions will formalize enhancements to
         SOP-COLDWEATHER-OPS made as immediate corrective actions as well as to include precautions
         about conditions of high humidity and low temperatures and to lower the threshold for
         advancing roll filters with observed icing.</correctiveActions>
   </narrative>
</ler>
