<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-08-27" id="3972011002">
   <abstract>At 2021 hours on August 27, 2011, a loss of shutdown cooling occurred due to a spurious
      undervoltage signal in one of two, in series, Electrical Protection Assembly (EPA) circuit
      breaker supplying the B train of the Reactor Protection System (RPS) power bus (RPS-B).
      Response to the spurious signal resulted in loss of power to RPS-B and associated actuations
      including isolation of the common shutdown cooling suction valves. The spurious signal
      originated in a logic board (GE Model 147D8652G007) associated with the EPA Breaker. Post
      event testing was unable to specifically identify the discrete component responsible for the
      failure. The root cause was that Energy Northwest was not proactive in replacing older,
      obsolete model boards (including the one that caused the event) with a new model recommended
      by the vendor. The faulty logic board and the other logic board in series for RPS-B were
      replaced with newer model boards. Further corrective actions will replace the remaining logic
      boards currently installed in the plant with the newer models. This event is being reported
      under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v) as an event that could have prevented fulfillment of a safety
      function, as well as an invalid actuation of containment isolation in multiple systems per 10
      CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv).</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>
         <P>At the time of the event, the plant was in Mode 4 and 144 days ,,into refue,ling outage
            20 (R-20). Shutdown cooling was provided by Loop B of the shutdown cooling (SDC) [BO]
            system. Reactor temperature was approximately 107 degrees Fahrenheit and RPV Level was
            in the 80 -100 inch range as indicated on shutdown range instrumentation. There was no
            equipment that was inoperable at the time of the event which contributed to the event. '
         </P>
      </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>
         <P>At 2021 hours on August 27, 2011, the Reactor Protection System (RPS) electrical power
            system bus &quot;B&quot; (RPS-B) [EC] was lost resulting in isolation of the active loop
            of shutdown cooling. Field survey, noted that both ElectricaJ Protection
            Assembly'(EPA),circui~breake~s [52] providing rlormal power supply for RPS-B were in the
            trip free position. The. upstream EPA preaker (J;l,PS-EPA&lt;3,B) had undervoltage and
            power in Hghts illuminated.' No jndicating lights were present,on,the downstream breaker
            (RPS-EPA-3D). Immediat~ly following the event, the motor generator [MG] set supplying
            RPS-8 was noted to be running at 120 V with approximately 0 amps indicated current. Loss
            of RPS-8 results in isolation of primary containment isolation valves in multiple
            systems including closing the common shutdown cooling suction line rendering both
            shutdown cooling loops inoperable. Due, to ,both shutdown cooling,Joops being
            inoperable, Technical Specification Action Statement 3.4.1 O.A was entered. </P>

         <P>All expected isolations were validated to have occurred due to the loss of RPS-8,
            including isolation of containment isolation valves in Groups 2, 4, 6, &amp; 7 including
            the residual heat removal, reactor water cleanup [CE], reactor r~circulation,[AD],
            radiological drain [WK], 'contra! rod dr!ve,-[AA] and traversing incore probe [IG]
            systems. ImrY;lediate investigations confirmed that the loss of RPS-B was not caused by
            ongoing work, or by manual action directly on the Circuit breaker. This eyent'is
            reportable as an event that could have prevented fulfillment of a safety function needed
            to remove residual heat in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8), as well as an
            invalid system actuation resulting in containment isolation in more than one system. A
            10 CFR 50:72(b)(3)(v)(8) notification was made via Event Number 47209. ' </P>
      </eventDesc>
      <correctiveActions>
         <P>RPS-8 was repowered from the alternate power supply, the valve isolations were reset per
            plant procedures, and the technical specification action statement was exited. </P>

         <P>Following the event, a faulted logic board (GE Model 147D8652G007) [EC8D] was replaced
            with a vendor recommended newer replacement model. The logic board on the other in-line
            EPA circuit breaker for RPS-8 normal power supply was also replaced with a newer model
            board. </P>
      </correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>
         <P>The total time without shutdown cooling was 34 minutes and the reactor coolant system
            (RCS) temperature rose approximately 4 ,degrees Fahrenheit. The calculatedJime to reach,
            200 degrees Fahrenheit was approximately 11 hours. An extended loss of shutdown cooling
            could have led to excessive fuel temperatures and ultimately fuel damage. However, the
            actual significance was limited due to the short duration of the SDC outage and minimal
            temperature rise with substantial margin to 200 degrees. If the event had occurred
            earlier in the refueling outage shortly after shutdown, the significance would have been
            greater since the time to 200 degrees F is much shorter and could have resulted in an
            unintended and unplanned MODE change from MODE 4 to MODE 3. ' •.1, Had the logic card
            failure occurred in Modes 1 or 2, the same isolations and actuations would occur but
            would not be expected to result in a plant trip. The resulting isolations would require
            operator intervention to mitigate, • but all response actions are covered by existing
            station procedures.</P>
      </safetyConsequences>
      <eventCause>The reason for the loss of RPS-B was due to a spu'rious unde'rvoltage trip signal
         from a logic board which is part of the EPA circuit breaker for RPS-B. The spus,ious
         yi1deivolt~g~ s,ig.nal was caused by a logic board fault&quot; which has been identified
         aEj the direct cause of the 'event. Theroat cause is that Energy Northwest was not '
         proactive in replacing older, obsolete., logic boards to new models recommended by the
         vendor. '&quot;</eventCause>
      <previousEvents>No previous occurrences involvin'g a logic b0ard failure leading to an EPA
         breaker trip have been identified at Columbia.</previousEvents>
      <correctiveActions>At the time of the event, a total of six of the GE
         Model&quot;'147D8652G007:logic boards were installed in the plant. Two were replaced as
         part of the immediate corrective actions and the remaining four will be replaced as part of
         the corrective actions to prevent recurrence. Analysis of the logic board by the vendor was
         inconclusive.</correctiveActions>
   </narrative>
</ler>
