<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2011-06-28" id="3972011001">
   <abstract>
         <P>On June 28, 2011, while the plant was in Mode 5 for refueling outage R20, Columbia
            Generating Station (Columbia) failed to enter a required Technical Specifications (TS)
            Action Statement while performing control rod exercises. During stroke time testing,
            control rod 34-47 displayed an erroneous indication. Upon initial withdrawal, the four
            rod display showed an alternating indication of &quot;XX&quot; (meaning the reed switch
            was not open during movement) and &quot;00&quot; (full in indication) requiring the
            position indication to be declared inoperable per TS 3.9.4. Control rod 34-47 was
            subsequently fully inserted and testing resumed on other rods contrary to the required
            action statement of TS 3.9.4. Upon discovery of the noncompliance, the TS required
            actions were subsequently performed and the failed reed switch replaced. The Control
            Room Supervisor and Shift Manager did not verify the required action statements
            specified in the TS and Bases as required. This was determined to be the apparent cause.
            A contributing cause included not performing all of the required steps in the procedure
            for control rod stroke time testing. Columbia has had no previous occurrences of a
            failure to enter the required action statement of TS 3.9.4. </P>
   </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>The plant was operating in Mode 5 at 0% power.</plantConds> 
         <eventDesc>On June 28, 2011, during the performance of control rod [ROD] stroke
                  time testing, control rod 34-47 was given a continuous withdrawal signal. The
                  Reactor Operator (RO) at the controls immediately noticed the four rod display
                  initially indicated blank, as expected, then began alternating displays between
                  &quot;00&quot; and &quot;XX&quot;. It was noted that the green ''full in&quot;
                  light cleared. The RO stopped the rod withdrawal and the display then indicated
                  &quot;XX&quot; with the ''full in&quot; light still extinguished. The RO
                  subsequently inserted the control rod to position &quot;00&quot; and its ''full
                  in&quot; light was re-energized. The Control Room Supervisor (CRS) consulted the
                  System Engineer and the Station Nuclear Engineer who indicated that that the
                  failure was most likely due to the &quot;00&quot; reed switch being stuck closed.
                  The crew continued with stroke timing achieving an additional full out / full in
                  cycle on the next control rod. A work request was written to replace the rod
                  position indication system (RPIS) probe containing the stuck reed switch on
                  control rod 34-47. On June 29,2011, after review of the control rod exercises
                  performed the previous day, it was determined that the ''full in&quot; position
                  indication channel for control rod 34-47 was inoperable based on not meeting the
                  requirements of TS SR 3.9.4.1. Since the control rod position indication channel
                  was not declared inoperable and the required actions were not taken before
                  movement of another rod, the station was in non-compliance with Technical
                  Specification Action Statement (TSAS) 3.9.4.A while performing the additional
                  control rod stroke timing following the initial encounter with the indication
                  problems. Immediate Corrective Actions Upon discovery of the TS violation,
                  Columbia entered TSAS 3.9.4.A for control rod 34-47 due to the erroneous
                  indication during stroke timing. Control room staff performed the required actions
                  to verify no in-vessel fuel movement, stop all control rod withdrawal and verify
                  all control rods are full in. In addition, the control rod drive (CRD) [AA] for
                  rod 34-47 was disarmed. A condition report was written documenting the failure to
                  comply with TS Limiting Condition of Operation (LCO) 3.9.4. The responsible CRS
                  and RO were removed from standing watch in the control room. Causes The CRS and SM
                  did not verify and validate the control rod position indication surveillance
                  requirements by reviewing the TS and Bases prior to proceeding with rod movement.
                  A review of the TS and Bases is required prior to authorizing surveillance
                  procedures and other maintenance and clearance order activities in accordance with
                  Operations Department instructions. Failure to meet the requirement to review the
                  TS and Bases was determined to be the apparent cause. In addition, the RO
                  performing the stroke time testing did not complete the last two steps in the
                  associated procedure for stroke time testing. This presented a missed opportunity
                  for the crew to discuss the control rod position indication and address the TS
                  requirements indicated by the uncompleted procedure steps. This was identified as
                  a contributing cause to this event.</eventDesc>
         <correctiveActions>The following corrective actions are planned
                  or have been completed: • Provided remediation training for the on-duty RO and CRS
                  to address inadequate verification of required TS. (Completed) • Developed
                  training for licensed operators concerning shutdown TS. (In Progress) • Reinforced
                  expectations for TS implementation and verification through a night order.
                  (Completed) • Replaced the control rod RPIS probe for control rod 34-47.
                  (Completed)</correctiveActions> 
                  <safetyConsequences>The full-in position indication
                  channel is required to be operable so that the refueling interlocks can ensure
                  that fuel cannot be loaded with any control rod withdrawn and that no more than
                  one control rod can be withdrawn at a time. These restrictions prevent inadvertent
                  criticality during refueling operations. At the time that the rod position
                  indication failed to meet the TS surveillance requirements, Columbia was not
                  moving fuel, only one control rod was being withdrawn, and all other control rods
                  were fully inserted. There was no potential for an inadvertent criticality. The
                  plant remained within the assumptions of the safety analysis at all times.
                  Withdrawal of control rod 34-47 was suspended and the rod was fully inserted prior
                  to movement of another rod. This event was of low safety consequence.</safetyConsequences> 
                  <previousEvents>A search of the last ten years of Columbia's condition reports and LERs
                  showed no previous occurrences of a failure to enter the required action statement
                  of TS 3.9.4. However, there have been four similar events in which other TS and
                  their bases were not verified prior to performance of an evolution that resulted
                  in a TS not being met at Columbia within the last ten years. These incidences are
                  documented in LERs 2001-001-00, 2003-004-00, and 2004-001-00. Energy Industry
                  Identification System (EllS) Information EllS codes are bracketed [ ] where
                  applicable in the narrative.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
      