<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2012-12-30" id="3972012007">
   <abstract>On December 30, 2012, Columbia was operating at 100% power with all safety systems
      operable. At 0530 PST both doors of the 471 elevation airlock entrance of the Reactor Building
      were simultaneously opened for a short period of time. This was the result of the failure of
      the interlock between the outer security door R-204, and the inner door R-205. Having a
      condition where both doors in a Reactor Building airlock were opened simultaneously while not
      undergoing a planned evolution for maintenance or surveillance testing, results in an
      unintended entry into Technical Specification (TS) 3.6.4.1 Secondary Containment due to a
      failure to satisfy Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.6.4.1.3. It was determined that this
      condition resulted in a loss of safety function (Secondary Containment) and was reported to
      the NRC (Event Notification 48639) at 1245 PST on December 30,2012.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>Columbia was operating at 100% power with all safety systems operable when this
         event occurred.</plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On December 30, 2012, at 0530 PST both doors [EllS: DR] of the 471 elevation
         airlock [EllS: AL] entrance of the Reactor Building [EllS: NG] were simultaneously opened
         for a short period of time. This was the result of the failure of the interlock [EllS:
         IMEC] between the outer security door R-204, and the inner door R-205. The interlock's
         mechanical bolt on the outer security door failed to engage allowing the outer security
         door to be opened when the inner door was already open. A security officer and an equipment
         operator were involved. They immediately realized the problem, quickly shut the doors, and
         contacted the main control room. Both doors were simultaneously open for only a few
         seconds. Having a condition where both doors in a Reactor Building airlock were opened
         simultaneously while not undergoing a planned evolution for maintenance or surveillance
         testing, results in an unintended entry into Technical Specification (TS) 3.6.4.1 Secondary
         Containment due to a failure to satisfy Surveillance Requirement SR 3.6.4.1.3. SR 3.6.4.1.3
         requires verification that each secondary containment access inner door or each secondary
         containment access outer door in each access opening is closed. It was determined that this
         condition resulted in a loss of safety function (Secondary Containment) and was reported to
         the NRC (Event Notification 48639) at 1245 PST on December 30, 2012. The reactor building
         is maintained at a negative pressure to minimize potential leakage of radioactivity to the
         environment. During normal operations, the reactor building ventilation system maintains
         this negative pressure. During a design basis accident, the Standby Gas Treatment System
         [EllS: BH] maintains this negative pressure. This brief opening of the doors had no
         measurable impact on the reactor building pressure indication.</eventDesc>
      <correctiveAction>Access through the airlock was restricted by locking the outer security door
         (R-204) until repairs could be made. The interlock mechanism was repaired the following
         day.</correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>root cause evaluation of the issue determined that there were two root causes.
         First Root Cause (RC1 ): A legacy design weakness for the Secondary Containment airlock
         door interlocks allows conditions where both the inner and outer doors can be opened at the
         same time. Second Root Cause (RC2): Implementation of TSTF-18-A, Rev 1, at Columbia
         (November 1998) changed the wording of TS SR Bases 3.6.4.1.2 and SR 3.6.4.1.3, reducing the
         clarity of the description of conditions that define Secondary Containment
         operability.</eventCause>
      <correctiveAction>1. Evaluate potential alternatives, then process and implement a design
         change which results in a more reliable door lockin device, im rove the interlock 10 ic to
         eliminate current desi n im erfections, and provide warning to personnel outside the
         airlock when the airlock is in use. 2. Revise Technical Specification bases for SR
         3.6.4.1.2 and SR 3.6.4.1.3 to ensure that the wording clearly identifies that Secondary
         Containment operability requires that one door in each airlock be closed at all times when
         Secondary Containment is required.</correctiveAction>
      <safetyConsequences>There was no equipment damage, injuries or dose exposure to station
         personnel. There was no change in plant status or operating condition and there was no
         actual risk to the public at any time. There was no impact to public health and safety as
         the Primary Containment was intact, and Secondary Containment ventilation system maintained
         the designed negative pressure inside the Reactor Building during the event. There was a
         potential significance if there had been an event where the Primary Containment was
         breached concurrent with a loss of coolant accident or a fuel handing accident such that
         radioactive materials were released to the Reactor Building. Having both Reactor Building
         airlock doors open would potentially provide a release path for radioactive materials to
         enter the external environment.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>A review of various databases at Columbia found a total of 40 similar events
         dating back to 1995. Not all of these events resulted in a loss of Secondary Containment.
         Some of these events occurred during a Mode in which Secondary Containment was not required
         to be operable. Some were an interlock failure only and both doors were not opened
         simultaneously. A review of the NRC Event Notification database found the following similar
         events: • Event Notification 45975, 6/3/10 at Monticello • Event Notification 46155, 8/5/10
         at Monticello • Event Notification 46394, 11/4/10 at Monticello • Event Notification 48282,
         9/6/12 at Quad Cities • Event Notification 48295, 9/10/12 at Cooper </previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
