<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler>
   <abstract>On February 28, 2010, following investigations of a small amount of oil found in the
      vicinity of the division 3 emergency diesel generator (OG-3) electro-hydraulic type governor
      (governor), OG-3 was being operated to validate no oil leakage from the governor. OG-3 started
      experiencing load oscillations of approximately 300 kW after 45 minutes of full load
      operation. Subsequent investigative actions revealed the load instabilities were present in
      all modes of operation (idle, rated speed, and fully loaded) which indicated a governor
      control problem. Following troubleshooting, the OG-3 governor was replaced. OG-3 testing was
      completed and was returned to service on March 4, 2010. The direct cause of the event was
      determined to be the result of foreign material left in the governor as early as 2005. The
      root cause of the event was organizational decision making did not adequately consider long
      term risks and consequences associated with operating the governor with known foreign material
      intrusion. Contributing factors included wear due to aging, flushing the governor with fuel
      oil, and overfilling the governor.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>Columbia Generating Station (CGS) was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. There
         were no structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start of this event
         and that contributed to this event.</plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On February 28,2010, following investigations of a small amount of oil found in the
         vicinity of the division 3 e~ergency diesel generator (OG-3) lOG] electro-hydraulic type
         governor (governor) [65], OG-3 was being operated to validate no oil leakage from the
         governor. ' OG-3 started experiencing load oscillations of approximately 300 kW after 45
         minutes of full load operation. Subsequent investigative actions revealed the load
         instabilities were present in all modes of operation (idle, rated speed, and fully loaded)
         which indicated a governor control problem. Following troubleshooting, the governor was
         replaced. OG-3 completed testing and was returned to service on March 4, 2010. The forensiG
         investigation of the removed governor revealed a large amount of foreign material
         throughout. Prior to disassembly, the oil was drained from the governor and evidence of oil
         product breakdown and fuel oil contamination was found. There were small pieces of terminal
         strip material (blue in color) found throughout the governor that came from a larger piece
         that fell into the governor in 2005. Although the blue material was identified as a major
         contributor to the load oscillations by the forensic investigation vendor, other factors
         such as wear from aging, flushing the governor with fuel oil, and overfilling the governor
         could also have contributed to the failure. On October 14, 2005, during the repair of a
         failed shutdown solenoid [SOL], a vendor broke a terminal strip which resulted in a broken
         piece approximately 1/8&quot; by 3/16&quot; falling into the governor. The governor was
         flushed with fuel oil in an effort to retrieve the piece of broken strip; however, the
         piece was not found nor recovered. OG-3 was returned to service on October 15, 2005
         following satisfactory completion of the monthly surveillance. The justification for
         continued operation with the foreign material assumed that the softness and the physical
         size of the material would not adversely impact the ability of the governor to maintain
         OG-3 engine speed at a specified value. In addition, the foreign material was heavier than
         the oil and was assumed to sink to the bottom of the oil reservoir. No load oscillations
         were observed in OG-3 during subsequent surveillance runs prior to the February 28, 2010
         post maintenance test event. Total run time on OG-3 from the last biennial 24 hour
         surveillance run on May 21,2008 until the load oscillation event on February 28, 2010 was
         approximately 78 hours. An evaluation was performed to assess OG-'3' operability status
         from May 21, 2008 to February 28, 2010. Based on the results of the evaluation, which
         utilized Probabilistic Risk Assessment methods, it is postulated that OG-3 would not have
         been able to fulfill its design function during a 24 hour run for portions of the timeframe
         from September 10, 2009 through February 28, 2010. As such, OG-3 would have been inoperable
         during the portions of the timeframe stated in the evaluation. Technical Specifications
         (TS) 3.8.1, Condition B requires an inoperable OG to be restored to operable status within
         14 days, otherwise Condition F requires the unit to be in Mode 3 within 12 hours and Mode 4
         within 36 hours. Consequently, the condition of CGS not in compliance with Condition F is a
         condition prohibited by TS and reportable to the NRC in accordance with 10 CFR
         50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). Immediate Corrective Actions OG-3 was declared inoperable on February
         28, 2010, the governor was replaced on March 2, 2010, surveillance testing was completed,
         and OG-3 was declared operable on March 4, 2010.</eventDesc>
      <eventCause> Causes The direct cause of the event was due to foreign material left in the
         governor as early as 2005. The root cause of the event was organizational decision making
         did not adequately consider long term risks and consequences associated with operating the
         governor with known foreign material intrusion. Contributing causes included wear due to
         aging, flushing the governor with fuel oil, and overfilling the governor.</eventCause>
      <correctiveActions>Further corrective actions included strengthening foreign material
         intrusion actions in operability determinations and maintenance procedures and providing
         training on lessons learned to the management committee responsible for station health
         issues.</correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>There were no actual safety consequences as a result of this condition.
         Critical electrical bus SM-4 [BU] is normally energized from Normal Auxiliary transformer
         TR-N1 [XFMR] thru non-critical bus SM-2 when the main generator [GEN] is operating and from
         Startup Auxiliary transformer TR-S thru SM-2 when the main generator is not operating. OG-3
         provides emergency power to SM-4. SM-4 was available and powered by either TR-N1 or TR-S
         throughout the time frame OG-3 was postulated to be inoperable.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>A search of CGS Licensee Event Reports and the Corrective Action Program for
         the last 10 years found no other instances where load oscillations were observed on an
         emergency diesel generator due to a failed governor. </previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
