<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler when="2012-10-03" id="3972012005">
   <abstract>In July 2012, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) questioned Columbia Generating
      Station's (Columbia) practice of applying the Service Water (SW) Technical Specification (TS)
      3.7.1, as called out in procedures and work instructions, when taking safety related room
      coolers or fans out of service. This question was entered into Columbia's corrective action
      process and on October 3, 2012, it was determined that this practice had resulted in instances
      in which Columbia had been in a condition prohibited by TS. Specifically, Columbia did not
      enter the appropriate TS for an inoperable system, subsystem, train or component when the
      necessary attendant non-technical specification support equipment was not capable of
      performing its support function. Columbia entered the TS Limiting Condition for Operation
      (LCO) Action for one SW subsystem inoperable rather than entering the appropriate TS Action
      for the equipment supported by the room coolers. Columbia's procedures and work instructions
      were based on an inappropriate example provided in TS Bases 3.7.1. This information was added
      to the TS Bases in 1999. A review identified multiple occurrences over the past three years in
      which Columbia had not entered the appropriate TS, and on five occurrences, Columbia was in a
      condition prohibited by TS. The cause is due to human error in failing to recognize that the
      change to the TS Bases in 1999 required NRC review and approval. Corrective actions consist of
      revising the affected procedures and work instructions and correcting the TS Bases language.
      There were no actual safety consequences associated with this event.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <eventDesc>In July 2012, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) questioned Columbia
         Generating Station's (Columbia) practice of applying the Service Water (SW) [EllS: BI]
         Technical Specification (TS) 3.7.1, as called out in procedures and work instructions, when
         taking safety related room coolers [EllS: CLR] or fans out of service. This question was
         entered into Columbia's corrective action process and on October 3,2012, it was determined
         that this practice was inappropriate. Specifically, Columbia did not enter the appropriate
         TS for an inoperable system, subsystem, train or component when the necessary attendant
         non-technical specification support equipment was not capable of performing its support
         function. Columbia entered the TS Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) Action for one SW
         subsystem inoperable rather than entering the appropriate TS Action for the equipment
         supported by the room coolers. Columbia's procedures and work instructions directed entry
         into TS 3.7.1 Actions when either room coolers or main control room envelope fans [EllS:
         FAN] were inoperable. The room coolers contain cooling coils cooled by SW. The procedures
         and work instructions were based on an example provided in TS Bases 3.7.1 which stated that
         &quot;if DC Sources -Operating (LCO 3.8.4) is not met solely due to room cooler degradation
         and entry into LCO 3.7.1 Conditions and Required Actions is made, the electrical equipment
         in the affected equipment room(s) are required to be declared inoperable, however, the
         Conditions and Required Actions associated with this supported system (LCO 3.8.4) are not
         required to be entered.&quot; Due to the application of this provision in the TS Bases,
         Columbia failed to enter the appropriate TS Condition and, in some cases, failed to
         complete the Required Actions within the associated Completion Times upon removal of a
         safety related room cooler from service. This resulted in several occurrences in which
         Columbia was in a condition prohibited by TS and reportable under 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </eventDesc>
      <extentConds>An extent of condition review was performed to determine when, in the past three
         years, this provision has been used when room coolers were removed from service. Thirty
         instances were found. Of these, five instances were found when the total out of service
         time exceeded the TS allowed outage time as follows: • On 11/24/09, RRA-FN-11 (room cooling
         for Division 1 125 V AC power distribution system [EllS: ED]), was inoperable 32.7 hours.
         TS 3.7.1.B &quot;One SW subsystem inoperable&quot; and TS 3.8.1.B &quot;One required DG
         inoperable&quot; were entered instead of TS 3.8.7.A &quot;Division 1 or 2 AC electrical
         power distribution subsystem inoperable.&quot; TS 3.8.7.A requires restoration of Division
         1 AC electrical power distribution subsystem within 8 hours or else be in Mode 3 in the
         following 12 hours. Contrary to this Columbia remained in Mode 1. • On 4/26/10, RRA-FN-10
         (room cooling for Division 2 125 V AC power distribution system [EllS: ED]) was inoperable
         20.0 hours. TS 3.7.1.B &quot;One SW subsystem inoperable&quot; and TS 3.8.1.B &quot;One
         required DG inoperable&quot; were entered instead of TS 3.8.7.A &quot;Division 1 or 2 AC
         electrical power distribution subsystem inoperable.&quot; TS 3.8.7.A requires restoration
         of Division 2 AC electrical power distribution subsystem within 8 hours or else be in Mode
         3 in the following 12 hours. Contrary to this Columbia remained in Mode 1. • On 8/4/10,
         RRA-FN-11 was inoperable 25.7 hours. TS 3.7.1.8 &quot;One SW subsystem inoperable&quot; and
         TS 3.8.1.8 &quot;One required DG inoperable&quot; were entered instead of TS 3.8.7.A
         &quot;Division 1 or 2 AC electrical power distribution subsystem inoperable.&quot; TS
         3.8.7.A requires restoration of Division 1 AC electrical power distribution subsystem
         within 8 hours or else be in Mode 3 in the following 12 hours. Contrary to this Columbia
         remained in Mode 1. • On 9/1/10, RRA-FN-12 (room cooling for Division 1 250 V DC power
         distribution system [EllS: EJ]) was inoperable for 18.2 hours. TS 3.7.1.8 &quot;One SW
         subsystem inoperable&quot; and TS 3.8.1.8 &quot;One required DG inoperable&quot; were
         entered instead of TS 3.8.7.0 &quot;Division 1 250 V AC electrical power distribution
         subsystem inoperable.&quot; TS 3.8.7.0 requires declaring supported features inoperable
         immediately. A supported feature, RWCU-V-4 (a primary containment isolation valve [EElS:
         ISV]) should have been declared inoperable and in accordance with TS 3.6.1.3.A be isolated
         within 4 hours or be in Mode 3 within 12 hours. Contrary to this Columbia remained in Mode
         1. • On 9/1/10, RRA-FN-11 was inoperable 21.3 hours. TS 3.7.1.8 &quot;One SW subsystem
         inoperable&quot; and TS 3.8.1.B &quot;One required DG inoperable&quot; were entered instead
         of TS 3.8.7.A &quot;Division 1 or 2 AC electrical power distribution subsystem
         inoperable.&quot; TS 3.8.7.A requires restoration of Division 1 AC electrical power
         distribution subsystem within 8 hours or else be in Mode 3 in the following 12 hours.
         Contrary to this Columbia remained in Mode 1.</extentConds>
      <correctiveAction>Plant procedures and work order instructions were revised to direct entry
         into the correct TS Action.</correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>LCO 3.0.6 provides guidance regarding the appropriate actions to be taken when a
         single inoperability of a support system also results in the inoperability of one or more
         supported systems. However, for LCO 3.0.6 to be applied, there must be a specific LCD
         covering the supported system. For instance, SW is a support system for ECCS. If SW is
         inoperable, LCO 3.0.6 allows you to just enter the Actions for SW and not enter the Actions
         for ECCS. For cases where there is no specific LCO for the support equipment, the supported
         system Actions must be entered. LCO 3.0.6 was added to the TS during the conversion to
         Improved TS (ITS) in 1997. The ITS conversion was based on NUREG-1434 Rev. 1 for BWRl6
         plants. SW is the ultimate cooling water for all of the safety related room coolers. If an
         entire subsystem of SW is inoperable, LCO 3.0.6 requires that TS 3.7.1 be entered. The
         individual safety related room coolers were not covered by their own TS LCD. In 1999, plant
         staff concluded that it was not logical to have to enter a more restrictive TS for having
         one room cooler inoperable, versus an entire subsystem of SW. Consequently, the TS Bases
         were modified to provide an example of entry into TS 3.7.1 Actions for inoperable room
         coolers. This change was done under 10 CFR 50.59 and did not receive NRC approval. This
         change was not consistent with TS rules of usage and did not comply with TS language. The
         change incorrectly identified the room coolers as supporting the function of SW so that an
         inoperability of the room cooler would only require entry into the associated actions for
         the SW system. This then incorrectly allowed the provisions of LCD 3.0.6 to be used to
         avoid entering the Conditions and Required Actions of the supported system(s). This change
         to the TS Bases was made to address a lack of specificity in the TS concerning safety
         related room coolers. However, the correct change mechanism was not utilized. The plant
         staff used the 10 CFR 50.59 process rather than obtaining a License Amendment under 10 CFR
         50.90. Plant staff did not recognize the change as being a change to the TS. Since the
         change was made over a decade ago, the causes of the human error cannot be determined with
         any certainty. However, it is believed that the staff may have made a technical argument
         for the acceptability of the change without recognizing that they were not in compliance
         with the rules for making changes.</eventCause>
      <previousEvents>On February 14, 2012, Arkansas Nuclear Unit-1 received a similar NCV for
         improperly entering TS 3.7.1 instead of TS 3.8.4.</previousEvents>
      <correctiveActions>The language in the TS Bases will be revised as
         appropriate.</correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>CGS is analyzed and evaluated for a loss of one subsystem of service water
         for 72 hours (TS 3.7.1). Service water is the ultimate cooling source for all of the safety
         related room coolers. Having an individual room cooler out of service for up to 72 hours is
         bounded by the loss of one subsystem of service water.</safetyConsequences>
   </narrative>
</ler>
