<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-03-28T07:55:49-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-03-28T07:55:49-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-03-28T07:55:49-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:7b8c7fc5-7c8d-4300-8d51-7b6a820efb7e</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:6d4d4ac0-2c8f-9044-9ca0-2e2bd31b8684</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>Bradley J. Sawatzke Columbia Generating Station </P><Part><H1>ENERGY </H1><P>P.O. Box 968, PE08 Richland, WA 99352-0968</P></Part><Part><H1>NORTHWEST </H1><P>Ph. 509.377.4300 IF. 509.377.4150 bjsawatzke@energy-northwest.com </P><P>March 15, 2012 G02-12-039 </P><P>10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397 LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2012-002-00 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2012-002-00 for Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </P><P>There are no commitments being made to the NRC herein. If you have any questions or require additional information, please contact Mr. ZK Dunham at (509) 377-4735. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><P>BJ awatzke Vice President, Nuclear Generation &amp; Chief Nuclear Officer </P><P>Enclosure: Licensee Event Report 2012-002-00 </P><P>cc: NRC Region IV Administrator NRC NRR Project Manager NRC Senior Resident Inspector/988C RN Sherman -BPAl1399 WA Horin -Winston &amp;Strawn </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2012_03_15_ML12088A035_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 10/3112013 (10-2010) Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: ·so hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAlPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) 0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of (See reverse for required number of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an digits/characters for each block) information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE Columbia Generating Station 05000397 10F3 4. TITLE Technical Specification Non-Compliance Due to Inadequate Procedure Guidance 5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NIIMR~R 7. ncr-un . DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED MONTH DAY YEAR YEAR JSEQUENTIALj REV NUMBER NO. MONTH FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER DAY YEAR 05000 01 17 2012 2012 -002 -00 03 15 2012 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 05000 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check al/ that apply) 1 0 20.2201 (b) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 0 20.2201 (d) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) 0 20.2203 (a)(1) 0 20.2203(a)(4) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(i) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 10. r-uvvcn LEVEL 0 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) 100 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.36(c)(2) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71 (a)(4) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 0 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71 (a)(5) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER 0 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A 12. \,UI'I I H... FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME TFI .~ ._ NUMBER (Include Area Code) Lisa L. Williams -Principal Licensing [i I~III&quot;''''' (509)377-8148 13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT :411 IIR~ DESCRIBI:D IN THIS HCt'UHI CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT FA~~~~ER Rt:;~~~~:LE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT FA~~~~ER M&lt;:;~~~~:LE 14. SUPPLEMENTAL ncr-un I cAr-c.... fED 15.I:.At'I:.\;II:.U I MONTH I DAY YEAR o YES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 181 NO SUBMISSION I IDATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On January 16, 2012, at 0505 hours, the Division 1 Control Room Emergency Filtration filter unit was declared inoperable in preparation for performing a number of maintenance activities. Technical Specification (TS) Action Statement 3.7.3.B was entered for one or more subsystems inoperable due to an inoperable control room envelope (CRE). TS 3.7.3.B.2 requires an evaluation be performed within 24 hours to verify that the mitigating actions ensure CRE occupant exposures to radiological hazards will not exceed limits. The plant procedure for control of breaches to the CRE specified the required mitigating actions. It was subsequently determined that the mitigating actions specified by the procedure were not adequate to ensure the dose to control room occupants would remain below design basis accident consequences. Thus, TS 3.7.3.C should have been entered on January 17, 2012, for the Required Action and Associated Completion Time of Condition B not met. This TS Action Statement was not entered and the Required Action was not completed. The cause of the event was determined to be inadequate procedure guidance for implementing the revised TS Bases requirements. A stop work order was issued on all planned CRE breaches until planned corrective actions are completed. Planned corrective actions will revise guidance for performing maintenance on the CRE. </Figure><P>( </P><P>26158 R5 </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL 1 NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>20F3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -002 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE Plant Conditions The plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. There were no structures, systems or components that were inoperable at the start of the event and contributed to the event. Event Description On January 16, 2012, at 0505 hours PST, the Division 1 Control Room Emergency Filtration (CREF) [VI] air handling unit [AHU], which includes filters [FLT] and a fan [FAN], was declared inoperable in preparation for performing a number of maintenance activities on the filter unit. The maintenance activities involved opening an access panel on the filter unit thereby breaching the control room envelope (CRE). Technical Specification Action Statement (TSAS) 3.7.3.B was entered for one or more CREF subsystems inoperable due to inoperable CRE boundary in Mode 1,2, or 3. TSAS 3.7.3.B.1 requires actions be taken to implement mitigating actions immediately. The plant procedure for control of breaches to the CRE, PPM 1.3.57 &quot;Barrier Impairment&quot; was used to identify the mitigating actions. The specific barrier impairment permits for the work activities specified the required mitigating actions tobe a dedicated individual stationed at the access panel in constant communication with the Control Room with the supplies necessary to close up the panel if boundary integrity is required. TSAS 3.7.3.B.2 requires an evaluation be performed within 24 hours to verify that the mitigating actions ensure CRE occupant exposures to radiological, chemical, and smoke hazards will not exceed limits. Since the procedure specified the mitigating actions, plant personnel assumed that the requirements of TSAS 3.7.3.B.2 had been met. On January 22,2012, at 0202 hours PST, the Division 1 CREF air handling unit was declared operable and the associated TSAS were exited. On January 31, 2012, Quality Assurance personnel discovered that, for a period of approximately 10 minutes on January 18, 2012, the duties of the dedicated individual had been delegated to an individual unfamiliar with the job requirements. As part of the investigation into this issue, it was subsequently determined that the mitigating actions specified by PPM 1.3.57 were not adequate to ensure the dose to control room occupants would remain below design basis accident (DBA) consequences documented in the Final Safety Analysis Report (FSAR). Thus, even if the dedicated individual position had been properly staffed throughout the maintenance activities, the mitigating measures still would have been inadequate to meet the requirements of TSAS 3.7.3.B.2. In this case, TSAS 3.7.3.C should have been entered no later than January 17, 2012, at 0505 hours PST, for the Required Action and Associated Completion Time of Condition B not met in Mode 1,2 or 3. This TSAS was not entered and the Required Actions were not completed as required. Immediate Corrective Action A stop work order was issued on February 10, 2012, on all planned CRE breaches until planned corrective actions are completed. Cause The root cause of the event was determined to be that PPM 1.3.57 did not adequately implement the TS Bases requirements. A contributing cause was identified to be that Revision 23 of PPM 1.3.57 in November 2008 failed to implement the TS requirements due to miSinterpretation of the TS Bases requirements. On June 30, 2008, the NRC approved adoption of TS Task Force (TSTF) traveler TSTF-448, &quot;Control Room Habitability,&quot; Revision 3 at Columbia. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158 R5 26158 R5 </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1 0-20i 0) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>30F3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -002 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE Further Corrective Actions Planned corrective actions include clarifying the requirements for continuous communication and the duties of the dedicated individual and specifying a maximum timeframe for restoring the CRE boundary as supported by the existing DBA calculations. Those work activities that may not be able to meet the restoration time requirements will be evaluated to determine the required actions prior to being worked. Other planned corrective actions include revising PPM 1.3.57 and providing training to affected personnel. A review was performed on other barrier impairments which were opened since TSTF-448 was implemented at Columbia and which affected the control room ventilation boundary. No other cases were found in which the Required Actions and Completion Times of TSAS 3.7.3.B were not met. Assessment of Safety Consequences There were no actual safety consequences associated with this event since no events involving radiological hazards were experienced during the work activities. If a radiological event had occurred during the maintenance activities, the Division 2 CREF system would have started as required. Since there was communication between the two divisions of CREF on the outlet side during the maintenance, there would be a delay in pressurizing the control room due to air flow out the breach. However, there would not be an increase in unfiltered in-leakage. Engineering calculations establish that adequate time was available to close the access panel prior to control room occupant exposures reaching the 10 CFR 50.67 limit of 5 rem TEDE. In addition, engineering analysis indicates that the access panel could be installed with a minimum of four bolts to restore the CRE boundary. Similar Events LER 2004-001-00 reported the unanticipated inoperability of both CREF subsystems when common ducts for both CREF subsystems were breached multiple times by removing duct access panels to install and remove test equipment. The cause is attributed to inadequate guidance in the Columbia Generating Station barrier impairment procedure. The cause of the inadequate guidance in the procedure was a lack of understanding of regulatory guidance associated with barrier impairments. LER 2003-012-00 reported unanticipated inoperability of both CREF subsystems when the normal and both remote outside air intakes for the CREF system were manually isolated for a period of approximately 4 hours during testing to measure control room in-leakage. The cause of this event is attributed to inadequate preparation and review of the test procedure used to measure control room in-leakage. Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) Information EllS codes are bracketed [ ] where applicable in the narrative. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>