<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>On January 16, 2012, at 0505 hours, the Division 1 Control Room Emergency Filtration
      filter unit was declared inoperable in preparation for performing a number of maintenance
      activities. Technical Specification (TS) Action Statement 3.7.3.B was entered for one or more
      subsystems inoperable due to an inoperable control room envelope (CRE). TS 3.7.3.B.2 requires
      an evaluation be performed within 24 hours to verify that the mitigating actions ensure CRE
      occupant exposures to radiological hazards will not exceed limits. The plant procedure for
      control of breaches to the CRE specified the required mitigating actions. It was subsequently
      determined that the mitigating actions specified by the procedure were not adequate to ensure
      the dose to control room occupants would remain below design basis accident consequences.
      Thus, TS 3.7.3.C should have been entered on January 17, 2012, for the Required Action and
      Associated Completion Time of Condition B not met. This TS Action Statement was not entered
      and the Required Action was not completed. The cause of the event was determined to be
      inadequate procedure guidance for implementing the revised TS Bases requirements. A stop work
      order was issued on all planned CRE breaches until planned corrective actions are completed.
      Planned corrective actions will revise guidance for performing maintenance on the
      CRE.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>The plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. There were no structures, systems
         or components that were inoperable at the start of the event and contributed to the
         event.</plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On January 16, 2012, at 0505 hours PST, the Division 1 Control Room Emergency
         Filtration (CREF) [VI] air handling unit [AHU], which includes filters [FLT] and a fan
         [FAN], was declared inoperable in preparation for performing a number of maintenance
         activities on the filter unit. The maintenance activities involved opening an access panel
         on the filter unit thereby breaching the control room envelope (CRE). Technical
         Specification Action Statement (TSAS) 3.7.3.B was entered for one or more CREF subsystems
         inoperable due to inoperable CRE boundary in Mode 1,2, or 3. TSAS 3.7.3.B.1 requires
         actions be taken to implement mitigating actions immediately. The plant procedure for
         control of breaches to the CRE, PPM 1.3.57 &quot;Barrier Impairment&quot; was used to
         identify the mitigating actions. The specific barrier impairment permits for the work
         activities specified the required mitigating actions tobe a dedicated individual stationed
         at the access panel in constant communication with the Control Room with the supplies
         necessary to close up the panel if boundary integrity is required. TSAS 3.7.3.B.2 requires
         an evaluation be performed within 24 hours to verify that the mitigating actions ensure CRE
         occupant exposures to radiological, chemical, and smoke hazards will not exceed limits.
         Since the procedure specified the mitigating actions, plant personnel assumed that the
         requirements of TSAS 3.7.3.B.2 had been met. On January 22,2012, at 0202 hours PST, the
         Division 1 CREF air handling unit was declared operable and the associated TSAS were
         exited. On January 31, 2012, Quality Assurance personnel discovered that, for a period of
         approximately 10 minutes on January 18, 2012, the duties of the dedicated individual had
         been delegated to an individual unfamiliar with the job requirements. As part of the
         investigation into this issue, it was subsequently determined that the mitigating actions
         specified by PPM 1.3.57 were not adequate to ensure the dose to control room occupants
         would remain below design basis accident (DBA) consequences documented in the Final Safety
         Analysis Report (FSAR). Thus, even if the dedicated individual position had been properly
         staffed throughout the maintenance activities, the mitigating measures still would have
         been inadequate to meet the requirements of TSAS 3.7.3.B.2. In this case, TSAS 3.7.3.C
         should have been entered no later than January 17, 2012, at 0505 hours PST, for the
         Required Action and Associated Completion Time of Condition B not met in Mode 1,2 or 3.
         This TSAS was not entered and the Required Actions were not completed as required.
         Immediate Corrective Action A stop work order was issued on February 10, 2012, on all
         planned CRE breaches until planned corrective actions are completed. </eventDesc>
      <eventCause>The root cause of the event was determined to be that PPM 1.3.57 did not
         adequately implement the TS Bases requirements. A contributing cause was identified to be
         that Revision 23 of PPM 1.3.57 in November 2008 failed to implement the TS requirements due
         to miSinterpretation of the TS Bases requirements. On June 30, 2008, the NRC approved
         adoption of TS Task Force (TSTF) traveler TSTF-448, &quot;Control Room Habitability,&quot;
         Revision 3 at Columbia.</eventCause>
      <correctiveActions>Planned corrective actions include clarifying the requirements for
         continuous communication and the duties of the dedicated individual and specifying a
         maximum timeframe for restoring the CRE boundary as supported by the existing DBA
         calculations. Those work activities that may not be able to meet the restoration time
         requirements will be evaluated to determine the required actions prior to being worked.
         Other planned corrective actions include revising PPM 1.3.57 and providing training to
         affected personnel. A review was performed on other barrier impairments which were opened
         since TSTF-448 was implemented at Columbia and which affected the control room ventilation
         boundary. No other cases were found in which the Required Actions and Completion Times of
         TSAS 3.7.3.B were not met.</correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>There were no actual safety consequences associated with this event since
         no events involving radiological hazards were experienced during the work activities. If a
         radiological event had occurred during the maintenance activities, the Division 2 CREF
         system would have started as required. Since there was communication between the two
         divisions of CREF on the outlet side during the maintenance, there would be a delay in
         pressurizing the control room due to air flow out the breach. However, there would not be
         an increase in unfiltered in-leakage. Engineering calculations establish that adequate time
         was available to close the access panel prior to control room occupant exposures reaching
         the 10 CFR 50.67 limit of 5 rem TEDE. In addition, engineering analysis indicates that the
         access panel could be installed with a minimum of four bolts to restore the CRE
         boundary.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>LER 2004-001-00 reported the unanticipated inoperability of both CREF
         subsystems when common ducts for both CREF subsystems were breached multiple times by
         removing duct access panels to install and remove test equipment. The cause is attributed
         to inadequate guidance in the Columbia Generating Station barrier impairment procedure. The
         cause of the inadequate guidance in the procedure was a lack of understanding of regulatory
         guidance associated with barrier impairments. LER 2003-012-00 reported unanticipated
         inoperability of both CREF subsystems when the normal and both remote outside air intakes
         for the CREF system were manually isolated for a period of approximately 4 hours during
         testing to measure control room in-leakage. The cause of this event is attributed to
         inadequate preparation and review of the test procedure used to measure control room
         in-leakage.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
