<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler>
   <abstract>On August 22, 2012, it was discovered that during maintenance on breaker E-CB-S/1,
      required Technical Specification (TS) 3.8.1 Condition A was not entered. The breaker provides
      power to an essential bus from one of the credited offsite power sources. While E-CB-S/1 was
      out of service, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) would not have been able to meet
      acceptance criteria in a surveillance procedure used to satisfy Surveillance Requirement (SR)
      3.8.1.1. Therefore, per SR 3.0.1, failure to meet the surveillance requirement indicates that
      Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.8.1 was not met. The breaker was inoperable for
      approximately 30 hours, resulting in the failure to meet the Required Actions described in
      Condition A and F within the specified Completion Times. The apparent cause was determined to
      be a failure to follow station processes and procedures for determining operability.
      Contributing causes included conflicting information between the associated TS Bases and
      operations procedures that fulfill the requirements of TS SR 3.8.1.1</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power.
         There were no structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start of this
         event and that contributed to this event.</plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On August 22, 2012, it was discovered that during maintenance on breaker E-CB-S/1
         [BKR], required Technical Specification (TS) Action Statement (TSAS) 3.8.1 Condition A was
         not entered. The breaker provides power to the Division 1 critical electrical bus E-SM-7
         [BU] from the credited offsite source, E-TR-S [XFMR]. It was discovered that while E-CB-S/1
         was out of service, Columbia would not have been able to satisfy acceptance criteria in the
         associated surveillance procedure used to satisfy Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.8.1.1.
         Therefore, per SR 3.0.1, failure to meet the surveillance requirement indicates that
         Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.8.1 was not met. The breaker was inoperable for
         approximately 30 hours, resulting in the failure to meet the Required Actions described in
         TS 3.8.1 Condition A and F, within the specified Completion Times.</eventDesc>
      <correctiveActions>Night orders were initiated notifying operations personnel of the issue and
         the appropriate measures to take going forward when planning work with the associated
         breakers. Specifically, any work which impacts the ability of E-TR-S to supply power to the
         critical electrical bus for Division 1 or Division 2 will require entry into TS 3.8.1
         Condition A. Causes The apparent cause was determined to be a failure to follow the process
         for operability determination as stated in plant procedures, which require ensuring
         equipment can meet its SA. Contributing causes included conflicting information between the
         associated TS Bases and procedure that fulfills the requirements of TS SR 3.8.1.1 Further
         Corrective Actions The following corrective actions are planned or have been completed: •
         Develop methodology to be used by operations when making operability determinations for
         equipment removed from service. • Enhance procedures concerning operability determinations
         for equipment removed from service. • Initiate training requests to train operators on
         methodology to be used when making operability determinations for equipment removed from
         service. • Revise associated operations procedures based on TS Bases requirements. •
         Develop a formal position for offsite power requirements. • Conduct a focused
         self-assessment to ensure the adequacy of TS Bases and implementation of TS SRs. </correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>There were no actual safety consequences as a result of this condition.
         Critical electrical buses E-SM-7 and E-SM-8 [BU] are normally energized from Normal
         Auxiliary transformer, E-TR-N1 [XFMR], when the main generator [GEN] is
         operating.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>A search was performed for each time E-CB-S/1 was taken out of service in the
         past three years. The associated work orders (WO) and control room logs were reviewed to
         determine whether the duration the breaker was out of service exceeded the Completion Times
         of TS 3.8.1 Conditions A and F. On two occasions separate from the event being reported in
         this LER, E-CB-S/1 was taken out of service and the TS allowed outage time was exceeded.
         These two other events occurred on 11/22/2010 and 8/31/2011. A similar search was performed
         on E-CB-S/3 as it performs the same function as E-CB-S/1 , but on Division 2. On 3/28/2011
         ECB-S/3 was taken out of service and the TS allowed outage time was exceeded. Enerqy
         Industry Identification System (EllS) Information EllS information is denoted as [XX],
         [XXX), or [XXX X] throughout the narrative.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
