<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2010-12-20" id="3972010002">
   <abstract>On December 20, 2010, the low pressure core spray pump was started and the minimum flow
      valve lost indication. An annunciator was received indicating that the valve had lost power.
      The three line power fuses for the starter for the motor operator were found to be cleared.
      The cleared fuses were Cooper/Bussman Fusetron dual-element, time-delay, current-limiting, 600
      Volt, 1.25 Amp fuses (model FRS-R-I-1I4). The overload element in each fuse was failed
      (triggered). Troubleshooting did not reveal any binding within the valve, binding within the
      motor operator, or sticking or dirty contacts within the starter. An examination ofthe cleared
      fuses revealed a poor solder joint in the trigger assembly in one fuse. The cause of this
      event is premature failure of one of the three fuses from momentary inrush current at a
      current value under the fuse curve which led to overload and failure of the remaining two
      fuses. Corrective actions consisted of quarantine of fuses from the same lot as that of the
      cleared fuses and inspection of fuses in all safety-related motor operated valves in support
      of ECCS to ensure they were not the same brand fuse of the same 1.25 Amp size from the same
      lot.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>The plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. All trains ofthe low pressure
         coolant injection (LPCI) system (BO), high pressure core spray (HPCS) system (BG), and
         standby service water (SSW) system (KE) were operable at the time of the event. Maintenance
         on the low pressure core spray (LPCS) (BM) water leg pump (LPCS-P-2) (P) was scheduled for
         December 20, 2010. In preparation for the water leg pump being out of service, the LPCS
         system was planned to be aligned to the suppression pool with the LPCS pump (LPCS-P-l) in
         operation to maintain pump discharge pressure. The procedure for aligning the LPCS system
         to the suppression pool requires declaring LPCS inoperable. LPCS was declared inoperable on
         December 20,2010 at 0435 hours. There were no structures, systems, or components that were
         both a) inoperable at the time of the event and b) contributed to the event. Event
         Description Subsequent to declaring LPCS inoperable in preparation for alignment to the
         suppression pool, LPCS-P-l was started at 0437 hours. The minimum flow valve (LPCS-FCV-ll)
         (FCV) for LPCS-P-llost indication when the valve was expected to open. In addition,
         annunciation for &quot;LPCS OUT OF SERVICE&quot; and &quot;MOV NETWORK PWR LOSS/OL&quot;
         was received indicating that LPCS-FCV-ll had lost power. LPCS-P-l was secured at 0438 hours
         and LPCS-FCV-ll was declared inoperable. LPCS-FCV-ll functions as a primary containment
         isolation valve (PCIV) and the Technical Specification (TS) Required Action for Limiting
         Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.6.1.3 Condition C, one or more penetration flow paths with
         one PCIV inoperable, was complied with by isolating the affected penetration flow path by
         closing the LPCS minimum flow isolation valve (LPCS-V-52). In addition, PCIVs are required
         to have operable position indication in accordance with TS Table 3.3.3.1-1 Function 7. The
         TS Required Action for LCO 3.3.3.1 Condition A, one or more functions with one required
         channel inoperable, was complied with by closing LPCS-V-52 within the required completion
         time. An investigation was initiated to determine the cause of the loss of power to the
         valve. The three line power fuses (FU) for the reversing starter (MSTR) for the minimum
         flow valve motor operator were found to be cleared. The circuit was meggered satisfactorily
         indicating that a short-circuit condition did not exist. The valve was manually unseated to
         allow it to be stroked for measurements of starting and running motor current amps. The
         fuses were replaced and the valve stroked open and closed normally; the fuses did not
         clear. At the conclusion of the troubleshooting activities, the valve stroke time
         surveillance was completed satisfactory at 2300 hours and the valve was declared operable.
         The surveillance establishing LPCS operability was completed on December 21, 2010 at 0024
         hours and LCPS was declared operable. The elapsed time from the occurrence of the event
         until LPCS was returned to service was 19 hours 49 minutes.</plantConds>

      <correctiveActions>Immediate corrective actions consisted of protecting the alternate sources
         of emergency core cooling system (ECCS) injection/spray including residual heat removal
         (RHR), which performs the LPCI function, and HPCS. The supporting systems of SSW and the
         diesel generators [EK] were also protected.</correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>The safety functions for LPCS are to provide inventory makeup and spray
         cooling during large breaks in the reactor coolant system that uncover the core. All
         remaining ECCS subsystems were operable and at no time did this event result in the loss of
         a safety function. The low pressure injection function was not challenged due to all three
         loops of RHR system LPCI mode being operable while the core spray function was satisfied by
         the operable HPCS system. This event did not pose a threat to the health and safety of the
         public. The TS Required Action for LCO 3.5.1 Condition A, one low pressure ECCS
         injection/spray subsystem inoperable, was complied with by restoring the LPCS system to
         operable within the allowed completion time. In addition, the TS Required Actions for LCO
         3.6.1.3 Condition C and LCO 3.3.3.1 Condition A were completed within the required
         completion time. Thus, Columbia Generating Station was never in a condition prohibited by
         TS. This event is being reported under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) as an event or condition
         that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems
         that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident for a single train system. The
         minimum flow valve supports LPCS operability by providing a flow path to prevent pump
         damage during situations where the LPCS pump has been started in response to a transient
         but reactor vessel pressure is not low enough to allow LPCS injection. Historically, when
         LPCS has been inoperable at Columbia Generating Station, it was not considered to be
         reportable as a single train system. This treatment is consistent with the plant safety
         analysis and the associated system and safety function groupings which do not identify LPCS
         as a single train system. There are two pertinent groupings in the safety analyses which
         are aligned with the credited safety functions of LPCS. The two groupings are the low
         pressure injection system function (combined with LPCI), and a core spray system function
         (combined with HPCS). Industry precedent has been consistent with the historical position.
         However, recent NRC interpretations have considered safety function at the lowest system
         level, which results in LPCS being considered a single train performing a safety
         function.</safetyConsequences>

      <eventCause>The direct cause of LPCS-FCV-11 failing to open as expected was a loss of power
         that occurred when the overload elements cleared within the three line power fuses.
         Possible reasons to fail or trigger the overload elements in the fuses are binding within
         the flow control valve, binding within the motor operator, sticking or dirty contacts
         within the reversing starter, or a premature failure of a fuse. Once the fuses were
         replaced, normal operation was restored with no observed binding of the valve or motor
         operator or abnormalities with the reversing starter. Diagnostic testing of the motor
         operator was completed which showed that the amps drawn by the motor were under the fuse
         manufacturer's time-current curve. The failed fuses had been installed approximately two
         years ago but were 12 years old. An examination of the three failed fuses revealed a poor
         solder joint in the trigger assembly in one of the failed fuses. The apparent cause of this
         event is attributed to premature failure of one of the three installed power line fuses
         from momentary inrush current at a current value under the fuse curve. This conclusion is
         based on the examination of the fuse trigger solder which displayed evidence of cold
         unattached solder and trapped resin flux in the trigger solder joint. Also, no heating
         damage of the PET (polyethylene terephthalate) insulating spool was observed. Two of the
         fuses obviously failed from current overload on the resulting failure of the first fuse.
         These two fuses were determined to have functioned normally. Initially, this event was
         considered to be not reportable until discussions were held with the NRC Resident Inspector
         and Regional staff. Upon determination of reportability of this event, a prompt
         notification was made to the NRC in accordance with 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(v)(D) via Event
         Notification #46604. As such, the event investigation was conducted as an apparent cause
         rather than a root cause evaluation. A root cause analysis is in progress but has not yet
         been completed for this event. If new information is gained, which invalidates the stated
         cause or corrective actions, this report will be revised to incorporate the new
         information.</eventCause>

      <corretiveActions>The fuses that failed were Cooper/Bussmann Fusetron dual-element,
         time-delay, current limiting, 600 Volt, 1.25 Amp fuses (model FRS-R-1-1/4). Since the fuse
         overload element was found to be triggered, the operating history of the LPCS-FCV-l1 motor
         operator and starter was investigated: 1) In March 2008, a diagnostic test of the motor
         operator was completed satisfactorily with no abnormalities noted. 2) In March 2009, an
         inspection of the reversing starter was completed satisfactorily. The fuses were replaced
         at this time. 3) In April 2010, the motor operator was lubed and inspected with no problems
         found. 4) The last quarterly LPCS surveillance test prior to the event was completed
         satisfactorily on September 29,2010. Warehouse and tool crib stock of the Bussmann
         FRS-R-I-1I4 fuses from the same GI0 date code lot as that of the three failed fuses were
         quarantined and segregated to prevent further installation of suspect fuses. This lot of
         fuses was received at Columbia Generating Station in 2000. Enhancements to the Bussmann
         fuse dedication process to require additional receipt inspections and testing are planned.
         A search was performed of all safety-related ECCS motor operated valves which may possibly
         contain the same Bussmann 1.25 Amp fuses from the same lot. Inspections were performed and
         no additional fuses of the same lot were found to be installed. </corretiveActions>

      <previousEvents>No similar events have been reported by Columbia Generating
         Station.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
