<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler when="2012-08-22" id="3972012004">
   <abstract>On August 22,2012, it was discovered that during maintenance on breaker E-C8-S/1,
      required Technical Specification (TS) 3.8.1 Condition A was not entered. The breaker provides
      power to an essential bus from one of the credited offsite power sources. While E-C8-S/1 was
      out of service, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) would not have been able to meet
      acceptance criteria in a surveillance procedure used to satisfy Surveillance Requirement (SR)
      3.8.1.1. Therefore, per SR 3.0.1, failure to meet the surveillance requirement indicates that
      Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.8.1 was not met. The breaker was inoperable for
      approximately 30 hours, resulting in the failure to meet the Required Actions described in
      Condition A and F within the specified Completion Times. An apparent cause evaluation is
      currently in progress. A supplemental LER is planned to add additional details concerning the
      evaluation's conclusions and corrective actions. </abstract>
   <narrative>

      <plantConds>Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power.
         There were no structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start of this
         event and that contributed to this event. </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On August 22, 2012, it was discovered that during maintenance on breaker E-CB-S/1
         [BKR], required Technical Specification (TS) Action Statement (TSAS) 3.B.1 Condition A was
         not entered. The breaker provides power to the Division 1 critical electrical bus E-SM-7
         [BU] from the credited offsite source, E-TR-S [XFMR]. It was discovered that while E-CB-S/1
         was out of service, Columbia would not have been able to satisfy acceptance criteria in the
         associated surveillance procedure used to satisfy Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.B.1.1.
         Therefore, per SR 3.0.1, failure to meet the surveillance requirement indicates that
         Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.B.1 was not met. The breaker was inoperable for
         approximately 30 hours, resulting in the failure to meet the Required Actions described in
         TS 3.B.1 Condition A and F, within the specified Completion Times. </eventDesc>
      <correctiveActions>Night orders were initiated notifying operations personnel of the issue and
         the appropriate measures to take going forward when planning work with the associated
         breakers. Specifically, any work which impacts the ability of E-TR-S to supply power to the
         critical electrical bus for Division 1 or Division 2 will require entry into TS 3.B.1
         Condition A. </correctiveActions>
      <eventCause>The apparent cause of the event has not been determined. The apparent cause
         investigation is still in progress. A supplemental LER is planned to provide the additional
         conclusions and details discovered in the evaluation. </eventCause>
      <safetyConsequences>There were no actual safety consequences as a result of this condition.
         Critical electrical buses E-SM-7 and E-SM-B [BU] are normally energized from Normal
         Auxiliary transformer, E-TR-N1 [XFMR], when the main generator [GEN] is
         operating.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>A search was performed for each time E-CB-S/1 was taken out of service in the
         past three years. The associated work orders (WO) and control room logs were reviewed to
         determine whether the duration the breaker was out of service exceeded the Completion Times
         of TS 3.B.1 Conditions A and F. On two separate occasions E-CB-S/1 was taken out of service
         and the TS allowed outage time was exceeded. A similar search was performed on E-CB-S/3 as
         it performs the same function as E-CB-S/1, but on Division 2. On one occasion E-CB~S/3 was
         taken out of service and the TS allowed outage time was exceeded. </previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
