<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>On July 24, 2012, secondary containment pressure exceeded technical specification
      allowable limits for a period of approximately four and a half minutes. The pressure excursion
      was due to an inadvertent trip of reactor building fans ROA-FN-1 Band REA-FN-1 B. The trip
      occurred during ongoing maintenance on the Standby Gas Treatment (SGT) system. While technical
      specification limits were exceeded, the resulting pressure excursion was bounded by analytical
      results, and thus there were no safety consequences for this event. The investigation
      concluded that there was no direct ~vidence that a human performance error caused this event.
      The cause for the event was determined to be that operations does not have guidance on
      swapping to redundant lineups when work is to be performed on the SGT or reactor building HVAC
      . Corrective actions will revise standard operating procedures and Instrument Master Data
      Sheets by adding a note about reactor building fan trip risk.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>
         <P>At the time of event, the plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. There were no
            structures, systems or components that were inoperable at the start of the event that
            contributed to the event. SGT Train B was out of service for planned maintenance and
            work performed as part of the maintenance contributed to the initiation of this event.
         </P>
      </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>
         <P>On July 24, 2012, at 11 :22, the main control Room received both OIV 1 and OIV 2 RB HVAC
            board R trouble alarms indicating high secondary containment pressure and that both
            reactor building fans were off. In response to the alarms, operations started ROA-FN-1A
            and REA-FN-1A to recover reactor building ventilation. Plant data shows that for
            approximately 4 and a half minutes the secondary containment vacuum was less than -0.25
            inches water vacuum. </P>

         <P>The fans were noted to have tripped during maintenance on Standby Gas Treatment (SGT)
            system with alarms coming in shortly after reconnecting leads to a portion of the SGT
            system. No deficient maintenance practices were identified however it is possible that
            the work being performed caused the fans to trip. </P>

         <P>This event is reportable as an event that could have prevented fulfillment of a safety
            function needed to control the release of radiation and mitigate the consequences of an
            accident per 1 OCFR50. 73(a)(2)(v)(C) and 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(v)(O). An 8 hour event
            notification (48131) was previously made to the NRC based on meeting the reporting
            criteria of 10CFR50.72(b)(3)(v)(C) and 10CFR50.72(b)(3)(v)(O). </P>
      </eventDesc>
      <extentConds>
         <P>Extent of condition is limited to the SGT system since it is the only safety related
            cross divisional system at Columbia. Normal maintenance work control practices ensure
            operability and functionality is maintained by components out of scope of the division
            being worked on. The preventive maintenance work orders for both A and B SGT loop
            calibrations have been revised to provide information that the ROA/REA fans need to be
            lined up on the correct division to eliminate future trips. </P>
      </extentConds>
      <correctiveAction>

         <P>Maintenance planning revised all SGT preventive maintenance tasks, to ensure SGT loop
            logiC and ROA/REA fan trip logic conflicts are clearly defined. </P>
      </correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>

         <P>The cause of the trip was that work control does not have guidance on swapping to
            redundant lineups when taking systems out of service. </P>
      </eventCause>
      <previousEvents>
         <P>Searches in the INPO database and the Energy Northwest Corrective Action Program were
            not able to identify related issues or previous occurrences of this event. No specific
            internal or external related operating experience could be found that related to this
            issue. As a result of the searches performed there were no missed opportunities
            identified that could have prevented the event. </P>
      </previousEvents>
      <correctiveAction>
         <P>operations work control rocedures will be revised to ensure that 0 erations reviews
            redundant lineups when work is to be performed on SGT or Reactor building fan. In
            addition, the Instrument Master Data Sheet for SGT is being revised to add a note about
            reactor building fan trip risk. An Operations support task and a note on all maintenance
            work orders related to SGT/RBHVAC work that will ensure a swap occurs to the alternate
            ROA/REA fans prior to commencing work are being added.</P>
      </correctiveAction>
      <safetyConsequences>This event resulted in an unplanned entry into TS 3.6.4.1 condition A.
         Secondary containment pressure was more than -0.25 inches water gauge for approximately
         four and a half minutes. The peak pressure was 0.06 inches water gauge. While the actual
         pressure is beyond the range allowed by technical specifications, the purpose of
         maintaining slight vacuum is to assist in drawdown of secondary containment to support
         accident response of the SGT system. Existing engineering analysis demonstrates that for
         this event, the drawdown credited in accident response could have been attained using the
         operational A train of SGT, thus there were no potential safety consequences. There were no
         actual safety consequences associated with this event since no events involving
         radiological hazards were experienced during the work activities.</safetyConsequences>
   </narrative>
</ler>
