<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-08-19T12:32:42-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-08-19T12:32:42-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-08-19T12:32:42-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>r \ </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>W. Grvwer HetI8I CoIuIIIbie o.nerating StaIon </P><P>P.O. Box ••PE23 </P><P>RiI:hI8m. WA 99S52.()988 Ph. 509.377.83111 F. 509.377.4150 </P><P>~O~com </P><P>August 1, 2013 
G02-13-109 10 CFR 50.73 
</P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
</P><P>Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENEAAnNG STA1'ION, DOCKET NO.I04t7 
UCENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2013-GOMO 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2013-003-00 for Columbia Generating 
Station. This report Is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(8)(2)(1)(8). 
</P><P>'\ </P><P>, There.are no commitments being made to the NRC by this letter. If you have any questions or require additional information, please contact Mr. J. R. Trautvetter, Regulatory Compliance Supervisor, at (509) 377-4337. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>W. G. Hettel Vice President, Operations </P><P>Enclosure: Licensee Event Report 2013-003-00 </P><P>co: NRC Region IV Administrator </P><P>NAC NRR Project Manager </P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector19B8C </P><P>A. J. Rapacz -BPA/1399 </P><P>W.A. Horin -Winston &amp; strawn </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A111_img_3.jpg"/>•• (1()'201 0) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LEA) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) 1. FACtLITY NAME Columbia '''A&quot;6I''Cl~.rtn Station 4. TITLE o 2O.220t(b) o 2O.2201(d)a 20.2203 (a)(1)o 20.2203(8)(2)(1) o 2O.2203(a)(2)(U) 0 C 2O.2203(a)(2)(li1) a 2O.2203(a)(2)(Iv) a 2O.2203(8)(2)(v) [J 2O.2203(a)(2)(vt) 2. DOCKET C 2O.2203(a)(3)(1) C 2O~a)(3)(li)a 2O.2203(a)(4) a 5O.36(c)(1)(I)(A) o 5O.36(c)(1)(H)(A)C 50.36(0)(2)o 50.46(8)(3)(11)a 6O.73(a)(2)(I)(A)181 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(8) o 5O.13(a)(2)(1)(C)C 5O.73(a)(2)(1I)(A)a 50.73(8)(2)(11)(8) a 5O.73(a)(2)(1H) o 5O.73(a)(2)(1v)(A) (J 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(A)o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(8)o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) a 5O.73(a)(2)(V)(0) a. PAGE 10F3 5O.13(a)(2)(Yil) 5O.73(a)(2)(vtU)(A) 5O.13(a)(2)(vtH)(8)a 5O.73(a)(2)(lx)(A) a 5O.13(a)(2)(x) a 73.71(a)(4)o 73.71(a)(5) o OTHER In Abstract below </Figure><P>Lisa WIlliams. </P><Table><TR><TH>CAUSE 181 YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) </TH><TH>C </TH><TH>CAUSE </TH><TH/></TR><TR><TD>NO </TD><TD/></TR></Table><P>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1M)() spaces, I.e., approximately 15 Slngl~typewritten 11n8s) On June 3, 2013, with Columbia Generating Station In a planned refueling outage ~nd the reactor cavity flooded up (Mode 5), leakage past a closed isolation valve associated With one hydraulic control unit on the control rod drive system was observed through a drain line. This leakage Originated from the reactor vessel and constituted an operation with the potential to drain the reactor vessel (OPDRV). When the leakage was initially identified. it was not recognized as an OPDRV. The leakage rate was estimated to be less than 10 gaHons per hour. This leakage persisted for 16 hours until the maintenance actMtles were completed. During this time period. the secondary containment was inoperable. Technical Specifications (TS) require that with secondary containment inoperable during OPDRV activities, action must be Initiated immediately to suspend OPDRVs. Contrary to this requirement, action was not taken to suspend the OPDRV. This represents a condition prohibited by T8. The cause of this event was inadequate procedure guidance for actions to take when unexpected OPDRV conditions are encountered. Immediate corrective actions were taken to establish expectations regarding the appropriate actions to take for discovered unplanned OPDRV conditions. This event is not safety significant since the leakage rate was so small that there was no measurable loss of level In the reactor cavity. </P><P>26158 A5 </P><P>, 
</P><P>NRC FORM 388A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATOA'I COIIMI8SION</P><Part><H1>r-------------------------------------------------------------~
</H1><P>(10·2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A111_img_5.jpg"/>YEAR 05000397</Figure><P>Columbia Generating Station </P><P>20F3 </P><P>2013 -003 -00 </P><P>NARRAnVE 
Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) codes are identified in the text as {XX]. 
</P><P>Introduction </P><P>Initial Conditions </P><P>At the time of the event, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) was in Mode 5, at 0 percent of rated thermal power. The preferred source of oftsite power from the 230 kV source through the startup transformer [XMFR] was inoperable. The Division 2 emergency cUesel generator system (EK] was inoperable. The Division 2 emergency core cooling systems (ECCS) consisting of two trains of low pressure coolant injection (LPCI) [BO] were inoperable. The Division 1 emergency diesel generator and ECCS, consisting of one LPCI train and the low pressure core spray system [BM), were operable and protected. </P><P>Reportability Criteria </P><P>Secondary containment (NG] operability was not maintained during an operation with a potential to drain the reactor vessel (OPDRV) actMty and Required Action C.1 of Technical SpecifICation (TS) 3.6.4.1 to immediately initiate actions to suspend OPDRV activities was not completed. This condition is being reported in accordance with 10 CFR 5O.73(a)(2)(1)(B) as an operation prohibited by the plant's TS. </P><P>Event Description </P><P>On June 3, 2013, with Columbia in a planned refueling outage and the reactor cavity flooded up (Mode 5), leakage past a closed Isolation valve associated with one hydraulic control unit [HCU] on the control rod drive system [AA] was observed through a drain tine. This leakage originated from the reactor vessel and constituted an operation with the potential to drain the reactor vessel (OPDRV). When the leakage was initially identified, it was not recognized as an OPDRV. The leakage rate was estimated to be 1ess than 10 gallons per hour. This leakage perSisted for 16 hours on June 3,2013, from 0405 hours to 1955 hours until the maintenance activities were completed and the drain line was isolated. The leakage was observed by Engineering personnel conducting a field walk down of the control rod drive system. A subsequent review of the issue by Licensing personnel determined that, although the leakage was minimal, it constituted an OPDRV under the plain language definition provided by Enforcement Guidance Memorandum (EGM) 11-003, &quot;Enforcement Guidance Memorandum on Dispositioning Boiling Water Reactor Licensee Noncompliance with Technical Specification Requirements during Operations with a Potential for Draining the Reactor Vessel,&quot; dated October 4, 2011. </P><P>Event Cause </P><P>The cause determination is still in progress. The preliminary cause of this event is attributed to inadequate procedure guidance for actions to take when unexpected OPDRV conditions are encountered. The TS require that actions be initiated immediately to suspend the OPDRV activity. In this case, upon discovery of the leakage, the maintenance activity should have been stopped and a determination undertaken to identify the necessary actions to isolate the leakage while still preserving equipment and personnel safety. A supplement to this licensee event report will be submitted if the final cause determination is substantively different from the initial cause determination. ' . </P><P>26158 AS </P><P>... . 
</P><P>NRC FORM 386A U.1.. NlAOI.I:&quot;... RlGULATORY COMIIl8SIOH (1 ()&quot;2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A111_img_6.jpg"/>UCENSEE EVENT REPORT (LEA)• \4 YEAR 30F3 2013 .. 003 -00 </Figure><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>Safety Assessment </P><P>The safety significance of this event is considered to be negligibte. At the time of the event. Columbia was in Mode 5 with the reactor cavity flooded up. The teakage rate was small. on the order of 10 gaHons per hour. Approximately 500,000 gallons of water are added to flood up the reactor cavity; thus, this amount of water would be available to drain prior to reaching the top of active fuel. Additionally, the makeup capability of the ECCS far exceeded the observed leakage rate. </P><P>Corrective Actions </P><P>The following corrective actions were completed: A Night Order was issued to identify that when CRD-V12612635 (V] is open, the known leakage past CAD-V·10112635 requires this configuration be considered an OPDRV. Additionally, the Night Order reinforced the expectation that upon notification that leakage has been discovered that may constitute an OPORV, action must be cOmmenced immediately to allow isolation of the drain path in order to satisfy the TS requirements. These actions must be done in a controlled manner to ensure industrial, radiological, and nuclear safety is not jeopardized. </P><P>The corrective action plan is still being developed. The preHmInary plan wiD revise procedure PPM 3.4.1 to incorporate the expectations from the Night Ord$r. A supptement to this Ucensee event report will be submitted if the final corrective action plan is substantively different than that included here. </P><P>Previous Similar Events </P><P>During the refueling outage that was in progress during this event, a number of evolutions were properly classified as OPDRVs using the guidance in EGM 11-003. For these planned evolutions, the TS requirements were met. There are no previous similar events involving unpiaMed OPDRV activities. </P><P>26158 R5 </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>