<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2013-06-27" id="3972013006">
   <abstract>
      <P>On June 27, 2013 at 17:58 hours a laborer was exiting the Clesel Generator [00] 3 Room when
         he Inadvertently brushed against the control switch (JS) for the Diesel Mixed Air fan [FAN}
         causing it to tum to the OFF position. In response to an annunciator alarm in the main
         control room, an operations supervisor proceeded to the Oiesel Generator 3 Room. After
         ascertaining what had happened by questioning the laborer, the operator turned the fan
         control switch back to ON and the switch operated smoothly. The Diesel Mixed Air fan was
         back In service at 18:19 hOUTS. so the fan was inoperable for approximately 21 minutes. </P>

      <P>With the Diesel Mixed Air fan switch in the OFF position. the following supported equipment
         were declared inoperable and the appropriate Technical Speclflcatlons were entered: Diesel
         Generator 3. High Pressure Core Spray (HPCS) [BJ1. Division 3125 VDC battery charger {BYC],
         Division 3 battery (BTRY], and the Division 3 AC electrical power distribution system [JX). </P>

      <P>The loss of the HPCS system resulted In the temporary toss of safety function for a single
         train system. There was no radiological retease associated with this event. No safety
         system actuations or isolations occurred. The licensee notified the NRC Resident Inspector
         and Event Notification No. 49152 was submitted. </P>
   </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>The event occurred on June 21, 2013 at 17:58 hours when the plant was in Mode 1 at
         62 peroent power following a refueling outage. </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On June 21, 2013 at 17:58 hours a laborer was exiting the Diesel Generator [OG) 3
         Room when he Inadvertently brushed against the control Switch [JS) for the Diesel Mixed AIr
         fan [FAN} causing it to tum to the OFF position. In response to an annunciator In the main
         control room, an operations SUPervisor proceeded to the DIesel Generator 3 Room. After
         ascertaining what had happened by questioning the laborer, the operator tumed the fan
         control switch back to the ON position. The Diesel Mixed Alt fan was back in service at
         18:19 hours, so the fan was Inoperable for approximately 21 minutes. Technical
         Specifications were entered for the foHowing equipment supported by the fan and declared
         inoperable: High Pressure Core Spray (HPCS) [BJ], Diesel Generator (00-3) (OG], Division 3
         125 VOC battery charger (BYC], Division 3 125 VDC battery (BTRy], and the Division 3 AC
         electrical powel distribution system (JX]. The Diesel Mixed Air fan and its supported
         equipment and systems were declared operable at 18:19 hours and retumed to service. The
         event affected the safety function for 8 single trafn system, the High Pressure Core Spray
         (HPCS) system; therefore, this Licensee Event report is flied in accordance with 10 CFR
         5O.73(a)(2)(v)(8) and SO.13(a}(2)(v)(D). There were no radiological releases because of
         11118 event, and there were no system actuatiOns or isolations as 8 result of the
         event.</eventDesc>
      <correctiveAction>The proper control switch position was restored and the fan (OMA·FN-32) was
         placed back into service by Operations personnel.</correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>The cause Evaluation Identified the apparent cause of this event as ineffective
         Implementation of error prevention tools. A contributing cause was Identified as the
         station not having adequately addressed poor human factor deSigns in some cases for
         components susceptible to inadvertent contact due to their location and proximity in the
         plant.</eventCause>
      <correctiveAction>Conduct a briefing with Site Support Contractor craft workers focusing on
         procedure PPM 1.3.81 (Maintaining Plant Component Status Control) requirements and
         supporting behaviors. Perform plant walk-downs and compile a list of components that are
         susceptible to bumping and provide recommendations for additional actions to prevent bump
         incidents.</correctiveAction>
      <safetyConsequences>The Diesel Mixed Air fan DMA·FN-32 functions as part of the 00-3 Engine
         Room ventilation supplying air flow to the room's air handling unit, and supports
         maintaining room air temperatures for diesel generator operation and for protection of
         electrical equipment. The fan serves the electrical equipment and generator area which .are
         normaUy in standby. This HVAC component is required to ensure long-term emergency diesel
         generator and HPCS system operations. The HPCS system and Diesel Generator 3 were at/II
         available to respond to an accident condition. this event had no Impact to the health and
         safety of the public.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents> There have not been similar event reports at the station in the fast ten
         years.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
