<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>On June 3, 2013, with Columbia Generating Station In a planned refueling outage ~nd the
      reactor cavity flooded up (Mode 5), leakage past a closed isolation valve associated With one
      hydraulic control unit on the control rod drive system was observed through a drain line. This
      leakage Originated from the reactor vessel and constituted an operation with the potential to
      drain the reactor vessel (OPDRV). When the leakage was initially identified. it was not
      recognized as an OPDRV. The leakage rate was estimated to be less than 10 gaHons per hour.
      This leakage persisted for 16 hours until the maintenance actMtles were completed. During this
      time period. the secondary containment was inoperable. Technical Specifications (TS) require
      that with secondary containment inoperable during OPDRV activities, action must be Initiated
      immediately to suspend OPDRVs. Contrary to this requirement, action was not taken to suspend
      the OPDRV. This represents a condition prohibited by T8. The cause of this event was
      inadequate procedure guidance for actions to take when unexpected OPDRV conditions are
      encountered. Immediate corrective actions were taken to establish expectations regarding the
      appropriate actions to take for discovered unplanned OPDRV conditions. This event is not
      safety significant since the leakage rate was so small that there was no measurable loss of
      level In the reactor cavity. </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>

         <P>At the time of the event, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) was in Mode 5, at 0
            percent of rated thermal power. The preferred source of oftsite power from the 230 kV
            source through the startup transformer [XMFR] was inoperable. The Division 2 emergency
            cUesel generator system (EK] was inoperable. The Division 2 emergency core cooling
            systems (ECCS) consisting of two trains of low pressure coolant injection (LPCI) [BO]
            were inoperable. The Division 1 emergency diesel generator and ECCS, consisting of one
            LPCI train and the low pressure core spray system [BM), were operable and protected.
         </P>
      </plantConds>
      <reportabilityCriteria>
         <P>Secondary containment (NG] operability was not maintained during an operation with a
            potential to drain the reactor vessel (OPDRV) actMty and Required Action C.1 of
            Technical SpecifICation (TS) 3.6.4.1 to immediately initiate actions to suspend OPDRV
            activities was not completed. This condition is being reported in accordance with 10 CFR
            5O.73(a)(2)(1)(B) as an operation prohibited by the plant's TS. </P>
      </reportabilityCriteria>
      <eventDesc>
         <P>On June 3, 2013, with Columbia in a planned refueling outage and the reactor cavity
            flooded up (Mode 5), leakage past a closed Isolation valve associated with one hydraulic
            control unit [HCU] on the control rod drive system [AA] was observed through a drain
            tine. This leakage originated from the reactor vessel and constituted an operation with
            the potential to drain the reactor vessel (OPDRV). When the leakage was initially
            identified, it was not recognized as an OPDRV. The leakage rate was estimated to be 1ess
            than 10 gallons per hour. This leakage perSisted for 16 hours on June 3,2013, from 0405
            hours to 1955 hours until the maintenance activities were completed and the drain line
            was isolated. The leakage was observed by Engineering personnel conducting a field walk
            down of the control rod drive system. A subsequent review of the issue by Licensing
            personnel determined that, although the leakage was minimal, it constituted an OPDRV
            under the plain language definition provided by Enforcement Guidance Memorandum (EGM)
            11-003, &quot;Enforcement Guidance Memorandum on Dispositioning Boiling Water Reactor
            Licensee Noncompliance with Technical Specification Requirements during Operations with
            a Potential for Draining the Reactor Vessel,&quot; dated October 4, 2011. </P>
      </eventDesc>
      <eventCause>
         <P>The cause determination is still in progress. The preliminary cause of this event is
            attributed to inadequate procedure guidance for actions to take when unexpected OPDRV
            conditions are encountered. The TS require that actions be initiated immediately to
            suspend the OPDRV activity. In this case, upon discovery of the leakage, the maintenance
            activity should have been stopped and a determination undertaken to identify the
            necessary actions to isolate the leakage while still preserving equipment and personnel
            safety. A supplement to this licensee event report will be submitted if the final cause
            determination is substantively different from the initial cause determination. ' . </P>
      </eventCause>
      <safetyConsequences>
         <P>The safety significance of this event is considered to be negligibte. At the time of the
            event. Columbia was in Mode 5 with the reactor cavity flooded up. The teakage rate was
            small. on the order of 10 gaHons per hour. Approximately 500,000 gallons of water are
            added to flood up the reactor cavity; thus, this amount of water would be available to
            drain prior to reaching the top of active fuel. Additionally, the makeup capability of
            the ECCS far exceeded the observed leakage rate. </P>
      </safetyConsequences>
      <correctiveActions>
         <P>The following corrective actions were completed: A Night Order was issued to identify
            that when CRD-V12612635 (V] is open, the known leakage past CAD-V·10112635 requires this
            configuration be considered an OPDRV. Additionally, the Night Order reinforced the
            expectation that upon notification that leakage has been discovered that may constitute
            an OPORV, action must be cOmmenced immediately to allow isolation of the drain path in
            order to satisfy the TS requirements. These actions must be done in a controlled manner
            to ensure industrial, radiological, and nuclear safety is not jeopardized. </P>

         <P>The corrective action plan is still being developed. The preHmInary plan wiD revise
            procedure PPM 3.4.1 to incorporate the expectations from the Night Ord$r. A supptement
            to this Ucensee event report will be submitted if the final corrective action plan is
            substantively different than that included here. </P>
      </correctiveActions>
      <previousEvents>
         <P>During the refueling outage that was in progress during this event, a number of
            evolutions were properly classified as OPDRVs using the guidance in EGM 11-003. For
            these planned evolutions, the TS requirements were met. There are no previous similar
            events involving unpiaMed OPDRV activities. </P>
      </previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
