<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2013-01-07" id="3972013001">
   <abstract>On January 7,2013, Columbia was operating at 100% power. At 1427 PST both doors of the
      501 elevation airlock entrance of the Reactor Building were simultaneously opened for a short
      period of time. This was the result of the failure of the interlock between the outer door
      (R304), and the inner door (R305). Maintenance personnel were moving scaffolding through the
      Reactor Building outer security door when an equipment operator opened the inner door to exit
      the Reactor Building. This equipment operator immediately closed the inner door and contacted
      the Main Control Room. The outer door was key locked closed until corrective actions could be
      implemented. Having a condition where both doors in a Reactor Building airlock were opened
      simultaneously while not undergoing a planned evolution for maintenance or surveillance
      testing, results in an unintended entry into Technical Specification (TS) 3.6.4.1 Secondary
      Containment due to a failure to satisfy Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.6.4.1.3. It was
      determined that this condition resulted in a loss of safety function (Secondary Containment)
      and was reported to the NRC (Event Notification 48656) at 1629 PST on January 7,
      2013.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>Columbia was operating at 100% power. Standby Gas Treatment (SGT) System
         &quot;A&quot; was in an operability run following corrective maintenance on an electric
         heater disconnect. This did not contribute to the event. </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On January 7,2013, at 1427 PST both doors [EllS: DR] of the 501 ft. elevation
         airlock [EllS: AL] entrance of the Reactor Building [EllS: NG] were simultaneously opened
         for a short period of time. This was the result of the failure of the interlock [EllS:
         IMEG] between the outer door (R304), and the inner door (R305). Maintenance personnel were
         moving scaffolding through the Reactor Building outer door when an equipment operator
         opened the inner door to exit the Reactor Building. This equipment operator immediately
         closed the inner door and contacted the Main Control Room. It was estimated that door was
         only open for a few seconds. The outer door was key locked closed until corrective actions
         could be implemented. Having a condition where both doors in a Reactor Building airlock
         were opened simultaneously while not undergoing a planned evolution for maintenance or
         surveillance testing, results in an unintended entry into Technical Specification (TS)
         3.6.4.1 Secondary Containment Condition A due to a failure to satisfy Surveillance
         Requirement (SR) 3.6.4.1.3. SR 3.6.4.1.3 requires verification that each secondary
         containment access inner door or each secondary containment access outer door in each
         access opening is closed. It was determined that this condition resulted in a loss of
         safety function (Secondary Containment) and was reported to the NRC (Event Notification
         48656) at 1629 PST on January 7, 2013. The reactor building is maintained at a negative
         pressure to minimize potential leakage of radioactivity to the environment. During normal
         operations, the Reactor Building Ventilation System maintains this negative pressure.
         During a design basis accident, the Standby Gas Treatment System [EllS: BH] maintains this
         negative pressure. This brief opening of the doors had no measurable impact on the Reactor
         Building pressure.</eventDesc>

      <correctiveAction>Access through the airlock was restricted by locking the outer door (R304)
         until Reactor Building airlock inner door R305 was repaired. Access to and from the Reactor
         Building was restricted to two airlock doors on the 441 ft. elevation. Personnel were
         stationed at the doors to ensure Secondary Containment integrity was maintained. A
         temporary modification was implemented installing warning lights on the outsides of both
         airlock doors and a buzzer to alert station personnel when an individual is transiting the
         airlock. The surveillance procedure for SR 3.6.4.1.3 was updated to verify proper operation
         of airlock doors and interlocks without compromising Secondary
         Containment.</correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>A root cause evaluation of the issue determined that there were two root causes.
         First Root Cause: A legacy design weakness for the Secondary Containment airlock door
         interlocks allows conditions where both the inner and outer doors can be opened at the same
         time. Second Root Cause: Implementation of TSTF-18-A, Rev 1, at Columbia changed the
         wording of TS Bases for SR 3.6.4.1.2 and SR 3.6.4.1.3, reducing the clarity of the
         description of conditions that define Secondary Containment operability.</eventCause>
      <correctiveAction>A design change is being evaluated that includes replacing the existing
         mechanical locks on all Secondary Containment airlock inner doors with a more reliable door
         locking device, improving the interlock logic to eliminate current design imperfections,
         and installing warning lights on the outside of the airlock to warn personal when the
         airlock is in use. The TS Bases for SR 3.6.4.1.2 and SR 3.6.4.1.3 is being revised to
         ensure that the wording clearly identifies that Secondary Containment operability requires
         that one door in each airlock be closed at all times when Secondary Containment is
         required.</correctiveAction>
      <safetyConsequences>There was no equipment damage, injuries or dose exposure to station
         personnel. There was no change in plant status or operating condition and there was no
         actual risk to the public at any time. There was no impact to public health and safety as
         the Primary Containment was intact with Primary Containment Isolation Valves operable. The
         Reactor Building Ventilation System maintained the designed negative pressure for Secondary
         Containment during the event. There was a potential significance if there had been an event
         where the Primary Containment failed to isolate concurrent with a loss of coolant accident
         such that radioactive materials were released to the Reactor Building. Having both Reactor
         Building airlock doors open would potentially provide a release path for radioactive
         materials to enter the external environment or would inhibit the ability to draw down
         Secondary Containment within the time frame assumed in the dose
         analysis.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>A similar event occurred at Columbia on December 30, 2012 (Event Notification
         48639) and reported in LER 2012-007 -00.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
