<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2013-08-25" id="3972013007">
   <abstract>On August 25,2013 at 1818 hours secondary containment was declared Inoperabl~ during a
      suddenly occurring thunderstorm. Secondary containment pressure was not maintained greater
      than or equal to 0.25 inches of vacuum water' gauge as required by Technical Specification
      3.6.4.1. This condition was experienced for a period of no greater than 160 seconds.
      Operations took manual control of the system and quickly adjusted Reactor Building Exhaust Air
      flow to restore secondary containment to less than -0.25 Inches water gauge. While Technical
      Specification limits were exceeded, the resulting pressure excursion was bounded by analytical
      results, and.,thus there were no safety , consequences tor this event. The cause for the event
      was detennined to be failure o·t the Reactor Exhaust AirlReactor Outside Air system to
      automatically maintain a stabilized negative differential press.ure in th_e Reactor Building
      at the controller setpoint value of '-O.e inches water gauge. The system controller is not
      designed to respond to very quick changes in building differential pressure 'as was
      experienced during thiS period of suddenly shifting wind direction and increasing wind speed.
      Corrective actions include investigating methods to alert operati~ns to a potential is~ue with
      secondary containment before the Technical Specification, LeO ~.e.4.1.A, for secOndary
      containment pressure is ;reached.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>At the time of event, the plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. There were
         no structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start of the event that
         contributed to the event.</plantConds>
      <eventDesc>On August 25,2013 at 1818 hours, during a suddenly occurring thunderstorm, the
         secondary containment (NHJ pressure was not maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 inches
         of vacuum water gauge. This condition existed for a period of no greater than 160 seconds.
         Because Reactor Building [NG] pressure increased above -0.25 inches of water gauge (inwg)
         secondary containment was logged as inoperable in the surveillance log and Technical
         Specification 3.6.4.1 Action A was entered.</eventDesc>
      <extentConds>This condition of Reactor Building differential pressure momentarily rising above
         the prescribed limit Is specific to the Reactor Building Heating Ventilation and Air
         Cooling (HVAC) [VA] and Standby Gas Treatment (SGT) [BH] systems, and their capability to
         establish and maintain secondary containment vacuum. No other systems are affected as a
         result of this condition.</extentConds>
      <correctiveAction>Operations took manual control of the Reactor Exhaust Air (REA) differential
         pressure (dP) controller [PDC] and quickly adjusted Reactor Building Exhaust Air flow to
         restore secondary containment pressure to less than -0.25 inwg. Later, after the storm had
         passed, operators placed the controller back In automatic.</correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>During normal plant operation, the non-safety related Reactor Building HVAC system
         maintains environmental conditions within the Reactor Building at a vacuum with respect to
         the outside. Various operational equipment manipulations and environmental conditions can
         result in the momentary Increase of differential pressure to above the Technical
         Specification maximum allowable pressure of -0.25 Inwg. Operational activities include the
         starting or stopping of SGT or Reactor Exhaust Air/Reactor Outside Air (REA/ROA) fans
         [FAN]. Environmental conditions which can cause a momentary increase In pressure include
         high, outside gusting winds. During normal operation with no extemal driving forces, the
         REA/ROA system does an excellent job of automatically maintaining a stabilized negative
         differential pressure in the Reactor BUilding at the controller setpolnt value of -0.6
         inwg. However, the system (:entroller is not designed to respond to very quick changes in
         building differential pressure due to a nearly instantaneous shift in wind direction as was
         experienced during the thunderstorm.</eventCause>
      <previousEvents>A loss of the ability to maintain secondary containment below the required
         negative pressure has occurred at Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) twice In the past
         two years. On July 24. 2012, reported under LEA 2012-003-00, secondary containment was
         compromised due to an inadvertent trip of one set of the redundant Reactor Building HVAC
         fans, during ongoing maintenance on the SGr system. The second Instance occurred on
         December 10, 2011, reported under LER 2011-004-00. Secondary containment was declared
         Inoperable and the cause was determined to be Ice buildup and subsequent release on
         exterior equipment supplying the Reactor Building HVAC system. Each of these events have
         associated corrective actions and the causes are not applicable to the current cause of
         weather related pressure excursion, nor would corrective actions from these past events
         prevented occurrence of this event.</previousEvents>
      <correctiveActions>The potential for these momentary pressure excursions will continue to
         occur with the currently designed control system. Columbia is investiaating methods to
         alert operations to a potential issue with secondary containment before the Technical
         Specification secondary containment pressure is reached. </correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>This event resulted in an unplanned entry into LeO 3.6.4.1.A. Secondary
         containment pressure was above -0.25 inwg for no more than 160 seconds. The peak pressure
         during this event was -0.03 Inwg. While the actual pressure was beyond the range allowed by
         Technical Specifications, the purpose of maintaining a slight VElcuum Is to assist in
         drawdown of secondary containment to support accident response of the safety related SOT
         systom. existing engineering analysis demonstrates that for this event, the drawdown
         credited in accident response could have been attained using either of the two available
         trains of the SGT system, thus there were no potential safety consequences. There was no
         actual safety consequence associated with this event since no event involving radiological
         hazards were experienced during the event. </safetyConsequences>
   </narrative>
</ler>
