<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>On 611512013 at 1222 POT Columbia Generating Station was In a refueling outage In Mode
      4 when vaRd Essential Safety Function (ESF) actuation signals of Division ,1 and 2 Emergency
      Diesel Generators were received due to a momentary loss of 115kV (1 of 2) offslte power
      sources. In addition valid actuation signals of DMsion 1 and 2 Essential Service Water System
      pumps were also received due to the start of DMslon 1and 2 Emergency Diesel Generators. The
      4.16kV Division 1 and 2 critical switchgear buses were de-energlzed resulting In load shed of
      several systems and an Invalid actuation of containment Isolation valves for multiple systems.
      Power to the 4.16kV critical switchgear was automatically restored by the Emergency Diesel
      Generators. <P>Plant systems which had been load shed were returned to operating status. The
         4.16kV critical switchgear buses were subsequently realigned to an offslte power source. </P>
      <P>The momentary loss of the 115kV offsite power source was due to relays opening and
         reclosing to clear a fine fault associated with a range fire under the transmission line.
      </P>
   </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>

         <P>At the time of event. the plant was in a refueling outage In Mode 4 at OCYo power with
            ali rods in. In preparation for heating up the reactor to support the Reactor Pressure
            Vessel hydro surveillance test. shutdown cooling had been secured and Residual Heat
            Removal (RHA) pump &quot;C&quot; had been started In Suppression Pool mixing. Due to
            recently performed testing on the 230kV Startup Transformer [XMFR}, the 4.16kV DivIsion
            1 and 2 critical switChgear buses [eU) were powered from the 115kV offsite power source
            through the Backup Transformer [XFMR). </P>
      </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>
         <P>On 611512013 at 1222 PDT Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) received valid Essential
            Safety Function (ESF) [JE] actuation signals of DivISion 1 and 2 Emergency Diesel
            Generators [DG] due to a momentary loss of the 115kV offslte power source and valid
            actuation signals of Division 1 and 2 Essential Service Water System [BI] pumps due to
            the start of OMsion 1 and 2 Emergency Diesel Generators. This event is reportable under
            10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(iv)(A) .. Event NotifiCation #49120 and 10 CFR 6O.73(a)(2)(Iv)(A). </P>

         <P>On the loss of the 115kV offsite power source. the 4.16kV Division 1and 2 critical
            switchgear de-energized. The te~por.ry.Ioss of power to these critical switchgear buses
            resulted in the following: </P>

         <P>It Start of Division 1 and 2 Emergency Diesel Generators re-energizing the 4.16kV
            Division 1 and 2 critical .switchgear buses. The subsequ~nt start of OMsion 1 and 2
            essential Service Water System pumps. </P>

         <P>• Closure of containment isolation valves In the Reactor Water Cleanup System [CEl,
            Equipment DraJn System and the. Floor. Drain System (WK]. This was an Invalid isolation
            and Is reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) </P>

         <L>
            <LI>
               <LI_Label>•. </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Fuel.Pool Cooling IDA) pumps tripped. </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>•. </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Residual Heat Removal [SO) Pump &quot;e&quot; operating In Suppression Poot
                  mixing mOde tripped and the system . depressurized. </LI_Title>
            </LI>
         </L>

         <P>._. Control Rod Drive 1M) pump tripped '!'&quot;. );.'t:&quot;~~·):t.·· .: ;')1&quot;.',
            ·.~C j J ~;.~·~{.·i :~::J~' .. ~ , ~.~..' &quot;:~~~~.\ ~:: </P>

         <L>
            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Reactor building [NO) ventilation tripped </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Plant Service Water [KG] pump tripped </LI_Title>
            </LI>
         </L>

         <P>Shutdown cooling was not in operation at the time of the loss. Reactor coolant
            temperature was maintained in the temperature range of 130-170 degrees Fahrenheit.
            Reactor pressure remained at 0 pslg. IMMEDIATE CORRECTIVE ACTION Division 1 and 2
            Emergency Diesel Generators automatically repowered the 4.16kV DMsion 1 and 2 critical
            switchgear </P>

         <P>buses in less than 15 seconds. Fuel Pool COOling pump liB&quot; started automatically
            upon repowering the Division 2 critical switchgear bus. Division 1 and 2 Essentlat
            Service Water pumps started automatically due to the start of Division 1 and 2 Emergency </P>

         <P>Diesel Generators Actions were taken to restore the following systems to operating
            status: </P>

         <L>
            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Controt rod drive at 1227 </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Plant service water at 1238 </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Reactor building ventilation at 1243 </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>R~~rwater cfeanup at 1258 </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>4.16kV Division 2 critical switchgear bus (transferred to the 230kV startup
                  transformer) at 1259 </LI_Title>
            </LI>
         </L>
         <L>
            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>4.16kV DMslon 1 critical switchgear bus (transferred to the 230kV startup
                  transformer) at 1310 </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Shutdown cooling at 1343 (due to potential delays In the reactor pressure
                  vessel hydro surveillance) </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>DMslon 1 and 2 Emergency Diesel Generators (returned to standby condition)
                  at 1506 </LI_Title>
            </LI>

            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label>

               <LI_Title>Residual heat removal system UC&quot; (filled and vented and returned to
                  operable status) at 1554 </LI_Title>
            </LI>
         </L>

         <P>• 116kV Backup Transformer (returned to operable status) at 1824 CAUSE Bonneville Power
            Authority (SPA) reported that a line fault was detected In the 115kV line. Protective
            relays properly </P>

         <P>reacted to the fault by tripping and reclosing In approximately 1.17 seconds, clearing
            the line fault. A range fire under the 115kV line is believed to be the cause of the
            fail </P>
      </eventDesc>
      <correctiveAction>None</correctiveAction>
      <safetyConsequences>
         <P>All off-site electric transmission systems functioned as designed. An analysis of the
            response of plant equipment and protective systems concludes all safety related plant
            equipment and systems operated correctly for this condition. There were no safety system
            functional failures. There were no adverse effects on the health and safety of the
            public as a result of this event. </P>
      </safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>
         <P>There has not been any occurrence of an event or concfltion In the past three years at
            Columbia Generating Station involving the actuation of a ESF due to a grid disturbance.
         </P>
      </previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
