<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-05-21T09:23:25-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-05-21T09:23:25-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-05-21T09:23:25-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>&quot;'·
</P><P>. . 	<Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>Alex L Javorik </P><P>ColumbIa Gelwralilg Station</P><P>J </P><P>P.O. Box 988. PE04 </P><P>. ' .. </P><P>Richland, WA 89352.()888 Ph. fi09.377-85551 F. !iCJ9.377-2354</P><P>0 
aIjavorIkO~com 
</P><P>, 	May 1, 2013 G02-13-069 10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 
</P><P>Subject: 	COLUIIIIA GlHlRAnNO STATION, DOCKET NO. 10-. 
LICENSEe EVENT IIDOR1' NO. aotMO:MO 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Ucenaee Ewnt Report No. 2013-002&quot;()o tor Columbia Generating Station. This report Is submitted pwauantto 10CFR 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(9).. </P><P>There are no commitments being made to the NRC by this Jetter. If you have any questions or require additional information, please contact Ma. LL WHlIams at (509) 3n· 8148. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><Part><H1>Li)~101'-</H1><P>AL Javorik </P><P>Vice President, Engineering </P><P>Attachment: Licensee Event Repot12013-002-QO </P><P>00: NRC Region tV Administrator 
NRC NRR Project Manager 
NRC Senior Resident Inspectorl988C 
AJ Rapacz -BPAl1399 
WA Horin -Winston &amp;Strawn 
</P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>(10-2010) </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LEA) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </P><P>1, . FACILITY &quot;AME Columbia [iAINUAfI&quot;tn Station 4.11TLE </P><P>Main Control Room Cooler Failed Surveillance .. </P><P>04 estimated burden per mponse to comply tMth this mandatory collection request: 80 houfa. AepoJted IeIIona learned anJ Incorporated Into the licensing process and fed beck to Industry. StncI comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAIPrtvacy SectIon (ToS F53). U.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washington. DC 205550001. or by Internet e-mail to Infgcol!tda.rpoyrpe.nrc.ggy. and to the Desk OffIcer, Office of Information and Regulatory AffaIrs. NEOB-10202 (3150-0104). OffIce of Management and Budget. WllhlngD'I. DC 20503. &quot;a means I*Id to Impon en information colleCtIon doe. not dltplay a CUJnIDlIy valid OMS control number. the <Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>NRC not oonduc:t or eponlOl&quot;. and a peraon Is not I9qu1l'1d to respond to. the </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>NUIIIER </P><P>a.'AGE </P><P>1 OF3 0l0003I7 </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_05_01_ML13141A288_img_4.jpg"/>~~~~~~~~~~ o 20.2201 (b) [J 2O.2203(a)(3)(I) o 5O.73(I)(2)(I)(C) SO.73(a)(2)(vll) o 20.2201 (d) o 20.2203(1)(3)(11) o 5O.73(a)(2)(UXA) o 5O.73(a)(2)(vlll)(A) [] 20.2203 (a)(1) [] 20.2203(1)(4) [] 5O.73(&amp;)(2)(11)(B) [] 5O.73(a)(2)(vllI)(B) o 2O.2203(a)(2)(I) o 5O.36(c)(1)(I)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(1I1) [] 5O.73(a)(2)(Ix)(A) [J 20.2203(8)(2)(11) o 5O.38(c)(1)(II)(A) C 5O.73(I)(2)(iv)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(x) CAUSE SYSTEM CAUSE E VI [J YES (If COtnPilts 1S. EXPECTEDSI.IBMISSIONDATE) NO </Figure><P>o 2O.2203(a)(2)(11i) o 50.38(0)(2) [] 5O.73(a)(2Xv)(A) C 73.71(8)(4) [] 20.2203(a)(2)(Iv) C 5O.46(I)(3)(iI) [] 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(1)(5) [J 2O.2203(a)(2Xv) o 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER [] 20.2203(a)(2)(vl) 1m 5O.73(I)(2)(I)(B) C 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(D) SpecIfy In Abstract below </P><P>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, I.e., approximately 15 sJngItJ-.paced typewritten lines) In October 2012, It was determined that the Technical Specification (TS) surveillance procedure to verify that each control room air conditioning (AC) subsystem has the capability to remove the assumed heat load for TS Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.7.4.1 did not satisfy the surveiRance requirement. The methodology for the existing surveillance had been in use since 1998 around the time Energy Northwest converted to the Improved Technical Specifications. T8 SR 3.0.3 was Invoked and a new surveillance procedure was developed. On March 2, 2013, while perfonning the new surveillance procedure, the test results revealed that the air handler thermal performance for the MAn train did not meet the acceptance criteria. this failure to satisfy SR 3.7.4.1 in March. following entry Into SR 3.0.3, is reportable under 10 CFR 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(9) -Any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's technical specifications. </P><P>The control room AC subsystem has been cleaned, retested, and returned to operable status. </P><P>26158 R5 </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 388A (1 ()'2010) u.s. NUCLeAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LEA) ,CONTlNUAnON SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>0l000317 </TD><TD>YEAR .. LEA I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3.PMiE 20F3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 002 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRAnVE PLANT CONDInoNS At the time of event, the plant WIt operating'&quot; Mode 1 &quot;100% power. EVENT DESCRlP110N In October 2012, it was determined that the Technical Specification (TS) surveiHanoe procedure to verify that each control room air conditioning (AC) subsystem (VI) has the capabHtty to remove the assumed heat load for TS Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.7.4.1 did not satisfy the surveillance requirement. The methodology for the existing survelllance had been in use since 1998 around the time Energy Northwest converted to the Improved Technical Specifications. T8 SR 3.0.3 was Invoked. An informational test was perfonned on November 3,2012, indicating acceptable pelformance of the cooter lelR). A new surveillance procedure was developed and on March 2, 2013. whOe performing the new surveiHance, the test results revealed that the air handler thermal perfonnance for the &quot;Aft train did not meet the acceptance criteria. This faUure to satisfy'SR 3.7.4.1 in March, following entry into SR 3.0.3, is reportable under 10 eFA 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(8) -Any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's technical specifications. IMMEDIATE CORAEcnve ACTION • Addition of Hydrogen Pero)(ld&amp; to the service water spray ponds to kill biological material in the cooling water. • Cleaning and Inspection of the air Side of the cooling coils. • Cleaning. flushing and inspection of the water side of the cooling coits (CCl) • Adjustment of the water flow to balance coil flow and heat removal capacity. A finat performance of the test on March 21, 2013 demonstrated heat removal capacity significantly above the minimum acceptance criteria. CAUSE The direct cause was determined to be macro-fouling of the water side of the tubes. The presence of large anode deposits, due to degradation of the zinc sacrificial anode. and sediment In the tower tubes of the cooling coils were blocking flow. The apparent cause was tack of a periodic performance test. With no component specific periodic performance test specified timely identtflcation of degradation. and subsequent action to mitigate the degradation. was not possible to prevent component faUure. No routine surveiHance on this cooler had been performed for '16 years. . , Contributing to this failure was a lack of procedural guidance to balance flow through the cooling coils. The control room coolers are unique in that they are the only doubte coli coolers used for service water systems [Bll. There Is no flow indication for the individual COils. only the total flow. Thermal performance testing found that flow was not properly balanced between the coils. Another contributing cause was a general Increase in the sediment levels of the service water system. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158 RS </P><P>4 ' . ',. </P><P>NRC FORM 36IA u.s...-...~REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(1()'2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_05_01_ML13141A288_img_7.jpg"/>YEAR 05000317</Figure><P>Columbia Generating Station </P><P>3OF3 </P><P>2013 -002 -00 </P><P>NARRAnVE FURTHER CORRECTIVE ACnON </P><P>The surveillance procedure for the control room cooler wHi be scheduled and performed on a routine basis. </P><P>Develop periodic inspection, cleaning, and anode replacement plan for aft coolers. </P><P>ASSESSMENT OF SAFETY CONSEQUENCES </P><P>The main Control room has two divisions of air handling units, each with the capability to maintain temperatures within the required limits during accident conditions. The main control room air coolers are required to have a minimum efficiency of 65% to provide the required cooling for a design basis event. In November 2012, the measured effic4ency of the &quot;A&quot; train AC was 67% as obtained by a maintenance test. The measured efficiency for the &quot;A&quot; train AC in March 2013 was 62.6%. The &quot;8&quot; train AC efficiency was greater than 65%. The &quot;B&quot; train AC was fully capable of maintaining required control room temperatures. The &quot;A&quot; train AC was still capable of providing adequate cootlng for most situations. Since November 2012 the &quot;S&quot; train was not been available for service on three occasions each with an outage duration of less than 1 day. During these times the MA&quot; train would still have been capable of maintaining the control room within the required limits due to actual conditions being signlficantty less than design basis conditions (ambient temperature of 105°F and service water temperature of noF). </P><P>In addition to the coolers utiliZing service water, the main control room AC subsystem also has the capability to be aligned to emergency chillers (KMJ, which provide additional cooling capability. Each diviSion of the main control room air handier has two sets of coolers. One emergency cooler and one for normal HVAC. Both emergency coolers can be lined up to either servtce water or an emergency chiller, a clean ctosed-toop system. Typically, the flA&quot; train Is &quot;ned up to service water and the fiB&quot; train to an emergency chiller. </P><P>The safety significance of one main control room cooler having a slightly reduced efficiency was minimal. </P><P>SIMILAR EVENTS </P><P>A review of various databases at Columbia found no simHar issues of a component not being tested per surveillance. </P><P>ENERGY INDUSTRY IDENTIFICATION SYSTEM (EllS) INFORMA11ON CODEe </P><P>EUS COdes are twacketad 0...applicable in the narrative. </P><P>26158 RS </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>