<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>
      <P>When performing a logIc system functIonal test (LSFT) of the Remote Shutdown Panel transfer
         switch during refueling </P>

      <P>outage R21 on June 4, 2013, the procedure for testing the remote transfer switch for the
         suppression pool spray valve </P>

      <P>fal/ed because ajumper had been left Installed following a new bucket (breaker)
         Installation at the Motor Control Center during the previous refueling outage R20. A
         satisfactory LSFT was perfonned prior to the Installation of the new bucket into the MCC
         but this LSFT was not re-performed to verify the operability of the new bucket after
         installation. The problem went undetected until the R21 LSFT test failed. The remote
         transfer switch was inoperable from May 16, 2011 . until June 4, 2013 when the condltlon
         was discovered. This resulted In failure to meet Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.3.3.2.4
         and non-compliance with Technical Specifications (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation
         (LCO) 3.3.3.2. </P>

      <P>The preliminary apparent causes have been Identified as: (1) a lack of a standard for Work
         Order instructions Involving the removal and InstallatIon of jumpers, resulting In
         personnel having to rely on experience and skill ot the craft tor the proper way of
         executing and documenting required modifications; and (2) Inadequate decision making
         resulting In the use of a post maintenance testing procedure after the Installation of the
         Spectrum bucket in May 2011 that did not adequately prove operability. </P>
   </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>
         <P>The event was discovered June 4,2013 when a logic system functional test (LSFT) of the
            Suppression Pool Remote Transfer Switch (JS] failed. The plant was in Mode 5 during
            refueling outage R21 with the reactor mode switch In Refuel. </P>
      </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>
         <P>On 610412013, during performance of surveillance procedure on the control power transfer
            switch (JS] located in the Remote Shutdown Panel, a step to verify no continuity
            (contacts open) for the transfer switch for the suppression pool spray valve RHR-V-27B
            [ISV] failed. Failure of the surveillance was attributed to a jumper [57} Installed
            (as-found) in 480V Motor Control Center (MCC) starter controls contained In the new
            bucket. The jumper had been left in place since refueling outage R20 when the Spectrum
            bucket (breaker) was installed on May 16, 2011. The transfer switch was, therefore.
            Inoperable since the jumper was left in place, because Surveillance Requirement
            3.3.3.2.4 under Technical Specifications (TS) Umltlng Condition for Operation (LCO)
            3.3.3.2. The Remota Shutdown System Functions Shall Be Operable. would not have been met
            when in Modes 1 or 2. </P>
      </eventDesc>
      <correctiveAction>
         <P>The jumper was removed and the loosened terminals were torqued to restore bucket to
            design configuration. </P>
      </correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>
         <P>The Cause Evaluation Identified preliminary apparent causes of this event as follows:
            (1) a lack of a standard for Work Order Instructions Involving removal and installation
            of Jumpers. which requires personnel to rely on experience and .sklll of the craft for
            the proper way of executing and documenting required modifications; and (2) Inadequate
            decision making 'resulting in the use of a post maintenance testing procedure after the
            Installation of the Spectrum bucket In May 2011 that did not adequately prove
            operability. </P>
      </eventCause>
      <correctiveAction>
         <P>,Procedures will be revised to provide additional level of detail for work order steps
            Involving determination and termination 'of wires. cables and Jumpers. . </P>

         <P>'Additional corrective actions are being investigated that may result In additional
            proposed corrective measures. A supplement to this Licensee Event Report will be
            submitted If the final corrective action plan is substantively different than ·that
            Included In this form. </P>
      </correctiveAction>
      <safetyConsequences>
         <P>The remote transfer switch Is located at the Remote Shutdown Panel. The switch transfers
            control of the Division 2 suppression pool spray valve from the Main Control Room to the
            Remote Shutdown Panel and vice versa. The suppression pool spray valve Is used to
            provide cooling to the wetwelf portion of the primary containment as a means to control
            containment pressure during an accident. </P>

         <P>The jumpered terminals in the remote shutdown transfer switch did not impact the
            operation of the suppression pool spray valve from the Main Control Room. </P>

         <P>With the jumper left in place the operation of the suppression pool spray valve eould be
            impacted from the Remote ,Shutdown Panel because of loss of starter control power for
            valve RHA·V·278 under some abnormal scenarios (Le.• fire in the M~ln C~mtrol Room).
            which would require the replacement of a blown fuslS prIor to able to operate the valve
            operated from the Remote Shutdown Panel In the event of a fire In the Control Room.
            Therefore the safety significance of this failure Is low. </P>
      </safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>
         <P>There are several documented conditions with similar circumstances Involving Improper
            removal or Installation of jumpers. However. they were due to Improper placement or
            removal of Jumpers and did not Involve jumpers being laft in for an extended period of
            time. </P>
      </previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
