<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler when="2014-03-11" id="3972014002">
   <abstract>On March 11, 2014. with the plant operating in Mode 1 at 100 percent power, an extent
      of condition evaluation, resulting from a review of nuclear industry operational experience,
      Identified areas in the plant that may be susceptible to secondary fires due to hot shorts
      from unfused ammeters in the Direct Current distribution system. In the postulated event, a
      fire In the station cable raceway, cable spreading room, or Control Room could cause a ground
      loop through unprotected ammeter wiring or control circuit wiring and potentiafly result in
      excessive current flow and heating to the point of causing a secondary fire. The postulated
      secondary fire coufd affect the availability of equipment needed to place the plant in a safe
      shutdown condition. This scenario has not been analyzed in accordance with 10 CFR 50 Appendix
      R commitments. Compensatory hourly fire watch measures have been put in place and will remain
      in place for the affected areas of the plant until analyses are completed and modifications
      are put in place to eliminate the concern. The condition affects 14 Class 1E DC ammeters and 2
      non-Class 1E DC ammeters in 3 plant divisions. The cause of the unfused DC ammeter circuits Is
      that the original plant design did not include overcurrent protection features to isolate
      fault current In the current flow path from the shunts for each direct current battery or
      charger to the remote ammeter circuits In the Control Room. The corrective action plant
      modification will provide fuses to the unprotected ammeters.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <background>
         <P>Operational experience available from INPO on December 10, 2013 through report
            IER-l4-1354, &quot;Unprotected Direct Current Ammeters Result in Unanalyzed Conditions,b
            involved Control Room direct current (DC) ammeters [II] lacking overcurrent protection
            In their original plant wiring designs, which significantly degraded plant safety.
            Specifically, wiring designs for the DC ammeter circuits In the Control Room often
            included a shunt [17] in the current flow path from each DC battery [BTRY] or charger
            [BYC]. Overcurrent protective devices were not used to Isolate fault current in the
            ammeter wiring attached to the shunts at stations that reported this condition. A
            postulated fire in the station cable raceway, cable spreading room, or Control Room
            could cause an ammeter wire short to ground. If another DC wire from the opposite
            polarity on the same DC source shorted to ground, fault current would flow through the
            unprotected ammeter cable with the potential for overheating and initiating a secondary
            fire. Either the secondary fire or the ground condition could adversely affect safe
            shutdown equipment and hinder the ability of the plant to safely shut down as committed
            to 10 CFR 50 Appendix R. </P>
      </background>
      <plantConds>
         <P>The identification of specific applicability to Columbia of the unfused DC ammeters
            condition occurred on February 27,2014 after issuance of an extent of condition report;
            however, analysiS to determine impact to safety systems was not completed until March
            11, 2014. The NRC was notified through Event Notification 49898 on the same date, in
            accordance with 10 CFR 50.72(b)(3)(iI)(B) reporting requirements for the unanalyzed
            condition. The plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100 percent power. within design
            temperature and pressure conditions, and there were no structures, systems, or
            components that were inoperable at the start of the event and that contributed to the
            event. </P>
      </plantConds>
      <extentConds>
         <P>Plant wiring design drawings for the DC Electrical System ammeter circuits that utilize
            a shunt in the current flow path for each DC battery or charger were analyzed to
            determine affected components. </P>
         <P>The extent of condition analysis identified the following Columbia components that
            provide remote monitoring or Control Room Indication associated with 24 VDC. 125 VDC. or
            250 VDC circuits as being vulnerable to the condition: </P>
         <L>
            <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label> <LI_Title>Division 1: a total of six ammeters that provide
                  operator indication for associated battery or battery charger current output, and
                  remote monitoring of current flow. </LI_Title>
            </LI> <LI>
               <LI_Label>• </LI_Label> <LI_Title>Division 2: a total of six ammeters that provide
                  operator indication for associated battery or battery charger current output, and
                  remote monitoring of current flow. </LI_Title>
            </LI>
         </L> Division 3: a total of two ammeters that provide operator Indication for associated
         battery or battery charger current output, and remote monitoring of current flow. DC
         ammeter circuitry cables for two of the Division 2 ammeters are non-safety related feeding
         their corresponding non-safety related DC ammeter. All other DC ammeter circuitry
         divisional cables referenced above are safety-related in class 1 E raceways feeding their
         respective safety-related DC ammeters. Failures and Errors There were no safety system or
         safety component failures or errors resulting from this condition. </extentConds>
      <safetyResponses>The plant's safety systems that could have been affected by this condition
         have not experienced a condition-related abnormal response. The condition has not resulted
         in declarations of system inoperabilities at the plant. QausegfCK;vuence This condition
         occurred because the original plant wiring design did not include overcurrent protection
         features to isolate fault current in the current flow path from the shunts for each DC
         station battery and/or charger to the remote ammeter circuits in the Control Room. The
         postulated event requires two concurrent extremely low resistance (hard) grounds; one on
         the positive side of the battery through the ammeter circuit wiring routed to the Control
         Room and one on the negative side of the battery. Because this is a very low probability
         event, it was likely not considered in the original design.</safetyResponses>
      <safetyConsequences>The discovered condition is being reported under criterion in 10 CFR
         SO.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) -Any event or condition that results in the nuclear plant being In an
         unanalyzed condition that significantly degraded plant safety. There have been no actual
         adverse nuclear, radiological, or industrial safety consequences resulting from the
         reported condition. The administrative controls of the Fire Protection Program, the
         availability of fire detection and suppression systems, the established compensatory
         measures, and a trained on-site fire brigade all combine to mitigate the event postulated
         in the scenario until permanent corrective actions described below are
         Implemented.</safetyConsequences>
      <correctiveActions> Due to the complexity of the engineering review that is being conducted
         towards mitigation of this condition, a conservative decision was made to establish hourly
         fire tours for the fire areas of concern. Barrier Impairment measures have been implemented
         per established station procedures. In addition to the immediate compensatory action
         conSisting of hourly fire watches and establishment of barrier Impairments in the affected
         areas, an engineering change is being developed to modify the affected DC electrical
         circuits to comply with the commitments of 10 CFR 50 Appendix R. Specifically, the scope of
         the engineering change will modify the eXisting DC ammeter circuits to include fuses,
         credited as overcurrent protective devices, to ensure that the postulated fire scenario
         does not impact the plant safety systems. Ensuing corrective action implementation work
         orders will Include design changes, analysis updates, and physical work orders to bring
         affected DC circuits In full compliance with Columbia commitments t010 CFR 50 Appendix
         R.</correctiveActions>
      <previousEvents>Columbia has not experienced similar occurrences in the past, based on a
         review of LER historical records.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
