<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-10-23T11:53:55-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-10-23T11:53:55-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-10-23T11:53:55-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="O "><ImageData src="images/2014_10_09_ML14296A383_img_0.jpg"/>O </Figure>W. Grover Hettel </P><P>Columbia Genetating Station</P><P>.... ENERGY </P><P>P.O. Box 968. PE23 </P><P>Richland. WA 99352-0968</P><Part><H1>,~-.&quot;.,' NORTHWEST </H1><P>Ph. 509.3n.8311I F. 509.3n.4150 </P><P>wghettel@enetgy-nOI1hwes.com </P><P>October 9, 2014 </P><P>G02-14-146 </P><P>10CFR50.73 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><P>AnN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: COLUMBIA GENERAnNG STATION, DOCKET NO. 5O-3t7 </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2014-004040 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report.No. 2014-004-00 for Columbia Generating Station. This report Is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(8)(2)(1)(8). </P><P>There are no commitments being made to the NRC by this letter. If you have any questions or require adcfttional information, please contact Mr. J.R. Trautvetter, Regulatory Compliance Supervisor, at (509) 3n-4337. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><P>o.~ </P><P>W. G.Hettei Vice PreSident, Operations </P><P>Enclosure: Licensee Event Report 2014-004-00 </P><P>00: NRC Region IV Administrator NRC NRR Project Manager NRC Senior Resident Inspectorl988C MA Jones -8PAl1399 WA Horin -Winston &amp;Strawn </P><Table><TR><TH>NRCFORM3U U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (01-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each blOCk). </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 01/31112017 Estimated burden per response to COIIl'Iy with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are Incorpo!lIled into the licensing process end fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden esIlmBIe to !he FOIA, Privacy and Infonnation Collections Branch (T-5 F53), u.S. Nucleer Regulatoly Corrvnission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by Internet e-mail to InIocoIIec:ts.ResoureeOnre.gD\I, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informstion and Regulatory AffaIrs. NEOB-l0202 (3150-0104), ClIfIC8 01 Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. II a means used to IIT1IOS8 an InIormBlion collection does not display a currently valid OMS conITOI number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person Is not required to respond to, the fnformstlon ooIIection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 397 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE TS Surveillance 3.7.1.1 Compliance, UHS Spray Pond Level </TH></TR><TR><TH>S. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO, </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>08 </TH><TD>14 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 -004 -00 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>09 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>8. OPERAnNG MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMmED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR I: (Check.n thtJt apply) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2201 (b) </TD><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(3)(I) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(C) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(vll) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 2O.2201(d) </TD><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(3XII) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(aX2)(H)(A) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(vllI)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203 (a)(1) </TD><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(4) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(iI)(B) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(vlil)(B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(2)(I) </TD><TD>o 5O.36(c)(1)(I)(A) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(iiI) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(lx)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(2)(1I) </TD><TD>o 5O.36(c)(1)(iI)(A) </TD><TD>o SO.73(a)(2)(lv)(A) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(III) </TD><TD>o 5O.36(c)(2) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(A) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(4) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(1v) </TD><TD>o 5O.46(a)(3)(II) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(5) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(2)(v) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(A) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) </TD><TD>o OTHER </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(2)(vI) </TD><TD>181 5O.73(a)(2)(1)(B) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(D) </TD><TD>Specify In Abstract below or In NRC Form 386A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOA THIS LEA ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include AIN Code)</TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Des!&quot; Wotfgrarnm 509-3n-4792 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONeNT FAILURE DESCRIBeD IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU· FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABlE TOEPIX </TD><TD/><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TOEPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMeNTAL RE IORT ~&quot;II:U o YES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 1m NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECT! ~ I MONTH I DAY SUBMISSION I lDATE </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Umlt to 1400 spaces, I.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On August 14, 2014 it was discovered that Columbia Generating Station's (Columbia) method of complying with Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.7.1.1 for Ultimate Heat Sink (UHS) spray pond level was inadequate. The SR requires level in each spray pond to be verified to be greater than or equal to the minimum water level whereas procedures allowed for an arithmetic average of the two ponds to be taken when a single Service Water (SW) pump is in operation which creates a differential between the pond levels. The two spray ponds that make up Columbia's UHS are connected by a siphon line to allow water to be shared between the two ponds. Columbia's original TS did not specify that a minimum water level be checked in each pond and a procedural note was added to clarify compliance with the TS SR during single SW pump operation. When Columbia upgraded the TSs in 1997 the word 'each' was introduced to the TS. Corrective actions inclu.cIe a TS amendment submitted to the NRC on August 22, 2014. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158 R6 NRC Fonn 368 (01-2014) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3160-0104 EXPIRES: 01/3112017 </P><P>(OH014) </P><P>Eslimated burden per respI)/1S8 10 comply witll tI!is mandatOl)' collection request: 80 IIours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing proceas and led back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information CoUections Branch (T-Ii FS3), U.S. Nuclear RegulalOl)' Commission, Washington, DC 20565-000t, or by internet e-mail to InIocoIJects.ResourceOnrc.gov, and \0 the Desk Officer, Office 01 Information </P><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </P><P>CONTINUAnON SHEET </P><P>and RegufatOl)' Affairs, NEOB·I0202, (315().OI04), Office of Management and Budget, Wash/r9DR. DC 20500. Ha means tBed fo Impose an inlomlalion coIIedion does not display a curranIIy valid OMS conIIOl number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not requled to respond 10, the information collection. </P><P>1. FACILITYNAME </P><P>6. LER NUMBER </P><P>3. PAGE</P><P>2. DOCKET </P><P>Columbia Generating Station </P><P>YEAR ISe:u~AL I REV </P><P>NO. </P><P>2 OF</P><P>05000 397 </P><P>2014 -004 -00 </P><P>NARRAnVE </P><P>Plant Conditions 
At the time of the event the plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. This event documents an 
administrative issue with TS compliance, therefore no structures, systems, or components were inoperable 
that contributed to this event. 
</P><P>Event Description 
On August 14. 2014 It was discovered that Columbia Generating Station's (Columbia) method of complying 
with Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.7.1.1 for Ultimate Heat Sink (UHS) [as) 
spray pond level was Inadequate. 
</P><P>Columbia's UHS consists of two concrete spray ponds. These spray ponds provide suction and discharge points for the redundant pumping and spray facilities of the Service Water (SW) [BI) system. SW loop A draws water from pond A and discharges through a spray ring into pond afor heat diSSipation. Similarly. SW loop a draws water from pond B and discharges through a spray ring into pond A. The water then retums to the initial pond through a siphon line. During operation with one SW pump running, a differential level develops between the ponds until flow through the siphon line equalizes with the running SW pump. The spray ponds remain with this differential level until the running pump is stopped and flow through the siphon line equalizes the spray pond levels. The ponds were licensed such that the combined water volume of the spray ponds is adequate to provide cooling water for 30 days of operation. assuming maximum evaporation and drift losses. </P><P>Prior to implementation of improved TS (ITS) in June of 1997. there were separate TS for 5W and UH5. The UH5 T5 contained a SR to verify the UH8 water level was within its limit of 432 ft 9 inches mean sea level at a frequency of 24 hours. The operations surveillance procedure contained a note to take an arithmetic average of the spray pond levels if only one loop of SW was in operation. In March 1997, Columbia received license amendment 149 for ITS with a full Implementation date of June 30. 1997. The ITS combined-the 8W and UHS into one TS. The UHS water level surveillance requirement was changed to require the level in ~spray pond to be within the limit of 432 ft 9 inches. Due to the design of the spray ponds and 8W system. it is difficult to meet this requirement in each pond when only one SW pump is In operation. </P><P>This discrepancy between the new T5 SR and how it is implemented in operations surveillance procedures was identified in 1997 and license document changes were initiated to change the TS SR and the T8 Bases to allow for an arithmetic average of the two ponds when a single pump is in operation. The T8 Bases change was processed; however the T8 SA change was not completed. The reason why the TS SR wasn't completed and submitted to the NRC for approval Is undocumented and unknown. </P><Sect><H2>Cau8e </H2><P>The cause of this event is that although it was recognized In 1997 that Columbia was out of verbatim compliance with TS SA 3.7.1.1. Columbia's licensing document change process in 1997 allowed for changes to the TS SA and T8 Bases to be processed separately. This allowed the TS Bases change to be implemented while the TS SR change was never completed or approved by the NRC. </P><P>26158A R3 NRC FORM 366A (01-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 3&amp;6A (01-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TD>05000 397 </TD><TD>YEAR r SEQUENTIAl r REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 004 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARAAnVE Extent of Condition An extent of condition review determined that there have been multiple Instances when SW would need to be declared inoperable based on spray pond level as it is common practice to operate individual service water pumps based on plant needs. The 12 hour Limiting Conditions for Operation per TS 3.7.1 was exceeded on August 13, 2014 with additional occurrences since implementation of the ITS on June 30, 1997. Immediate Corrective Action Once it was discovered that the operations procedure was not compliant with the T8 SR all oncoming operations crews were briefed on the correct implementation of the TS SR. Guidance was also given to start both SW pumps if one is required to run. The operations surveillance procedure was also updated to remove the wording which allowed for the arithmetic average of the two ponds when a single pump is in operation. Columbia has submitted a TS change to the NRC to allow verification that the average water level in the UHS spray ponds is within the limit. The licensing change process is being updated to ensure processing of TS SR changes with TS Bases changes if related. Operating Experience &amp; Previous Occurrencea No previous occurrences have been found to have the same cause of a license amendment change not processed. One event reported under LER-12-004-02 was a failure to enter a TS action statement due to conflicting information between the associated TS Bases and the surveiHance procedure. Corrective actions focused on operability determinations for equipment removed from service. It also included a focused selfassessment to review TS Bases and TS SRs. The self-assessment did not Identify the discrepancy described in this LER, and therefore a re-review of the wor1&lt; performed by this individual Is being completed to ensure no other discrepancies between T8 SR, T8 Bases and Implementing procedures exist. Further Corrective Actlona A review of all TS Bases amendments was conducted to identify whether any other Licensing Document Changes were issued that introduced conflicts with the literal wording in the T8. Asaeaament of Sefety Consequencea There were no actual safety consequences associated with this event as during periods of SW single loop operation when one pond level was below TS minimum the actual inventory of the UHS was unaffected. The combined Inventory between the two ponds remained above the licensed amount required to provide adequate cooling for 30 days of operation. Energy Induatry identification Syatem (EllS) Information Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) Information codes from IEEE Standards 805-1984 and 803-1983 are represented In brackets as [XX] and [XXX] throughout the body of the narrative. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158A R3 NRC FORM 368A (01-2014) </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>