<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract> On March 12. 2014, it was Identified that three manhole covers (E10, E11, and E 15)
      for vaults containing 4160 vott electric cables were missing the hold down bolts. The hold
      down bolts are required as part of the tornado missile barrier for the manhole cover for the
      underground electric vault. It was later determined that the hold down bolts for manhole cover
      E11 (Division 2 Service Water) had been identified as missing since September 6, 2013. When
      the bolts were identified as missing on September 6. 2013. the manhole cover and bolts were
      not recognized as a tornado missile barrier: because this information was not availabfe in
      routinely used databases and procedures. No Compensatory action was taken until March 12,2014.
      when large concrete blocks were placed on top of the manholes to prevent the covers from
      potential removal In the event of a tornado. The degraded miSsile barrier is considered to
      have rendered the Division 2 Service Water system Inoperable from September 6. 2013. to March
      12. 2014. This Is reportable as a condition prohibited by Technical SpecIfIcations.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>Columbia was operating at 100% power. There were no Inoperable plant systems at
         the time of discovery that contributed to this event.</plantConds>
      <eventDescription>On March 12. 2014, it was identified that three manhole covers (E10, E11,
         and E 15) for vautts containing 4160 volt electric cables [Cell were missing the hold down
         botts. The electric cables in vautts E10 and E11 support the Division 2 Service Water [BI}
         system. The electric cables in vaults E15 support the Division 3 Service Water system. The
         hold down bofts are required as part of the tornado missile barrier for the manhole cover
         for the underground electric vault. It was later determined that the hold down bofts for
         manhole cover E11 (Division 2 Service Water) had been Identified as missing in two
         condition reports on September 6. 2013. and again on December 3, 2013. When Operations
         performed an immediate operability determination for the September and December 2013
         condition reports, the manhofe cover and bofts were not recognized as a tornado missile
         barrier; therefore. no compensatory actton was taken until March 12, 2014. The degraded
         missile barrier is considered to have rendered the Division 2 Service Water system
         Inoperable from September 6,2013. to March 12,2014. This is reportable as a condition
         prohibited by Technical Specifications.</eventDescription>
      <correctiveAction>It was verified through the Weather Service that no tornados were predicted
         for our area In the next 24 hours. Large concrete blocks were placed over the manhole
         covers on March 12. 2014. to prevent the cover from lifting In the event of a tornado. The
         Information fields in the master equipment list for the applicable manhole covers were
         completed Identifying them as a tornado missile barrier.</correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>The Information In this section Is based on the preliminary results of a root
         cause evaluation. If any significant changes In the cause or corrective actions are rna'in
         the final evaluation, a suppJement will be submitted for this report. The direct cause for
         the missing hold down bolts was not determined. The root cause of the faHure to recognize
         the manhole cover as a tornado barrier was that station procedures that Implement the
         process to establish quality classifications for safety-retated systems. structures. and
         components (SSCs) did not ensure accurate Information was available In a timely manner for
         these components. There are multiple methods available for determining the safety
         significance of a degraded component; however, the computerized master equipment list is
         typically the preferred method. The equipment plant numbers (EPNs) for the manhole covers
         had been entered into master equipment list in 2012. but no action was taken to complete
         the remaining data fields for the components to identify that the manhole covers fulfHled a
         tornado barrier function, and have the information verified and approved. The master
         equipment list that station personnel used identified these manhole covers as
         nonsafety-retated. In the immediate operability determination process for the two Condition
         Reports in 2013, Operations personnel did not have information readity available to them to
         determine that the manhole cover was a tornado missile barrier. Most plant personnel,
         including Operations, did not recognize that the information In the computer master
         equipment list for the manhole covers was not at an approved status and should not be used.
         The manhole covers did not have any label indicating that It was a tornado missile barrier.
         Plant drawings did not identify the manhole covers 88 tornado missile barriers.
         Additionally, the station barrier Impairment procedure did not list the manhole covers as a
         tornado missile barrier.</eventCause>
      <correctiveAction>Work requests were inmated to repair/replace the missing bolts for the
         manhole covers. Revise Engineering procedures to provide clear direction to establISh
         Quality Classifications for safety-related SSCs within the Master Equipment List within a
         specific time frame. Ensure that procedures Include timeliness requirements for
         establishing and upgrading/downgrading EPNs for Installed plant equipment. Appfy a marking
         on the manhole covers that identify these covers as a tornado missile barrier. Revise the
         station barrier Impairment procedure to identify manhole covers as a tornado missile
         barrier.</correctiveAction>
      <safetyConsequences>No actual tornados occurred during the time of interest. The Division 2
         Service Water system remained capable of fulfilling its safety function during this time
         period. AdditionaUy. at least one other division of Service Water was available during this
         time period (September 6,2013 to March 12, 2014) to be abfe to fulfill the safety function;
         therefore, the actual safety consequence of this Issue was minimal.</safetyConsequences>
      <previousEvents>There have been no similar events at Columbia Generating Station In the last
         three years.</previousEvents>
   </narrative>
</ler>
