<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
<abstract>On August 25, 2013 at 1818 hours secondary containment was dactared Inoperable during a
            suddenly occurring thunderstorm. Secondary containment pressure was not maintained
            greater than or equal to 0.25 inches of vacuum water gauge as required by Technical
            SpecIfication 3.6.4.1. This condition was experienced for a period of no greater than
            160 seconds. Operations took manual control of the system and quickly adjusted Reactor
            Building Exhaust Air flow to restore secondary containment to less than ...().25 Inches
            water gauge. While Technical Specification limits were exceeded, the resulting pressure
            excursion was bounded by analytical results, and thus there were no safety consequences
            for this event. The cause for the event was determined to be failure of the Reactor
            Exhaust AirlReactor Outside Air system to automatically maintain a stabilized negative
            differential pressure in the Reactor Building at the controller setpolnt value of -0.6
            Inches water gauge due to less than optimal control system tuning for the system.
            Corrective actions include determining, Implementing, and documenting the optimum
            control system tuning for the system, increasing margin by lowering differential
            pressure set point, and alerting operations before the Technical SpeCification limit for
            secondary containment pressure is reached.</abstract>
      <narrative>
         <plantConds>At the time of event, the plant was operating In Mode 1 at
            100% power. There were no structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the
            start of the event that contributed to the event. Event Deacrlptlon . . On August
            25,2013 at 1818 hours, during a suddenly occumngthunderstonn, the secondary containment
            [NH] pressure was not maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 Inches of vacuum water
            gauge. This condition existed for a period of no greater. than 160 seconds. Because
            Reactor Building [NG) pressure Increased above ..Q.25 Inches of water gauge (Inwg)
            secondary containment was logged as inoperable In the survell!ance Iog~nd TeChnical
            Specification 3.6.4.1 Action A was entered. </plantConds>
            <extentCond>This condition of
            Reactor Building differential pressure momentarily rising above the prescribed limit Is
            speclflc to the Reactor Building Heating Ventilation and Air Cootlng (HVAC) (VA) and
            Standby Gas Treatment (SGT) IBH) systems, and their capability to estabJish and maintain
            secondary COnfalnment·vacuum. No other systems are affected as a result of this
            condition. Immediate Corrective ActIon Operations took manual control of the Reactor
            Exhaust AIr (REA) differential pressure (dP) controller [POe) and quickly adjusted
            Reactor Building Exhaust AIr flow to restore secondary containment pressure to less than
            -0.25 inwg. Later, after the storm had passed, operators placed the controller back in
            automatic.</extentCond> 
            <eventCause>During normal plant operation. the non-safety related Reactor Building
            HVAC system maintains environmental conditions within the Reactor Building at a vacuum
            with respect to the outside. The cause of secondary containment not being maintained
            greater than or equal to -0.25 Inwg was due to Improper tuning of the Reactor Building
            Outside Air (ROA) differential pressure controller. The transient response of the
            controller was not properly tuned to compensate for sudden pressure changes that are
            expected during operation of the pressure control system.</eventCause> 
            <previousEvent>A loss of the ability to maintain secondary containment below the
            required negative pressure has occurred at Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) twice
            In the past two years. On July 24, 2012, reported under LER 2012..Q03-OO, secondary
            containment was compromised due to an inadvertent trip of one set of the redundant
            Reactor Building HVAC fans, during ongoing maintenance on the SGT system. The second
            Instance occurred on December 10, 2011, reported under LER 2011..()()4..()(). Secondary
            containment was declared inoperable and the cause was determined to be ice buildup and
            subsequent release on exterior equipment supplying the Reactor Building HVAC system.
            Each of these events have associated corrective actions and the causes are not
            applicable to the current cause of weather related pressure excursion, nor would
            corrective actions from these past events prevented occurrence of this event.</previousEvent>
         
         <correctiveActions>The potential for these momentary pressure
            excursions will continue to occur as there has been no change In the deSign of the
            equipment. To minimiZe recurrence actions are being taken to update the current
            calibration procedures to reflect the optimum control system tuning for the REAfROA
            system, and increasing margin In secondary containment by lowering the differential
            pressure set point on the REA controllers. Columbia is also investigating methods to
            alert operations to a potential Issue with secondary containment before the Technical
            Specification secondary containment pressure is reached.</correctiveActions> 
            
            <safetyConsequences>This event resulted In an unplanned entry Into LeO 3.6.4.1,A. Secondary
            containment pressure was above -0.25 inwg for no more than 160 seconds. The peak
            pressure during this event was -0.03 tnwg. While the actual pressure was beyond the
            range allowed by Technical Specifications, the purpose of matntalnlng a slight vacuum Is
            to assist In drawdown of secondary containment to support accident response of the
            safety related SGT system. existing engineering analysis demonstrates that for this
            event, the drawdown credited In accident response could have been attained using either
            of the two available trains of the SGT system, thus there were no potential safety
            consequences. There was no actual safety consequence associated with this event since no
            event Involving radiological hazards were experienced during the event. Energy Industry
            identification System (EllS) Information Energy Industry Identification System (EllS)
            Infonnatlon codes from IEEE Standards 805-1984 and 803-1983 are represented in braCkets
            as [XX} and (XXX) throughout the body of the narrative.</safetyConsequences>
      </narrative>
</ler>