<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-06-10T09:36:40-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-06-10T09:36:40-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-06-10T09:36:40-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>Alex L Javorik ColumbIa GeneratIng Station </P><P>P.O. Box 968, PE04 RIchland, WA 99:152-0968</P><P>C)B'fA&quot;WEST Ph. 509.3n.8555 1F. 509.3n.4150 </P><P>a1javorikOenergy-northweslcom </P><P>May 29,2014 </P><P>10CFR50.73</P><P>G02-14-092 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 
</P><P>. Subject: 	CQLUMBIA GENERA~.IGSTATION, DOCKET NO. 50-387 UCENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2014-001-01 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Revision 1to liCensee Event Report No. 2014-001 for Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR SO.73(a)(2)(v)(C), and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O). </P><P>There are no commitments being made to the NRC by this letter. If you have any 
questions or require additional information, please contact Mr. J.R. Trautvetter, 
Regulatory Co~pliance Supervisor, a1t (509) 3n-4337. 
</P><P>Respectfully, </P><P>A. L. Javo k 
Vice PreSident, Engineering 
</P><P>Attachment: 	Licensee Event Report 2014-001-01 </P><P>00: NRC Region IV Administrator 
NRC NRR Project Manager 
NRC Senior Resident Inspector/9SSC 
MA Jones -BPAl1399 
WA Horin -Winston &amp;Strawn 
</P><P>I ... </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 388 U.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY. COUMISSION (01-2014) . . LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) . (see P.2for required nUmber of . d/gltslcharacle!Sfor each block). </TH><TH>APPROVED BV OMB: NO. 31500010. EXPIRES 011S1112017 Esttmatad burden per raspanae to comply with IIIla mandalllly coJIec:IIon requaat: 80 hours. Reported Iesaona Ieemed 818 IncaIporatled Into die licensing procIlSIlII1CI fed bIJdc to 1ndusIIy . Send comtnen1a l8Q8Idlng bunIen IIIIImaIe to die FOIA, PrIv8cy MIl InfonTIdon CoUectlona Bnmch (T.a F53), u.s. Nuclear Regu/atDly CommIIIIon, WaIIdngton. DC 2055500001. 01 by 1nt.meC 8'IIIIII1D~.RIDdle DeIIk 0IIIcer. 0tIIce tIIlnIDrmaton and ReguIatoIy AII'In. NEOB-10102 (31Il0-0104), 0IIIce til Managemanlllld Budget. VIaNngIDn. DC 20503. II • _ used to Irnpo8e an InfannaIIan caIIedIon ca. nat dIpIay • cumJIIIIy vdd OMS contiDI number. die NRC may nat canducI fill 1IJOftIfIIr. lind II peI'IOII .. nol requInId to reIpond to. I18Inranna11on CDIIecIIan. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACIUTV NAME Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 397 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>... TITLE secondary Containment Pressure Exceeded ... </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>8. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>.. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREVNUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>01 </TH><TD>09 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 -001 -01 </TD><TD>OS </TD><TD>l.'i </TD><TD>J.D\4 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>t. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THI8 REPORT IS IUIIMITT!:D PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR I: (ChecIr all &quot;,.t IIpply) </TD></TR><TR><TD>Cl 2O.2201(b) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(8)(3)(1) </TD><TD>Cl 5O.73(a)(2)(IXC) </TD><TD>Cl 50.73(aX2}(vli) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2201(d) </TD><TD>[J 2O.2203(a)(3)(1I) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(1I)(A) </TD><TD>CJ 5O.73(a)(2)(vlH)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203 (8)(1) </TD><TD>[J 2O.2203(a)(4) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(1I)(8) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(vlll)(B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>CI 20.2203(8)(2)(1) </TD><TD>[J 5O.36(cX1)(I)(A) </TD><TD>CI 5O.73(a)(2)(ilI) </TD><TD>C] 5O.73(a)(2)(Jx)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH><TD>o 2O'2203(a)(2)(11) </TD><TD>o 5O.36(c)(1)(Ii)(A) </TD><TD>CJ 5O.73(a)(2)(Iv)(A) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(1II) </TD><TD>o 5O.36(c)(2) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(A) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(4} </TD></TR><TR><TD>Cl 2O.2203(a)(2)(Iv) </TD><TD>o 5O.46(a)(3)(1I) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(5) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 2O.2203(a)(2)(v) </TD><TD>[J 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(A) </TD><TD>181 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) </TD><TD>o OTHER </TD></TR><TR><TD>CJ 20.2203(a)(2)(vl) </TD><TD>o 5O.73(a)(2)(1)(B) </TD><TD>181 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(D) </TD><TD>Spedfy In AbsIract below or In NRC Fonn 368A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT fOR THIS LEA </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACIUTY NAME tTELEPHONE NUMBER (Include AnIa COde) DesIree Wolfgramm. Senior Licensing Engineer 509-377-4792 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THt8 REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU. FACrURER </TD><TD>RE!~!.~ iOEPIX </TD><TD/><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TOEPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>1.. SUPPLEMENTAL &quot;exPl:CTED aVES (ffyes. complete 16. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) IS NO </TH><TD>15.~~ED I MONTH I DAY SUBMI8S1ON I IDATE </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces, I.e., spproxlmately 16 slng/8-8Peced typewritten lines) On January 9,2014 at 1743 and 1834 hours secondary containment was declared inoperable during repositioning of the dampers. These two events had durations of 3 and 2 minutes respectively. Control Room operators took manual control of the Reactor Building Exhaust Air flow system to restore secondary containment in the first event, and the controller restored pressure automatically In the second.. On January 15, 2014 at 0907 hours and February 1jr, 2014 at 0304 hours secondary containment was declared Inoperable during repositioning of the dampers and during high winds respectively. These two events had durations of 6 and 2 minutes respectively. The system controller automatically restored secondary containment differential preSSUre in both events. In each of these events secondary containment vacuum was not maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 Inches of vacuum water gauge as required by Technical Specification 3.6.4.1, due to less than optimal control system tuning for the system. Corrective actions Include determining, Implementing, and documenting the optimum control system tuning for the system, Increasing margin by lowering d/fferentferl pressure set point, and alerting operations before the Technical Specification limit for secondary containment pressure Is reached. </TH></TR></Table><P><Figure ActualText=", "><ImageData src="images/2014_05_29_ML14161A144_img_0.jpg"/>, </Figure>·</P><P>'. </P><P>APPROVED BY OM.: NO. 311100010. EXPIRES: 01131J2017</P><P>NRC FORM 368A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION</P><P>..----------------------------------..------------------------------~ 
</P><P>(01-2014) </P><P>EaIinalBd burden per IISIJIIIII8 to conw wHIt this ITIIIIdatDry ooIec:IiDn request 80 hoIn. </P><P>Reported IIlsaons IeImed are IncorporaIId IntD tile licensing procea end tad back 10 1ndusIIy. Send CDIIIIlIII18 I8gfftIIng ludell edmata to Ute FOIA, Privacy and InbInelion CoAedIane IInn:h (T-6 F53). U.S. NudIar ReguIIIDry CGnvniIIIon. WIIhIngIon, DC 2.QIl55.OOO1, or by ~Hllllto InIacoIlec.ts.RasouraIOnrc.IJCI'I, and to the Desk 0IIIc:er, 0fIIce d Infonnallon </P><P>UCENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </P><P>CONTINUATION SHEET </P><P>and Regulatory AIratrs, NE08-102l12, (3150-0104), 0IIce d Management and Budget, ~DC 2IJ503. If ameana Illl8ClIo ....an ~CDfIec:fon dolll not cIiIpIay a QIIIWIItIy VIIId OMS controIlIUlIk, the NRC may not condutt or sponsor, and • perEGI1ls nol requIrIId 10 IIIjIOIId to. the Informalon caRecIIon. </P><P>t •.FACILI1Y NAME </P><P>8. LER NUM8&amp;R </P><P>3. PAGE</P><P>2,DOCKET </P><P>C~um~aG..~ngSmU~ </P><P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>2' OF</P><P>05'GOO 397 </P><P>2014 -001 -01 </P><P>~ARRAT1VE </P><P>Plant Conditions </P><P>Event 1: January 9, 2014 at 1743 hours 
E~ent 2: January.9,.2014 at 1834 hours 
Event 3: January 15, 2014 at 0907 hours 
Event 4: February 17. 2014 at 0304 hours 
</P><P>At the tlma of all events. the plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. There were no structures, systems, or 
components that were Inoperable at the start of any of the events that contributed to. the events. 
</P><P>Event Description </P><P>Events 1 &amp;2-</P><P>On January 9, 2014 at 1743 and 1834 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained while Reactor Building Outside Air (ROA) heating coil face and bypass dampers ware repositioning due to outside ambient temperature fluctuation past the set point. These dampers and heating coli allow for outside air to be heated as it enters the system. These two events had durations of 3 and 2 minutes respectively. In Event 1 control room operators took manual control of the Reactor Building Exhaust Air (REA) flow In-service differential pressure controller (OPIC) (REA-OPIC-1A) to restore secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 inches of vacuum water gauge. In Event 2 th, REA in-service controller (REA-OPIC-1A) automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 Inches watl9r gauge (Inwg). </P><P>Event 3-</P><P>On January 15, 2014 at 0907 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained while the ROA heating coli face and bypass dampers ware repositioning due to outside ambient temperature fluctuation past the set point. This event had duration of 6 minutes. In this event the REA in-seMce controller (REA-OPIC-1A) automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 inwg.. </P><P>Event 4-</P><P>On February 17, 2014 at 0304 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained during a period of high winds. 
This event had duration of 2 minutes. In this event the REA in-service controller (REA-OPIC-1B) automatically restored 
secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25Inwg. 
</P><P>fn each event described above, because Reactor Building [NG} vacuum decreased below 0.25 inches of water gauge, secondary containment was logged as Inoperable In the surveillance log and Technical Specification 3.6.4.1 Action A was enterad. </P><P>Extent of Condition </P><P>This condition of Reactor Building vacuum momentarily dropping below the prescribed limit is specific to the Reactor 
Building Heating Ventilation and Air Cooling (HVAC) [VA] and Standby Gas Treatment (SGT) [BH1 systems, and their 
capability to establish and maintain secondary containment vacuum. No other systems were affected as a result of this 
condition. 
</P><P>• 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 3I6A (0140&quot;, UCENSEE I:-vENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>'.LERNUMBER </TD><TD>3.PACJE </TD></TR><TR><TD>05000 397 </TD><TD>YEAR I se::::a-l:i 2014 001 -01 </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRAllVE During an extent of conditiOn review performed to datermJne past operability, it was determined that there were multiple instances where secondary containment vacuum was less than the TS required value of 0.25 Inwg. In these Instances secondary containment vacuum went below the TS required value of 0.25 Inwg and went unnoticed by operators as the annunciator alarm comes In at 0.0 inwg. This alann value has been identified as Incorrect to alert operators to secondary containment vacuum below the TS required value 0&quot;0.25 inwg and the condition has been documented in the comlctive action process to be aligned with the TS value of 0.25Inwg. In each of these events the REA In-service controtler automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25Inwg. Immediate Corrective ActIon In Event 1 Operators took manuaf control of the REA differential pressure (dP) controUer [PDC) and quickly adjusted REA flow to restore S8C0~arycontainment vacuum to greater than 0.25 Inwg. In Events 2, 3, and 4 the REA flow In-servlce controller automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 Inwg. Cause In accordance with NUREG-1022 Revision 3 Section 2.3 theSe four events are being reported together as these have all occurred in the 80 day LER reporting period and appear to have similar cause(s) for each event. Events 1 &amp; 2 ware reported together as they were related and occulT8d within an hour of each other. Events 3 and 4 were reported under indMdual ENS notifications. Secondary vacuum dropping below the TS required value of 0.251nwg happened in four separate events in this LER reporting period. All four of these events were similar in that an extemal weather related event, three temperature related transients and one wind related transient, occurred that required the exhaust ventilation fan to adjust its flow to maintain a vacuum above the TS required value of 0.25 inwg. The cause of secondary containment vacuum not being maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 inwg was due to improper tuning of the Reactor Building Outside Air (ROA) differential pressure controUers. The transient response of the controtlers were not properly tuned to compensate for sudden pressure changes that are expected during operation of the pressure control system. Operating experience &amp; Previous Occurrences A loss of the ability to maintain secondary containment vacuum greater than required has occurred and was reported at Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) three times In the past two years. On August 25,2013, reported undar LER 2013-007-00, secondary containment was declared Inoperable during 8l sudden thunderstonn when secondary containment vacuum was not maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 inwg. On July 24, 2012, reported under LER 2012-003-00, secondary containment vacuum was not maintained due to an inadvertent trip of one set of the redundant Reactor Building HVAC fans (FAN), during ongoing maintenance on the SGT system. On December 10, 2011, reported under LER 2011-004-00, secondary containment vacuum was not maintained and the cause was determined to be lca buildup and subsequent release on exterior equipment supplying the Reactor Bui/ding HVAC system. The first Operating Experience (OE) event Is similar in cause as the four events reported in this LER. Due to the single occurrence and the extreme weather conditions at the time, multfple causal factors were not considered. A corrective action which could have prevented recurrence of this event, to alert operations to a potential issue with secondary containment before the Technical Specification, LCO 3.S.4.1.A, for secondary containment vacuum is reached, was in </TH></TR></Table><P>t' </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 388A (010201~ LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONnNUAnON SHEET U.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMl8SlON </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>I. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TD>01000 397 </TD><TD>YEAR 1s:u,;::-J~ 2014 001 -01 </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE progress at the time of the four events ntported In this LER. The last two OE events have associated corrective actions, and the causes are not applicable to the current cause of weather related secondary containment vacuum changes, nor would corrective actions from these past two events prevented occurrence of these four events reported In this LER. As discussed In the Reactor Oversight Process wortdng group public meeting hetd on January 16, 2014 the Industry has experienced an Increase in ntports of safety system functional failures (SSFF) in where there Is not a true loss of safety function, but momentary conditions In which Technical Specification operability criteria ant not satisfied. Specifically temporary losses of secondary containment vacuum have Increased In the Industry. The four events described In this LER fall Into this Increase in number of reports. Further Corrective ActIons The potential for these momentary pressure excursions will continue to occur as there has been no change In the design of the equlpmenl To minimize ntCUrrence actions are being taken to update the current calibration procedures to reflect the optimum control system tuning for the REAlROA system, and incntaslng margin In secondary containment by lowering the differential pressure set point on the REA controllers. Columbia Is also investigating methods to alert operations to a potential Issue with secondary containment before the Technical Specification secondary containment pressure Is reached. M ....ment of Safety Consequencu This event resulted in an unptanned entry Into LCO 3.6.4.1.A. Secondary containment vacuum was less than 0.26 Inwg for between 2 and 6 minutes. While the actual vacuum was beyond the range allowed by Technical Specifications, the Reactor Building HVAC system Is designed to, amolr'lg other things; maintain the ntactor building during normal operating at a negative pressure with respect to atmosphere to minimize the release of airborne radioactive material. During emergency operation, the SGT system maintains the reactor building at a negative pntssure. Ourlng each of the events described in this LER at least one train of SGT was In standby condition and available to ntstore the reactor building to a vacuum above the TS required value of O.25Inwg. An engineering safety function analysis was performed which demonstrated that the ability for SGT to achieve secondary containment vacuum to above O.25Inwg, credited In the accident ntSpOR88 analysis, could have been attained using either of the two available trains of the SGT system at the time of each of the events, thus there were no potential safety consequences. There was no actual safety consequence associated with this event since no event Involving radiological hazards were experienced during the event. NEI 99-02 allows the licensee to perform an engineering analysis to determine if the event is reportable as a SSFF performance Indicator occurrence. The engineering analysis has shown that these events did not result In a SSFF; therefont this event does not affect the NRC Regulatory Oversight Process Indicators. Energy Industry identification System (EllS) Information Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) Information codes from IEEE Standards 806-1984 and 803-1983 are represented In brackets as [XX] and (XXX] throughout the body of the narrative. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>