<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler when="2014-01-09" id="3972014001">
   <abstract>On January 9,2014 at 1743 and 1834 hours secondary containment was declared inoperable
            during repositioning of the dampers. These two events had durations of 3 and 2 minutes
            respectively. Control Room operators took manual control of the Reactor Building Exhaust
            Air flow system to restore secondary containment in the first event, and the controller
            restored pressure automatically In the second.. On January 15, 2014 at 0907 hours and
            February 1jr, 2014 at 0304 hours secondary containment was declared Inoperable during
            repositioning of the dampers and during high winds respectively. These two events had
            durations of 6 and 2 minutes respectively. The system controller automatically restored
            secondary containment differential preSSUre in both events. In each of these events
            secondary containment vacuum was not maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 Inches of
            vacuum water gauge as required by Technical Specification 3.6.4.1, due to less than
            optimal control system tuning for the system. Corrective actions Include determining,
            Implementing, and documenting the optimum control system tuning for the system,
            Increasing margin by lowering d/fferentferl pressure set point, and alerting operations
            before the Technical Specification limit for secondary containment pressure Is reached.
   </abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>
   <P>Event 1: January 9, 2014 at 1743 hours E~ent 2: January.9,.2014 at 1834 hours Event 3: January
      15, 2014 at 0907 hours Event 4: February 17. 2014 at 0304 hours </P>

   <P>At the time of all events. the plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power. There were no
      structures, systems, or components that were Inoperable at the start of any of the events that
      contributed to. the events. </P>
      </plantConds>
      <eventDesc>
  
   <P>Events 1 &amp;2-</P>

   <P>On January 9, 2014 at 1743 and 1834 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained
      while Reactor Building Outside Air (ROA) heating coil face and bypass dampers ware
      repositioning due to outside ambient temperature fluctuation past the set point. These dampers
      and heating coli allow for outside air to be heated as it enters the system. These two events
      had durations of 3 and 2 minutes respectively. In Event 1 control room operators took manual
      control of the Reactor Building Exhaust Air (REA) flow In-service differential pressure
      controller (OPIC) (REA-OPIC-1A) to restore secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25
      inches of vacuum water gauge. In Event 2 th, REA in-service controller (REA-OPIC-1A)
      automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 Inches watl9r gauge
      (Inwg). </P>

   <P>Event 3-</P>

   <P>On January 15, 2014 at 0907 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained while the
      ROA heating coli face and bypass dampers ware repositioning due to outside ambient temperature
      fluctuation past the set point. This event had duration of 6 minutes. In this event the REA
      in-seMce controller (REA-OPIC-1A) automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to
      greater than 0.25 inwg.. </P>

   <P>Event 4-</P>

   <P>On February 17, 2014 at 0304 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained during a
      period of high winds. This event had duration of 2 minutes. In this event the REA in-service
      controller (REA-OPIC-1B) automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than
      0.25Inwg. </P>

   <P>In each event described above, because Reactor Building [NG} vacuum decreased below 0.25
      inches of water gauge, secondary containment was logged as Inoperable In the surveillance log
      and Technical Specification 3.6.4.1 Action A was enterad. </P>
      </eventDesc>
      <extentCondition>
   <P>This condition of Reactor Building vacuum momentarily dropping below the prescribed limit is
      specific to the Reactor Building Heating Ventilation and Air Cooling (HVAC) [VA] and Standby
      Gas Treatment (SGT) [BH1 systems, and their capability to establish and maintain secondary
      containment vacuum. No other systems were affected as a result of this condition. </P>

During an extent of conditiOn review performed to datermJne past operability,
            it was determined that there were multiple instances where secondary containment vacuum
            was less than the TS required value of 0.25 Inwg. In these Instances secondary
            containment vacuum went below the TS required value of 0.25 Inwg and went unnoticed by
            operators as the annunciator alarm comes In at 0.0 inwg. This alann value has been
            identified as Incorrect to alert operators to secondary containment vacuum below the TS
            required value 0&quot;0.25 inwg and the condition has been documented in the comlctive
            action process to be aligned with the TS value of 0.25Inwg. In each of these events the
            REA In-service controtler automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater
            than 0.25Inwg. Immediate Corrective ActIon In Event 1 Operators took manuaf control of
            the REA differential pressure (dP) controUer [PDC) and quickly adjusted REA flow to
            restore S8C0~arycontainment vacuum to greater than 0.25 Inwg. In Events 2, 3, and 4 the
            REA flow In-servlce controller automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to
            greater than 0.25 Inwg. Cause In accordance with NUREG-1022 Revision 3 Section 2.3 theSe
            four events are being reported together as these have all occurred in the 80 day LER
            reporting period and appear to have similar cause(s) for each event. Events 1 &amp; 2
            ware reported together as they were related and occulT8d within an hour of each other.
            Events 3 and 4 were reported under indMdual ENS notifications. Secondary vacuum dropping
            below the TS required value of 0.251nwg happened in four separate events in this LER
            reporting period. All four of these events were similar in that an extemal weather
            related event, three temperature related transients and one wind related transient,
            occurred that required the exhaust ventilation fan to adjust its flow to maintain a
            vacuum above the TS required value of 0.25 inwg. The cause of secondary containment
            vacuum not being maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 inwg was due to improper
            tuning of the Reactor Building Outside Air (ROA) differential pressure controUers. The
            transient response of the controtlers were not properly tuned to compensate for sudden
            pressure changes that are expected during operation of the pressure control system.
            Operating experience &amp; Previous Occurrences A loss of the ability to maintain
            secondary containment vacuum greater than required has occurred and was reported at
            Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) three times In the past two years. On August
            25,2013, reported undar LER 2013-007-00, secondary containment was declared Inoperable
            during 8l sudden thunderstonn when secondary containment vacuum was not maintained
            greater than or equal to 0.25 inwg. On July 24, 2012, reported under LER 2012-003-00,
            secondary containment vacuum was not maintained due to an inadvertent trip of one set of
            the redundant Reactor Building HVAC fans (FAN), during ongoing maintenance on the SGT
            system. On December 10, 2011, reported under LER 2011-004-00, secondary containment
            vacuum was not maintained and the cause was determined to be lca buildup and subsequent
            release on exterior equipment supplying the Reactor Bui/ding HVAC system. The first
            Operating Experience (OE) event Is similar in cause as the four events reported in this
            LER. Due to the single occurrence and the extreme weather conditions at the time,
            multfple causal factors were not considered. A corrective action which could have
            prevented recurrence of this event, to alert operations to a potential issue with
            secondary containment before the Technical Specification, LCO 3.S.4.1.A, for secondary
            containment vacuum is reached, was in progress at the time of the four events ntported In this LER. The last two OE
            events have associated corrective actions, and the causes are not applicable to the
            current cause of weather related secondary containment vacuum changes, nor would
            corrective actions from these past two events prevented occurrence of these four events
            reported In this LER. As discussed In the Reactor Oversight Process wortdng group public
            meeting hetd on January 16, 2014 the Industry has experienced an Increase in ntports of
            safety system functional failures (SSFF) in where there Is not a true loss of safety
            function, but momentary conditions In which Technical Specification operability criteria
            ant not satisfied. Specifically temporary losses of secondary containment vacuum have
            Increased In the Industry. The four events described In this LER fall Into this Increase
            in number of reports. Further Corrective ActIons The potential for these momentary
            pressure excursions will continue to occur as there has been no change In the design of
            the equlpmenl To minimize ntCUrrence actions are being taken to update the current
            calibration procedures to reflect the optimum control system tuning for the REAlROA
            system, and incntaslng margin In secondary containment by lowering the differential
            pressure set point on the REA controllers. Columbia Is also investigating methods to
            alert operations to a potential Issue with secondary containment before the Technical
            Specification secondary containment pressure Is reached. 
      </extentCondition>   
         <safetyConsequences>
               This event resulted in an unplanned entry Into LCO 3.6.4.1.A. Secondary
            containment vacuum was less than 0.26 Inwg for between 2 and 6 minutes. While the actual
            vacuum was beyond the range allowed by Technical Specifications, the Reactor Building
            HVAC system Is designed to, among other things; maintain the ntactor building during
            normal operating at a negative pressure with respect to atmosphere to minimize the
            release of airborne radioactive material. During emergency operation, the SGT system
            maintains the reactor building at a negative pntssure. Ourlng each of the events
            described in this LER at least one train of SGT was In standby condition and available
            to ntstore the reactor building to a vacuum above the TS required value of O.25Inwg. An
            engineering safety function analysis was performed which demonstrated that the ability
            for SGT to achieve secondary containment vacuum to above O.25Inwg, credited In the
            accident ntSpOR88 analysis, could have been attained using either of the two available
            trains of the SGT system at the time of each of the events, thus there were no potential
            safety consequences. There was no actual safety consequence associated with this event
            since no event Involving radiological hazards were experienced during the event. NEI
            99-02 allows the licensee to perform an engineering analysis to determine if the event
            is reportable as a SSFF performance Indicator occurrence. The engineering analysis has
            shown that these events did not result In a SSFF; therefont this event does not affect
            the NRC Regulatory Oversight Process Indicators. Energy Industry identification System
            (EllS) Information Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) Information codes from
            IEEE Standards 806-1984 and 803-1983 are represented In brackets as [XX] and (XXX]
            throughout the body of the narrative.</safetyConsequences>
      