<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-03-28T06:31:02-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-03-28T06:31:02-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-03-28T06:31:02-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>• -,,1\ </P><P>.:.-&quot; \ </P><P>Alex L. Javorilt Columbia Generating StatIon </P><P>P.O. Box 988. PE04 Richland, WA 99352.0968 </P><P>Ph. 509.S1T.i5S51 F. 609.377.4150 </P><P>aljavorikOenergy-northwescom, </P><P>March 10,2014 
G02-14-034 
</P><P>10CFR50.73 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatoty CommJssion 
ATTN: Document COntrol Desk 
Washington,O.C. 20555-0001 
</P><P>SubjeCt: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATtON, 00CKeT NO. 504t7 
LICENSEI EVEtff AEPOAT NO. 2014401.00 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted hereWith is Ucensee Event Report No. 2014-001&quot;()o for Columbia Generating </P><P>Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10CFR 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C), and 10 CFR </P><P>50.73(a)(2)(v)(D). </P><P>There are no commitments being made to the NRC by this letter. If you have any </P><P>questionS or require additional Information, please contact Mr. J.R. Trautvetter, </P><P>Regulatory Compliance SupervisOr, at (509) 377-4337. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><Part><H1>~~{\!Yv\\~'(~~\JOv,·\::.. </H1><P>A. l. Javorik 
Vice President, Engineering 
</P><P>Attachment: Ucensee Event Report 2014..Q01-OO </P><P>cc: NRC Region IV Administtator 
NRC NRR Project Manager 
NRC Senior Resident Inspectorl988C 
</P><P>AJ RapaCl-BPAl1399 </P><P>WA Horln -	Winston &amp; Strawn </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2014_03_10_ML14087A008_img_0.jpg"/>~FORIf_ u.s. Uln.';4D ReGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED 8V OMS: NO.315O-Ot4M EXPIFIES 01131//2017 (01-2014) ~burden per rapDnS8 to ~Iywith this mandaIoIy collectlon request. 80 hours. Reponed I88Ions leameclllllllncolporated Into lhe ~118and led back to Indust!y. LICENSEE EveNT REPORT (LER) Sand 00111111811111 ~burden astlmat8 to the FOlA, and InformaIIon CoIIac:IIons Branch (f-6 F53), u.s. Nuclear Regulaloly CommIssIon, W='=' DC 20556-0001, or by (See Pag&amp; 2 for required number of Intemal e-ma!l1O ~nrc.gcv,and to the Desk , 0IIice of Infarrmtion and ReguIa!oty Af!'alra, NEQB.10202 (3150-0104), 0IIice 01 MalIagIIIIIenI and Budget, WashlnQIon, DC digits/characters for each block). 20S03. /I a IlIIIIIJI$ used to ffl1Xl88 an InIornaIJon caIIecIIan doe8 not dIIIpIay a CUInII1IIv valid OMB CGIltn)l number, the NRC may no! cond1.lCl or 1SpOIIIlOT, and B pere;on Is not required 10 rlISIIOftd to, the informatIon cofIacIIon. 1. FACfLtTY NAME a. DOCKET NUMBER a PAGE Columbia Generating Station 05000 397 1 OF5 4. TItLE Secondary Containment Pressure Exceeded S. EVENT DATE e.LPNUMBEA 7.~.DATE 8. OTHeR FAClLmES INVOLVED SEQUENTIAl. REV FACIUTY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MONTH DAY YEAR YeAR NUMBER NO. MONTH DAY YEAR 05000 FACIUTY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 01 09 2014 2Ot4 -001 -00 03 10 2014 05000 8. OPERAllNG UOOE 11. 11fI8 AEPORf IS SUBMm'ED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMEHTS OF 10 CFA I: (etr.k IJ/IIII., sppIyJ o 2O.2201(b) o 2O.2203(a)(3)(1) o 5O,73(a)(2)(I)(C) (J 5O.73(a)(2)(vll) 1 o 2O.2201(d) o 2O.2203(a)(3)(11) a 5O.73(a)(2)(U)(A) o 6O.73(a)(2)(vliI)(A) CJ 20.2203 (8)(1) o 2O.2203(a)(4) [J SO.73(a)(2)(6)(8) o 5O.73(a)(2)(ViIl)(B) o 2O.2203(a)(2)(1) o 5O.3G(c)(1){I)(A) IJ 5O.73(a)(2)(HI) o 5O.73(a)(2)(lx)(A) 10. POWER a.eVEL [J 2O.2203(a)(2)(lI) (J 5O.36(c)(1)(U)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(x) D 2O,2203(a)(2)(IH) IJ 5O.36(c)(2) o 5O.13(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) 100 (] 2O,2203(a)(2)(1v) o 5O.46(a)(3)(iJ) [J 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5) [J 2O.2203(a)(2)(v) o 60,73(a){2)(i)(A) 181 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vl) o SO.73(a)(2)(1)(B) em 5O,73(a)(2)(v)(O) Specffy in Abstract below or In NRC Form 366A fa. e.IC&amp;NSEe CONTACT FOR THIS LEA FACILITY NAME ITElEPHONE NUMBER (fnclude Area Code) Deslr6\e Wolfgramm, Senior Ucenslng Engineer 509-377-4792 13. COMPI.E11! ONe UNE FC)A eACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT CAuse SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU· REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTUREA TOEPIX FACTURER TO EPIX 14.SU ___ II&quot;&quot;'&quot;IOI~. ~100 f6, 'EXPECTED I MON H DAY YEAR lSI YES (N yes. complet9 'S. EXPECTED SUBMISSION OATE) CJ NO SUBMI88ION r 04 30 2014DATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, I.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On January 9, 2014 at 1743 and 1834 hours secondary containment was declared Inoperable during repositioning of the dampers. These two events had durations of 3 and 2 minutes respectively. Control Room operators took manual control of the Reactor BuUding Exhaust Air flow system to restore secondary containment in the first event, and the controller restored pressure automatically in the second. On January 15,2014 at 0907 hours and February 17,2014 at 0304 hours secondary containment was declared inoperable dur/~ repositioning of the dampers and during high winds respectively. These two events had durations of 6 and 2 minutes respectively. The system controller automaticallY restored secondary containment. differential pressure in both events, .. . . In each of these events secondary containment vacuum was not maintained greater than or equal to 0.25 inches of vacuum water gauge as required by Technical specmcation 3.6.4.1, While Technical Specification limits were exceeded, the resulting pressure excursion was bounded by analytical results, and thus there were no safety consequences for this event The cause(s) for the event is currently under investigation. A supplemental LER is planned for when testing and Investigation Is completed. Corrective actions will be developed based upon the cause(s). </Figure><P>26158 R6 NRC Fonn 366 (01-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>U.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMIIISSlOH (01-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET RCFORM36fA&quot;N</TH><TH>APPROVED BY 0118: NO. 816000104 EXPIRES: 01181flO17 Es1imaIed burden per response 10 comply wl1h IIIis mandatory coIIecIiOll request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are IncorporaIed into lite lll:ensing process and led back 10 Indusby. Send tomIIleII!s regarding burden eslimate to lite FOIA. PrIvacy and InIorma1lon CoIIacIlons BrancIl (T-o F63), U.s. Nuclear Flegu!aloly CommissIon, WasIIing1Dn, DC 20565-0001, Of by internet e-mail to lnfocollectB.ResourceOnrc.gov, and to !he Desk Officer, Office of InfDrmallon end ReguIatoJy AfIaIrs, ~t0202, (31~104), 0IIice 01 Management and Budget. WasIIirGIM. DC 206IX!. II a means used to Impase an InfonnaIIon collection does not cispIay 8 curmnI!y valid OUB COIIInII number, file NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a pe!8OIl is not required 10 respond 10, IIle Information coII8c1ion. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACtLITY NAME ColumbIa Generating Station </TH><TD>08000 397 </TD><TD>e. U!R NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE! 2 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NAARATMi Plant Conditions Event 1: January 9,2014 at 1743 hours Event 2: January 9, 2014 at 1834 hours Event 3: January ~5, 2014 at 0907 hours Event 4: Februaty 17, 2014 at 0304 hours At the time of all events, the plant was operating In Mode 1 at 100% power. There were no structures,' systems. or components that were inoperabte at the start of any of the events that contributed 10 the events. Event Description Event81 &amp;2-On January 9, 2014 at 1743 and 1834 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained while Reactor Building Outside Air (ROA) heating coil face and bypass dampers were repositioning due to outside ambient temperature fluctuation past the set point. These dampers and heating colt allow for outside air to be heated as it enters the system. These two events had durations of 3 and 2 minutes respectively. In Event 1 control room operators took manua' control of the Reactor Building Exhaust Air (REA) flow in-service differential pressure controller (DPlC) (REA&quot;[)PIC-1A) to restore secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 inches of vacuum water gauge. In Event 2 the REA in-service controller (AEA-DPIC-1 A) automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 inches water gauge (inwg). Event 3-On January 15, 2014 at 0907 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained while the ROA heating coil face and bypass dampers were repositioning due to outside ambient temperature fluctuation past the set point. This event had duration of 6 minutes. In this event the REA in-service controller (AEA-DPIC-1 A) automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 Jnwg. -Event 4-On February 17. 2014 at 0304 hours secondary containment vacuum was not maintained during a ~riod of high wlnds. This event had duration of 2 minutes: tn this event the REA In-service controller (REA-DPIC-1B) automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 inwg. In each event described above, because Reactor Building [NGJ vacuum decreased below 0.25 inches of water gauge, secondary containment was logged as inoperable in the surveillance Jog and Technical Specification 3,6.4.1 Action A was entered. </TH></TR><Caption><P>26158A R3 NRC FORM 366A (01·2014) </P></Caption></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FOAM 38M (ot-2014t LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (&amp;.ER) CONTINUATION SHEET u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORV COMMISSION..--------------------------------------------------------~ </TH></TR><TR><TH>,. FACIUTY NAME Columbia Generattng StatIon , </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>e. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>a.PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TD>05000 397 </TD><TD>YEAR I se:fAL I~~~ 2014 081 -00 </TD><TD>3 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARMlWE Extent of CondItion This condition of Reactor Building vacuum momentarily dropping below the prescribed limit is specific to the Reactor Buikfing Heating Ventilation and Air Cooling (HVAC) [VAl and Standby Gas Treatment (SGT) (BH) systems. and their capability to estabUsh and maintain secondary containment vacuum. No other systems were affected as a result of this condition. During an extent of condition review performed to detennine past operability. It was determined that there were multiple instances where secondary containment vacuum was tess than the T5 required value of 025 inwg. In these instances secondary containment vacuum went below the T8 required value of 0.25 inwg and went unnoticed by operators as the annunciator alann comes in at 0.0 inwg. This alarm value has been identified as incOrrect to alert operators to secondary contalnment vacuum below the T5 required value of 0.25 inwg and the condition has been documented in the corrective action process to be aligned with the T5 value of 0.25 inwg. In each of these events the REA in-service controf1er automatically restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 mwg. immediate Corrective Action In Event 1 Operators took manual control of the ReA differential pressure (dP) controUer [POC} and quickly adjusted REA flow to restore secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 inwg. In Events 2, 3, and 4 the REA flow in-service controtler automaticaUy restored secondary containment vacuum to greater than 0.25 inwg. Cause In accordance with NUREG-1022 Revision 3 Section 2.3 these four events are being reported together as these have all occurred in the 60 day LER reporting period and appear to have similar cause(s) for each event. Events 1 &amp; 2 were reported together as they were related and occurred within an hour of each other. Events 3 and 4 were reported under individual ENS notifications. Secondary vacuum dropping below the TS required value of 0.25 inwg happened in four separate events in this LER reporting period. All four of these events were similar in that an external weather related event, three temperature related transients and one wind reJated transient. occurred that requi~d the exhaust ventilation fan to adjust its flow to maintain a'vacuum above the T5 required value of 0.25 inwg. To futly understand the ,cause of these events an apparent cause an~lYSis has b&quot;en initiated to determine causal factors. . .' '. . . . At thi$ time there are five possible causal factors that are being considered, with a possibility of a combination of tWo or more of these factors. Actions are currently being taken to confirm or refute each of these possible causal factors. These actions include, bUt are not Umited to, verifying set-points on the two differential pressure controllers, design and calculation review. equipment Inspection. and testing of the ventilation system, gathering operating data from each train while in-service. This testing will perform an equipment inspection of both trains of the ROAIREA system, verify the setpoints for each of the differential pressure controllers, and determine the'system response of both of the Independent systems reaction to weather related transients. </TH></TR><Caption><P>26158A R3 NRC FORM 366A (01-2014) </P></Caption></Table><P>... 
</P><P>, 
</P><Table><TR><TH>LICENSE! EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION..----------------------------------------------------------~ </TH></TR><TR><TH>t. FACfLfTV NAME COlumbia GtneratintStation ~ </TH><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD><TD>3-PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVNUMBER NO. </TD><TD>40F 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 ... GOt ... 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE Once testing is completed the system response wHI be oompared to the system design to validate the response and corrective actions wiIJ be developed based upon the causal factors. A supplement to this LEA wUl be submitted once causal factors and corrective actions have been established. Operating Experience • PrevioUs Occurrences A loss of the ability to maintain secondary c:ontalnment vacuum greater than required has occurred and was reported at Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) three times in the past two years. On August 25,2013. reported under LER 2013..()()7'()(), secondary containment was declared Inoperable during a sudden thunderstorm when secondary containment vacuum was not maintained greater than or equal to O.25Inwg. On July 24,2012, reported under LER 2012-003-00. secondary containment vacuum was not maintained due to an inadvertent trip of one set of the redundant Reactor Building HVAC fans (FAN). during ongoing maintenance on the SGT system. On December 10, 2011, reported under LEA 2011..()()4..()O, secondary containment vacuum was not maintained and the cause was determined to be Ice buildup and subsequent release on exterior equipment supplying the Reactor BuHding HVAC system. The first Operating EJCperience (OE) event is similar in cause as the four events reported In this LEA. Due to the single occurrence and the extreme weather conditions at the time, multiple causal factors were not considered. A corrective action whiCh could have prevented recurrence of this event, to alert operations to a potential issue with secondary containment before the Technicat Specification. LCO 3.6.4.1.A, for secondary containment vacuum is reached, was in progress at the time of the four events reported in this LEA. The last two OE events have associated corrective actions, and the causes are not applicable to the current cause of weather related secondary containment vacuum changes, nor would corrective actions from these past two events prevented occurrence of these four events reported in this LEA. As discussed in the Reactor Oversight Process working group public meeting held on January 15, 2014 the industry has experienced an increase in reports of safety system functional fanures (SSFF) in where there is not a true loss of safety function, but momentary conditions in which Technlcal Specification operability criteria are not satisfied. Specifically temporary losses of secondary containment vacuum have increased in the . Industry. The four events described In this LER fall into this increase in number of reports. Further Corrective ActIon8 Corrective actions will be submitted with a supplement to this LER once testing and determination of cause is completed. Assessment of Safety Consequences This event resulted in an unplanned entry into Leo 3.6.4.1.A. Secondary containment vacuum was less than </TH></TR><Caption><P>26158A R3 NRC FORM 386A (01-2014) </P></Caption></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 380A (Ot-2Ot4) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LEA) CONTINUATION SHEET u.s. NUCLeAR REGULATORY COMMISSION,r-------------------------------------------------------------~ </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACIUTY NAME Columbia Genenl1In9 StatIon </TH><TD>2. DOCKeT </TD><TD>8.1.ER NUlllER </TD><TD>a.PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD><TD>YEAR I SEaUE~ IREV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>6 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 ... oot -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE 0.25 inwg for between 2 and 6 minutes. WhOe the actual vacuum was beyond the range aUowed by Technical Specifications. the Reactor Building HVAC system is designed to, among other things; maintain the reactor building during normal operating at a negative pressure with respect to atmosphere to minimize the release of airborne radioactive material. During emergency operation. the SGT system maintains the reactor building at a negative pressure. During each of the events described in this LER at least one train of SGT was In standby condHion and available to restore the reactor building to a vacuum above the T8 required value of 0.25 inwg. An engineering safety function analysis was performed which demonstrated that the ability for SGT to achieve secondary containment vacuum to above 0.25 inwg. credited In the accident response analysis, could have been attaJned using either of the two available trains of the SGT system at the time of each of the events, thus there were no potential safety consequences. There was no actual safety consequence associated with this event sk\ce no event Involving radiological hazards were experienced during the event. NEI 99-02 allows the licensee to perfonn an engineering analysis to determine if the event is reportable as a SSFF petformance indicator occurrence. The engineering analysis has shown that these events did not result in a SSFF; therefore this event does not affect the NRC Regulatory Oversight Process Indicators. Energy Induatry identification Syetem (EllS) information Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) Information codes from IEEE Standards 805-1984 and 803·1983 are represented in brackets as (XX) and [XXX) throughout the body of the narrative. </TH></TR><Caption><P>26158A R3 NRC FORM 368A (01-2014) </P></Caption></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>