<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler when="2014-08-14" id="3972014004">
   <abstract>On August 14, 2014 it was discovered that Columbia Generating Station's
               (Columbia) method of complying with Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance
               Requirement (SR) 3.7.1.1 for Ultimate Heat Sink (UHS) spray pond level was
               inadequate. The SR requires level in each spray pond to be verified to be greater
               than or equal to the minimum water level whereas procedures allowed for an arithmetic
               average of the two ponds to be taken when a single Service Water (SW) pump is in
               operation which creates a differential between the pond levels. The two spray ponds
               that make up Columbia's UHS are connected by a siphon line to allow water to be
               shared between the two ponds. Columbia's original TS did not specify that a minimum
               water level be checked in each pond and a procedural note was added to clarify
               compliance with the TS SR during single SW pump operation. When Columbia upgraded the
               TSs in 1997 the word 'each' was introduced to the TS. Corrective actions inclu.cIe a
               TS amendment submitted to the NRC on August 22, 2014.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <plantConds>
      <P>At the time of the event the plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100% power.
         This event documents an administrative issue with TS compliance, therefore no structures,
         systems, or components were inoperable that contributed to this event. </P></plantConds>
      <eventDesc>
      <P>On August 14. 2014 It was discovered that Columbia Generating Station's
         (Columbia) method of complying with Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement
         (SR) 3.7.1.1 for Ultimate Heat Sink (UHS) [as) spray pond level was Inadequate. </P>

      <P>Columbia's UHS consists of two concrete spray ponds. These spray ponds provide suction and
         discharge points for the redundant pumping and spray facilities of the Service Water (SW)
         [BI) system. SW loop A draws water from pond A and discharges through a spray ring into
         pond afor heat diSSipation. Similarly. SW loop a draws water from pond B and discharges
         through a spray ring into pond A. The water then retums to the initial pond through a
         siphon line. During operation with one SW pump running, a differential level develops
         between the ponds until flow through the siphon line equalizes with the running SW pump.
         The spray ponds remain with this differential level until the running pump is stopped and
         flow through the siphon line equalizes the spray pond levels. The ponds were licensed such
         that the combined water volume of the spray ponds is adequate to provide cooling water for
         30 days of operation. assuming maximum evaporation and drift losses. </P>

      <P>Prior to implementation of improved TS (ITS) in June of 1997. there were separate TS for 5W
         and UH5. The UH5 T5 contained a SR to verify the UH8 water level was within its limit of
         432 ft 9 inches mean sea level at a frequency of 24 hours. The operations surveillance
         procedure contained a note to take an arithmetic average of the spray pond levels if only
         one loop of SW was in operation. In March 1997, Columbia received license amendment 149 for
         ITS with a full Implementation date of June 30. 1997. The ITS combined-the 8W and UHS into
         one TS. The UHS water level surveillance requirement was changed to require the level in
         ~spray pond to be within the limit of 432 ft 9 inches. Due to the design of the spray ponds
         and 8W system. it is difficult to meet this requirement in each pond when only one SW pump
         is In operation. </P>

      <P>This discrepancy between the new T5 SR and how it is implemented in operations surveillance
         procedures was identified in 1997 and license document changes were initiated to change the
         TS SR and the T8 Bases to allow for an arithmetic average of the two ponds when a single
         pump is in operation. The T8 Bases change was processed; however the T8 SA change was not
         completed. The reason why the TS SR wasn't completed and submitted to the NRC for approval
         Is undocumented and unknown. </P></eventDesc>
      <eventCause>

         <P>The cause of this event is that although it was recognized In 1997 that Columbia was out
            of verbatim compliance with TS SA 3.7.1.1. Columbia's licensing document change process
            in 1997 allowed for changes to the TS SA and T8 Bases to be processed separately. This
            allowed the TS Bases change to be implemented while the TS SR change was never completed
            or approved by the NRC. </P>
      
               <P>An extent of condition review determined that there
                  have been multiple Instances when SW would need to be declared inoperable based on
                  spray pond level as it is common practice to operate individual service water
                  pumps based on plant needs. The 12 hour Limiting Conditions for Operation per TS
                  3.7.1 was exceeded on August 13, 2014 with additional occurrences since
                  implementation of the ITS on June 30, 1997. Immediate Corrective Action Once it
                  was discovered that the operations procedure was not compliant with the T8 SR all
                  oncoming operations crews were briefed on the correct implementation of the TS SR.
                  Guidance was also given to start both SW pumps if one is required to run. The
                  operations surveillance procedure was also updated to remove the wording which
                  allowed for the arithmetic average of the two ponds when a single pump is in
                  operation. Columbia has submitted a TS change to the NRC to allow verification
                  that the average water level in the UHS spray ponds is within the limit. The
                  licensing change process is being updated to ensure processing of TS SR changes
                  with TS Bases changes if related.</P>
      </eventCause>
                  
                  <previousEvents>
                  No previous occurrences have been found to have the same cause of a license
                  amendment change not processed. One event reported under LER-12-004-02 was a
                  failure to enter a TS action statement due to conflicting information between the
                  associated TS Bases and the surveiHance procedure. Corrective actions focused on
                  operability determinations for equipment removed from service. It also included a
                  focused selfassessment to review TS Bases and TS SRs. The self-assessment did not
                  Identify the discrepancy described in this LER, and therefore a re-review of the
                  wor1&lt; performed by this individual Is being completed to ensure no other
                  discrepancies between T8 SR, T8 Bases and Implementing procedures exist. Further
                  Corrective Actlona A review of all TS Bases amendments was conducted to identify
                  whether any other Licensing Document Changes were issued that introduced conflicts
                  with the literal wording in the T8.</previousEvents> 
                  
                  <safetyConsequences>There were no actual safety consequences associated with this event as during periods of SW
                  single loop operation when one pond level was below TS minimum the actual
                  inventory of the UHS was unaffected. The combined Inventory between the two ponds
                  remained above the licensed amount required to provide adequate cooling for 30
                  days of operation.</safetyConsequences>
   </narrative>
</ler>