<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2005-05-09T14:33:03-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2005-05-09T14:33:03-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2005-05-09T14:33:03-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:c80c82be-67e6-4d39-91a4-0cb7ebcb7f06</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:ea751da4-6df2-1242-a272-c28d0f3e3b9a</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>EMERGY 
</H1><Sect><H5>NORTHWEST </H5><P>p.o. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>April 10, 2001 G02-01-056 </P><P>Docket No. 50-397 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, OPERATING LICENSE NPF-21, LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2001-001-00 </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2001-001-00 for Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73. The enclosed report discusses items of reportability and corrective action taken. </P><P>Should you have any questions or desire additional information regarding this matter, please call me or Mr. PJ Inserra at (509) 377-4147. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Vice Presi t, Generation Mail Drop PE988V </P><P>Attachment </P><P>cc: EW Merschoff -NRC-RIV JS Cushing -NRC-NRR INPO Records Center NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) DL Williams -BPA/1399 TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn WB Jones -NRC RIV Ifax </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2001_04_10_ML011070292_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 (1-2001 ) COMMISSION Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T-6 E6), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to bjs1@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose information collection does digits/characters for each block) not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) Columbia Generating Station 50-397 1 OF2 TITLE (4) TRAVERSING INCORE PROBE SYSTEM WAS OPERATED WITHOUT ADMINISTRATIVE CONTROLS AS REQUIRED BY TECHNICAL SPECIFICATION LCO 3.6.1.3, NOTE 1 EVENT DATE (5) LER NUMBER (6) REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED (8) YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MO DAY YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 02 06 2001 2001 -001 -00 04 10 2001 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER OPERATING 1 THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUiREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) (11) MODE (9) 20.2201 (b) 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) POWER 100 20.2201 (d) 20.2203(a)(4 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(x) LEVEL (10) 20.2203 (a)(1) 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) 50·n(a}(~iv)(A) 73.71 (a)(4) 20.2203(a)(2)(i) 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) 73.71 (a )(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 50.36(c)(2) 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) Other 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 50.46(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(:2llv)(c) Specify in Abstract below or 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) 50.73(all~v)(D) in NRC Form 366A 20.2203(a)(2)(v) x 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 20.2203(a}(2)(vi) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 50.73(a )(2)(viii )(A) . 20.2203(a )(3}(i) 50.73(&lt;D(2)(ii)(A) 50.73(a }(2)(viill(B 1 .&quot; LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER (12) NAME I TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) R Brownlee 509-377-2085 COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT (13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU· REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TO EPIX FACTURER TO EPIX SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED I MONTH J DAY YEAR IYES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). NO SUBMISSION I IDATE (15) ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, I.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) On February 6, 2001, a Local Power Range Monitor calibration surveillance was being performed which required the operation of the Traversing Incore Probe (TIP) System. While the TIP System was energized the requirement of Technical Specification LCO 3.6.1.3, Note 1 for administrative control of containment penetration flow paths was not met. An individual was not assigned to be the dedicated operator of TIP System contra! switches to ensure isolation of containment penetration flow paths in the event of a valid containment isolation signal. The cause of this event was the lack of a procedural standard for establishing administrative controls in accordance with the Technical Specifications and Bases. A standard was not available when changing the method of administrative control of TIP System containment isolation valves from the use of a clearance order and tags to a revised procedure for operating the TIP System. There are no safety consequences associated with this event. The procedure for operating the TIP System has been revised to provide instructions for satisfying the TS LCO 3.6.1.3 requirement for administrative controls. </Figure><P>968-26158 (1101) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001 ) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>2 OF 2 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2001 001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) Event Discription: Traversing Incore Probe (TIP) System containment isolation valves TIP-V-1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 are considered inoperable due to the potential for spurious opening of the valves with the TIP drive units energized. Technical Specification (TS) LCO 3.6.1.3, Note 1 states &quot;Penetration flow paths may be unisolated intermittently under adminstrative controls.&quot; TS Bases 3.6.1.3 states: &quot;These controls consist of stationing a dedicated operator at the controls of the valve, who is in continuous communication with the control room. In this way, the penetration can be rapidly isolated when a need for primary containment isolation is indicated.&quot; At the time the concern with TIP valve spurious operation was identified, the power supply circuit breakers for the TIP drive units were danger tagged &quot;open&quot; per a clearance order. On those occasions when the danger tags were lifted for TIP System operation, one individual was assigned the responsiblity to verify closure of the TIP containment isolation valves should a valid containment isolation signal occur. This clearance order was removed permanently after the TIP operating procedure was revised to maintain the TIP drive power supply circuit breakers normally open. There are several steps in the TIP operating procedure that require the TIP drive power supply breakers to be closed. However, no guidance was included in the procedure to require &quot;stationing a dedicated operator at the controls of the valve&quot; to satisfy the TS requirements. On February 6, 2001, a Local Power Range Monitor calibration surveillance was being performed which required the operation of the TIP System. While the TIP System was energized the requirement of TS LCO 3.6.1.3, Note 1 for administrative control of containment penetration flow paths was not met. An individual was not assigned to be the dedicated operator of TIP System valves to ensure isolation of containment penetration flow paths in the event of a valid containment isolation signal. Immediate Corrective Action: Caution tags were hung on TIP System drive mechanism breakers and control switches so that the TIP System containment isolation valves will be controlled administratively per TS LCO 3.6.1.3. Cause of the Event: The cause of this event was the lack of a procedural standard for establishing administrative controls in accordance with the Technical Specifications and Bases. A standard was not available when changing the method of administrative control of TIP System containment isolation valves from the use of a clearance order and tags to a revised procedure for operating the TIP System. Two contributing causes were that control room personnel did not recognize key information available for determining the necessary TS actions while the TIP System was being operated, and that information regarding the inoperability of TIP System containment isolation valves was not adequately reviewed by the individuals who revised the procedure used to operate the TIP System. Further Corrective Action: Procedures associated with operation of the TIP System have been revised to provide explicit direction for satisfying TS administrative requirements when the TIP System is energized. Also, Columbia Generating Station will implement a procedural standard for establishing administrative controls when required for Technical Specification compliance. Assessment of Safety Consequences: There are no safety consequences associated with this event. Had there been an actual plant accident or transient requiring containment isolation while performing the LPRM surveillance, failure of the TIP containment isolation valves to close would have been identified and corrected by operations personnel as required by accident response procedures. Similar Events: There have been no similar events at Columbia Generating Station. </TH></TR></Table></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>