<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2005-04-25T08:58:14-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2005-04-25T08:58:14-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2005-04-25T08:58:14-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:38834b8d-6188-4f5d-9adb-a13f07d54fc1</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:5ac238b6-533b-7244-934f-27e16ce6837c</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>EMERGY 
</H1><Sect><H5>NORTHWEST </H5><P>P.O. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>April 10, 2002 G02-02-063 </P><P>Docket No. 50-397 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, OPERATING LICENSE NPF-21, LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2002-001-00 </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2002-001-00 for Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A). The enclosed report discusses items of reportability and corrective action taken. </P><P>Should you have any questions or desire additional information regarding this matter, please call Ms. CL Perino at (509) 377-2075. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Vice President, Operations Support/PIO Mail Drop PE08 </P><P>Attachment </P><P>cc: EW Merschoff -NRC-RIV JS Cushing -NRC-NRR INPO Records Center NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) DL Williams -BPA/1399 TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn WB Jones -NRC RIV/fax </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>NRC FORM 366 3150-0104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2002_04_10_ML021130475_img_2.jpg"/></Figure><P>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the· Records Management Branch (T -6 E6), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington DC </P><P>(1-2001) COMMISSION </P><P>20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to bjs1@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of </P><P>Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of </P></Sect><Sect><H4>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </H4><P>Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose information collection does digitsfcharacters for each block) </P><P>not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a is not the information collection. </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2002_04_10_ML021130475_img_3.jpg"/>FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) 05000397 PAGE (3) 10F3Columbia Generating Station </Figure><P>TITLE (4) </P><P>Completion of Technical Specification required shutdown to comply with Technical Specification LCO 3.8.1 Required Actions of Condition F. </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2002_04_10_ML021130475_img_4.jpg"/>REV NO 00 YES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). MO 04 CAUSE EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE (15) REPORTABLE TO EPIX </Figure><P>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) </P><P>On February 11,2002 at 0314 with Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) operating at 100% power, planned online maintenance commenced on Emergency Diesel Generator (EDG) </P><P>2. Maintenance was completed as scheduled. Surveillance testing to demonstrate operability of the EDG-2, and exit from the Limiting Condition of Operation (LCO), was started on February 13. Immediately after the EDG-2 output breaker was closed, the control room received an annunciator alarm. Investigation and evaluation revealed that the circuit breaker had closed but the Mechanism Operated Cell (MOC) switch assembly had failed to change state as expected, Columbia was at 100% power, when it was decided to shutdown the plant within the 72 hour completion time of TS 3.8.1 Required Action B.4. On February 14, 2002 at 1257 the plant entered Mode 3 as required by TS 3.8.l.F.1. The failure of the MOC switches to not fully actuate was due to lack of preventive maintenance and a breaker replacement that produced less drive force to actuate the MOC assembly. The root cause was the failure to recognize the importance of MOC assembly maintenance. The corrective actions are to establish maintenance on all 4160 volt and 6900 volt cubicle switchgears, and to enhance an existing Circuit Breaker Program to provide guidance on breaker and cell maintenance. </P><P>968-26158 R1 (9/01) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (1-2001) </P></Sect><Sect><H4>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) 
</H4><P>FACILITY NAME (1) </P><P>DOCKET (2) </P><P>LER NUMBER (6) </P><P>PAGE (3) </P><P><Figure ActualText="I "><ImageData src="images/2002_04_10_ML021130475_img_5.jpg"/>I </Figure>SEQUENTIAL J REVISION</P><P>YEAR </P><P>NUMBER NUMBER</P><P>Columbia Generating Station </P><P>2 OF 3</P><P>50-397 </P><P>~----------------------~--------~----~--~------------~----------~ </P><P>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) </P><P>Description of Event </P><P>On February 11, 2002 at 0314 Columbia Generating Statiun (Columbia) began plaJl11ed online </P><P>maintem.nce on Emergency Diesel G.;:nerator (ED G) 2. Maintenance was completed as </P><P>scheduled. Surveillance teJting to demonstrate operability of the EDG-2, and exit from the </P><P>Limiting Condition of Operation (LCO), was started on February 13. Immediately after the </P><P>EDG-2 output breaker was closed, the control room received an annunciator alarm. As this </P><P>was not an expected alarm, the System Engineer and the Electrical Su{.ervisor were contacted </P><P>for evaluation. Further investigation revealed that the circuit breaker nad closed but the </P><P>Mechanism Operated Cell (MOC) switch assembly had failed to change state as expected. The </P><P>circuit breaker is a Westinghouse model DHP-VR, which was installed during an upgrade </P><P>process in June 2001. Columbia was at 100% power ~lhen the decision was made to shutdown </P><P>the plant, due to the inability to restore EDG-2 to an Operable status within the 72 hour </P><P>completion time of TS 3.8.1 Required Action BA. On February 14, ::!002 at 1257 the plant </P><P>entered Mode 3 as required by ':':'S 3.8.l.F.1. On February 15, 2002 at 0242 the plant entered </P><P>Mode 4 as required by TS 3.8.l.F.2, </P><P>A four hour event notification telephone cal! was made to the NRC Operations Center at 0418 </P><P>EST on February 14, 2002 pUrSUai1.t to 10 CFR 50.72(b)(2)(i) after the plant shutdown was </P><P>initiated (Event Number 38694). </P><P>Immediate Corrective Actions </P><P>All Safety Related circuit breakers of the DHP-VR design and associat~d breaker cubicle, and </P><P>other 4160 and 6900 volt breakers and their cubicles, that have an active safety function, have </P><P>had preventive maintenance performed in accordance with the guidance developed by </P><P>Columbia, Westinghouse, and Cutler Hammer staff. The MOC assemblies for these breaker </P><P>cubicles were completely disassembled, inspected for wear, cleaned, re-greased, and worn </P><P>parts were replaced as needed. The Vendor also helped to establish acceptable operating limits </P><P>for the breaker applied MOC operating pin hrce and the MOC linkage resistance force to be </P><P>used to assess the degradation rate of the breaker's MOe switch interface. </P><P>Cause of the Event </P><P>The failure of the MOC switches to fully actuate was excessive resistance in the pantograph assembly due to a lack of preventive maintenance. The root cause was the failure to recognize the sensitivity of the new breakers to the importance of MOC assembly maintenance. During the last refueling outage that ended July 2, 2001, 22 obsolete magnetic air DHP type breakers were replaced with vacuum element DHP-VR type breakers. The originai DHP breakers </P><P>968-26158 R1 (9/01) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET(2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>r PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>provided such force as to overcome any MOC linkage resistance, whereas the new DHP-VR breakers did not provide the same force. Assessment of Safety Consequences An evaluation WaS performed of the period of time from when the DHP-VR breakers were installed until the plant was shutdown as a result of this event. There was no time at which any of the affected systems were called 11pon where they were unable to perform their required safety functions; therefore there were no safety consequences. Actuation force analysis performed on the MOC switch assemblies subsequent to plant shutdown showed that the reduced breaker applied force would not have resulted in a loss of any safety function. Actions to Prevent Recurrence Additional corrective actions include establishing the preventive maintenance frequency and scope of work for the MOe switches, MOC switch linkage,and pantograph channels of all the 4160 VAC and 6900 VAC cubicle switchgears. A plant procedure will be revised to include lubrication and maintenance instructions for the pantograph and MOC linkage assemblies. The Circuit Breaker Program will be enhanced +0 provide guidance on circuit breaker and cell maintenance. Previous Similar Events Three previous similar events have been identified. Two cases were intermittent, could not be repeated, and both occurred in the same cubicle. In the first instance the cause was degradation in the MOC switch linkages. Corrective actions were to inspect all cubicles with the 22 DHP-VR type breakers installed and change the procedural guidance to lubricate the MOC switches that are in the DHP type switchgears. In the second case, looseness with side-to-side movement in the pantograph was the cause. I Generic MOC linkage maintenance was a concern and corrective action was initiated to evaluate the preventive maintenance program for C'.ll MOC linkages and pantograph assemblies. However this action was not scheduled to be complete on all 22 breakers until JuI:' 1, 2002. The third case that occurred on January 17, 2002, was an unexpected alarm in the control room of a breaker trip that immediately clea:r:i!d. The breaker functioned correctly and did not trip. The system engineer was concerned and a work order was initiated to address the failure, but the February 13,2002 failure occurred before the work order was worked. </TH></TR></Table><P>968-26158 Rl (9/01) </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>