<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2003-09-12T13:53:24-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2003-09-12T13:53:24-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2003-09-12T13:53:24-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>\ 	EMERGY </H1><P>NORTHWEST-</P><P>P.O. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>August 28, 2003 G02-03-136 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATIN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397-
LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2003-007-00 _ 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2003-007-00 for the Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 -CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A). The enclosed report discusses items of reportability and corrective actions taken. -</P><P>If you have 	any questions or require additionaliriformation, please contact Ms. CL Perino at </P><P>(509) 377-2075. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><P>~~ </P><P>Vice President, Nuclear Generation Mail Drop PE04 </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: TP Gwynn -NRC RIV BJ Benney -NRC-NRR INPO Records Center NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) RN Sherman -BPAI1399 TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn WB Jones -NRC RIVIfax </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_08_28_ML032550326_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150&quot;()104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information coIIedion request 50 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the lcensing process and fed tiack to indUStry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T-6 Ee). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washington DC 20555-0001. or by internet e-man to bisl@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. NEOB-l0202 (31~104). Office of Management and Budget. Washington. DC 20503. If a means used to Impose Information collection does not display a currently valid OMS control number. the NRC may not condud or sponsor. and a person Is not required to respond to. the information collection. LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digitslcharacters for each block) FACIUTY NAME (1) Columbia Generating Station TITLE(4} DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) -05000397 1 OF 4 Automatic Reactor Scram due to a Main Transformer Differential Current Relay Actuation EVENT DATE 5) LER NUMBER (6) REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILInES INVOLVED181 YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MO DAY YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 6 30 2003 2003 007 00 8 28 2003 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER OPERAnNG MODE (9) 1 THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR I: (Check aillhat apply) (11) 20.2201(b) 20.2203 a 3leii) 50.73 a 2 ~I B) 5O.73(aX2)(ix)(A) POWER LEVEL (10) 79 20.2201(d) 20.2203 a 4 50.73 a 2 til 5O.73(aX2)(x) 20.2203 (aX1 5O.36(c 1 i A) x 50.73 a 2 MeA) 73.71(aX4) &quot; ,20.2203(aX2)(I) 5O.36(cX1XiiXA) 50.73(aX2 vXA 73.71(aX5)~:;r--r~20~2~203~1~8a~~2~!)(~~I)~---+--~5O~.~36~C~:~=2~~---;--~5O~.7=3~a~2~v~B~--+--+~~~e~r~~----~ &gt; 202203(aX2)(lii) 50.46 a 3 II 50.73 a 2 v C SpecifyilAbs1ractbelowor : 2O.2203(a)2)(iv) 50.73 a 2 I A 50.73 a 2 v D iI NRC Form366A •. :: 2O.2203(a) 2)(v) 50.73 a 2 i B 50.73 a 2 vii ,. , ..', 2O.2203(a) 2)(vi) 50.73 a 2 i C 50.73 a 2 viiiXA)c/ .'. .. ..•. ' ':,L&lt;';L+'\;;t--t-::20==:.2203==?(a=!I)7.:3~)«(ii::')t-----+--+-:5O:=.:::7~~aX'=2~)(~il':=iA:':-.)---+--+-=5~O.=73?(a~2~vi~l=iX=B~)--ri» .... ',,;;',•. :,:' LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER (12 NAME RBrownlee ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 509-377-2085 COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT (13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU. . REPORTABLEh:, CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU. ~______~~____~~~__-+~F~~~~E~R~~~TO~E~P=~~~, F~R B EL CBL2 Rome Y r'&quot; SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED MONTH DAY I SUBMISSION YES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). x NO DATE (15) ABSTRACT (limit to 1400 spaces. I.e •• approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) REPORTABLE TOEP~ YEAR On June 30,2003 while operating at 79% power, Columbia Generating Station automatically scrammed due to a main transformer differential current relay actuation. All equipment operated within design parameters. The cause of the relay actuation was traced to an insulation failure on a current transformer secondary wire that created an'impedance unbalance in the sensing circuitry. The root cause of this event is the original construction use of non-jacketed cable (single conductor wiring) which is more prone to failure due to fretting action. Corrective actions were to replace main transformer current transfonner wiring with jacketed cable. Jacketed cable has heavier insulation which is less susceptible to fretting. The plant's normal transformers were inspected and similar wiring was found in ideal condition. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) YEAR r SEQUENTIAl IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>20F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (&quot;mote space is required, use additional copies ofNRC Fonn 366A) (17) Event Description On June 30, 2003 at 0918 hours, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) experienced a main turbine trip followed by an automatic reactor scram. The plant was operating at approximately 79% power prior to the scram. The plant had recently commenced power operation on June 28,2003, after completing the R16 refueling outage. As a result of the scram, all control rods fully inserted and the plant was brought to Mode 4. Plant personnel collected data on the plant trip. It was noted that only a single main transformer differential relay target was found tripped, indicating that a true differential current fault condition probably did not occur. Additional troubleshooting inspected the current transformer (CT) circuits for non-design grounds (CTs are designed with a single point grounded). The circuits of all three main transformer phases that input into the 87TM/A, 87TMIB, and 87TM/C differential current relays were tested for grounds after the designed ground had been lifted. One of the circuits was still grounded indicating the presence of a nondesign ground. Further troubleshooting revealed that the ground was on a wire in the CT circuit of the 'A' phase input to both the 87TM/ A and 87TMIB relays. Inspections of the CT circuit wiring revealed that the grounded wire and two other wires in the same conduit run showed surface damage due to fretting. Therewas no damage noted in other transformer wire bundles that were inspected. The fault was found in a vertical run of conduit. The particular type of wire used was a thermoplastic insulated wire with a nylon outer jacket, rated at 90°C. Approximately one inch of the outer jacket was stripped, a portion of the thermoplastic insulation was damaged, and a small spot of copper conductor was exposed. The failed wire was not found to be pulled tight or forced against a conduit access box inner surface upon inspection. There is no record of any maintenance on these wires since original installation ofthe equipment. Cause of Event The root cause of this event is the use ofnon-jacketed cable (single conductor wiring) that was more prone to failure through fretting action.· The insulation fretting damage was caused when the wire came into contact with the inner surface of a conduit access box while in relative motion. The relative motion was caused by vibration from the transformer and other adjacent equipment such as cooler group pumps and fans. </TH></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET(2) </TD><TD>.YEAR SEQUEtmAL REVISION r LER NUMBER (6.), I NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>PAGE(3J </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>30F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD></TR><TR><TH>A contributing cause of this event was a limited extent of condition evaluation leading to ineffective corrective actions in response to a similar event in June 2000. In the previous event, a plant scram occurred due to a grounded CT. The cause of the ground was fretting at a tight elbow in the conduit. The previous corrective actions failed to prevent the event described in this LER because there was a narrow focus on bends in the conduit runs where wire may have been pulled tight across an edge, and not in vertical runs of conduit. Safety Significance This event posed no threat to the health and safety of the public or plant personnel. All safety equipment was available during this transient and performed as expected.. Generator load rejection is bounded by the plant safety analysis. The plant trip was accompanied·by a loss of one feed pump turbine due to a Reactor High Water LevelS trip. Operations staff restarted the feed pump, and the balance of the plant shutdown to Mode 4 was uneventful. Corrective Actions The primary corrective action was to replace the CT conductors for main transformers TR-Ml, M2 and M4 with jacketed cable. This provides a cable with heavier insulation that is less susceptible to fretting damage during installation and operation. In addition, the CT wiring for the normal transformers and the main generator was inspected, with no fretting damage observed. Further Corrective Actions Current transformer wiring circuits that are: 1) associated with safety and non safety-related components; 2) may be subject to fretting wear; and 3) whose failure could prevent equipment operation or cause a spurious trip, will be analyzed, inspected, and repaired or replaced as necessary during the current operating cycle and upcoming R17 refueling outage. Previous Similar Events As previously discussed, on June 26, 2000, a similar event occurred at Columbia when a plant scram occurred due to· a grounded CT (LER 2000-003-(0). The cause of the ground was fretting at a tight elbow in the conduit. The previous corrective actions associated the June 2000 event failed to prevent the event discussed in this LER because there was a narrow focus on the failure. In the June 2000 event, bend areas were inspected and the failed wire was repaired. For the event discussed in this LERthe failure was found in a vertical run of conduit that was not previously investigated. </TH></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_08_28_ML032550326_img_6.jpg"/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) </TH><TH>u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME_(1). </TH><TD/><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>YEAR r LER NUMBER (6) I SEQUENTIAL REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD/><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>40F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-007.(l() </TD></TR><TR><TH>EllS InformationText Reference Main Turbine Main Transformer Differential Relay </TH><TD>System TA EL EL Component TRB XFMR RLY-87 </TD></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>