<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2003-08-14T14:58:31-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2003-08-14T14:58:31-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2003-08-14T14:58:31-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Part><H1>·EItfERGY 
</H1><Sect><H4>NORTHWEST </H4><P>p.o. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>August 7,2003 </P><P>G02-03-121 </P><P>. U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATIN:Document·Control·Desk· 
Washington, D.C.20555-000t. ::' -'-</P><P>.__S...,.,ubjeg; </P><P>COLUMBIA.GENERATING__ .8TATION&quot;._.JlOCKET NO. 50-397;LICEN'SEEEVENT.REP&lt;&gt;IiT 2003~04-O0 .... -'C.•.. '.. </P><P>. Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>.----</P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee. Event Rep6rtNo. 2003-004-00 for Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR§50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). The report discusses items of repo~bilityand corr~tive actions ,taken•. </P><P>. : 	-~ -.:: =-~ </P><P>If you I:la~eany'questi~Ds{)rdesireaddit;onalinformationregarding this matter, please contact Ms.CLPennoat'{5(9) 377~2075.·· &quot;'c.:. &quot;.&quot;. : .. '. . </P><P>'. .'&quot; :.~ 	• • -&quot; &quot;-••~ &lt; -, </P><P>... ; .</P><P>. 	~ -.&quot; -:;~.'.. -~&lt;~&lt;~. </P><P>.. ~ ~&quot; ~ . ! </P><P>Respe~lly, ...., ,','&quot; </P></Sect><Sect><H1>'fft~.. </H1><P>RL Webring </P><P>~--.--........¥i~ideilt.·Nl!elea~:H'ti9lHJlI------'-----._.---_..._-Mail Drop PE04 </P><P>.. </P><P>&quot;. </P><P>Enclosure: . Licensee Event Report-2()(j3-004~ </P><P>cc: 	TP Gwynn -NRC -RlV 
BJ Benney -NRC -NRR 
</P><P>'. 	·INPO Records, Center.. '. , 
NRC Sr.~e~i~~nt Insp~or.·.988G ~(2). 
RN Sherman -BPA/1399 
TC Poindexter· -Winston &amp; Strawn 
WB Jones -:... NRC RIV/fax 
</P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_08_07_ML032260643_img_2.jpg"/>~ NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3160-0104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 (1-2001) COMMISSION estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory Informal/on collection request: 50 hours. Reported lessons leamed are Incorporated Into the licensing process and fed back to Industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T-8 E6). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washington DC LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) 20555'()001. or by Intemet e-mail to bls1@nrc.QOv, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150'()104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to Impose Information collection does digits/characters for each block) not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person Is not required to respond to, the Informal/on collection. FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) Columbia Generating Station 05000397 10F3 TITLE (4) Condition Prohibited by Technical Specifications Limiting Condition for Operation 3.10.4 EVENT DATE (5) LER NUMBER (6) REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED (8) MO YEAR ISEQUENTW.. REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER DAY YEAR NlJIlBER NO MO DAY YEAR 06 08 2003 2003 -004 -00 08 (J7 2003 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER --ePERATfNG&quot;-I 1'1 IS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSOANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR I: Check all that ap )Iy (11) MODE(S) &quot; 20.2201(b 20.2203 a 3 Ii) 50.73 a 2 Ii B) 50.73 a 2 ix)(A) POWER 20.2201(d 20.2203 a 4 50.73 a 2 iii 50.73 a 2 x) LEVEL (10) 000 20.2203 a)(1) 5O.36(c 1 1)1 At 50.73 a 2 M(Al 73.71 a 4 20.2203{a}(2)(I) 50'36(c){1 )(ii){A) 5O.73{a)(2)(v)(A) 73.71{a}(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 5O.36(c)(2) 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) Other 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 5O.46(a)(3)(ii) 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) Specify i1 Abstrad below or 20.2203(a 2)(iv) 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(A 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) in NRC Form 366A 20.2203 a 2lev) X 5O.73(a 21(i)(B 50.73(a 2)(vii 20.2203 al(2levi) 5O.73(a 2i)(C 50.73(a)' 2)(viii)(A) 20.2203 a (3 (I) 5O.73(a (2 (ii)(A) 50.73(a) 2)(viii )(B) LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER (12 NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Fred A. Schill (509) 377-:-2269 COMPLETE ONE UNE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT (13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TOEPIX FACTURER TOEPIX SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEARIYES (H yes. complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). SUBMISSION X NO DATE(1S) ABSTRACT (Linit to 1400 spaces. I.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) On June 8, 2003, with the reactor shutdown in mode 4 and the mode switch in the refuel position, a condition prohibited by the Columbia Generating Station Technical Specifications erJ5ted --&amp;peciHoally;=Fmieti&lt;m 'T:e&quot;&quot;ef Tebl~.9. 1.1&quot;1 ~as not operable ~ ~ &quot;''iU~~~1 -c· • operations Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO)-3.10.4.c.1. Function 7.a of Table 3.3.1.1-1 is the transmitter/trip unit instrumentation [LT]that initiates a Reactor Protection System (RPS) trip on high Scram Discharge Volume (SDV) water level.. This requirement of LeO 3.10.4 was not met because the transmitter/trip unit instrumentation on both SDVs was isolated in support of an SDV flushing procedure that was not in progress at the time. Special operations LCO 3.10.4 permits withdrawal of a single control rod for testing or maintenance and may be applied when the reactor is in cold shutdown. This LCO allows placing the reactor mode switch in the refuel position to enable the single control rod withdrawal permissive in order to perform control rod scram timing pursuant to Technical Specifications Surveillance Requirement 3.1.4.1 prior to reactor startup. The cause of the condition prohibited by Technical Specifications is attributed to human performance errors. No safety consequences were associated with the condition and redundant SDV float switches [LS] (Function 7.b) were operable to provide the RPS trip on high SDV level as required by LeO 3.10.4. This condition existed for approximately 5.5 hours during which time testing was performed on four control rods. </Figure><P>26158 Rl </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TD>NRC FORM 366A </TD><TD>U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TD></TR><TR><TD>(1-2001) </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TD></TR></Table><P>FACILITY NAME (1) </P><P>DOCKET (2) </P><P>LER NUMBER (6) </P><P>PAGE (3) </P><P><Figure ActualText="I "><ImageData src="images/2003_08_07_ML032260643_img_4.jpg"/>I </Figure>SEQUENTIAL I REVISION</P><P>YEAR </P><P>NUMBER NUMBER</P><P>05000397 </P><P>20F3</P><P>Columbia Generating Station </P><P>2003-004-00 </P><P>-</P><P>~ </P><P>NARRATIVE (N more space is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) </P><P>Event Description </P><P>On June 3, 2003, with the reactor shutdown in mode 4 and the mode switch in the refuel position, a condition prohibited by the Columbia Generating Station Technical Specifications existed. Specifically, Function 7.a of Table 3.3.1.1-1 was not operable as required by special operations Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.10.4.c.1. Function 7.a of Table </P><P>---43~.3l--.1......-t:t-t is the tIarJSmhter/trip-umt tilStrUfiientauon&quot;1Llf thit lIDfiares a Reactor ProlZ'e~'-cti&quot;&quot;'o-n----·~.-System (RPS) trip on high Scram Discharge Volume (SDV) water level. This requirement of LCO 3.10.4 was not met because the transmitter/trip unit instrumentation on both SDVs was isolated in support of an SDV flushing procedure that was not in progress at the time. Special operations LCO 3.10.4 permits withdrawal of a single control rod for testing or maintenance and may be applied when the reactor is in cold shutdown. This LCO allows placing the reactor mode switch in the refuel position to enable the single control rod withdrawal permissive in order to perform control rod scram timing pursuant to Technical Specifications Surveillance Requirement 3.1.4.1 prior to reactor startup. </P><P>Immediate Corrective Action </P><P>Upon discovery that all requirements of LCO 3.10.4 were not met, plant operators exited the condition of applicability for LCO 3.10.4. All control rods were inserted into the reactor core and the mode switch·was placed in the shutdown position preventing control rod withdrawal. Additionally, the SDV water level transmitter/trip unit·instrumentation was restored to service and a night order documenting this event and lessons learned was transmitted to all operating crews. </P><P>~--Uft1Sl&quot;l!e----------&quot;'------------~---&quot;&quot;'-'-----</P><P>.,',..,</P><P>. </P><P>. .... ~ </P><P>The cause of the condition prohibited· by. Technical Specifications is' attributed to human performance errors. These errors occurred during preparation of the procedure used for the SDV flushing activity and in assessing the impact of the flushing activity upon compliance with LCO 3.10.4. </P><P>Further Corrective Action </P><P>This event will be reviewed with all operations personnel and pre-job planners to convey the importance of thorough pre-job review of the scope of maintenance activities and assessment of Technical Specifications requirements when maintenance activities are performed. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/>-----------------------..,.,---------</Figure><P>~ ---------</P><P>.-.:..--~~---</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME 1 </TH><TD>DOCKET 2 </TD><TD>LERNUMBER 6 </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 30F3</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR SEQUENTIAL REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-004-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Assessment of Safety Consequences No safety consequences were associated with the condition prohibited by Technical Specifications and plant operators would have -been alerted to _increasing water level in the SDVs. As the water level in the SDV increases, a control room alarm is actuated followed by control rod withdraw block and a reactor scram. These functions would have been initiated by r~undant SD~floaLswitch~~.Jb§UFunction 7.~ 01. '4~!.H) tbatwere-DperabJe to ---provide the RPStrip-on h1gii SDV level as required by -LCO 3~10.4.. -The condition prohibited by Technical Specifications existed for approximately 5.5 hours during which time testing was performed on four control rods. The SDV is sized to receive and contain all of the water discharged by 185 control rod drives during a reactor scram. Because scram testing was performed on only four control rods, considerable margin existed to the water level at which alarms or automatic safety functions are initiated. Similar Events On May 2, 2001, Licensee Event Report 2001-002 reported a condition prohibited by Technical Specification LCO 3.3.l.1 existed due to a human performance error. This occurred when an SDV float switch instrument channel was not returned to service after performance of a 92-day Channel Functional Test. ~__'&gt;o&quot;&quot;-&quot;-~-.---_..-o..-....~~.....:..____~~__--_oo..;;-~.-_._-_&quot;&quot;'__-~........._....--_. -~.. </TH></TR></Table></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>