<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2003-12-19T14:51:24-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2003-12-19T14:51:24-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2003-12-19T14:51:24-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>EMERGY 
</H1><Sect><H5>NORTHWEST </H5><P>P.O. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>December 8, 2003 G02-03-181 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397; LICENSEE EVENT REPORT 2003-010-00 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Rep·ort No. 2003-010-00 for Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR § 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D). The report discusses items of reportability and corrective actions taken. </P><P>If you have any questions or desire additional information regarding this matter, please contact Ms. CL Perino at (509) 377-2075. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><P>Rt~ RL Webring Vice President, Nuclear Generation Mail Drop PE04 </P><P>Enclosure: Licensee· Event Report 2003-010-00 </P><P>cc: 	BS Mallet -NRC -RIV BJ Benney -NRC -NRR INPO Records Center NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) RN Sherman -BPAI1399 TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn WB Jones -NRC RIV Ifax </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>... </P><P>r ' </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_12_08_ML033530427_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 (1-2001) COMMISSION Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request 50 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T-6 E6). U.S. Nudear Regulatory Commission, Washington DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to bjs1@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer, Office of LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose information collection does digits/characters for each block) not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to. the information collection. FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) Columbia Generating Station 05000397 10F3 TITLE (4) Unanticipated Inoperability of the Single Train High Pressure Core Spray System EVENT DATE 5) LER NUMBERJ6 REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED (8) YEAR ISEQUENTIAL REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MO DAY YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 10 7 2003 2003 -010 -00 12 08 2003 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER OPERATING THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) (11) MODE (9) 1 20.2201(b) 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) POWER 20.2201 (d) 20.2203(aK41 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(x) LEVEL (10) 100 20.2203 (a 1(1) 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) 50. 73( a )(2)(iv A) 73.71 (a)(4) 20.2203 a 2), i) 50.36 c 1 ii)(A) 50.73 a 2)(v A 73.71 (a)(5) 20.2203 a 2), ii) 50.36 c 2 50.73 a 2)(v B Other 20.2203 a 2), iii) 50.46 a 3 ii 50.73 a 2)(v C Specify in Abstract below or 20.2203(a 2) iv) 50.73 a 2 i) A) X 50.73 a 2)(v)(D) in NRC Form 366A 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 50.73 a 2)1 'ilB) 50.73 a 2)(vii) 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 50.73(a), 2)(viii)(A) 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER (12) NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Fred A. Schill (509) 377-2269 COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT (13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TO EPIX FACTURER TOEPIX SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEARIYES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). SUBMISSION X NO DATE (15) ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) At 1231 on October 7, 2003, with the plant in mode 1, a depressurization of the High Pressure Core Spray (HPCS) system [BG] occurred while the HPCS system waterleg piping was isolated during an unscheduled maintenance activity to replace the power frame on the waterleg pump motor. System pressure unexpectedly decreased to below the low pressure alarm point requiring plant operators to remove fuses for the main HPCS pump and perform a system fill and vent procedure. These actions rendered the single train HPCS system inoperable. With the HPCS system inoperable, the action required by Technical Specifications Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.5.l.B to verify operability of the Reactor Core Isolation Cooling system [BN] and restore HPCS within 14 days was taken. Approximately three hours later at 1538, after verifying the system was filled and vented, and the pump fuses reinstalled, the HPCS system was declared operable and all requirements of LCO 3.5.1 were met. The cause of this event is attributed to the judgment of control room operators who allowed the maintenance to proceed when contingency actions to be taken in the event of unexpected system conditions had not been preplanned. Prior to the maintenance, the control room operators developed contingency actions that were not adequate to manage a rapid depressurization of the HPCS system. There were no safety consequences associated with the inoperable HPCS system and this event did not represent an actual loss of a safety function for greater than the time allowed by Technical Specifications. </Figure><P>26158 Rl </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001 ) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 20F3</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL JREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-010-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (/fmore space is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) Event Description At 1231 on October 7,2003, with the plant in mode 1, a depressurization of the High Pressure Core Spray (HPCS) system [BG] occurred while the HPCS system waterleg piping was isolated during an unscheduled maintenance activity to replace the power frame on the water leg pump motor. System pressure unexpectedly decreased to below the low pressure alarm point requiring plant operators to remove fuses for the main HPCS pump and perform a system fill and vent procedure. These actions rendered the single train HPCS system inoperable. Immediate Corrective Action With the HPCS system inoperable, the action required by Technical Specifications Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.5.1.B to verify operability of the Reactor Core Isolation Cooling (RCIC) system [BN] and restore HPCS within 14 days was taken. Approximately three hours later at 1538, after verifying the system was filled and vented, and the pump fuses reinstalled, the HPCS system was operable and all requirements ofLCO 3.5.1 were met. As an additional measure, control room operators have been instructed to maintain an oversight role of maintenance activities and be less involved in the work planning process. Root Cause The cause of this event is attributed to the judgment of control room operators who allowed the unscheduled maintenance to proceed when contingency actions to be taken in the event of unexpected system conditions had not been pre-planned. Currently, development of contingency plans is included in the work planning process only for higher risk maintenance activities. In this case, plant operators developed the contingency plan during a pre-job briefing that was conducted just prior to performance of the maintenance activity. The operator's plan was to start the main HPCS pump (HPCS-P-l) if system pressure decreased significantly (to below -80 psi) from the initial pressure of approximately 105 psi while the power frame was being replaced. However, the system pressure decreased more rapidly than expected and HPCS-P-l could not be started before the low-pressure alarm actuated. Alternatives to the operator's contingency plan that would not have resulted in a reportable event would be to run HPCS-P-l during the power frame replacement to maintain system pressure or remove the HPCS system from service in accordance with approved procedures and Technical Specifications prior to maintenance. </TH></TR></Table><P>r&quot; .... .... </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001 ) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKETJ2). </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 30F3</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER IREVISION </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-010-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Further Corrective Action The work planning process will be revised to ensure unscheduled (emergent) work will receive the same level of rigor for assessing potential risks as normally scheduled maintenance acti v iti es . Assessment of Safety Consequences There were no safety consequences associated with this event and the HPCS system was not inoperable for greater than the 14-day outage time allowed by Technical Specifications. Additionally, the independent RCIC system was available to perform the safety function of high-pressure injection during the time HPCS was inoperable. Similar Events There have been no previous similar events in which a condition reportable pursuant to 10 CFR § 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) existed due to allowing maintenance to be conducted without pre-planned contingency actions. </TH></TR></Table></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>