<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2003-06-20T12:00:32-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2003-06-20T12:00:32-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2003-06-20T12:00:32-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>EMERGY 
</H1><Sect><H5>NORTHWEST </H5><P>p.o. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>Iune 13, 2003 
G02-03-100 
</P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>-&quot;'-~~----~---</P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION,-nOCKEt NO. 5(f-J97,-LICENSE NO. NPF-21; 3D-DAY FOLLOW-UP REPORT REGARDING EVENT NOTIFICATION 39852 </P><P>Dear Sir or -Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is the 3O-day follow-up report for the subject event notification pursuant to 10 CFR 73.71(b)(2) in accordance with paragraph (a)(4) of that section. </P><P>Should you have any questions or desire additional information regarding this matter. please call Ms. CL Perino at (509) 377-2075. </P><P>. '/ . </P><P>Respectfully, </P></Sect></Part><Part><H1>&amp;.20.~ </H1><P>DW Coleman, Manager Performance Assessment and Regulatory Programs _________M~pr~_?~_20~__ </P><P>Attachment </P><P>cc: 	TP Gwynn -NRC -RIV TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C BJ Benney -NRC -NRR RN Sherman -BPAIl399 </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>--.</P><P>-</P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2003_06_13_ML031710547_img_1.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150~104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 (1-2001) COMMISSION Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T..s Eel, u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington DC 20555-0001, or by Intemet e-mail to bjs1@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose Information collection does digits/characters for each block) not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the Information collection. FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) Columbia Generating Station 50-397 10F4 TITLE (4) Vulnerability in a Safeguards System that Could have Allowed Unauthorized or Undetected Access to a Protected Area EVENT DATE 5) LER NUMBER (6) REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED (8) YEAR ISEQUENTIAL REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MO DAY YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 05 15 2003 2003 -002 -00 06 13 2003 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER OPERAnNG__ 6~ THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that ap)/y (11) MODE (9) 20.2201(b) -. &quot;U.&quot;&quot;U~la)(3)(II) -:1S(e)R){it)(B}---...n ix)(A). POWER 0% 20.2201 (d) 20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73 a 2lex) LEVEL (10) 20.2203 (a)(1) 50.36 c)(1 )(i)(A) 50.7~(a)(2)(iv)(A) X 73.71 a 4 20.2203 a 2i) 50.36 c 1 ii)(A) 50.73 a 2 v A 73.71 (a)(5 20.2203 a 2 ii 50.36 c 2 50.73 a 2 v B Other 20.2203 a 2 iii) 50.46 a 3 ii 50.73 a 2 v C Specify il Abstract below or 20.2203 a 2 iv) 50.73 a 2 i A) 50.73 a 2 v D in NRC Fonn 366A 20.2203 a 2 v 50.73 a 2 i B) 50.73 a 2 vii 20.2203 a1(2)1 vi) 50.73 a 2 n(C) 50.73 a 2 viii)(A) 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER {12} NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Fred A. Schill (509) 377-2269 COMPLETE ONE UNE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT (13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TOEPIX FACTURER TO EPIX SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEARIYES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). ~ SUBMISSION NO DATE (15) ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) (16) On May 15, 2003, with Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) shut down for a refueling outage, a vulnerability in a safeguards system was discovered that could have allowed ---.-unauthorized-ortmdetected llCcess-to--the-C-olumbia protected area (ref:-Event-Report&quot;39852)T-llle_ --vulnerability existed due to a Safeguards Information (SGI) container that was determined to be unlocked and unattended for a period of approximately 24 hours. The unlocked SGI container allowed access to site-specific drawings, diagrams, and technical details regarding the physical security system that could facilitate access to the protected and vital areas. Subsequent to discovery of the vulnerability, the contents were inventoried and fully accounted for. The SGI container is located in a room for which access is controlled with a keycard reader and there was no evidence of forced entry. Neither is there indication the vulnerable condition resulted in an actual unauthorized or undetected entry into the protected area nor has this event presented a challenge to the safe operation of Columbia. </Figure><P>j. </P><P>~-</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001 ) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) .~ &quot; </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 20F4 --</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTlAL NUMBER NUMBER IREVISION </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-002-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) (17) DESCRIPTION OF EVENT On May 15, 2003, with Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) shut down for a refueling outage, a vulnerability in a safeguards system was discovered that could have allowed unauthorized or undetected access to the Columbia protected area (ref: Event Report 39852). The , . . vulnerability existed due to a Safeguards Information (SGI) container that was determined to be , -.. --UDIocked' and'tmattendOO1&quot;orapenodof1lPproxiInately-24'hours:-'The . unlocked -5GI-oontainer ---Iallowed access to site-specific drawings, diagrams, and technical details regarding the physical security system that could facilitate access to the protected and vital areas. Subsequent to discovery of the vulnerability, the contents were inventoried and fully accounted for. The SGI container is located in a room for which access is controlled with a keycard reader and there was no evidence of forced entry. Neither is there indication the vulnerable condition resulted in an actual unauthorized or undetected entry into the protected area nor has this event presented a challenge to the safe operation of Columbia. This 30-day follow-up written report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 73.71(b)(2) in accordance with paragraph (a)(4) of that section. Regulatory Guide 5.62, revision I, section 3.2 instructs licensees to use the Licensee Event Report form, NRC Form 366 and describes the report content that is sufficient for NRC analysis and evaluation. Because this event does not involve a security system failure or a threat related incident, only items 1 through 14 in section 3.2 of the Regulatory Guide are germane to this issue and are addressed below: Date and Time of Event May-15,-2003~t 13-1S.PDT. . -Location of Actual or Threatened Event The SGI container that was open and unattended is in a plant records storage area in a building adjacent to Columbia's protected area and within the owner controlled area. Plant Operating Phase Columbia Generating Station was shutdown for a refueling outage. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 30F4</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-002-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Safety Systems Threatened, directly or indirectly Because the vulnerability did not result in an actual unauthorized entry into the protected area, no safety systems were threatened. Type of Security Force onsite ~--~------~---------.. -------~------.---------------.-------Columbia Generating Station maintains a proprietary security force. Number and type of personnel involved The personnel involved with the discovery and mitigation of the vulnerability were a records management clerk, distribution clerk, records management supervisor, and a safeguards information specialist. Method of discovery of vulnerability A records management clerk observed the unlocked and unattended SGI container and reported the condition. FToceduralerrorsinvolved A records management clerk left the SGI container unlocked and unattended. The unlocked SGI container was a violation of security procedure SWP-SEC-02, &quot;Protection of Safeguards Information. &quot; ImmediateaCtions takenlii reSI)()flSeto-tneVuInerability Upon discovery of the vulnerability, the contents were inventoried, fully accounted for, and the SGI container secured. The security computer was queried to determine the scope of keycard access to the room during the time the SGI container was unlocked. Personnel that gained access to the room were either cleared for access to SGI or were escorted by SGI-cleared individuals. Local copiers were checked to determine usage during the tjrne the SGI container was unlocked and unattended. This investigation revealed no copier usage during the period. </TH></TR></Table><P>_..... 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 40F4</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>50-397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2003-002-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Corrective actions taken or planned All Energy Northwest employees having access to SGI will receive training on protection of SGI with emphasis on this event to promote awareness of the potential consequences of unlocked and unsecured safeguards containers. -----LocaI,-8tate-,-orFederal.JaW-enforcement agencies -contacteL____._ -------No local, State, or Federal law enforcement agencies were contacted regarding this condition. Description of media interest or press release A press release was not issued regarding this condition and there has been no media interest. Indication of previous similar events No indication of previous similar events that could have allowed unauthorized or undetected access to the Columbia Generating Station protected area due to an unsecured SGI container have been found. Knowledgeable contact For questions or additional information the point of contact is Mr. Fred Schill at the Columbia Generating Station Licensing department, who may be reached by telephone at 509-377-2269. ._</TH></TR></Table><P>26158 Rl </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>