<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2004-04-27T11:40:48-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2004-04-27T11:40:48-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2004-04-27T11:40:48-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>EItfERGY 
</H1><Sect><H5>NORTHWEST </H5><P>P.O. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>April 20, 2004 </P><P>G02-04-075 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATIN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397 LICENSEE EVEl\TT REPORT NO. 2004-002-00 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2004-002-00 for the Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D). The enclosed report discusses items of reportability and corrective actions taken. </P><P>If you -hav,e-'any questions' or' require additional information, please contact Ms. CL Perino at </P><P>(509) 377-2075.' .' '. ,', . </P><P>Respectfully, </P></Sect></Part><Part><H1>-R(~</H1><P>RL Webring Vice President, Nuclear Generation Mail Drop PE04 </P><P>. -</P><P>Enclosure: Licensee Event Report 2004-002-00 </P><P>cc: BS Mallett -NRC RIV \VA Macon -NRC-NRR INPO Records Center NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) RN Sherman -BPAI1399 TC ,Poindexter -\Vinston &amp; Strawn WB'Jones -NRC RIV/fax </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>'. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2004_04_20_ML041180303_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 6-30-2001 (1-2001) COMMISSION Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory Information collection request 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated Into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimale 10 the Records Management Branch (T.6 E6). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washington DC 20555-0001. or by Intemet e·mail to bjs1@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer, Office of LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202 (3150-0104). Office of Management and (See reverse for required number of Budget. Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to Impose Information collection does digits/characters for each block) not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to. the Information collection. FACILITY NAME (1) DOCKET NUMBER (2) PAGE (3) Columbia Generating Station 05000397 10F4 TITLE (4) Reactor Core Isolation Cooling Declared Inoperable Due to Relay Failure EVENT DATE 5) LER NUMBER (6) REPORT DATE (7) OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED (8) YEAR ISEQUENTIAL REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MO DAY YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 02 21 2004 2004 02 00 04 20 2004 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER OPERATING 1 THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply (11) MODE (9) 20.2201 (b) 20.2203 a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a )(2)(ii)(B) 50.73 a 2 l(ix)(A) POWER 100 20.2201 (d) 20.2203 a){4) 50.73{a )(2){iii) 50.73 a 2I{X) LEVEL (10) 20.2203 (a){1) 50.36{c) 1)(i)(A) 50.73{a )(2)(iv){A) 73.71 a 4 20.220~a){2){iL 50.36Lc 1)@LAl 50.73(aJ(2)(v)(A 73.71 a 5 20.220:Ka)(2)(iil 50.36{g{2) 50.73(C3}i2) (v)(Bi Other 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 50.46(a)(3)(ii) . 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C Specify i1 Abstract below or 20.2203{a)(2){iv) 50.73{a){2){i){A) X 50.73{a)(2)(v){D in NRC Form 366A 20.2203(a)(2){v) 50.73(a)(2){i)(B) 50.73(a)(2){vii) 20.22031a)(2)(vi) 50.73{a)(2){i){C) 50.73{a){2){viii)(A) 20.2203{a)(3j(i) 50.73(aj(2j(iij(A) 50.73(a)(2)(viiij(B) LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER 12) NAME JTELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Craig D. Sly; Principal Engineer -Licensing 509-377-8616 COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT (13) CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU· REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU· REPORTABLE FACTURER TO EPIX FACTURER TO EPIX E BN 27 ITE Y SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED (14) EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEARIYES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). SUBMISSION X NO DATE (15) ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single·spaced typewritten lines) (16) On February 21,2004, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) was in Mode 1 with the reactor operating at approximately 100 percent rated thermal power. At approximately 08:41 the Reactor Core __ -Isolation_Cooling .(RCIC) system was declared inoperable due to a loss of control power to the RCIC reactor pressure vessel injection valve (RCIC-V-i3).-Thecausewasarailure of a normally energized-'-under-voltage relay. The function of the relay is to sense a loss of voltage to the valve motor operator, interrupt valve control power and provide annunciation in the control room. The relay failed due to a failed relay coil that was subjected to long-term heating. Previous reviews to identify relays that should be periodically replaced did not capture this relay because it had no equipment part number and was not included in the master equipment list, the database used to conduct these reviews. This event posed no threat to the health and safety of the public or plant personnel. The failed relay was replaced and the RCIC system returned to operable status in 12 hours 48 minutes. Thermography was performed on 43 relays in the DC distribution system and one relay was identified for replacement. Additional actions are planned to identify other relays in the DC distribution and selected portions of the 480 Volt AC systems that need periodic replacement. </Figure><P>::-&quot; '-..... </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1·2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>20F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2004-02-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required. use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) Description Of Event On February 21, 2004, Columbia Generating Station (Columbia) was in Mode 1 with the reactor operating at approximately 100 percent of rated thermal power. At approximately 08:41, the control room received alarms for Reactor Core Isolation Cooling System (RCIC) Division lOut Of Service and Motor Operated Valve Network Power Loss. Investigation found that motor operated valve RCICV-13 (RCIC reactor pressure vessel injection valve) position indication lights were deenergized, indicating a loss of control power. The RCIC system was declared inop,erable and the High Pressure ---Core Spray system (HPCS) andtheHPCS 'dedicated diesel-generator' (DG-3) were verified operable -andplaced in protected status. An operator was dispatched to investigate the problem and reported that the disconnects to the RCIC-V13 motor operator were shut and the overloads were reset. RCIC-V-13 still indicated deenergized in the control room. Maintenance was contacted and a work request was initiated to investigate. Maintenance determined that an under-voltage relay (27 relay) in the RCIC-V-13 motor starter (RCIC42-S21A5B) cubicle had failed. The function of this under-voltage relay is to sense a loss of voltage (250 Volts DC) to the valve motor operator and to interrupt the 125 V DC control power to the valve motor operator and provide .annunciation in the control room. In this case, the relay failure had the same effect as a loss of voltage to the valve motor operator. It was later determined that RCIC-V-13 motor operator power was available. However, the failed relay interrupted control power to the valve motor operator. A new relay was bench tested and installed. Operators verified the indication to RCIC-V-13 was working properly and declared the RCIC system operable on February 21,2004, at approximately 21:29. Cause of Event .----.-----,-------The relay that failed was an ITE Model J13P20 relay rated at 250 V DC. This particular relay is normally energized. A failure analysis determined the relay coil had failed due to a shorted coil and that the coil was subjected to long term heating. No evidence has been found to indicate this relay had been replaced prior to this event. A root cause analysis was performed and identified this relay was not included in the preventative maintenance program. During the 1990s, industry experience and plant operating experience identified that normally energized relay failures were occurring due to thermal aging (reference NRC Information Notice 92-27 and 92-27 Revision 2). Energy Northwest took action during this time period to review relay failure trends and determine what preventative actions were required. The reviews showed that Columbia had experienced failures of normally energized relays involving different manufacturers. As a result, critical relay types were identified and periodic replacement schedules were developed. The </TH></TR></Table><P>-&quot;&quot; ..-
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) YEAR r SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>30F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2004~2'()() </TD></TR><TR><TH>developed. The relay population reviewed were those that had unique identification numbers and were included in the plant Master Equipment List (MEL). The MEL includes plant components that have Equipment Part Numbers (EPNs). Not all plant sub-components have EPNs. The relay that failed during this event does not have a specific EPN. Therefore this relay was not in the MEL and was not captured during the reviews in the mid-1990s. Safety Significance ~-.----' -. The RCIC system is designed to operate either manually or automatically following reactor pressure vessel isolation accompanied by a loss of coolant flow from the feedwater system to provide adequate core cooling and control of reactor pressure vessel water level. Under these conditions, the HPCS and RCIC systems perform similar functions. After the loss of RCIC, control room operators entered Technical Specification (TS) Action Statement 3.5.3.A, which requires that with the RCIC inoperable, the High Pressure Core Spray must be verified operable immediately and the RCIC system restored to operable status within 14 days. Since the HPCS was operable and protected and the total duration of this event was approximately 12 hours 48 minutes, the TS requirements were satisfied. In addition, the relay failure did not affect the ability of the RCICV-13 to be controlled from the remote shutdown panel. Therefore, it is concluded that this event posed no threat to the health and safety of the public or plant personnel. This event is reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), &quot;Any event or condition that alone could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident. &quot; Immediate Corrctive Actions _._ ~C.ontrol room 9perators_entered and complied with TS Action Statement3.5.3.A,J:&gt;y-Yerifyingthat ______ HPCS W&quot;as operable. Operators then proceeded to protect HPCS and its dedicated diesel generator (DG-3). A work request was initiated, and the investigation determined that the reason for the loss of control power and indication to RCIC-V-13 was a failed undervoltage relay. The failed relay was replaced and the valve indication was verified to be working properly. RCIC-V-13 was inoperable for a period of approximately 12 hours and 48 minutes. Further Corrective Actions 1. Thermography was performed on 43 installed normally energized relays in the DC distribution system. One relay was found to be approximately 18 degrees Farenheight warmer than the others of the same voltage rating. A work request was written to replace this relay. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) YEAR r SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>PAGE (3) </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>40F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2004-02-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>2. Work requests will be generated to replace the currently known normally energized relays in the DC distribution system that do not have EPNs. 3. DC switchgear drawings will be reviewed to identify other normally energized relays and work requests will be created to replace any new relays that are found. Preventative Manitenance procedures (PMs) will be developed or enhanced to replace any additional normally energized relays identified in DC switchgear. 4. A selected population of 480 V AC switchgear drawings will be reviewed to search for normally _. __ ---energized relays that do not have EPNs. Any relays identified will be replaced &quot;as necessary&quot;and PMs----.developed as necessary. &quot;&quot;&quot; . 5. Other selected DC system equipment, such as battery chargers and inverters, will be reviewed to identify normally energized relays that should be periodically replaced and PMs developed as necessary. Previous Similar Events This is the second known event involving this relay manufacturer/model or similar model at Columbia Generating Station. Maintenance Work Request (MWR) AS0640 replaced a defective undervoltage relay in the DC switchgear for RCIC-V-I9 in June 1989. However, the exact relay failure mechanism was not described in the MWR. There has been one previous reportable event due to a relay failure at Columbia Generating Station. LER 397/95-006, Revision I, describes a reactor scram which occurred on AprilS, 1996, during performance of a surveillance test of the of the high reactor water level turbine trip channel B logic. This scram occurred because a normally energized Agastat relay in the redundant channel A logic had previously failed in an intermediate position. Text Reference _._.-._. ---.. ---~--&quot;. System &quot;~ ComponeIlt _ Reactor Core Isolation Cooling System High Pressure Core Spray System RCIC-V-I3 Diesel Generator-3 RCIC-42-S2IA5B Under-voltage relay BN BG BN BN BN BN INV DG MSTR 27 </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>