<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2004-03-31T10:58:32-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2004-03-31T10:58:32-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2004-03-31T10:58:32-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>EMERGY 
</H1><Sect><H5>NORTHWEST </H5><P>p.o. Box 968 • Richland, Washington 99352-0968 </P><P>March 23, 2004 G02-04-048 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATIN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397 LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO~ 2004-001-00 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2004-001-00 for the Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(vii). The enclosed report discusses items of reportability and corrective actions taken. </P><P>If you have .any questions or· require additional information, please con~act Ms. CL Perino at </P><P>(509) 377~2075. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>DK Atkinson Vice President, Technical Services Mail Drop PE08 </P><P>--~---. </P><P>Enclosure: 1) Licensee Event Report 2004-001-00 </P><P>cc: 	BS Mallet -NRC -RIV BJ Benney -NRC -NRR IN PO Records Center NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) RN Sherman -BPAI1399 TC Poindexter -Winston &amp; Strawn WB Jones -NRC RIV/fax </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>..., .. -~ </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2004_03_23_ML040910195_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 (7-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 7-31·2004 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request 50 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated into the ficensing process and fed back to Industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records Management Branch (T-6 E6). U.S. Nuclea' Regulatory Commission. Washington DC 20555-0001, 0( by Intemet e·mail to bisl@nrcgov, and \0 \lie Desk Officer, Office of Infonnation and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB·l0202 (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to Impose Information conection does not display a currenUy vafid OMB control number, \lie NRC mat nol conduct or sponsor. and aperson Is nol required 10 respond 10. the information collection. LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for requIred number of diqitslcharacters for each block) 1. FACIUTY NAME Columbia Generating Station 4. TITLE 2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000397 3. PAGE 10F3 Unanticipated inoperability of both Control Room Emergency Filtration (CREF) subsystems 5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED YEAR ISEQUENTIAl IREV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MO DAY YEAR NUMBER NO MO DAY YEAR 1 23 2004 2004 -001 -00 3 23 2004 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 9. OPERATING 1 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR : (Check alilhat apply) MODE 20.2201 (b) 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 10. POWER 100% 20.2201 (d) 20.2203 a)(4) 50.73 a 2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(x) -LEVEL 20.2203 (a)(1) 5O.36(c)11)(i)(A) 50.73 a 2)(lv)(A) 73.71(a)(4) 12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER NAME Pamela K. Ankrum ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) (509) 377-4513 13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE '., MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TO EPIX ~.; I--_CA_U_S_E~I--_SY_S_T_EM_-+-C_O_M_PO_N_ENT--I--=-FA:.::C:.:.TU.:.:Rc:::E::.:R-I-_T.:.:O:.,:E:.:,.P:.;.IX---I 14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEARIYES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). X NO 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE 16. ABSTRACT (LImit to 1400 spaces, I.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) At 1315 on January 23, 2004, with the plant in Mode 1 at approximately 100 percent rated thermal power, it was determined that a condition prohibited by the Columbia Generating Station Technical Specifications (TS) existed from 1500 on October 27 through 2100 on October 29,2003 and from 1305 on November 10 through 1052 on November 11,2003 when testing was conducted to measure control room in-leakage. During this test, common ducts for both Control Room Emergency Filtration (CREF) __sub§ystems were_breached multiple times by removing duct access panels to install and remove test . equipment. During the time-ihe access panels were removed:B:flowpath was created'Uiat'would-have'-challenged the CREF's ability to pressurize the control room and mitigate the consequences of an . accident. Both CREF subsystems were determined to have been inoperable when the access panels were removed. With two CREF subsystems inoperable, TS 3.7.3 directs immediate entry into TS Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.0.3. The fact that removing the access panels caused both CREF subsystems to become inoperable was not recognized at the time the tests were performed because the HV AC ducts were allowed to be breached for short periods of time by the plant barrier impairments procedure. The cause of this event is attributed to inadequate guidance in the Columtiia Generating Station barrier impairment procedure. The cause of the inadequate guidance in the procedure was a lack of understanding of regulatory guidance associated with barrier impairments. </Figure><P>26158 RI </P><P>r;-~: \~ i· ~.,. (':' '. ':.. </P><P>... . -'l. . &quot;:,':' </P><P>.. : .~: ~ ~ -&quot;. : </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) IREVISION </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 20F3</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2004 001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE (Ifmore space is required, use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) DESCRIPTION OF EVENT At 1315 on January 23,2004, with the plant in Mode 1 at approximately 100 percent rated thermal power, it was determined that a condition prohibited by the Columbia Generating Station Technical Specifications (TS) existed from 1500 on October 27 through 2100 on October 29,2003 and from 1305 on November 10 through 1052 on November 11, 2003 when testing was conducted to measure control room in-leakage. The test employed ANSI N51O-1989 component test methodology and was not a __ routine surveillance ..During.preparationjor and restoration from this test,.theapproved-test.procedure ___ allowed common ductS for bath-Control Room Emergency Filtration (CREF) subsystems to be breached by removing duct access panels. The access panels were removed to allow installation and removal of test equipment. During the time that the access panels were removed, an airflow path was created that would have challenged the ability of both CREF subsystems to pressurize the control room to the pressure required by the TS. Since the extent of the system challenge could not be determined, both CREF subsystems were conservatively determined to have been inoperable when the access panels were removed. With two CREF subsystems inoperable TS 3.7.3, Required Action 0.1, directs immediate entry into TS Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.0.3. TS LCO 3.0.3 requires actions to be initiated within one hour to place the plant in applicable modes. It was not recognized at the time the tests were performed that both CREF subsystems were inoperable because removal of access panels was allowed by the plant barrier impairments procedure. This procedure allowed the access panels to be removed provided the breach was continuously attended and could be restored quickly. During performance of the test, the subsystem being tested was tagged out of service and the applicable TS Action Statement was entered for that subsystem. ASSESSMENT OF SAFETY CONSEQUENCES The CREF System is designed to provid'e a radiologically controlled environment to ensure the habitability of the control room for the safety of control room operators under all plant conditions . . Because there·was·no demand·to pressurize.the.main.control.room.with.filtered.air •. there were.no actual _ safety consequences assOCiated with bolli CREF subsystems being rendered inoperable. Since the duct -breach was continuously attended and could have. been restored quickly if the CREF system was called upon, there is a reasonable expectation that the CREF system would have been able to perform its safety function. It is expected that the system would have been restored within a short time period to keep dose to Control Room personnel within regulatory limits. This eveI!t is considered reportable in accordance with 10 CFR § 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) and 10 CFR § 50.73(a)(2)(vii). IMMEDIATE CORRECTIVE ACTIONS This event was discovered during a review of test documents after the test was completed. At the time of discovery, the testing was complete and the CREF system was in a normal standby configuration. </TH></TR></Table><P>,;.-.. &quot;. . </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2004_03_23_ML040910195_img_4.jpg"/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME (1) </TH><TD>DOCKET (2) </TD><TD>LER NUMBER (6) IREVISION </TD><TD>PAGE (3) 30F3</TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TD>2004 001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>A Stop Work Order was generated to ensure that breaches of plant systems and barriers were performed in accordance with regulatory requirements and guidance. Procedures and model work order instructions related to Control Room HV AC were reviewed to identify those activities that, if implemented as written, could challenge CREF system operability or result in conditions prohibited by TS. CAUSE OF THE EVENT The cause of this event is attributed to jnadequate . and incorrect guidance in .the .Columbia Generating ___--Station barrier impairment process' and proCedures: . The cause of the inadequate guidance in the procedure was a lack of understanding of regulatory guidance associated with barrier impairments. ACTIONS TO PREVENT RECURRENCE The Barrier Impairment procedure will be modified to clarify equipment operability requirements, to further reinforce the need for a thorough risk assessment of hazard barrier breaches, and to ensure other types of hazard barrier breaches do not result in violating TS requirements. Other procedures were reviewed for similar vulnerabilities. Several procedures were identified that referenced the Barrier Impairment procedure and/or had similar wording. These procedures have been corrected, are temporarily deactivated, or a Stop Work Order has been issued until adequate corrections have been implemented. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS LER 203-012-00 describes a previous similar event in which a condition reportable pursuant to 10 CFR § 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) and 10 CFR § 50.73(a)(2)(vii) existed. On November 4,2003, with the plant in Mode 1, it was determined that a condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of a safety function needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident had existed on November 1, 2003. This condition occurred when the normal and both remote outside air intakes for the CREF system were manually isolated for a period of.approx~ma~ely 4 !lours during testing.to.measure£ontrol.roomjn:le~~_age._In ~i~~onfiguraJi~I!,__ the CREF system cannot perform its design safety Junction to pressurize the main control room with filtered air as described in Columbia's accident analysis. The cause of this event is attributed to inadequate preparation and review of the test procedure used to measure control room in';'leakage. An Energy Northwest team investigating the root cause for the event described in LER 203-012-00 discovered the event described in this LER. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158 Rl </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>