<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2005-05-17T13:49:06-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2005-05-17T13:49:06-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2005-05-17T13:49:06-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:04676a96-fdff-4a1a-9e48-330c6724ef71</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:69228562-5ab4-ee47-a1fb-7a360728b0a4</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H2>@ENERGY</H2><Sect><H2>'®NORTHWEST </H2><P>People· Vision· Solutions </P><P>P.O. Box 968 • Richland, WA • 99352-0968 </P><P>May 10, 2005 </P><P>G02-05-089 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
</P><P>-----_._----------. -----&quot; ... ----_. -.---</P><P>..-Washington,&quot;D.C.-20555-0001--------~ ---	\ I </P><P>~ .&quot; ..&quot;.. ,-.. </P><P>Subject: 	COLUMBIA GENERATING'STATION, DOCKET NO. 50-397 
LICENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2005-002-00 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Licensee Event Report No. 2005-002-00 for the Columbia 
Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) and 10 
CFR50.73(a)(2)(v)(D).. The ~nclosed report discusses items of reportability and 
corrective. actions taken~ '. , . 
</P><P>If you have any questions' or require additional information, please contact Mr. GV Cullen </P><P>at (509) 377-6105. </P><P>Respectfully, </P></Sect></Part><Part><H1>wsoul/~</H1><P>Vice President,Technical-Services--</P><P>Mail Drop PE04 -	. </P><P>Enclosure: Licensee Event Report 2005-002-00 </P><P>cc: BS Mallett -NRC RIV 
BJ Benney -NRC-NRR 
INPO Records Center 
NRC Sr. Resident Inspector -988C (2) 
RN Sherman -BPAl1399 -. . . -.. 
</P><P>WA Horin -Winston &amp; Strawn 
'WB Jones &quot;':'. NRC RIV/fax -. .
</P><P>'.. '. . .; 	.'.: .' &quot;. <Figure ActualText=".. "><ImageData src="images/2005_05_10_ML051370438_img_0.jpg"/>...</Figure>,..... </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>: </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (6-2004) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150'()104 EXPIRES 6-30·2007 Estimated burden per response 10 comply with this mandalory collection request: 50 hours. Reported lessons leamed are Incorporated Into the licensing process and fed back 10 Industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch (T-5 F52). U.S. Nudear Regulatory Commission. Washington DC 20555-0001. or by Intemet e-mail 10 Infocollects@nrc.gov. and 10 the Desk Officer. Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. NEOB·10202 (3150'()104). Office of Management and Budget. Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to Impose an Information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person Is not required to respond 10. the Information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACIUTY NAME Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER OSOO0397 </TD><TD>3. PAGE lOF4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE High Pressure Core Spray System Inoperability Due to Cracks in the Pump Motor's Upper Air Deflector. </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACIUTIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>'IlONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER OSOOO </TD></TR><TR><TH>03 </TH><TD>16 </TD><TD>05 </TD><TD>2005·002·00 </TD><TD>05 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>05 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER OSOOO </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING _ -_ MODE 1 </TH><TD>·~·-:--11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT 'TOniE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check all that apply)o 2O.2201(b) o . 20.2203(a)(3)(i) . o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 5O.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 5O.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203 (a)(l) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 5O.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(iii) o 5O.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 2O.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 5O.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(x)o 2O.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 5O.36(c)(2) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4)o 2O.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 5O.46(a)(3)(ii) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5)o 2O.2203(a)(2)(v) o 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vl) ~ 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(B) ~ 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specily in Absttad below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>NAME IELEPHONE NUM8ER (Include Area Cede) Michael K. Brandon -Principal Engineer, Licensing 509·377-4758 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE UNE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU· FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TOEPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TOEPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>Maint </TH><TD>BG </TD><TD>MO </TD><TD>GE </TD><TD>Yes </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (Ifyes. complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ~ NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15single-spaced typewritten lines) On March 16, 2005, Energy Northwest took the High Pressure Core Spray (HPCS) pump out of service to investigate the source of a motor oil leak. During the course of this inspection, personnel _ . di~J~ov~Jed_cr~~ks in the J:!P...Q.S-,:~umpJlli&gt;tor uERer~rd~.uherooJ ca~se for_the degraded air deflector is critical dimensions were not maintained (Juring the motorreassembly process in'1992:---:-The degraded air deflector was removed and replaced within the completion time allowed 'by the Technical Specifications. Long term corrective actions include the development and implementation of a procedure to ensure Energy Northwest has or obtains the available critical information and vendor representation necessary to successfully perform major overhaul or refurbishment work on significant plant equipment. Prior to completing refueling outage17, a visual examination of selected large motors will be performed. This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of the public. Although this event is reported as a safety system functional failure, the ability and the duration of the system to perform its safety function in the as-found condition is the subject of a separate evaluation. By plant design, the emergency core cooling functions can be performed by several diverse systems that were not impacted by this condition. A similar event was reported by Energy Northwest as LER 92-025. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158 R2 </P><P>:'</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER IREVISION </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>20F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2005-002-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required. use additional copies ofNRC Form 366A) Plant Condition The plant was operating in Mode 1 at 100. percent power at the time of this event. Event Description At 0943 PST on March 16, 2005, the High Pressure Core Spray (HPCS) Rump [8.G:P] wa~_ . -taken 'outof&quot;service for~malnte-narfce·toinvestigate-thesourceofan-identified motor [MO] on-leak. During the course of this inspection, cracks in the HPCS pump motor upper air deflector were discovered. Energy Northwest personnel determined this constituted a condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of a safety function and was reported under 10 CFR 50.72(b}(3}(v}(D} (refer to event number 41499). Accordingly, this LER is provided in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) and as operations prohibited by the Technical Specifications in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8). Immediate Corrective Action Corrective actions were taken to restore the HPCS system to an operable status within the 14-day completion time provided in the Columbia Technical Specifications. The degraded air deflector was removed and replaced. To address the extent of condition for air deflector degradation, Energy Northwest reviewed the systems containing large vertical squirrel-cage induction style motors in safety related applications. Energy Northwest determined the design of the HPCS upper air deflector was unique with respect to other safety related motors for several reasons. Based on this determination, no immediate action for these other motors was deemed necessary. -.Cause-------~-._____-__-~____......_&gt; ___. _._______The root cause for the degraded air deflector is that critical dimensions were not maintained during the motor reassembly process in 1992 which led to clearance deficiencies between the motor rotor/fan assembly and the air deflector. Lack of detailed design drawings that included critical dimensions led to: • Incorrect planning for reassembly • Incorrect upper thrust bearing endplay (work order steps for a different bearing assembly was used) • Assembly methods that allowed excessive rotor overall travel that caused an up-thrust impact to the air-deflector and caused deformation, dimpling and displacement (air deflector not in rabbet groove) A significant contributing cause for the degraded air deflector is less than adequate control of critical dimensions during the manufacturing process which led to parts that did not meet manufacturer dimensional specifications. __ </TH></TR></Table><P>.:; :..:-:.:::-:-~ 
</P><P>-_.</P><P>._.. _ </P><P>&quot; </P><P>,, </P><P>, </P><P>---.,' </P><P>::-----~ </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>• 05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL NUMBER NUMBER I REVISION </TD><TD>30F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2005~OO2~OO </TD></TR><TR><TH>Further Corrective Action 1. Energy Northwest will develop and implement a site wide procedure and/or modify existing procedures to ensure Columbia has or obtains the available critical information and vendor representation necessary to successfully perform major overhaul or refurbishment work on significant plant equipment that is important to safety or plant reliability. &quot;&quot;'2.-~-'Pri6rtothe corripletio~of refuellng'outage-17 -(c~~~~nced-o~ M~;7:-2005), E.n'e~~~--Northwest will perform visual examination of selected large motors for indications of damage to air deflectors. Additional corrective actions are being pursued as identified in the Problem Evaluation Request 205-0175. Assessment of Safety Consequences HPCS is a part of the Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS). Its purpose is to supply water to the reactor vessel over a wide range of accident conditions. For small-break Loss of Coolant Accidents (LOCAs) that do not result in rapid reactor depressurization, the system is designed to maintain reactor water level. For large breaks, the system provides core spray cooling. The ECCS has built-in redundancy, and is comprised of High Pressure Core Spray (HPCS), Low Pressure Core Spray (LPCS) [8M], Low Pressure Coolant Injection (LPCI) [80] mode of the Residual Heat Removal (RHR) [80] system and the Automatic Depressurization System (ADS). Failure of the HPCS is bounded within the ECCS single failure analysis. The condition described in this report did not result in actual failure of HPCS during an event -when-itwas~required·to-operate.-,,:The·HPGS'motor·and'pump,have:been-successfu!lytestedand run num'erous times since 1992 when the air deflector replacement' was pertormed as .. discussed in the root cause analysis. The ability and duration of the system to perform its safety function in the as-found condition is the subject of a separate evaluation. This event did not adversely affect the health and safety of either the public or plant personnel. If the failure of HPCS had occurred during an actual event, the ECCS is designed to accommodate this failure and the ECCS safety function could still be performed. This event is reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), &quot;Any event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident.&quot; There were no structures, systems or components that were inoperable at the start of the event that contributed to the event. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1-2001) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Columbia Generating Station </TH><TD>05000397 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL J REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>40F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2005-002-00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Similar Events Energy Northwest performed a review of DE's, LER's, NPRDS/EPIX and Part 21 reports to . identify other industry experience in the area of failed air deflectors and oil leaks. For these searches, there were no recent similar events identified. However, a similar event involving the air deflector was reported for Columbia in 1992 (refer to LER 92-025). The conditions associated with the 1992 event and the corrective actions taken were reviewed in detail as part of the root cause investigation of this current failure. --;-&quot;-#_---,..------------.he root cause-analysis and~orre~tive-~cti~;;fi.~m this previous event did not prevent ' recurrence. This root cause analysis did not identify specific procedural or work instruction flaws or weaknesses. It also did not consider that the repair and reassembly performed in 1992 could be subjected to the same causes that resulted in the cracked air deflector at that time. The corrective actions included a review of the applicable procedures. This procedure review did not identify specific deficiencies in procedures involved in repairing the HPCS pump motor that can result in excessive uplift movement and forces. Since this procedure review did not detect any flaws or weaknesses in the applicable procedures, no procedure changes were made. EllS information denoted as [XX] _____ --_. 0..• __ , __ -._ ... --~----. </TH></TR></Table><P>26158 R2 </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>