<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<ler>
   <abstract>At 1949 on June 26, 2009, with Columbia operating at approximately 75% power, a small
      fire near the #2 high pressure turbine bearing was reported to the main control room. As
      directed by procedure, a manual scram was inserted at 1952. The in-service turbine lube oil
      vapor extractor system did not provide enough differential pressure to prevent lube oil from
      leaking out of the bearing pedestal. The fire occurred when the leaking lube oil came into
      contact with a hot pipe causing the oil to flash. The root causes were an out of calibration
      pressure switch and the integrated system knowledge of the main turbine lube oil exhauster
      system by Operations and Engineering was weak. The pressure switch has been replaced.
      Additional corrective actions taken to prevent recurrence include revisions to station
      procedures to ensure that the turbine lube oil vapor extractor system pressure is monitored
      via independent instruments during routine operator rounds as well as after any system
      manipulation. In addition, improvements in training for Operations and Engineering are planned
      to Iincrease overall system knowledge. No similar events have been reported by Energy
      Northwest.</abstract>

   <narrative>
      <plantCond>At the beginning of the time line described below, the plant was in Mode 1 at 43%
         power and was conducting startup activities. Power was raised to just above 75% at 0525 on
         6/26/09 and remained at that approximate power level until the manual scram was initiated
         at 1952 on 6/26/09.</plantCond>
      <eventDesc>On 6/25/09, between 0840 and 0900, two separate activities were conducted by
         personnel from maintenance and operations involving manipulations of the turbine lube oil
         [TO] system. The two activities performed in parallel were coincidental in timing, not
         intentional. The following activities are presented in the approximate sequence of events
         derived from alarm logs and interviews with the respective personnel: -Maintenance
         personnel were setting up to replace the Return Oil Basket Strainer [BSKT] for the turbine
         lube oil tank [TK] when the equipment operator arrived to support a swap of vapor
         extractors [VX]. -Operations secured the in-service turbine lube oil vapor extractor,
         TO-EX-1 B, in order to support the start of the other lube oil vapor extractor, TO-EX-1A.
         TO-EX-1A was being started to support a post maintenance test for the discharge valve of
         this vapor extractor. Maintenance noted an increase in oil overflow out of the basket
         strainer cover when TO-EX-1 B was secured. -TO-EX-1A tripped a few seconds after being
         started. -TO-EX-1 B was restarted by Operations personnel in the main control room, and the
         equipment operator in the field repositioned the inlet and outlet valves to the vapor
         extractor as per the normal operating procedure. Maintenance noted that the rate of oil
         overflow did not diminish when TO-EX-1 B was restarted. . -Maintenance removed the clogged
         basket strainer, noting that the oil overflow subsided after this action was taken. -The
         control room received a high demister differential pressure (dP) alarm (TG OIL RESVR
         DEMISTER ilP HI) [PAl and directed the equipment operator in the field to adjust the valve
         alignment to clear the alarm. The high dP condition was cleared following adjustment of the
         TO-EX-1 B discharge valve. -When Maintenance completed the replacement of the Return Oil
         Basket Strainer, the lid on the tank was closed resulting in an exhauster low output
         pressure condition. However, no low pressure alarm was received. At this juncture, with no
         system alarms present, Operations believed the turbine lube oil vapor extractor system had
         been properly restored to service. Subsequent investigation determined that the pressure
         switch [PS] that provides a signal to the vapor exhauster low pressure alarm was out I of
         calibration low. This resulted in Operations being unaware that the differential pressure
         provided by the turbine lube oil vapor extractor system was inadequate to preclude lube oil
         leakage at the high pressure turbine bearing #2. The plant was manually scrammed at 1952 on
         6/26/09 after the Control Room was notified of discovery of a small fire on a flange below
         turbine bearing #2 at 1949. The plant response to the manual scram was as expected except
         for the following: -When Reactor Core Isolation Cooling (RCIC) [BN] was initiated at 2015
         on 6/26/09 to assist in reactor vessel level control, one of the valves did not open
         automatically. The valve was successfully opened by Operations via the control switch.
         -When attempting to transfer control of reactor pressure vessel level a Reactor Feedwater
         [SJ] heater outlet isolation valve would not close (first attempt to close the valve
         occurred at 2001 on 6/26/09). An alternate valve lineup was established to facilitate level
         control at 2017 on 6/26/09. There was no inoperable equipment at the start of the event
         that contributed to the event. This LER is submitted pursuant to 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) as an
         event or condition that resulted in manual actuation of the Reactor Protection System.
         Cause The sustained bearing lube oil leak was caused by less than adequate (LTA) negative
         sump pressure, Le. inadequate delta pressure across the bearing. The L TA negative sump
         pressure condition was caused by insufficient flow through the in-service vapor extractor.
         One operating extractor is required to maintain the negative sump pressure. The inability
         of the plant staff to identify the low output from the extractor system, and subsequently
         the L TA negative sump pressure, was due to an out of calibration low pressure switch [PS]
         and has been identified as Root Cause 1 (RC1). The pressure switch is designed to provide a
         low pressure alarm at 0.25 inches water column (wc) decreasing. Investigation after the
         event determined the as-found setpoint to be 0.11 inches wc. The pressure switch was last
         calibrated on 3/25/07 and found to be within calibration tolerance at that time. With this
         alarm I being out of calibration low, none of the subsequent operations crews were directed
         to the alarm response procedure which had the following caution: &quot;Operating the Main
         Turbine without a vapor extractor may cause oil leakage from the #1 and #2 bearings. This
         oil leakage may lead to a fire in the High Pressure Turbine area.&quot; The pressure switch
         was recalibrated on 6/28/09 and was subsequently replaced with a different switch on
         8/16/09. The cause for TO-EX-1 B not providing sufficient negative pressure was determined
         to be the discharge valve throttled to an almost closed position. It is unclear if the
         valve's final position was the result of equipment condition (Le. an absent roll pin) and
         system perturbations which effectively closed the valve or if it was the as left condition
         by the operator. Both paths were explored as part of the investigation. Post event
         inspections noted that the TO-EX-1 B discharge valve was missing the handle to shaft roll
         pin. The absent roll pin could allow the butterfly valve to close in response to system
         perturbations resulting from the strainer basket change out. During post event
         investigation the valve was successfully manipulated prior to repair but performance was
         not consistent. This does not guarantee that the disc would remain in the as-left
         orientation. The valve was repacked in May 2003 with no subsequent work history to indicate
         how or why the pin was missing. The valve was repaired on 6/29/09. The equipment operator
         manipulated the valves on 6/25/09 to restore TO-EX-1 B to service after TO-EX-1 A had
         tripped off to achieve the appropriate system pressure as directed by the operating
         procedure. During this same time frame, maintenance personnel were changing out a clogged
         Return Oil Strainer Basket which impacted the differential pressure of the system. It
         should be noted that post event investigation identified that lifting the cover of the
         strainer basket does cause system pressure indications to change. After the initial
         restoration of TO-EX-1 B, the high dP alarm I was received and the Control Room directed
         the equipment operator to manipulate the valve alignment to clear the alarm. The alarm
         response procedure does not have any direction or requirements to monitor system pressure
         after valve adjustments are made. The valves were left in a pOSition which cleared the
         alarm. No follow-up monitoring of the vapor extraction system pressure was performed, which
         includes the lack of routine monitoring as this parameter is not included in the regular
         turbine building equipment operator rounds. The combination of making system adjustments
         while the strainer was being replaced, operation of the discharge valve with the missing
         roller pin yielding inconsistent system flows when set at the same position, and the system
         low pressure alarm being out of calibration low (see RC1 above) contributed to the
         likelihood that Operations personnel were unaware that there was less than adequate
         negative sump pressure after the above described system manipulations. Root Cause 2 (RC2)
         has been determined to be weaknesses in integrated system knowledge of the main turbine
         lube oil exhauster system by Operations and Engineering. The exhauster operations
         concurrent with main lube oil strainer cleaning caused the system to be placed in a
         condition in which it was riot performing its intended function. Once this condition was
         established, it was not recognized by Operations or Engineering personnel. </eventDesc>
      <correctiveActions> The following actions have been or are being pursued to prevent
         recurrence: 1) Procedures have been revised to require the as-left system pressure
         indications be confirmed after any manipulation of the vapor extractor suction or discharge
         valves. Cautions to these procedures were also be added to ensure adjustments are not made
         to the vapor extractor suction or discharge valves when the cover is removed from the
         Return Oil Basket Strainer 2) The turbine building rounds procedure has been revised to
         check lube oil vapor extraction system pressure each shift. 3) Improvements in Engineering
         and Operations lube oil exhauster training will be implemented. I Additional corrective
         actions to address contributing causes, extent of cause, and recurrence prevention include
         PM additions and clarifications such as the evaluation of the conditions and frequency for
         performing pressure switch calibrations, procedure revisions, and training material
         enhancements.</correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>For this event, High-Pressure Core Spray (HPCS) [BG], Low-Pressure Core
         Spray (LPCS) [BM], RCIC, and Residual Heat Removal (RHR)/Low Pressure Coolant Injection
         (LPCI) [BO] systems were capable of performing their intended safety functions. Off-site
         power was available and all three of the emergency diesel generators [EB and EK] were
         operable and available. This event did not involve an event or condition that could have
         prevented the fulfillment of any safety function described in 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). This
         event posed no threat to the health and safety of the public or plant personnel and was
         therefore, not safety significant. Similar Events No similar events have been reported by
         Columbia. A review of the Corrective Action Program CR database found no repeat occurrences
         of this event. Two Problem Evaluation Reports were found which identified cases of oil mist
         coming from TO-EX-1 B when in standby condition. In both cases the leaking condition was
         repaired. The corrective actions taken for the previous events have no application to the
         subject event. </safetyConsequences>
   </narrative>
</ler>
