<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-03-11T14:43:26-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-03-11T14:43:26-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-03-11T14:43:26-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>H 
</P><Part><H4>Nebraska Public Power District </H4><P>&quot;Always there when you need us&quot; </P><P>NLS2010021 March 5, 2010 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attention: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>&quot; </P><P>.. </P><P>Subject: Licensee Event Report No. 2610~001-00 Cooper Nuclear Station, Docket No. 50-298, DPR-46 Dear Sir or Madam: The purpose ofthis correspondence is to forward Licensee Event Report 2010-001-00. Sincerely, </P><P>~;;;;Jj;J~ »&quot;&quot;~&quot;' u)/lliJ </P><P>Demetrius L. Wi~·~~. ~.. General Manager ofPlant Operations </P><P>Ihk </P><P>Attachment </P><P>cc: 	Regional Administrator w/attachment NPG Distribution w/attachment USNRC -Region IV </P><P>Cooper Project Manager w/attachment INPO Records Center w/attachment USNRC -NRR Project Directorate IV-I </P><P>Senior Resident Inspector w/attachment SORC Chairman w/attachment USNRC-CNS </P><P>SRAB Administrator w/attachment CNS Records w/attachment </P><P>COOPER NUCLEAR STATION </P><P>P.o. Box 98/ Brownville, NE 68327-0098 
Telephone: (402) 825-3817 / Fax: (402) 825-5217 
</P><P>www.nppd.com NRC FORM 366 (9-2007) </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2010_03_05_ML100700590_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 08/31/2010 (9-2007) Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 80 hrs. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Forward comments regarding burden estimate to the LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch (T-5 F52). U,S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washington. DC 20555-0001. or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer. Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs NEOB-10202 (3150-0104). Office of Management and Budget. Washington. (See reverse for required number of DC 20503. If a means to impose an information collection does not display a currently digits/characters for each block) valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to. the information collection. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE Cooper Nuclear Station 05000298 1 of 4 4. TITLE Technical SpeCification Prohibited Condition Due to Safety Relief Valve Test Failures 5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED MONTH IDAY I I I FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER YEAR YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REVISION MONTH DAY YEAR NUMBER NUMBER 05000 ! 12 ! I I FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 01 2010 2010 -001 -00 03 05 [ 2010; I [ 05000 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) 1 0 20.2201(b) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 0 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 050.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) 0 20.2203(a)(1 ) 0 20 .2203( a)( 4 ) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(i) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(x) 10. POWER LEVEL 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.36(c)(2) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) 0 73.71(a)(4) 074 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 0 50.46(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) 0 73.71(a)(5) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) 0 OTHER 0 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A .__...._._-_........._.................__...........'''''.........&quot;._'''_'''_'''._''''''...'''''......''''...._.._..&quot;.....J,,2~J.LC.ENS..E.E&quot;,CONTAC.&quot;'T...EQRIHISJ,.E.R&quot;'_&quot;'_'&quot; &quot;.&quot;,&quot;&quot;''''''''''''_ ----_......_-..0. FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) David W. Van Der Kamp, Licensing Manager I (402) 825-2904 -_'-0' eM IOO&quot;~~~~,~c~~LO~~_~D-'~&quot;!:&quot;T&quot;'&quot;~CA I TO EPIX I; &quot;.... FACTURER TO EPIX B s~-&quot;''''''I RV I &quot;''''''' TO;~-'''''''''~' IJ' . 1-&quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;'&quot;'''' &quot;'&quot;. r--&quot;'''''''''''' &quot;......&quot;.............................. .................&quot;'....&quot;'......&quot;........... 14 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPEC_TED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR 0 YES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE). ~ NO SUBMISSION DATE 16. ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On January 12, 2010, two of eight Target Rock safety relief valve (SRV) pilot valve assemblies, removed during refueling outage 25, failed to lift within Technical Specification (TS) lift setpoint requirements. Wyle Laboratories, Inc. performed this testing. The pressure setpoint for the first pilot assembly is 1100 +/-33.0 psig; the SRV pilot assembly lifted at 1166 psig. The pressure setpoint for the second pilot assembly is 1090 +/-32.7 psig; it lifted at 1139 psig. Two subsequent informational lifts were performed for both SRV pilot assemblies and were within the TS pressure setpoint tolerances. Cooper Nuclear Station (eNS) was in Mode 1, Power Operation, at approximately 74% power at the time of the discovery. The remaining SRV and SRV pilot valve assemblies tested satisfactory for TS lift setpoint requirements. The cause is the same as previously reported in Licensee Event·Report 2008-002-00, pilot discto-seat corrosion bonding. The performance of the two-stage Target Rock pilot-actuated valves in the current design application at CNS is unsuccessful in consistently meeting the as-found lift test requirements. CNS is pursuing corrective actions to evaluate and revise the as-found test requirements contained within TS. This event is reportable as a condition prohibited by TS. The event has negligible safety significance. </Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A </TH><TH/><TH>u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TD>(9·2007) </TD><TD>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>CONTINUATION SHEET </TD><TD/></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBERISEOUENTIAL I REV)SION </TH><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Cooper Nuclear Station </TD><TD>05000298 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>NUMBER </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>2 </TD><TD>of </TD><TD>4 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2010 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>001 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>00 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of Form 366A) </P><P>PLANT STATUS </P><P>Cooper Nuclear Station (CNS) was in Mode 1, Power Operation, at approximately 74% power </P><P>to perform condensate booster pump [EIIS:P] repairs at the time of safety relief valve (SRV) </P><P>test failure discovery. Additionally, Division 2 of the residual heat removal system [EllS: BO] </P><P>was inoperable for planned maintenance. </P><P>BACKGROUND </P><P>The pressure relief system includes three American Society of Mechanical Engineers code safety valves [EllS: SB] and eight safety relief valves (SRV) [EllS: RV], all of which are located on the main steam lines [EllS: SB] within the drywell [EllS: NH], between the reactor vessel [EllS: RPV] and the first main steam isolation valve [EllS: ISV]. The safety valves provide protection against over pressurization of the nuclear system and discharge directly into the interior space of the drywell. The safety relief valves discharge to the suppression pool and provide three main functions: over pressure relief operation to limit the pressure rise and prevent safety valve opening, overpressure safety operation to prevent nuclear system over pressurization, and depressurization operation (opened automatically or manually) as part of the emergency core cooling system [EllS: BJ, BM, BO]. The nominal set pressure and tolerances for these valves are established in CNS Technical Specification (TS) Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.4.3.1. </P><P>The SRVs installed at CNS are Target Rock Model 7567F, two-stage, pilot-actuated valves with pilot assemblies comprised of Stellite 21 pilot discs and Stellite 6B pilot body seats. </P><P>During refueling outage 25 (RE25), three complete SRVs (pilot assemblies and main bodies) </P><P>and five SRV pilot assemblies were removed from the plant and replaced with refurbished </P><P>certified spares. The SRVs removed from service were shipped to Wyle Laboratories, Inc. for </P><P>required surveillance testing. </P><P>EVENT DESCRIPTION </P><P>On January 11 through January 13, 2010, three complete SRVs and five SRV pilot assemblies, removed during RE25 in the fall of 2009, were as-found tested at Wyle Laboratories, Inc. On January 12, 2010, as-found pressure setpoint testing for two SRV pilot assemblies (serial numbers 376 and 383) exceeded the TS limit. The SRV pilot assemblies were formerly installed in functional locations MS-RV-71 GRV and MS-RV-71 HRV, respectively. </P><P>The pressure setpoint for SRV pilot assembly serial number 376 is 1100 psig. The TS SR </P><P>3.4.3.1 as-found limit of acceptance is 1100 +/-33.0 psig (1067 psig to 1133 psig), a +/-3% tolerance. The first actual lift pressure of this SRV pilot assembly was recorded as 1166 psig, 6% above the setpoint. For informational purposes, the technicians performed a second and third lift. The results were 1100 psig and 1096 psig, both within 1 % of the pressure setpoint. </P><P>The pressure setpoint for SRV pilot assembly serial number 383 is 1090 psig. The TS SR </P><Sect><H5>3.4.3.1 as-found limit of acceptance is 1090 +/-32.7 psig (1057.3 psig to 1122.7 psig), also a </H5><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P></Sect><Sect><H4>(9·2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </H4><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBERISEQUENTIAL I REVISION </TH><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Cooper Nuclear Station </TD><TD>05000298 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>NUMBER </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>3 </TD><TD>of </TD><TD>4 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2010 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>001 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>00 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of Form 366A) </P><P>+/-3% tolerance. The first actual lift pressure of this SRV pilot assembly was recorded as 1139 </P><P>psig, approximately 4.5% above the setpoint. The technicians again performed two subsequent </P><P>informational lift tests. The results were 1111 psig and 1108 pSig, both within 2% of the </P><P>pressure setpoint. The remaining six SRVs and SRV pilot assemblies tested satisfactory for TS </P><P>lift setpoint requirements. The affected SRV pilot assemblies are not currently installed in the </P><P>plant. </P><P>All eight SRV pilot assemblies installed during RE25 were refurbished and certified to lift within </P><P>+/-1 % of as-left setpoint acceptance criteria prior to installation. Therefore, all currently </P><P>installed SRVs are capable of performing their intended function of providing protection against </P><P>over pressurization. </P><P>The failure mechanism is pilot disc-to-seat corrosion bonding. CNS reported this same </P><P>condition in November 2008 per Licensee Event Report (LER) 2008-002-00. SRV corrosion </P><P>bonding is an industry-wide issue which has been evaluated within CNS' corrective action </P><P>program. Past corrective actions include replacement of the 8RV pilot valve assemblies with </P><P>certified SRV pilot valve assemblies containing Stellite 21 pilot discs instead of platinum</P><P>impregnated Stellite 6B pilot discs; and installation of new Stellite 21 pilot discs during each </P><P>refurbishment. This is the second set of SRVs tested with new Stel/ite 21 pilotdiscs. The first </P><P>set of SRVs with new Stellite 21 pilot discs was tested in July 2008. </P><P>BASIS FOR REPORT </P><P>This event is being reported as an operation or condition prohibited by plant Technical Specifications per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </P><P>SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE </P><P>This event has negligible safety significance. One SRV opening at 1166 psig and a second opening at 1139 psig are bounded by the assumed opening pressure of 1210 psig utilized in the reload licensing reports for Cooper Nuclear Station RE24 (cycle 25) and RE25 (cycle 26). This event does not create a core damage scenario. There is inSignificant change in core damage frequency (CDF) or large early release frequency. This event did not compromise overpressure protection for the reactor pressure vessel. Even under postulated failure conditions (failure to open) of two safety relief valves, the CDF impact would be negligible. </P><P>CAUSE </P><P>The mechanistic failure was caused by corrosion bonding. The performance of the two-stage </P><P>Target Rock pilot-actuated valves in the current design application is unsuccessful in </P><P>conSistently meeting the as-found lift test requirements contained within the current CNS T3. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A </TH><TH/><TH>u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TD>(9·2007) </TD><TD>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>CONTINUATION SHEET </TD><TD/></TR></Table><P>1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE </P><P>. YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REVISION NUMBER</P><P>05000298</P><P>Cooper Nuclear Station 4 of 4 2010 -001 -00 </P><P>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of Form 366A) </P><P>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>CNS has not fully implemented the corrective actions reported in LER 2008-002-00. They are being tracked in the CNS corrective action program as follows: </P><L><LI><LI_Label>1. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Prepare a design document to determine how many of the eight SRVs must function to ensure plant safety. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>2. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Prepare and submit a TS license amendment request to allow one or two SRV failures during the SRV as-found TS lift testing as determined by the approved design document. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>Based on the test evidence, past evaluations of the failure mechanism, and corrective actions currently in process, no additional corrective actions are required. </P><P>PREVIOUS EVENTS </P><P>LER 2008-002-00 -On July 7 through July 9, 2008, the results of Target Rock SRV test data performed at Wyle Laboratories identified that one of eight SRV pilot assemblies failed asfound pressure setpoint testing. The SRV pilot assembly lifted at 1165 psig, outside its TS setpoint tolerance of 1100 +/-33.0 psig. The mechanistic cause was pilot disc-to-seat corrosion bonding between the Stellite 21 pilot disc and Stellite 6B pilot body seat to cause the SRV pilot assembly to lift outside its TS setpoint tolerance. </P><P>LER 2007-002-00 -On February 28 through March 2, 2007, the results of Target Rock SRV tests performed at Wyle Laboratories identified that one of eight SRV pilot valve assemblies failed to lift within its TS lift setpoint of 1090 +/-32.7 psig. The failure was a result of sufficient corrosion bonding between the SRV pilot valve assembly Stellite 21 disc and the pilot valve Stellite 6B body seat to cause the SRV pilot valve to lift outside its TS setpoint tolerance. </P><P>LER 2005-002-00 -On May 16 and May 19, 2005, a review of Target Rock SRV test data, provided by Wyle Laboratories, determined that three of eight SRV pilot valve assemblies failed to lift within their TS lift setpoint. Examination determined that sufficient corrosion bonding existed between the SRV pilot valve assembly Stellite 21 disc and the pilot valve Stellite 6B inbody seat to cause the SRV pilot valves to lift outside TS setpoint tolerances. </P><P>LER 2003-002-00 -On May 19, 2003, a review of Target Rock SRV test data, provided by Wyle Laboratories, determined that four of eight SRV pilot valve assemblies failed to lift within their TS lift setpoint. Examination determined that sufficient corrosion bonding existed between the SRV pilot valve assembly Stellite 21 disc and the pilot valve Stellite 6B in-body seat to cause the SRV pilot valves to lift outside TS setpoint tolerances. </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) </P><P>ATTACHMENT 3 LIST OF REGULATORY COMMITMENTS©4 
</P><P>ATIACHMENT 3 LIST OF REGULATORY COMMITMENTS©' </P><P>Correspondence Number: NLS2010021 </P><P>The following table identifies those actions committed to by Nebraska Public Power District . (NPPD) in this document. Any other actions discussed in the submittal represent intended or planned actions by NPPD. They are described for information only and are not regulatory commitments. Please notify the Licensing Manager at Cooper Nuclear Station of any questions regarding this document or any associated regulatory commitments. </P><Table><TR><TD/><TD>COMMITMENT </TD><TD>COMMITTED DATE </TD></TR><TR><TD>COMMITMENT </TD><TD>NUMBER </TD><TD>OR OUTAGE </TD></TR><TR><TD>None </TD><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><Caption><P>PROCEDURE 0.42 REVISION 24 PAGE 18 OF 25 </P></Caption></Table></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>