<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-01-07T08:05:04-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-01-07T08:05:04-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-01-07T08:05:04-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:03938422-dd95-49f2-b4b3-972ef7f22266</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:ec358f4f-0127-904c-978a-693250488847</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>H 
</P><Part><H4>Nebraska Public Power District </H4><P>&quot;Always there when you need us&quot; </P><P>NLS2010002 \ 
January 4,2010 
</P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
Attention: Document Control Desk 
Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 
</P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report No. 2009-003-00 
Cooper Nuclear Station, Docket No. 50-298, DPR-46 
</P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>The purpose of this correspondence is to forward Licensee Event Report 2009-003-00. </P><P>~~~__-n </P><P>Demetrius L.Willis 
General Manager of 
</P><P>Ijo </P><P>Attachment </P><P>cc: 	Regional Administrator w/attachment NPG Distribution w/attachment USNRC -Region IV </P><P>Cooper Project Manager w/attachment INPO Records Center wiattachment USNRC -NRR Project Directorate IV-l </P><P>Senior Resident Inspector w/attachment SORC Administrator w/attachment USNRC -CNS </P><P>SRAB Administrator w/attachment CNS Records w/attachment </P><P>COOPER NUCLEAR STATION </P><P>P.D. Box 98/ Brownville, NE 68327-0098 </P><P>Telephone: (402) 825-3877 / Fax: (402) 825-5277 www.nppd.com </P><P>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (9-2007) </P><Sect><H4>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </H4><P>(See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </P><P>1. FACILITY NAME Cooper Nuclear Station </P><P>APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 08/31/2010 </P><P>Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 80 hrs. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Forward comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch (T-5 F52). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Washington. DC 20555-0001. or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer. Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs NEOB-10202 (3150-0104). Office of Management and Budget. Washington. DC 20503. If a means to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to. the information collection. </P><P>2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE 05000298 1 of 4</P><P>1 </P><L><LI><LI_Label>4. </LI_Label><LI_Title>TITLE Isolation of Residual Heat Removal Shutdown Cooling </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>5. </LI_Label><LI_Title>EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER MONTH IDAY I YEAR YEAR ISEQUENTIAL JREVISION </LI_Title></LI></L><P>NUMBER NUMBER</P><P>I ! 11 107 i 2009 2009 -003 -00 </P><P>! </P><P>7. REPORT DATE i </P><P>MONTH DAY YEAR </P><P>I </P><P>! </P><P>01 	04 I2010 </P><P>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </P><P>FACILITY NAME </P><P>FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>05000 </P><P>DOCKET NUMBER </P><P>05000 </P><P>9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REOUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR 6: (Cher.k ~II th~t ~nnlv)</P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2201(b) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 50.73(a)(2)(vii)</LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2201(d) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(1) 0 20.2203(a)(4) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>4 </P><P>o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) t--------t 0 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 0 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(x) </P><P>10. POWER LEVEL 	o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.36(c)(2) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) 0 73.71(a)(4) 
000 o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 0 50.46(a)(3)(ii) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) 0 73.71(a)(5) 
</P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) 0 OTHER </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) ~~~i~o~':,t~:~~ct below or in </LI_Title></LI></L><P>m</P><P>FACILITYNAME· m• ••.....--.... .'.....•__ .12,!..1.G..1;~$J;!;_.c.QNTAC.I.EQ!U·I:IJ.s!,!;I~ELEPHONE NUMBER (InclueieAreaCodej&quot;·mm.---..m.-....... </P><P>David W. Van Der Kamp, Licensing Manager 	I (402) 825-2904 </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 	15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR </P><P>o YES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSIONDATE). 181 NO 	SUBMISSION </P><P>DATE </P><P>16. ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </P><P>At approximately 21 :08, Central Standard Time, on November 7,2009, isolation signals from </P><P>pressure switches in the Recirculation System caused Shutdown Cooling suction isolation </P><P>valves to close, which initiated a trip of the operating Residual Heat Removal (RHR) Pump D. </P><P>Cooper Nuclear Station was in Mode 4, Cold Shutdown, with reactor temperature at 167 </P><P>degrees Fahrenheit. </P><P>The closure of RHR suction isolation valves was a result of deficient operational procedures. </P><P>The procedures do not contain statements to ensure mechanical vacuum pumps are secured, </P><P>with steam lines open to the condenser and reactor pressure near or below 0 psig with RHR </P><P>suction isolation valves open. The operating crew did not demonstrate sufficient control of </P><P>reactor pressure while Shutdown Cooling was in operation. Reactor pressure decreased to a </P><P>negative value resulting in flashing of water to steam while in Shutdown Cooling. </P><P>This event is not risk significant. </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Cooper Nuclear Station </TH><TD>05000298 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REVISION NUMBER </TD><TD>2 of 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 -003 -000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of Form 366A) PLANT STATUS Cooper Nuclear Station (CNS) was at 0% Power in Mode 4, Cold Shutdown, at the time of the event. BACKGROUND The safety objective of the Residual Heat Removal (RHR) system [EIIS:BO] is to provide core cooling, in conjunction with other Emergency Core Cooling Systems (ECCS), and to provide containment cooling as required during abnormal operational transients and postulated accidents. The RHR system consists of two heat exchangers [EIIS:HX], four main system pumps [EIIS:P], and associated piping, valves, controls and instrumentation. Irradiated fuel in the shutdown reactor core generates heat during the decay of fission products and increases the temperature of the reactor coolant. This decay heat must be removed to maintain the temperature of the reactor coolant ~ 212 degrees Fahrenheit (OF) in preparation for performing Refueling operations, or the decay heat must be removed for maintaining the reactor in Cold Shutdown condition. EVENT DESCRIPTION On November 7,2009, at approximately 19:29, the B loop of RHR was placed in the Shutdown Cooling (SOC) mode of operations. At 20:26 hours, the plant entered Mode 4 due to reactor coolant temperature of less than 212°F. At approximately 21 :08, isolation signals from pressure switches (RR-PS-128A and RR-PS-128B) caused SOC suction isolation valves RHRMO-17 and RHR-MO-18 [EIIS:ISV] to close. At the time of the event, reactor temperature was approximately 167°F in the A Reactor Recirculation (RR) loop (operating) and 234°F in the B RR loop (idle). The closure of RHR suction isolation valves resulted from an improper configuration during low pressure SOC operation. This configuration entailed alignment of the reactor through steam line drains to the condenser with mechanical vacuum pumps running. This configuration, though proper for decay heat removal at higher pressure, should have been secured prior to reactor pressure reaching near 0 psig while in SOC. The slight negative pressure at reactor temperatures near saturation caused steam flashing and void collapse which resulted in a pressure spike, causing the RHR suction line overpressure protection pressure switches to actuate and close the SOC suction valves. This isolation caused the operating RHR pump to trip. Coincident with the isolation, loud noise and vibration were witnessed in proximity to RHR piping near the Drywell. Operations personnel opened Reactor Head Vents, removed Mechanical Vacuum Pumps from service, and reviewed pressure and temperature data to confirm the cause of the event. Engineering personnel conducted a systematic walkdown of affected RHR system piping and components and determined that no structural damage had occurred. SOC was restored at 23:02 on November 7,2009, with temperature at 174°F in A RR loop (operating) and 188°F in B RR loop (idle). </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (9·2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Cooper Nuclear Station </TH><TD>05000298 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REVISION NUMBER </TD><TD>3 of 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 -003 -000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of Form 366A) BASIS FOR REPORT This event is reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) due 60 days from date of discovery, i.e., by 01/06/2010. This was a condition which could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to remove residual heat. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE This is a Safety System Functional Failure. Although it is recognized that loss of decay heat removal is potentially a significant contributor to nuclear safety risk, this particular event is not considered risk significant. A human error induced pressure perturbation caused closure of SOC suction isolation valves and subsequent trip of the operating RHR Pump O. This isolation of SOC is not considered risk significant based on the following: • Decay heat levels were low. Based on temperature monitoring data, the time to boil was greater than four hours. • All RHR pumps and associated equipment required for SOC operation remained available for restoration. • All low pressure ECCS system trains were available for inventory control if necessary. • Reactor coolant temperature increased 10°F in the approximate 120 minutes before SOC restored. • The extended time for SOC restoration was not due to equipment problems or complications, but due to the relatively low heat-up rate. Precautionary RHR system inspections were performed to address perceived water hammer potential impacts. • SOC was restored within less than ~the time to boil. The event did not challenge fuel, reactor coolant pressure boundary, primary containment, or secondary containment. Timely restoration was assured given the adequate response time available to mitigate continued heat-up. Reactor coolant temperature did not approach unacceptable limits prior to restoration of SOC. Therefore, the incurred risk due to this event is not risk significant: CAUSE The closure of SOC suction isolation valves, which caused RHR Pump 0 to trip, was a result of deficient operational procedures. The procedures do not contain action steps to ensure mechanical vacuum pumps are secured (or steps that otherwise break vacuum), with steam lines open to the condenser and reactor pressure near or below 0 psig, and with SOC suction isolation valves open. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A </TH><TH/><TH>u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TD>(9·2007) </TD><TD>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>CONTINUATION SHEET </TD><TD/></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TH>2. DOCKET </TH><TH>YEAR </TH><TH>6. LER NUMBERI SEQUENTIAL I REVISION </TH><TH>3. PAGE </TH></TR><TR><TD>Cooper Nuclear Station </TD><TD>05000298 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>NUMBER </TD><TD/><TD/><TD>4 </TD><TD>of </TD><TD>4 </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD>2009 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>003 </TD><TD>-</TD><TD>000 </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>17 . NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of Form 366A) </P><P>The operating crew did not demonstrate sufficient control of reactor pressure while SOC was in </P><P>operation. Reactor pressure decreased to a negative value resulting in flashing of water to </P><P>steam while in SOC. </P><P>CORRECTIVE ACTION </P><P>The following actions are being tracked in the CNS corrective action program: </P><L><LI><LI_Label>1. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Develop and administer tailgate to all operating crews on this event, its causal factors, and associated corrective actions. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>2. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Revise procedures to include action steps to secure (or ensure secured) mechanical vacuum pumps (or otherwise break vacuum) or isolate the reactor from the condenser when reactor pressure is no less than 5 psig (or an alternate pressure determined through benchmarking) with SOC suction isolation valves open. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>3. 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Revise applicable Training lessons to include a discussion of the causal factors and corrective actions associated with the site-specific operating experience from this event. This discussion is to include the importance of operator control of reactor pressure during cooldown operations, to prevent flashing from PsatlTsat conditions. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>PREVIOUS EVENTS </P><P>There have been no reportable events in the last three years related to SOC. </P><P>(. </P><P>ATTACHMENT 3 LIST OF REGULATORY COMMITMENTS©4 
</P><P>ATIACHMENT 3 LIST OF REGULATORY COMMITMENTS©' </P><P>Correspondence Number: NLS2010002 </P><P>The following table identifies those actions committed to by Nebraska Public Power District (NPPD) in this document. Any other actions discussed in the submittal represent intended or planned actions by NPPD. They are described for information only and are not regulatory commitments. Please notify the Licensing Manager at Cooper Nuclear Station of any questions regarding this document or any associated regulatory commitments. </P><Table><TR><TH>COMMITMENT </TH><TH>COMMITTED DATE </TH></TR><TR><TH>COMMITMENT </TH><TD>NUMBER </TD><TD>OR OUTAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>None </TH><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>PROCEDURE 0.42 REVISION 24 PAGE 18 OF 25 .1 </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>