<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-08-11T08:08:21-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-08-11T08:08:21-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-08-11T08:08:21-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:98cdf38c-34d8-47ae-af4e-b2d5bf2f530f</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:dfcf7a7d-cfcf-b944-9ed0-dbcc2f6fc9df</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>.,.' 
</P><P>H 
</P><Part><H3>Nebraska Public Power District </H3><P>Always there when you need us </P><P>NLS2011081 August 8, 2011 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attention: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report No. 2011-003-00 Cooper Nuclear Station, Docket No. 50-298, DPR-46 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>The purpose ofthis correspondence is to forward Licensee Event Report 2011-003-00. </P><P>General Manager ofPlant Operations Ibk Attachment </P><P>cc: 	Regional Administrator w/attachment NPG Distribution w/attachment USNRC -Region IV </P><P>Cooper Project Manager w/attachment INPO Records Center w/attachment USNRC -NRR Project Directorate IV-1 </P><P>Senior Resident Inspector w/attachment SORC Chairman w/attachment USNRC -CNS </P><P>SRAB Administrator w/attachment CNS Records w/attachment </P><P>COOPER NUCLEAR STATION </P><P>Po. Box 98/ Brownville. NE 68321-0098 Telephone: (402) 825-3811 / Fax: (402) 825-5211 www.nppd.com </P><P>&quot; </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2011_08_08_ML11223A013_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 10/31/2013 (10-2010) Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 80 hrs, Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing processand fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) FOIA/Privacy Service Branch (T-5 F53). U,S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission,Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov,and to the Desk Officer. Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs NEOB-10202,(See reverse for required number of (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If ameans digits/characters for each block) used to impose an information collection does not display a currenlly valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and aperson is not required to respond to, the information collection. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE Cooper Nuclear Station 05000298 1 of 3 4. TITLE Potential Loss of Safety Function of Service Water Strainers 5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED I ; ; ! FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBERMONTH I DAY i YEAR YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV MONTH I DAY I YEAR 050001 j NUMBER NO.i ! I ! 071 i I 2011 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 06 2011 2011 -003 -00 08 08 I ! ! I 05000l 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REOUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR 6: {Check all that ann/v} 1 D 20.2201(b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) D 20.2201(d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1 ) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) 10. POWER LEVEL D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) 100 D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) D 73.71(a)(5) D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A 12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER--_.. •• _.H.............._ •• H ••••••• M ..... ,,-_._._..........__....... • ••••••••••••••••••••••• H •••• ............................ ••••••••••••••••• •••••••• • ••• H •••• ........_..........FACILITY NAME ...................................................................-.-.....-.-....----.---···.. -..TTELEPHONE·NUMBERiiii;;iiJdeAfea·Codej David W. Van Der Kamp, Licensing Manager I (402) 825-2904 CAUSE I SYSTEM ICOMP~~E~~!P~:~F~C~~R~~NE :oR.~!~~:~:'POt~..rNTf;~~~R(;·O'r(;S~~;~!OJ1J:HIS...8EPoRT ........................... IU-REPORTABLE----1---------1 -----r------------------mmL----II----·---r·--·-.. I RER ....... ! ... .........,IO'.EPIX...... i I 14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MQ/'ill::! DAY_ YEAR 181 YES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) 0 NO SUBMISSION 10 15 2011 DATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On March 27, 2010, the '1\ Service Water (SW) strainer failed to operate as expected. Cooper Nuclear Station (CNS) personnel investigated and found the strainer wiper motor-to-gearbox coupling was not engaged to turn the gearbox shaft. The gear side key had become dislodged allowing the coupling half to move enough to disengage the coupling sleeve. This condition impacted the ability of the strainer to successfully perform the automatic backwash function to keep it clear of debris. CNS maintenance personnel restored the coupling on March 27, 2010, and staked the gear side keyway to prevent the key from coming out. On July 19, 2010, and October 25,2010, CNS completed installation of new worm gear shafts and couplings with solid sleeves for both SW strainers. The condition was discovered during a backend review of the resulting 2010 root cause evaluation. CNS is reevaluating this evaluation and will provide additional event details, the safety significance, cause, corrective action(s) to prevent recurrence, and previous events in a supplement to this Licensee Event Report. </Figure><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION 110·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Cooper Nuclear Station </TH><TD>05000298 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENT)AL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>2 of 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 003 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE PLANT STATUS Cooper Nuclear Station (CNS) was in Mode 1, Power Operation, at 100 percent power at the time of the event discovery date, i.e., June 7, 2011. BACKGROUND The service water (SW) [EIIS:BI] system is designed to provide cooling water for the removal of heat from equipment, such as the diesel generators [EIIS:DG] and reactor equipment cooling (REC) system heat exchangers [EIIS:HX], and to provide a supply of water for the residual heat removal (RHR) [EIIS:BO] SW heat exchangers through the RHR SW booster system pumps [EIIS:P]. The SW system also provides cooling to turbine building [EIIS:NM] non-essential loads and other unit components, as required, during normal operation. The SW system consists of four pumps located in the intake structure [EIIS:ME]. These pumps are separated into two pairs. Each pair takes suction from the SW bay in the intake structure and discharges through a motorized, self-cleaning strainer [EIIS:STR] to the SW supply header. The two SW strainers remove suspended particles equal to or larger than 1/8 inch in size from the water in order to prevent or minimize fouling of the heat transfer surfaces in the downstream REC and RHR SW heat exchangers. Debris accumulated in the SW strainers is removed through a backwash function. This creates a low pressure area in between a set of wiper blades that draws a portion of the strained water backward through the strainer, down between the wiper blades, and out the backwash outlet. This backwash water is then returned to the Missouri River. EVENT DESCRIPTION On March 27, 2010, at 12:25 Central Daylight Time (CDT), when operators placed the 'A' SW strainer in the mode for continuous operation, the strainer did not operate as expected. Further investigation revealed that the SW strainer wiper motor-to-gearbox coupling [EIIS:CPLG] was not engaged to turn the gearbox shaft. The gear side key had become dislodged allowing the coupling half to move enough to disengage the coupling sleeve. This condition impacted the ability of the SW strainer to successfully perform the automatic backwash function to keep it clear of debris. At the time of the failure, differential pressure across the '{!\ SW strainer was steady at 0.1 to 0.2 psid and was not approaching the operational limit of 15 psid. CNS control room operators considered the SW 'A' subsystem operable based on the fact that differential pressure remained within operational limits, the ability existed to take manual actions to perform the strainer's backwash function per alarm card response procedures, and the lack of available information indicating an inoperable condition existed. As such, the applicable technical specification limiting condition for operation for SW was not entered. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A fl0·20101 </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Cooper Nuclear Station </TH><TD>05000298 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3 of 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 003 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17 . NARRATIVE CNS maintenance personnel restored the coupling at approximately 17:19 COT on March 27, 2010, and staked the gear side keyway to prevent the key from coming out. On July 19, 2010, and October 25, 2010, CNS installed new worm gear shafts and couplings with solid sleeves for both SW strainers. The condition was discovered during a backend review of the resulting 2010 root cause evaluation. eNS is reevaluating the previous root cause evaluation for this event. Additional event details, the safety significance, root cause, corrective action(s) to prevent recurrence, and previous events will be provided in a supplement to this Licensee Event Report (LER). CNS expects to submit the supplemental report by October 15, 2011. BASIS FOR REPORT CNS determined that the March 2010 SW strainer coupling failure was reportable on June 7, 2011. Therefore, the LER is due 60 days from the date of discovery, i.e., August 8, 2011. CNS is reporting this event in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v) -An event or condition that could have prevented fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to: (B) remove residual heat. Other criteria, if determined to be applicable, will be provided in the supplemental report. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><P>ATTACHMENT 3 LIST OF REGULATORY COMMITMENTS©4 
</P><P>ATTACHMENT 3 LIST OF REGULATORY COMMITMENTS©' </P><P>Correspondence Number: NLS2011 081 </P><P>The following table identifies those actions committed to by Nebraska Public Power District (NPPD) in this document. Any other actions discussed in the submittal represent intended or planned actions by NPPD. They are described for information only and are not regulatory commitments. Please notify the Licensing Manager at Cooper Nuclear Station of any questions regarding this document or any associated regulatory commitments. </P><Table><TR><TH>COMMITMENT </TH><TH>COMMITTED DATE </TH></TR><TR><TH>COMMITMENT </TH><TD>NUMBER </TD><TD>OR OUTAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>None </TH><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>PROCEDURE 0.42 REVISION 27 PAGE 18 OF 25 </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>