<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-11-07T08:52:45-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-11-07T08:52:45-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-11-07T08:52:45-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:49bf3153-de45-421e-9531-b043af2e9a3f</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:6bc1d751-b532-c448-a6d2-bd7fcce19ae3</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>" 
</P><P>H 
</P><Part><H4>Nebraska Public Power District </H4><P>Always there when you need us </P><P>NLS2012113 November 1, 2012 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attention: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report No. 2012-003-00 Cooper Nuclear Station, Docket No. 50-298, DPR-46 Dear Sir or Madam: The purpose ofthis correspondence is to forward Licensee Event Report 2012-003-00. There are no new commitments contained in this letter. </P></Part><Part><H1>ST:-), </H1><P>Brian J. O'Grady Vice President NuclearChief Nuclear Officer </P><P>Ijo </P><P>Attachment: Licensee Event Report 2012-003-00 </P><P>cc: 	Regional Administrator w/attachment NPG Distribution w/attachment USNRC -Region IV </P><P>Cooper Project Manager w/attachment INPO Records Center w/attachment USNRC -NRR Project Directorate IV-l via ICES entry </P><P>Senior Resident Inspector w/attachment SORC Chairman w/attachment USNRC-CNS </P><P>SRAB Administrator w/attachment CNS Records w/attachment </P><P>COOPER NUCLEAR STATION </P><P>P.G. Box 98/ Brownville, NE 68321-0098 
Telephone: (402) 825-3811 / Fax: (402) 825-5211 
</P><P>www.nppd.com NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) r </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2012_11_01_ML12312A063_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150'{)104 EXPIRES 10131/2013 (10-2010) Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 80 hrs. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555'{)001, or by internet e-mail to infacollects.resaurce@nrc.gav, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs NEOB-10202, (See reverse for required number of (3150'{)104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means digits/characters for each block) used 10 impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE Cooper Nuclear Station 05000298 1 of 4 4. TITLE Reactor Building Doors Opened Simultaneously Causes Loss of Safety Function 5. EVENT DATE 6. lER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED DAY l , FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MONTH: YEAR YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV MONTH DAY YEAR 05000NUMBER NO. , FACtLiTY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 09 10 i 2012 2012 -003 -00 11 01 i 2012 05000 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR 6: (Check all that aoolvl 1 0 20.2201(b) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 50.73(a)(2)(vii) 0 20.2201(d) 0 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) 0 20.2203(a)(1 ) 0 20 .2203( a)( 4 ) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(i) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(x) 10. POWER lEVEL 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) 0 50.36(c)(2) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) 0 73.71 (a)(4) 100 0 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 0 50.46(a)(3)(ii) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) 0 73.71(a)(5) 0 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) 0 OTHER 0 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) ~ 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A •••••••••••••••••••••••••••• H ..................-. ......,.·H ••••..• ..................H •••••••••••• H •••••••• H •••••••• H ••••H •••••••••• 12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS lER ............................................................. FACILITY NAME ['TELEPHoNENUMBERI;nc;udeAfeaCode} David W. Van Der Kamp, Licensing Manager , (402) 825-2904 •••••••••••••••H ............-.-...............~-.-. 13. COMplEJI;Q!IIE LINE fO~EACH COMPONI;NT fAILURE P,ESCRIBED II\!!..IHIS REPO~T......H._..H. ... ......................... CAUSE SYSTEM : COMPONENT : MANUFACTURER REPORTABLE 1 CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT J..FA~~~~R I REPORTABLE ................................&lt;. ··········..··f .................. TO.EPlX ......•...............; i ......To..EPIX.............······································4.···· .....................................~ ................................ ..................... I••••••••••••••••••••••• ••• ··.··._.·...• .....••• ...H ••~ ..................................................... A NG IEL , P370 YES i! , , 14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR 0 YES (If yes, complete EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ~ NO SUBMISSION DATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On September 10, 2012, both airlock doors to the Reactor Building were inadvertently opened simultaneously, breaching the secondary containment boundary. Personnel were attempting to exit the Reactor Building through the inner personnel airlock while personnel were also entering the Reactor Building through the outer personnel airlock. This condition resulted in the two airlock doors being open simultaneously for approximately two minutes. As a result, an indication was received in the Control Room and Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.6.4.1, Condition A, was entered to restore secondary containment. An operator was dispatched to the airlock, reset the door interlocks; the doors were declared operable and LCO 3.6.4.1, Condition A, was exited. Cooper Nuclear Station (CNS) determined the root cause to be previous reportability practices minimized the significance of having both airlock doors open which caused CNS to defer installing equipment that would have precluded this event. Interim corrective actions include establishing persons to serve as door monitors until an automated warning device or system is installed. To prevent recurrence of this event, a change in the reportability guidance has been adopted and new doors with a different interlock will be installed in Refueling Outage 28. </Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>,. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Cooper Nuclear Station </TH><TD>05000298 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>2 of 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -003 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE PLANT STATUS Cooper Nuclear Station (CNS) was in Mode 1, Power Operation, at 100 percent power at the time of the event on September 10, 2012. BACKGROUND Secondary containment serves as a barrier to confine and monitor potential releases during fuel handling operations and is a system that limits the release of radioactive materials to the environment and consists of four subsystems. One of these subsystems is the Reactor Building [EllS: NG], which encloses the Reactor Pressure Vessel [EllS: RPV] and Primary containment [EllS: NH]. The Reactor Building is designed to provide protection for the engineered safeguards and nuclear safety systems located in the building from postulated environmental events. Sets of sealed doors [EllS: DR] (inner and outer doors) are provided for personnel and equipment access. One set of doors in each penetration [EllS: PEN] is required to be closed to maintain secondary containment. In addition, the personnel access airlock doors are equipped with interlocks [EllS: IEL] so that one door cannot be opened unless the second door is closed. The interlocked door can be &quot;by-passed&quot; by actuating the Interlock Bypass Switch or by using the panic bar to open the adjacent inactive leaf. Reactor Building personnel airlock doors R101 and R102 form part of the secondary containment boundary. EVENT DESCRIPTION On September 10, 2012, at 14:43, the inner and outer airlock doors (R101 and R102) to the Reactor Building were inadvertently opened simultaneously, breaching the secondary containment boundary. Personnel were attempting to exit the Reactor Building through the inner personnel airlock while personnel were also entering the Reactor Building through the outer personnel airlock. This condition resulted in the two airlock doors being open simultaneously for approximately two minutes. Consequently, an indication was received in the Control Room and Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.6.4.1, Condition A, was entered to restore secondary containment. An operator was dispatched to the Reactor Building airlock to investigate the indication and subsequently reset the door interlocks. At 14:51, the doors were declared operable and LCO 3.6.4.1, Condition A was exited. Event Notification 48295 was made to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A 19-20071 NRC FORM 366A (9·2007) NRC FORM 366A (9·2007) </P><Table><TR><TH>~~~~~~~--------------------------------------------~~~~~~~~~~~~~NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Cooper Nuclear Station </TH><TD>05000298 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEOUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>3 of 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -003 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE Justification existed in 2007 to replace the Reactor Building personnel airlock doors R101 and R 102, noting in part that the interlock system was incapable of preventing simultaneous door opening causing entry into LCOs. Based upon this justification, new doors were procured and delivered; however, the priority given for installation was low and the doors remain in storage. As part of the Root Cause Evaluation of this event, a similar instance was found to have occurred within the past three years. On April 16, 2012, a technician was entering the Reactor Building personnel airlock through the outer door. Another technician was exiting the Reactor Building through the inner door. The interlock failed and both personnel airlock doors were opened simultaneously. An operator was dispatched to the Reactor Building airlock and the doors were successfully closed. Secondary containment was declared inoperable during the time both doors were open. BASIS FOR REPORT The event is reportable as a loss of safety function under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C and D) -An event or condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of structures or systems that are needed to control the release of radioactive material or mitigate the consequences of an accident. SAFElY SIGNIFICANCE This event is considered to have low safety significance. Having Reactor Building personnel airlock doors R101 and R102 open simultaneously does not have a direct or indirect impact on the frequency of core damage. Additionally, the short duration breach of secondary containment due to these doors being open simultaneously has a negligible impact on Large Early Release Frequency. This event is considered a safety system functional failure. CAUSE CNS determined the root cause to be previous reportability practices minimized the significance of having both airlock doors open which caused eNS to defer installing equipment that would have precluded this event. CORRECTIVE ACTION Corrective actions have been established that include posting individuals to serve as door monitors until CNS assesses, recommends, and installs an automated warning device or system (non-human activated) that provides warning to persons about to use the airlock doors that the opposite door has already been opened. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Cooper Nuclear Station </TH><TD>05000298 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEOUENTIAL I NUMBER REV NO. </TD><TD>4 of 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -003 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE To prevent recurrence of this event, a change in the reportability guidance has been adopted and the doors with the different interlock system will be installed during Refueling Outage 28, scheduled for 2014. PREVIOUS EVENTS A review of CNS records revealed five different occurrences of the Reactor Building airlock doors being open simultaneously that meet the reporting criteria of 10 CFR 50.72 and 10 CFR 50.73; however, none of these events were reported. Specifically, these events occurred on: May 31, 2002; July 19, 2002; February 14, 2003; February 17, 2005; April 2, 2009. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>