<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-01-11T09:13:56-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-01-11T09:13:56-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-01-11T09:13:56-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="• "><ImageData src="images/ML110110218_img_0.jpg"/>• </Figure>Entergy Operations, Inc . River Bend Station 5485 U.S. Highway 61 N S1. Francisville, LA 70775 </P><P>, . 	Tel 225381 4157</P><P>. ~Entergy </P><P>Fax 225 635 5068 dlorfin@entergy.com </P><P>David N. Lorfing 
Manager-Licensing 
</P><P>RBG-47104 January 5, 2011 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 50-458 / 10-004-00 River Bend Station -Unit 1 Docket No. 50-458 License No. NPF-47 </P><P>File No. 	G9.5 </P><P>RBF1-10-0192 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>In accordance with 10CFR50.73, enclosed is the subject Licensee Event Report. This document contains no commitments. If you have any questions, please contact me at 225-381-4157. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><Part><H1>E~~~~ </H1><P>Manager -Licensing Enclosure </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Licensee Event Report 50-458 I 10-004-00 January 5, 2011 RBG-47104 RBF1-10-0192 Page 2 of2 </P><P>cc: 	U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Region IV 612 East Lamar Blvd., Suite 400 Arlington, TX 76011-4125 </P><P>NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>P. O. Box 1050 
St. Francisville, LA 70775 
</P><P>INPO Records Center 
E-Mail (MS Word format) 
</P><P>Mr. Jim Calloway Public Utility Commission_ of Texas 1701 N. Congress Ave. Austin, TX 78711-3326 </P><P>Mr. Jeffrey P. Meyers Louisiana Department of Environmental Quality Attn: OEC-ERSD </P><P>P.O. Box 4312 
Baton Rouge, LA 70821-4312 
</P><P>/ </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) /' LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAIPrivacy Section (T-5 F53). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory&quot; Commission. Washington. DC 20555-0001. or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov. and to the Desk Officer. Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. NEOB-10202. (3150-0104). Office of Management and Budget. Washington. DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to. the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000 -458 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE High Pressure Core Spray System Inoperable Due to Failed Motor Oil Reservoir Drain Plug </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>11 </TH><TD>07 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>2010-004-00 </TD><TD>01 </TD><TD>05 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check aI/ that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2201 (b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201 (d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71 (a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71 (a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) [8] 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Indude Area Code) David N. Lorfing, Manager -Licensing 225-381-4157 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>E </TH><TD>BG </TD><TD>(see text) </TD><TD>(see text) </TD><TD>YES </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED ONOI:8l YES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>03 </TD><TD>03 </TD><TD>2011 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces. i. e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On November 7,2010, at 10:23 a.~ COT, with the plant operating at 100 p~rcent power, the high pressure core spray (HPCS) (8G) pump was declared inoperable following the discovery of an oil leak on the pump motor (**MO**). The source of the oil leak was found to be a cracked drain plug on the lower motor bearing oil reservoir. The oil plug was replaced, and the HPCS system was restored to its standby condition at 7:40 p.m. COT that same day. This is a preliminary report, as the causal analysis of this event , is not yet complete. A supplement to this report will be provided by March 3, 2011. This condition is being reported in accordance with 1 OCFR50. 73(a)(2)(v)(O) as the loss of a system needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident. No other safety-related systems were out of service during the time that the HPCS system was inoperable. This event was of minimal significance with respect to the health and safety of the public. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><P>" 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) U_S_ NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit.1 </TH><TD>05000-458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I . NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 -004 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>REPORTED CONDITION On November 7,2010, at 10:23 a.m. COT, with the plant operating at 100 percent power, the high pressure core spray (HPCS) (8G) pump was declared inoperable following the discovery of an oil leak on the pump motor (**MO**). This condition is being reported in accordance with 1 OCFR50. 73(a)(2)(v)(D) as the loss of a system needed to mitigate the consequences of an accident. The source of the oil leak was found to be a cracked drain plug on the lower motor bearing oil reservoir. The oil plug was replaced, and the HPCS system was restored to its standby condition at 7:40 p_m. COT that same day. No other safety-related systems were out of service during the time that the HPCS system was inoperable. INVESTIGATION On July 14, 2010, a minor, unquantifiable oil leak was found on the lower reservoir drain plug of the HPCS pump_ The leak appeared only as oil sheen around the drain plug. On August 7, the leak was quantified as approximately 1 drop every 3 minutes. The leakage rate was determined to be .stable, and it was concluded that the pump remained capable of performing its safety function. The approximate timeline of subsequent activities concerning this event, developed from documentation and from interviews with the operators and maintenance technicians, is as follows. Oil was added to the reservoir on September 13. The HPCS system was operated on September 20 for scheduled surveillance testing, and no increase in the leakage rate was seen. Oil was again added to the reservoir on October 26. No further oil additions were made until November 7. Twice-weekly inspections of the pump by the operators confirmed that the leakage had not increased. (Operators also perform a general inspection of the pump room each shift, checking for oil accumulation on equipment and other conditions. Those inspections continued to be satisfactory.) On October 29, the operators wrapped an absorbent pad around the plug to eliminate the need to clean up oil around the pump pedestal, and to eliminate the potential slipping hazard. These pads were subsequently replaced three times prior to November 7 (the last replacement was on November 5), and on each occasion, the oil leak rate had not increased. On November 7, the operator removed the absorbent pad, and found that the leak had '-. increased to a small stream approximately one-tenth of an inch in diameter. The HPCS pump was removed from service, and the oil drain plug was replaced with a new part. IMMEDIATE CORRECTIVE ACTIONS The failed drain plug was replaced, and the HPCS pump was restored to service at 7:40 p_m_ COT on the same day~ At the time of this event, no similar leaks had been reported on the other </TH></TR></Table><P>',' </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 --004 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>emergency core cooling system (ECCS) pumps, which share a common drain plug design with the HPCS pump. CAUSAL ANALYSIS and CORRECTIVE ACTIONS TO PREVENT RECURRENCE The investigation of this event is ongoing. The final results of the causal analysis will be provided in a supplement to this report. PREVIOUS OCCURRENCE EVALUATION There have been no similar events reported by RBS since January 1, 2005. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE Two of three divisions of ECCS are required for the RBS loss of coolant accident analyses. While HPCS was out of service, Division 1 and Division 2 ECCS systems and the automatic depressurization system were available, and would have met the ECCS performance criteria of 10CFR50.46. The HPCS system was returned to service within the time limit of the Required Action in the plant's Technical Specifications. This'event was of minimal safety significance with respect to the health and safety of the public. (NOTE: Energy Industry Component Identification codes are annotated as (**XX**).) </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10=2010) , </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>