<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-03-28T10:00:21-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-03-28T10:00:21-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-03-28T10:00:21-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="Q "><ImageData src="images/ML110870915_img_0.jpg"/>Q </Figure>Entergy Operations, Inc. 
</P><P>River Bend Station </P><P>5485 U.S. Highway 61 N St. Francisville, LA 70775 Tel 225381 4157 </P><Part><H2>~Entergy </H2><P>Fax 225 635 5068 dlorfin@entergy.com </P><P>David N. Lorfing </P><P>Manager-Licensing </P><P>RBG-47131 </P><P>March 21,2011 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATIN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: Licensee Event Report 50-458 / 11-001-00 </P><P>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </P><P>Docket No. 50-458 </P><P>License No. NPF-47 </P><P>File No. G9.5 </P><P>RBF1-11-0056 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>In accordance with 1 OCFR50.73, enclosed is the subject Licensee Event Report. This document contains no commitments. If you have any questions, please contact me at 225-381-4157. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>f)~71David N. Lorfing Manager -Licensing </P><P>Enclosure </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Licensee Event Report 50-458 / 11-001-00 March 21, 2011 RBG-47131 RBF1-11-0056 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>cc: 	U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Region IV 612 East Lamar Blvd., Suite 400 Arlington, TX 76011-4125 </P><P>NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>P. O. Box 1050 
St. Francisville, LA 70775 
</P><P>INPO Records Center 
E-Mail (MS Word format) 
</P><P>Mr. Jim Calloway Public Utility Commission of Texas 1701 N. Congress Ave. Austin, TX 78711-3326 </P><P>Mr. Jeffrey P. Meyers Louisiana Department of Environmental Quality Attn: OEC-ERSD </P><P>P.O. Box 4312 
Baton Rouge, LA 70821-4312 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOINPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to inlocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000 -458 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Unplanned Actuation of Standby Service Water System Due to Procedure Inadequacy </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>01 </TH><TD>20 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>2011-001-00 </TD><TD>03 </TD><TD>21 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2201 (b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) D 20.2201 (d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) D 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) ~50. 73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50. 73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71 (a)(4) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) D 73.71 (a)(5) D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 0 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) David N. Lorfing, Manager -Licensing 225-381-4157 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE \ CAUSETO EPIX , -</TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>n/a </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD>, </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) [gI NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) At 2:34 p.m. eST on January 20, 2011, while the plant was in a refueling outage, standby service water (SSW) pump &quot;e&quot; started automatically during system realignment. The Division 1 SSW subsystem (pumps &quot;A&quot; and &quot;e&quot;) was being started to facilitate maintenance on the normal service water system. When the &quot;A&quot; pump was manually started, the pressure transient caused by the realignment of the motor-operated valves in the system caused a momentary low system pressure, actuating SSW pump &quot;e&quot; automatically. This event resulted from a weakness in the operating procedure, in that the intended system configuration for this operation exceeded the flow capacity for one pump. Actions are being taken to strengthen this and other similar procedures to prevent recurrence. This event is being reported in accordance with 1 OCFR50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) as a condition that resulted in the automatic actuation of the &quot;e&quot; SSW pump. </TH></TR></Table><P>. </P><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10,2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 •• 001 ... 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>REPORTED CONDITION At 2:34 p.m. CST on January 20, 2011, while the plant was in a refueling outage, standby service water (SSW) (BS) pump (**P**) &quot;C&quot; started automatically during system realignment. The Division 1 SSW subsystem (pumps &quot;A&quot; and &quot;C&quot;) was being started to supply necessary cooling loads during the outage. When the &quot;A&quot; pump was manually started, the pressure transient caused by the realignment of the motor-operated valves in the system caused a momentary low system pressure, actuating SSW pump &quot;C&quot; automatically. This event is being reported in accordance with 1 OCFR50. 73(a)(2)(iv)(A) as a condition that resulted in the automatic actuation of the &quot;C&quot; SSW pump. The pump actuated as designed in response to a momentary low pressure signal in the non-safety related normal service water system. CAUSAL ANALYSIS As part of the refueling outage that was in progress at the time of the event, the Division 1 SSW subsystem was being started to facilitate maintenance on the normal service water system. Operators were executing the system operating procedure for a manual start. The procedure contains a chart for estimating the system flow demands for various loads and configurations. However, the chart provided no information concerning the flow required for the residual heat removal or spent fuel pool cooling systems. No notes or warnings were included in the . procedure prior to the performance of a step that has the potential to cause the actuation of a standby pump. The intended system configuration for this operation exceeded the flow capacity for one pump. During the valve alignment, a momentary low system pressure actuated SSW pump &quot;C&quot; automatically. PREVIOUS OCCURRENCE EVALUATION Two actuations of SSW that occurred during system configuration changes were reported by River Bend Station in 2006 (LERs 050-458/2006-03-00 and 050-458/2006-05-00). The investigation of this event found that the corrective actions for those events did not address potential procedural vulnerabilities to inadvertent SSW actuations similar to the reported event. Weaknesses in the affected procedures will be addressed by the corrective action plan for this event. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10=2010) NRC FORM 366A (10=2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (1 0-201 O} LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 •• 001 •• 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>CORRECTIVE ACTION TO PREVENT RECURRENCE The following actions have been incorporated into the station's corrective action program: 1) An engineering evaluation has been performed to determine the system configurations that can be supported by the capacity of one SSW pump. 2) The results of the engineering evaluation will be incorporated into a new revision of the system operating procedure, as well as other procedures that present a vulnerability to unplanned actuations of SSW. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The &quot;C&quot; SSW pump responded as designed to a valid low pressure signal. Therefore, this event was of minimal significance with regard to the health and safety of the public. (NOTE: Energy Industry Component Identification codes are annotated as ( ......XX......).) </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>