<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-04-26T06:16:23-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-04-26T06:16:23-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-04-26T06:16:23-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:1b64a1d1-f537-413d-a73c-432e4889c01a</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:695eab3b-a002-6f49-9fea-3d9810061b70</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="• "><ImageData src="images/ML13116A009_img_0.jpg"/>• </Figure>Entergy Operations, Inc. 
</P><P>River Bend Station 5485 U. S. Highway 61 N St. Francisville, LA 70775 </P><P>Tel 225381 4374</P><Part><H2>~Entergy </H2><P>Fax 225381 4872 eolson@entergy.com </P><P>Eric W. Olson </P><P>Site Vice President </P><P>RBG-47357 </P><P>April 18, 2013 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
Washington, DC 20555 
</P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 50-458 I 2013-001-00 River Bend Station -Unit 1 Docket No. 50-458 License No. NPF-47 </P><P>RBF1-13-0045 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>In accordance with 10 CFR 50.73, enclosed is the subject Licensee Event Report. This document contains no commitments. If you have any questions, please contact Mr. Joseph Clark at 225-381-4177. </P><P>Sincerely, </P></Part><Part><H1>&amp;«~d</H1><P>EWO/dhw </P><P>Enclosure </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Licensee Event Report 50-458 / 2013-001-00 April 18, 2013 RBG-47357 RBF1-13-0045 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>cc: 	U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Region IV 1600 East Lamar Blvd. Arlington, TX 76011-4511 </P><P>NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>P. O. Box 1050 
St. Francisville, LA 70775 
</P><P>I N PO Records Center 
E-Mail (MS Word format) 
</P><P>Central Records Clerk 
Public Utility Commission of Texas 
1701 N. Congress Ave. 
Austin, TX 78711-3326 
</P><P>Department of Environmental Quality Office of Environmental Compliance Radiological Emergency Planning and Response Section JiYoung Wiley </P><P>P.O. Box 4312 
Baton Rouge, LA 70821-4312 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAlPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-l0202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY .NAME River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000 -458 10F3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Operations Prohibited by Technical Specifications for Operations With a Potential to Drain the Reactor Vessel </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME n/a </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>03 </TH><TD>02 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>2013-001-00 </TD><TD>04 </TD><TD>18 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME n/a </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2201 (b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201 (d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71 (a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71 (a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) ~50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 0 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Joseph A. Clark, Manager -Licensing 225-381-4177 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>n/a </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED D YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) [gI NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, I.e., apprOXimately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On March 2, 2013, at approximately 1448 CST, with the plant in a refueling outage, maintenance on the reactor recirculation system was commenced without taking the required actions to comply with the applicable Technical Specifications. This maintenance constituted operations with a potential to drain the reactor vessel, and the required action for such an activity is restoration of the integrity of primary containment. This action was not taken, and the provisions of NRC Enforcement Guidance Memorandum 11-003 (Rev. 1) were instead invoked. The maintenance was completed and compliance with Technical Specifications was restored at 0830 CST on March 7. This event is being reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) as operations prohibited by Technical Specifications, as additionally specified by the Enforcement Guidance Memorandum. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 --001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>REPORTED CONDITION On March 2, 2013, at approximately 1448 CST, with the plant in a refueling outage, maintenance on the reactor recirculation system was commenced without taking the required actions to comply with the applicable Technical Specifications (TS). This maintenance constituted operations with a potential to drain the reactor vessel (OPDRV), and the required action for such an activity is restoration of the integrity of primary containment. This action was not taken, and the provisions of NRC Enforcement Guidance Memorandum 11-003 (Rev. 1) (EGM) were instead invoked. The maintenance was completed and TS compliance was restored at 0830 CST on March 7. This event is being reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) as operations prohibited by Technical Specifications, as additionally specified by the EGM. EVENT DESCRIPTION An OPDRV is an activity that could result in the draining or siphoning of the reactor pressure vessel (RPV) water level below the top of fuel without crediting the use of mitigating measures to terminate the draining prior to uncovering fuel. Based on Technical Specification applicability, an OPDRV is a change to the applicability as related to the Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO), and therefore treated much like a mode change. The NRC issued Revision 1 of the EGM on December 20, 2012, to provide guidance on how to disposition boiling water reactor licensee noncompliance with TS containment requirements during OPDRV operations. Certain safety systems must be operable during OPDRV activities to mitigate drain-down events and to provide protection against untreated fission product release in the event that the RPV water level drops below irradiated fuel. The TS does not define the term OPDRV or identify specific plant actions that constitute OPDRV activities. Because a definition is not provided, the NRC staff expects licensees to use the plain language meaning of the OPDRV wording for determining applicability. This means that any activity that could potentially result in draining or siphoning the RPV water level below the top of the fuel without taking credit for mitigating measures would be an OPDRV activity. In order to utilize the EGM and be eligible for enforcement discretion, the licensee is required to: (1) adhere to the NRC plain language meaning of OPDRV activities, (2) meet the requirements which specify the minimum makeup flow rate and water inventory based on OPDRV activities with .Iong drain-down times, </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10=2010) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000-458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013··001 .• 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>(3) ensure that adequate defense-in-depth is maintained to minimize the potential for the release of fission products by monitoring RPV level to identify the onset of a loss of inventory event by maintaining the capability to isolate the potential leakage paths, by prohibiting Mode 4 (cold shutdown) OPDRV activities, by prohibiting movement of irradiated fuel, and, (4) follow all other Mode 5 TS requirements for OPDRV activities. The station used the provisions of the EGM in order to replace the pump seals and the flow control valve packing in the &quot;A&quot; loop of the reactor recirculation system. When the loop was isolated to set the required conditions for the maintenance, the technicians determined that the baseline leakage through the loop isolation valves was approximately seven gallons per minute, which was well within the prerequisites of the EGM. The OPDRV was completed at 0830 CST on March 7, with no complications regarding pool water level control. PREVIOUS OCCURRENCE EVALUATION No similar events have been reported by River Bend Station in the last five years. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The prerequisites of the EGM and applicable station procedures were met prior to the start of the maintenance. The high pressure core spray, low pressure core spray, and &quot;A&quot; residual heat removal systems were designated for emergency water level control. The reactor cavity water level was greater than 23 feet above the RPV flange, and all pool gates were open. Contingency plans for potential leakage paths were in place, and two independent channels of pool water level were in service. No transients in pool water level occurred during the maintenance. Thus, this event was of minimal significance with respect to the health and safety of the public. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>