<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-03-19T16:23:16-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-03-19T16:23:16-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-03-19T16:23:16-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:49860823-b504-4ff8-a778-310767f2e274</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:21efb52b-a4d5-3d44-afb7-0d13232a09fd</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>Entergy Operations, Inc. </P><P>River Bend Station 5485 U. S. Highway 61 N SI. Francisville, LA 70775 Tel 225381 4374</P><Part><H2>, •~Entergy </H2><P>Fax 225381 4872 eOlson@entergy.com </P><P>Eric W. Olson </P><P>Site Vice President </P><P>RBG-47448 </P><P>March 10,2014 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>'Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 50-458/2014-001-00 River Bend Station -Unit 1 Docket No. 50-458 License No. NPF-47 </P><P>RBF1-14-0031 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>In accordance with 10 CFR 50.73,enclosed is the subject Licensee Event Report. This document contains no commitments. If you have any questions, please contact Mr. Joseph Clark at 225-381-4177. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>~~~</P><P>EWO/dhw </P><P>Enclosure </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>,. 
</P><P>Licensee Event Report 50-458/2014-001-00 March 10,2014 RBG-47448 Page 2 of2 </P><P>cc: 	U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Region IV 1600 East Lamar Blvd. Arlington, TX 76011-4511 </P><P>NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>P. O. Box 1050 
St. Francisville, LA 70775 
</P><P>INPO 
(via ICES reporting) 
</P><P>Central Records Clerk 
Public Utility Commission of Texas 
1701 N. Congress Ave. 
Austin, TX 78711-3326 
</P><P>Department of Environmental Quality Office of Environmental Compliance Radiological Emergency Planning and Response Section JiYoung Wiley </P><P>P.O. Box 4312 
Baton Rouge, LA 70821-4312 
</P><P>, 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (01.2014) ..&quot;&quot;-,,,~¥.~• . s ~ ) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) If.... ,. (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3160-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporaled inlo the licensing process and fed back 10 industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate 10 Ihe FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T·5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NE08-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME River Bend Station -Unit I </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 458 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 2 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Unanalyzed Condition Associated With Unfused Ammeters in DC Battery Indication Circuits </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACIUlY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>01 </TH><TD>09 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 -001 -00 </TD><TD>03 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACILIlY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TH>1 </TH><TD>D 20.2201(b) </TD><TD>D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2201 (d) </TD><TD>D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(1) </TD><TD>D 20.2203(a)(4) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) </TD><TD>D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) </TD><TD>D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>D 50.36(c)(2) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) </TD><TD>D 73.71(a)(4) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203{a)(2){iv) </TD><TD>D 50.46{a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>D 50.73{a)(2)(v){8) </TD><TD>D 73.71{a){5) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203{a)(2){v) </TD><TD>D 50.73{a)(2)(i)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73{a)(2){v){C) </TD><TD>D OTHER </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203{a)(2){vi) </TD><TD>D 50.73{a)(2){i)(8) </TD><TD>D 50.73{a)(2)(v){D) </TD><TD>Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME Joseph A. Clark </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) (225) 381-4177 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>na </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED DYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) o NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On January 9, 2014, with the plant operating at 100 percent power, the final review of industry operating experience regarding the adverse effects ofun fused direct current ammeter circuits in the main control room determined the described condition to be applicable to River Bend Station, resulting in a potentially unanalyzed condition with respect to 10 CFR 50 Appendix R analysis requirements. This condition is being reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B). Interim compensatory measures have been implemented. This condition has existed since the plant was constructed. Neither the original design criteria nor any industry standards in effect at the time accounted for the possibility ofthe multiple short-to-ground failure mode and therefore, did not require overcurrent protection for remote ammeter circuits. This condition was documented in the station's corrective action program. Compensatory measures were established to restore margin potentially reduced by postulated fire scenarios. The compensatory actions credit operator presence in the plant for maintaining heightened awareness and taking action to minimize fire hazards. Compensatory actions are incorporated in pertinent operating procedures. The compensatory actions remain in effect. There have been no actual adverse safety consequences resulting from the reported condition. The administrative controls of the fire protection program, the availability of fire detection and suppression systems, and a trained on-site fire brigade all combine to make it highly unlikely that a fire could occur and progress in a manner that actually leads to the event postulated in this scenario. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (01-2014) </P><P>) 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington. DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number. the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME River Bend Station -Unit I </TH><TD>2. DOCKET 05000 458 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3. PAGE 2 OF 2 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE REPORTED CONDITION On January 9, 2014, with the plant operating at 100 percent power, the final review of industry operating experience regarding the adverse effects of unfused direct current ammeter circuits in the main control room determined the described condition to be applicable to River Bend Station, resulting in a potentially unanalyzed condition with respect to 10 CFR 50 Appendix R analysis requirements. River Bend Station does have unfused ammeter circuits. This normally is not a concern, since two failures are required to cause the problem described in the document referenced above; an ammeter lead must short to ground, and another lead of the opposite polarity must also short to ground. Either of these events by itself will result in an alann annunciation, but not cause equipment damage. This allows for locating and repairing the problem before the second failure occurs. However, during a fire, there is a greater chance tHat these two failures could happen simultaneously, or before a single failure can be repaired. Ifan unfused ammeter lead shorts to ground while another conductor ofthe opposite polarity shorts to ground, the unfused path through the lead could allow enough current to flow that the lead will heat up and damage other wiring, with potentially adverse effects on the ability to safely shut down the plant in the event of a fire in the main control room. This condition is being reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B). Interim compensatory measures have been implemented. CAUSAL ANALYSIS This condition has existed since the plant was constructed. Neither the original design criteria nor any industry standards in effect at the time accounted for the possibility of the multiple short-to-ground failure mode and therefore, did not require overcurrent protection for remote ammeter circuits. CORRECTIVE ACTION This condition was documented in the station's corrective action program. Compensatory measures were established to restore margin potentially reduced by postulated fire scenarios. The compensatory actions credit operator presence in the plant for maintaining heightened awareness and taking action to minimize fire hazards. Compensatory actions are incorporated in pertinent operating procedures. The compensatory actions remain in effect. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE There have been no actual adverse safety consequences resulting from the reported condition. The administrative controls of the fire protection program, the availability of fire detection and suppression systems, and a trained on-site fire brigade all combine to make it highly unlikely that a fire could occur and progress in a manner that actually leads to the event postulated in this scenario. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>