<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-08-29T10:32:19-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-08-29T10:32:19-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-08-29T10:32:19-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="• "><ImageData src="images/ML14241A381_img_0.jpg"/>• </Figure>Entergy Operations, Inc. 
</P><P>River Bend Station 5485 U. S. Highway 61 N St. Francisville, LA 70775 Tel 225381 4374</P><Part><H2>~Entergy </H2><P>Fax 225 381 4872 eolson@entergy.com </P><P>Eric W. Olson </P><P>Site Vice President </P><P>RBG-47495 </P><P>August 11, 2014 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATIN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 50-458/2014-003-00 River Bend Station -Unit 1 Docket No. 50-458 License No. NPF-47 </P><P>RBF1-14-0122 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>In accordance with 10 CFR 50.73, enclosed is the subject Licensee Event Report. This document contains no commitments. If you have any questions, please contact Mr. Joseph Clark at 225-381-4177. </P><P>Sincerely, </P></Part><Part><H1>~1/~~ </H1><P>EWO/dhw </P><P>Enclosure </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Licensee Event Report 50-458/2014-003-00 August 11,2014 RBG-47495 Page 2 of2 </P><P>bc: 	U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Region IV 1600 East Lamar Blvd. Arlington, TX 76011-4511 </P><P>NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>P. O. Box 1050 
St. Francisville, LA 70775 
</P><P>INPO 
(via ICES reporting) 
</P><P>Central Records Clerk 
Public Utility Commission of Texas 
1701 N. Congress Ave. 
Austin, TX 78711-3326 
</P><P>Department of Environmental Quality Office of Environmental Compliance Radiological Emergency Planning and Response Section JiYoung Wiley </P><P>P.O. Box 4312 
Baton Rouge, LA 70821-4312 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) ..&quot;&quot;'........ ~¥~ ~.••.•) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3160-0104 EXPIRES: 01131/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Infonmation Collections Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Infonmation and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-l0202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. II a means used to impose an inlonmation collection does not display a currenijy valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the inlonmation collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 458 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Operations Prohibited by Technical Specifications Due to Concurrent Inoperability ofReactor Protection System Channels </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACIUTY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>06 </TH><TD>10 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 -003 -00 </TD><TD>08 </TD><TD>11 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACIUTY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TH>1 </TH><TD>o 20.2201(b) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) </TD><TD>[(] 50.73(a)(2)(vii) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2201(d) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(1) </TD><TD>o 20.2203(a)(4) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) </TD><TD>o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) </TD><TD>o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>o 50.36(c)(2) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(4) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) </TD><TD>o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) </TD><TD>o 73.71(a)(5) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) </TD><TD>o OTHER </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) </TD><TD>[(] 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) </TD><TD>o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) </TD><TD>Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSEE CONTACT Joseph A. Clark, Manager -Regulatory Assurance </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) (225) 381-4177 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE CAUSETO EPIX </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>nla </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED [ZJ YES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) D NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>04 </TD><TD>15 </TD><TD>2015 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces. i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 10,2014, with the plant operating at 100 percent power, technicians performing a scheduled surveilJance test found that one instrument channel in the reactor protection system failed its time response acceptance criterion. This was the second oftwo such tests that failed in similar fashion. Since it is conceivable that the second tested channel was out of specifications at the time the first channel was tested, this condition caused independent redundant channels in the same trip system to be inoperable at the same time. The actions required by the applicable Limiting Condition for Operation were not taken since the operators were not aware ofthe latent condition at the time ofthe first surveillance test failure. An engineering evaluation ofthis condition was performed, and the RPS system was declared operable with compensatory measures. Until this issue is resolved, the frequency ofthe calibration tests in the channels with Agastat relays has been increased to once per year. This condition is reportable in accordance with 10CFRSO.73(a)(2)(i) (b) as operations prohibited by Technical Specifications, as well as lOCFR50.73(a)(2)(vii), a potential common-cause inoperability of independent trip channels. Due to the design redundancy ofthe independent channels ofthe RPS system, this condition would likely have not prevented the system from performing its safety function. Had an actual full MSIV isolation occurred with the channel response times in their as-found condition, the reactor scram signal would likely have still occurred within the specified instrument response tim~. I </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (02-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01131/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (l-S FS3), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-l0202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budge~ Washington, DC 20503. H a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000 458 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE REPORTED CONDITION On June 10,2014, with the plant operating at 100 percent power, technicians performing a scheduled surveillance test found that one instrument channel in the reactor protection system (JC) failed its time response acceptance criterion. This was the second oftwo such tests that failed in similar fashion. Since it is conceivable that the second tested channel was out ofspecifications at the time the first channel was tested, this condition caused independent redundant channels in the same trip system to be inoperable at the same time. The actions required by the applicable Limiting Condition for Operation were not taken since the operators were not aware of the latent condition at the time of the first surveillance test failure. This condition is reportable in accordance with lOCFRSO.73(a)(2)(i)(b) as operations prohibited by Technical Specifications, as well as 10CFR50.73(a)(2)(vii), a potential common-cause inoperability of independent trip channels. BACKGROUND One of the functions in the reactor protection system is the initiation ofa reactor scram in the event of a closure ofthe main steam isolation valves (MSIVs). Limit switches on each ofthe eight MSIV actuators provide input to the individual, redundant RPS trip channels ifthe valve moves to a nominal 12 percent ofstroke length in the &quot;close&quot; direction. The design ofthe RPS system requires that a channel respond to an input from its MSIV limit switch and generate a trip signal. The maximum response time specified by the Technical Requirements Manual is 90 milliseconds. The calibration frequency is four years (24 months on a staggered test basis). The arrangement of the instrumentation includes 16 individual channels. Inboard and outboard MSIVs in each ofthe four main steam line are instrumented with redundant limit switches monitored by independent trip channels ofthe RPS system. IMMEDIATE ACTIONS In the calibrations performed in 2010, a degrading trend in the response times was noted in the four channels containing the Agastat relays (**94**). In the 2010 tests, the response time ofeach ofthe four channels was 89 milliseconds. The as-found response times found in the recent tests ranged from 90 to 102 milliseconds. In each case, the Agastat relay was replaced and the response time was then verified to be within specifications. The response times for the channels with no Agastat relays ranged from 41 to 51 milliseconds. An engineering evaluation of this condition was performed, and the RPS system was declared operable with compensatory measures. Until this issue is resolved, the frequency ofthe calibration tests in the channels with Agastat relays has been increased to once per year. This action is being tracked in the station's corrective action program. CAUSAL 'ANALYSIS The cause ofthis event remains under investigation. Corrective actions to prevent recurrence will be developed following the evaluation of future test results. These will be reported in a future supplement to this LER. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) NRC FORM 366A (02.2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02·2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000 458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE Due to the design redundancy ofthe independent channels of the RPS system, it is unlikely that this condition would not have prevented the system from performing its safety function. Had an actual full MSIV isolation occurred with the channel response times in their as-found condition, the reactor scram signal would have likely have still occurred within the specified instrument response time. This will be confirmed in the completion ofthe event investigation. (NOTE: Energy Industry Component Identification codes are annotated as (&quot;XX&quot;).) </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>