<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2015-02-24T16:27:25-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2015-02-24T16:27:25-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2015-02-24T16:27:25-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>Entergy Operations, Inc . </P><P>• River Bend Station 5485 U. S. Highway 61 N St. Francisville, LA 70775 </P><P>Tel 225381 4374 </P><Part><H2>~·Entergy </H2><P>Fax 225381 4872 eolson@entergy.conl </P><P>Eric W. Olson </P><P>Site Vice President </P><P>RBG-47545 </P><P>February 19, 2015 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Document Control Desk 
Washington, DC 20555 
</P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 50-458 I 2014-006-00 
River Bend Station -Unit 1 
Docket No. 50-458 
License No. NPF-47 
</P><P>RBF1-15-0136 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>In accordance with 10 CFR 50.73, enclosed is the subject Licensee Event Report. This document contains no commitments. If you have any questions, please contact Mr. Joseph Clark at 225-381-4177. </P><P>Sincerely, _./ </P><P>&amp;~~</P><P>EWO/dhw </P><P>Enclosure </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Licensee Event Report 50-458 / 2014-006-00 February 19, 2015 RBG-47545 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>cc: 	U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Region IV 1600 East Lamar Blvd. Arlington, TX 76011-4511 </P><P>NRC Sr. Resident Inspector </P><P>P. O. Box 1050 
St. Francisville, LA 70775 
</P><P>INPO 
(via ICES reporting) 
</P><P>Central Records Clerk 
Public Utility Commission of Texas 
1701 N. Congress Ave. 
Austin, TX 78711-3326 
</P><P>Department of Environmental Quality Office of Environmental Compliance Radiological Emergency Planning and Response Section Ji Young Wiley </P><P>P.O. Box 4312 
Baton Rouge, LA 70821-4312 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) ..+.,l.,..•.. II~O,,(:.o,.. ; ~ '; . : ~':t&quot; / LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) ...,., .. (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-l0202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not disptay a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME River Bend Station -Unit I </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000 458 </TD><TD>3. PAGE I OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Automatic Reactor Scram and Primary Containment Isolation Due to Loss of Power on the Division 2 Reactor Protection System With a Concurrent Division I Half-scram </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>12 </TH><TD>25 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 -006 -00 </TD><TD>02 </TD><TD>19 </TD><TD>2015 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check a/l that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TH>1 </TH><TD>D 20.2201(b) </TD><TD>D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2201 (d) </TD><TD>D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(1) </TD><TD>D 20.2203(a)(4) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(i) </TD><TD>D 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 85 </TH><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) </TD><TD>D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) </TD><TD>[{] 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) </TD><TD>D 50.36(c)(2) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) </TD><TD>D 73.71(a)(4) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) </TD><TD>D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) </TD><TD>D 73.71(a)(5) </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) </TD><TD>D OTHER </TD></TR><TR><TD>D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) </TD><TD>D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) </TD><TD>Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Fonm 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSEE CONTACT Joseph A. Clark. Manager -Regulatory Assurance </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) (225) 381-4177 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>I </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>n/a </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED DYES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) [{] NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i. e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On December 25,2014, at 0836 CST, a reactor scram occurred while the plant was operating at approximately 85 percent power. This event resulted from the loss of power on the Division 2 reactor protection system (RPS) bus, in conjunction with a pre-existing halfscram on Division I. The loss of Division 2 RPS power also resulted in a Division 2 containment isolation signal. Approximately four minutes after the scram, reactor water level increased to the Level 8 setpoint, causing the running main feedwater pump to trip. As reactor water level decreased back through the normal operating range, operators attempted to re-start main feedwater pump &quot;C,&quot; but its supply breaker failed to close. Main feedwater pump &quot;A&quot; was subsequently returned to service. As reactor water level decreased to the point at which the startup feedwater regulating valve (FRY) should have opened to establish automatic control, the valve failed to open. Attempts to open it with a manual input signal were unsuccessful, and the &quot;C&quot; main FRY was put back into service. By that time, reactor water level had decreased slightly below the Level 3 RPS actuation setpoint, resulting in a second scram signal. This event is being reported in accordance with IO CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) as an automatic actuation of the RPS system and the primary containment isolation logic. No plant parameters required the actuation of any standby diesel generators or emergency core cooling systems. No reactor safety-relief valves actuated. This event was of minimal safety significance with respect to the health and safety of the public. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-4104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA. Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202. (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington. DC 20503. If ameans used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and a person is not required to respond to. the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit I </TH><TD>05000 458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 006 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE REPORTED CONDITION On December 25,2014, at 0836 CST, a reactor scram occurred while the plant was operating at approximately 85 percent power. This event resulted from the loss of power on the Division 2 reactor protection system (RPS) (** JD**) bus, in conjunction with a preexisting half-scram on Division I. The loss of Division 2 RPS power also resulted in a Division 2 containment isolation signal. Approximately four minutes after the scram, reactor water level increased to the Level 8 setpoint, causing the running main feedwater pump (* * SJ* *) to trip. As reactor water level decreased back through the normal operating range, operators attempted to re-start main feedwater pump &quot;C,&quot; but its supply breaker failed to close. Main feedwater pump &quot;A&quot; was subsequently returned to service. As reactor water level decreased to the point at which the startup feed water regulating valve (FRV) should have opened to establish automatic control, the valve failed to open. Attempts to open it with a manual input signal were unsuccessful, and the &quot;C&quot; main FR V was put back into service. By that time, reactor water level had decreased slightly below the Level 3 RPS actuation setpoint, resulting in a second scram signal. This event is being reported in accordance with 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) as an automatic actuation of the RPS system and the primary containment isolation logic (** JM**). INVESTIGA TION and IMMEDIATE ACTIONS The Division I half-scram had been inserted two days prior to the event, in complial}ce with Technical Specifications, following the failure of an instrumentation channel on the no. 2 main turbine control valve. Teams were formed to investigate the separate significant aspects of the event, as follows: Loss ofDivision 2 RPS Bus Power was lost when the output breaker on the RPS motor-generator (MG) in the Division 2 subsystem tripped. The mostly likely cause of the output breaker trip was an intermittent failure of the MG field flash card due to a degraded capacitor. The capacitor was replaced, and the MG was tested and returned to a standby condition as a backup power supply. The alternate power supply will remain in service carrying the bus until completion of a modification to eliminate the field flash card as a potential source of recurrence of this problem. Misoperation of the Startup FRV The operation ofthe startup FRV was investigated to determine why it was unresponsive to either the automatic controller or the operator's manual input. Maintenance technicians discovered a failed circuit card in the &quot;manual&quot; side of the valve controller. The &quot;automatic&quot; function ofthe controller had operated correctly in the post-scram environment once reactor water level had returned to normal, and this was confirmed again during the troubleshooting. Additionally, Engineering personnel determined that the perfornlance of the valve was consistent with its design criteria. The valve and its control logic are designed for flow control, and not simply for isolation. When the valve receives a gradual &quot;open&quot; signal from the closed position, there is no specific time response requirement. This design feature can allow a delayed response that, in the scram recovery scenario, may be too slow to arrest a significant downward trend in reactor water level. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U_S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000 458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -006 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE The procedural guidance to isolate the main FRVs and use the startup FRV in a scram recovery was developed in 2010 to mitigate the effects of any seat leakage through the main FR V s. At that time. Operations developed the procedure change and validated its feasibility in the training simulator. However, no cross-discipline review by Engineering was requested. The investigation of December 25 event found that the simulator model does not accurately reflect the actual operating characteristics of the startup FRV, in that the simulated performance of the valve is more responsive than the actual valve. An Engineering review could have brought the actual operating characteristics to light. This factor, in conjunction with the simulator performance, reinforced the concept that the startup FRV was capable of controlling reactor water level in the post-scram transient condition. Malfunction of Main Feedwater Pump &quot;C&quot; The failure of main feedwater pump &quot;C&quot; was found to have been was caused by an &quot;over-racked&quot; condition of its supply breaker (that is, the breaker racking mechanism had slightly over-travelled the last time the breaker was returned to service). This caused the limit switches that detect the position of the breaker mechanism within the cabinet to give the control logic circuit a false indication that the breaker was not connected to the bus. Interim instructions have been implemented to have electricians verify the condition of all similar breakers each time they are racked in. CORRECTIVE ACTION TO PREVENT RECURRENCE The following corrective actions are planned, and will be tracked and documented in the corrective action program: Loss of Division 2 RPS Bus A design modification will be installed to eliminate the potential for a failure in the field flash card to affect the operation ofthe MG set once it is loaded. Misoperation of the Startup FRV Operating procedures have been revised to direct that, in the scram recovery environment, one ofthe main FRVs will remain in service. The startup FRV is not to be used in that condition. The main FRVs are on the schedule of work items for the upcoming refueling outage. Valve seat leakage is one ofthe deficiencies to be addressed. Malfunction of&quot;C&quot; Main Feedwater Pump Guidance on racking the main feedwater pump breakers (and those of similar design) will be incorporated into the pertinent operating procedures. Additionally, the deficiency that necessitated the insertion ofthe Division I half-scam on December 23 was corrected prior to plant startup. PREVIOUS OCCURRENCE EV ALUA TION River Bend Station previously reported an event that occurred on December 6,2014, in which the Division 2 RPS bus de-energized unexpectedly. That condition resulted in a Division 2 containment isolation and a half-scram. The investigation did not conclusively determine the cause of the trip of the Division 2 RPS motor-generator (MG) output breaker, which initiated the event. Repairs were made to the MG control circuits to address the most likely causes of the trip, and the MG was load tested for approximately 30 hours prior to being placed back into service. . It was postulated that another intermittent failure was occurring in the field flash </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>River Bend Station -Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000 458 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -006 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE circuit card, and a design modification is being developed to mitigate that failure, but that remains a future activity. As described above, the source ofthe MG output breaker trip on December 25 has not been conclusively identified, so it is not certain whether the corrective actions for the December 6 event should have precluded the December 25 event. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE No plant parameters requiring the actuation of any standby diesel generators or the emergency core cool ing systems were exceeded. No reactor safety-relief valves actuated. All reactor control rods properly inserted at the scram signal. This event was, thus, of minimal significance to the health and safety of the public. (NOTE: Energy Industry Component Identification codes are annotated as (**XX**).) </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>