<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-08-19T12:33:07-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-08-19T12:33:07-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-08-19T12:33:07-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>• </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>W. GtoIIer Hettel Columbia GeneraIInG StaIIon </P><P>P.O. Box 968. PE23 </P><P>Richland, WA 99352~ PIt. 509.317.83111 F. 509.377.4150 </P><P>~.energy-northWIScom </P><P>August 1, 2013 G02-13-110 10CFRSO.73 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, D.C. 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: COLUMBIA GENERATING STAnoN, DOCKET NO. 50-387 </P><P>UCENSEE EVENT REPORT NO. 2013-CJ04.00 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Transmitted herewith is Ucensee Event Report No. 2013-004-00 for Columbia Generating Station. This report is submitted pursuant to 10 CFA 5O.73(a)(2XO(B) and 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D). </P><P>There are no commitments being made to the NRC by this letter. If you have any questions or require additional infonnation, please contact Mr. J. R. Trautvetter, Regulatory Compliance Supervisor, at (509) 3n-4337. </P><P>Respectfully, </P><P>tJ{~ </P><P>W. G. Hettel Vice President, Operations </P><P>Enclosure: Licensee Event Report 2013·004-00 </P><P>co: NRC Region IV Administrator </P><P>NRC NRR Project Manager </P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector1988C </P><P>A. J. Rapacz -BPAl1399 </P><P>W.A. Horin -Winston &amp; Strawn </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A112_img_2.jpg"/>(1()'2010) ' ••&quot; *&quot; , ' UCENSEE'EVENT REPoRT (LER) (See reverse for requlred'numberCl . dlgilslcharacters for each block) 1. FAClUTVNAIIE Columbia ~AnarA1tirV'l Station 4. TITLE C 2O.2201(b) o 2O.2201(d)o 2O.220S (8)(1)o 20.2203(8)(2)(1)o 20.2203(8)(2)(11) o 20.2203(8)(3)0)C 20.2203(8)(3)(11)a 20.2203(&amp;)(4)o 5O.38(c)(1)(I)(A) o 5O.38(C)(1)(II)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(l)(C)o 5O.73(a)(2)(B)(A)o 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(8)C 5O.73(a)(2)(11) o SO.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) s.PAGI 10FJ 5O.73(a)(2)(v11) 50.73(a)(2)(vtiI)(A) 5O.73(a)(2)(YIII)(8) SO.73(a)(2)(Ix)(A) o 5O.73(8)(2)(x)</Figure><P>a 2O.2203(8)(2)(1Ii) o 50.38(0)(2) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(8)(4) 
[J 2O.22OS(a)(2)(1v) o 5O.ot8(a)(3)(i1) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(B) [J 73.71(8)(5) 
[J 2O.2203(a)(2)(v) o 5O.73(a)(2)(1)(A) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(C) C OTHER 
C 2O.2203(a)(2)(vI) II 5O.73(a)(2)(I)(8) II 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(D) In AbstnIct below 
</P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A112_img_3.jpg"/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A112_img_4.jpg"/>SYSTEM YES (Ifyes. compIste 15. EXPECTEDSUBMISSIONOATE) NO <Caption><P>ABSTRACT (Umlt to 1400 spaces, I.e., spproxJmat~ 15 slngI&amp;-spsced typewritten I/ne$) </P></Caption></Figure><P>CAUSE </P><P>181 </P><P>When perfonnlng a logic system functional test (LSFT) of the Remote Shutdown Panel transfer switch [JS) during refueling outage R21 on June 4,2013, the procedure for testing the remote transfer switch for the suppression pool spray valve [ISV] failed because a jumper [57] had been left Installed following a new bucket (breaker) installation at the Motor Control Center [MCC) during the previous refueling outage R20. Asatisfactory LSFT was perfonned prior to the installation of the new bucket into the MeC but this LSFT was not re-perfonned to verify the operability of the new bucket after installation. The problem went undetected until the R21 LSFT test failed. The remote transfer switch W8slnoperable from May 16, 2011 until June 4, 2013 when the condition was discovered. This resulted In failure to meet Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.3.3.2.4 and non-compliance with Technical Specifications (TS) Umlting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.3.3.2. The preli~inary apparent causes have been Identified a8: (1) a lack of a standard for Work Order instructions involving the removal and installation of jumpers. resulting In personnel having to rely on experience and skill of the craft for the proper way of executing and doCumenting required modifications; and (2) inadequate deciSion making resulting In the use of a post maintenance testing procedure after the installation of the Spectrum bucket In May 2011 that dJd not adequately prove operability. </P><P>26158 R5 NRCFORM3MA (1()'2010) </P><P>UCEH8E1 EYEHT AEPOR1' (L.ER) </P><Part><H3><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>A110NSHEIT </H3><Sect><P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>REV NO.</P></Sect><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A112_img_8.jpg"/></Figure><Sect><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure></Sect><P>Columbia Generating Station </P><P>050003I7 </P><P>2OF3 2013 -004 -00 </P></Part><Part><H3>NARRAnvE </H3><P>PlANT CONDITIONS </P><P>The event was discovered June 4,2013 when a logic system functionaJ test (LSFT) ~the Suppression Poof Remote Transfer Switch [JS) failed. The plant was in Mode 5 during refuefing outage R21 With the reactor mode switch in Refuef. </P><P>EVENT DESCRIPTION </P><P>On 610412013, during performance of surveillance procedure on the control power transfer switch [JS] lOcated in the Remote Shutdown Panel, a step to verify no continuity (contacts open) for the transfer switch for the suppression pool spray valve RHR-V-27B (ISV] failed. Failure of the surveillance was attributed to a jumper [S7] installed (88-found) in 480V Motor Control Center [MCC) starter controls contained In the new bucket. The jumper had been left in place since refueling outage R20 when the Spectrum bucket (breaker) was installed on May 16, 2011 . The transfer switch was, therefore, inoperable since the jumper was left in ptace, because SUrveillance Requirement 3.3.3.2.4 under Technical Specifications (TS) Umlting Condition for Operation (LeO) 3.3.3.2. The Remote Shutdown System Functions Shan Be Operable, would not have been met when In Modes 1 or 2. </P><P>IMMEDIATE CORRECTIVE ACTION </P><P>The jumper was removed and the loosened terminals were torqued to restore bucket to design configuration. </P><P>CAUSE </P><P>The Cause Evaluation identified preliminary apparent causes of this event as follows: (1) a tack of a standard for Work Order instructions Involving removal and installation of jumpers, which requires personnel to rely on experience and skill of the craft for the proper way of executing and documenting required modifications; and (2) Inadequate decision making resulting In the use of a post maintenance testing procedure after the Instanation of the Spectrum bucket In May 2011 that did not adequately prove operability. </P><P>FURTHER CORRECTIVE ACTION </P><P>Procedures will be revised to provide addftlonallevef of detail for work order steps InvoMng determination and termination of wires, cables and jumpers. </P><P>Additional corrective actions are being Investigated that may result In additiOnal proposed corrective measures. A supplement to this Licensee Event Report will be submitted If the final corrective action ptan Is substantively different than that Included In this form. </P><P>ASSESSMENT OF SAFETY CONSEQUENCES </P><P>The remote transfer switch is located at the Remote Shutdown Panel. The switch transfers control of the Division 2 suppress/on pool spray valve from the Main Control Room to the Remote Shutdown Panel and vice versa. The suppression pool spray valve Is used to provide cooling to the wetwell portion of the primary containment as a means to control containment pressure during an accident. </P><P>The jumpered terminals In the remote shutdown transfer switch did not Impact the operation of the suppression pool spray valve from the Main Control Room. </P><P>With the jumper left in place the operation of the suppression pool spray valve could be Impacted from the Remote Shutdown Panel because of loss of starter control power for valve RHR·V·27B under some abnormal scenarios (I.e., fire in the Main Control Room), which would require the r~plaC8ment of a blown fuse prior to being able to operate the valve from the Remote Shutdown Panel. However the normal osition for this valve Is closed and it would not normall be </P><P>26158 AS </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/2013_08_01_ML13231A112_img_10.jpg"/>NAC FOAM 38M (1()'201 0) Columbia Generating Station NARRAnVE SOFa 2013 .. 004 ... 00 operated from the Remote Shutdown Panel in the event of a fire In the Control Room. Therefore the safety significance of this failure is low. SIMILAR EVENTS There are several documented conditions with simitar drcumstances invoMng improper removal or installation of jumpers. However, they were due to Improper placement or removal of jumpers and did not invotve jumpers being left In for an extended period of time. ENERGY INDUSTRY IDENTIFICATION SYSTEM (ella) INFORMATION CODES EllS codes are bracketed 0where applicable in the narrative. </Figure><P>26158 AS </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>