<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-02-24T14:59:19-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-02-24T14:59:19-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-02-24T14:59:19-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>,,&quot; </P><P>\t.. ~, </P><Part><H1>WkFCREEK 
</H1><P>, NUCLEAR OPERATING CORPORATION 
</P><P>Rick L. Gardner </P><P>February 15, 2010 </P><P>Plant Manager </P><P>WO 10-0008 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: 	Docket No. 50-482: Lice'nsee Event Report 2009-011-00, Intermediate Range Detector NI-36 Inoperable </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>The enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted in accordance with 11 0 CFR 50.73, &quot;Licensee event report system,&quot; paragraph (a)(2)(i)(8) as a condition prohibited by the plant's Technical Specifications (TS). The LER involves the failure to meet the TS Table 3.3.11 Function 18.a when the intermediate range detector NI-36 was considered to be inoperable during Cycle 16. </P><P>This letter contains no commitments. If you have any questions concerning this matter, please contact me at (620) 364-4156, or Mr. Richard D. Flannigan at (620) 364-4117. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>RiCK L. Gardner </P><P>RLG/rit </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: E. E. Collins (NRC), w/e </P><P>G. B. Miller (NRC), w/e </P><P>8. K. Singal (NRC), w/e 
Senior Resident Inspector (NRC), w/e 
</P><P>P.O. Box 411 / Burlington, KS 66839/ Phone: (620) 364-8831 
An Equal Opportunity Employer M/F/HCNET 
</P><P>'I </P><P><Figure ActualText="» "><ImageData src="images/ML100550889_img_0.jpg"/>» </Figure>(9-2007) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 08131/2010 Estimated burden per response to comely with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons eamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments re~arding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch -5 F52), U.S. Nuclear R~ulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or ~intemet e-mail to in ocollec1s@nrc8°V' and to the Desk Officer, Office of In ormation and Regulatory Affairs, NE 8-10202, (3150-0104), Offlce of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000482 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Intermediate Ranoe Detector NI-36 Inoperable </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>12 </TH><TD>16 </TD><TD>\2009 </TD><TD>2009 -011 -00 </TD><TD>02 </TD><TD>15 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITrED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check all that apply) o 20.2201 (b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201 (d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50. 73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 181 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Richard D. Flannigan, Manager Regulatory Affairs (620) 364-4117 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 181 NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On December 16, 2009 the NRC Senior Resident Inspector proposed a violation of Technical Specification Table 3.3.1-1 Function 18.a. A Problem Identification and Resolution (PI&amp;R) inspection sample was performed on Intermediate Range Detector NI-36 and identified that during Refueling Outages 14 and 15 the detector repeatedly failed non-Technical Specification procedure STN IC-236. In one case, the detector failed to go below the intermediate range neutron flux interlock (P-6). This resulted in the detector being inoperable in Cycles 15 and 16. Events are reportable if they occurred within a timeframe of the previous three years. The last four months of Cycle 16 are in the three-year timeframe for reportability. This condition is of low safety significance. The detector was replaced on April 10, 2008 during Refueling Outage 16. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (9-2007) </P><P>(I </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR 1SEQUENTIAL 1 REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 -011 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PLANT CONDITIONS PRIOR TO EVENT MODE-1 Power-100 EVENT DESCRIPTION On December 16, 2009 the NRC Senior Resident Inspector proposed a violation of Technical Specification Table 3.3.1-1 Function 18.a, Reactor Trip System Interlocks -Intermediate Range Neutron Flux, P-6. A Problem Identification and Resolution (PI&amp;R) inspection sample was performed on Intermediate Range Detector NI-36 [EllS Code: IG-DET] and identified that during Refueling Outages 14 and 15 the detector repeatedly failed non-Technical Specification procedure STN IC-236, &quot;Intermediate Range N36 Compensation Voltage Adjustment.&quot; In one case, intermediate range detector NI-36 failed to go below the intermediate range neutron flux interlock (P-6). This resulted in the detector being inoperable in Cycles 15 and 16. Due to an internal detector fault, the compensating voltage on the intermediate range detector was not effective which resulted in a high intermediate range indication. The intermediate range detectors are of the compensated ion chamber type and the compensating voltage is set such that the instrument can discriminate between neutron and gamma radiation. The design of the nuclear instrumentation system is such that the source range instruments are automatically energized when the neutron flux levels drop below the intermediate range neutron flux interlock (P-6). In one case, during a reactor shutdown on October 7,2006, the intermediate range detector NI-36 did not reach the P-6 interlock value. The plant operators manually reset the source range channels [EllS Code: IG-DET] and they operated properly. Events are reportable if they occurred within a timeframe of the previous three years. The last four months of Cycle 16 are in the three-year timeframe for reportability. Wolf Creek Generating Station (WCGS) had two plant shutdowns during the last four months of Cycle 16, on January 18, 2008 and March 17,2008. During both of these plant shutdowns, intermediate range detector NI-36 operated properly and went below the P-6 setpoint. Intermediate range detector NI-36 detector was replaced on April 10, 2008 during Refueling Outage 16. BASIS FOR REPORT ABILITY This condition is being reported because the NRC Senior Resident Inspector proposed a violation of Technical Specification Table 3.3.1-1 Function 18.a. WCGS had two plant shutdowns during the threeyear reportability timeframe and prior to intermediate range detector NI-36 being replaced. In both shutdowns, intermediate range detector NI-36 operated properly and went below the P-6 interlock. This condition is being reported per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) as an operation or condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) </P><P>, &quot;&quot;', </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 -011 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ROOT CAUSE The cause of the condition is historical. The intermediate range detector NI-36 was undercompensated. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Intermediate range detector NI-36 was replaced on April 10, 2008 during Refueling Outage 16. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The safety significance of this condition is low. The abnormalities encountered with the Intermediate range detector NI-36 did not prevent maintaining the reactor in a safe shutdown condition. During the three-year timeframe for reportability, the intermediate range detectors operated properly. The intermediate range detector NI-36 was replaced in Refueling Outage 16. OPERATING EXPERIENCE/PREVIOUS EVENTS None. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>