<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-09-01T11:25:31-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-09-01T11:25:31-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-09-01T11:25:31-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:7d51e8a4-66b8-4bc8-90e7-6b22ef779278</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:715679de-c60e-cc4b-ac39-b5239f491e88</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>\• </P><Part><H1>w&lt;M.FCREEK 
</H1><P>'NUCLEAR OPERATING CORPORATION </P><P>August 24, 2011 </P><P>Russell A. Smith Plant Manager </P><P>WO 11-0065 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: 	Docket No. 50-482: Licensee Event Report 2011-007-00, &quot;Manual Reactor Trip due to Failed Controller.Cards in the 'B' Feedwater Pump Turbine Control System&quot; </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>The enclosed Licensee Event Report is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) regarding a Reactor Trip and an Engineered Safety Features Actuation at the Wolf Creek Generating Station. </P><P>This letter contains no commitments. If you have any questions concerning this matter, please contact me at (620) 364-4156, or Mr. Gautam Sen at (620) 364-4175. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>;M~ </P><P>Russell A. Smith </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: E. E. Collins (NRC), w/e </P><P>J. R. Hall (NRC), w/e </P><P>G. B. Miller (NRC), w/e 
Senior Resident Inspector (NRC), w/e 
</P><P>P.o. Box411 1 Burlington, KS 668391 Phone: (620) 364-8831 
An Equal Opportunity Employer M/F/HCNET 
</P><P>· . Jtl; '.'&gt;::;::;r~~.: 1:: ~:~:h </P><P>',' </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U,S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) , &quot;,0, (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch (T-5 F52), u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose' an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION ,r:· </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000482 1 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Manual Reactor Trip due to Failed Controller Cards in the '8' Feedwater Pump Turbine Control SYstem </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>I SEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>06 </TH><TD>26 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>2011 -007 -00 </TD><TD>Q~ </TD><TD>~41&quot;&quot;&quot;&quot; </TD><TD>:20jtl1_~,&quot;-' </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE Mode 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check al/ that apply) o 20.2201 (b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201 (d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) 18I 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71 (a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 82% </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Gautam Sen, Manager Regulatory Affairs (620) 364-4175 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>X </TH><TD>SJ </TD><TD>P </TD><TD>G080 </TD><TD>Y </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 18I NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 26, 2011, Wolf Creek Generating Station (WCGS) was at 82 percent power during a reactor startup when the '8' Main Feedwater pump tripped at 1609 COT. The control room operators manually tripped the reactor. All control rods fully inserted and the Reactor Trip System and the Engineered Safety Feature Actuation System performed as expected. The cause of the trip was the failure of one or both of two controller cards in the Main Feedwater turbine control system. Two controller cards in the main turbine control system were replaced. The safety significance of this event is low. This event is bounded by analyses as reported in the WCGS Updated Safety Analysis Report Section 15.2.7, &quot;Loss of Normal Feedwater Flow.&quot; There were no adverse effects on the health and safety of the public. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><P>[I </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 -007 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PLANT CONDITIONS AT THE TIME OF THE EVENT Mode 1 82% power DESCRIPTION OF THE EVENT On June 26, 2011 the Wolf Creek Generating Station (WCGS) was in the process of power ascension at approximately 82 percent power, following Refueling Outage 18. The &quot;8&quot; Main Feedwater (MFW) pump [EllS Code: SJ-P] unexpectedly tripped at 1609 CDT. The reactor was manually tripped with no complications. No structures, systems, or components were inoperable that contributed to the event. Plant data showed that prior to the trip of the &quot;8&quot; Main Feedwater pump (MFP) the feed flow increased and the suction pressure for the MFP decreased. This rapid increase in generator feedwater flow rate and corresponding decrease in MFP suction pressure are an indirect indication that the MFP was accelerating in speed at the time of the trip. Extensive troubleshooting was conducted on the MFP, which identified an intermittent failure on one or both of two controller cards in the main feedwater turbine control system. The failure of the controller cards resulted in the turbine accelerating and tripping the MFP. The reactor was manually tripped due to the loss of the &quot;8&quot; Main Feedwater pump, prior to an automatic trip occurring on low steam generator [EllS Code: SG] levels. All control rods fully inserted and all safety equipment performed as designed. The Reactor Trip System (RTS) and the Engineered Safety Feature Actuation System (ESFAS) [EllS Code: JE] performed as required. An Auxiliary Feedwater actuation signal occurred due to trip of both of the Main Feedwater pumps from a turbine trip and low SG levels. All auxiliary feedwater pumps started and operated as expected. 8ASIS FOR REPORTA81L1TY The reactor trip signal and actuation of the ESFAS instrumentation described in this event is reportable per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A), which requires reporting of &quot;Any event or condition that resulted in manual or automatic actuation of any of the systems listed in paragraph (a)(2)(iv)(8) of this section.&quot; Paragraph (8)(1) of 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv) includes &quot;Reactor protection system (RPS) including: reactor scram or reactor trip.&quot; Paragraph (8)(6) of 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(iv) includes &quot;PWR auxiliary or emergency feedwater.&quot; ROOT CAUSE The cause of the '8' MFP trip was a failure of one or both of two controller cards in the main feedwater turbine control system. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><P>, ..~ </P><P>. </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 -007 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>The controller cards are obsolete and no longer have vendor support. The equipment reliability program had targeted the controller cards for replacement. This original turbine control system is currently scheduled for replacement by a new MFP digital control system in Refueling Outage19 (Fall 2012). CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Two controller cards in the main feedwater turbine control system were replaced. The main feedwater turbine control system, for both MFPs, is currently scheduled for replacement by a new MFP digital control system in Refueling Outage19 (Fall 2012). SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The safety significance of this event is low. This event is analyzed as reported in WCGS Updated Safety Analysis Report (USAR) Section 15.2.7, &quot;Loss of Normal Feedwater Flow.&quot; Results of the analysis show that a loss of normal feedwater does not adversely affect the core, the reactor coolant system, or the steam system, since the auxiliary feedwater capacity is such that reactor coolant water is not relieved from the pressurizer relief or safety valves. There were no adverse effects on the health and safety of the public. OPERATING EXPERIENCE/PREVIOUS SIMILAR OCCURRENCES LER 2010-005-00 described a reactor trip due to a trip of a main feedwater pump caused by the failed transfer of an inverter to its alternate power supply. LER 2010-006-00 described a reactor trip due to a trip of a main feedwater pump caused by a failed servo valve in the main feedwater speed control system. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>