<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-08-01T12:17:55-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-08-01T12:17:55-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-08-01T12:17:55-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>wtLFCREEK 
</H1><P>NUCLEAR OPERATING CORPORATION </P><P>Matthew W. Sunseri President and Chief Executive Officer </P><P>July 23, 2012 WM 12-0021 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: 	Docket No. 50-482: Licensee Event Report 2012-005-00, &quot;Calculation Assumptions Lead to Inadequate Procedure, Resulting in LCO 3.0.3 Entry Due to Non-Functional Class 1 E Electrical Equipment Air Conditioning Unit&quot; </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>The enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) to report a violation of Technical Specification Limiting Condition for Operation 3.0.3 due to a Class 1 E electrical equipment air-conditioning unit being nonfunctional. </P><P>This letter contains no commitments. If you have any questions concerning this matter, please contact me at (620) 364-4008, or Mr. Gautam Sen at (620) 364-4175. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/>Sincerely, </Figure><P>MWS/rit </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: T. A. Beltz (NRC), w/e </P><P>E. E. Collins (NRC), w/e </P><P>N. F. O'Keefe (NRC), w/e Senior Resident Inspector (NRC), w/e </P><P>P.O. Box 411 / Burlington, KS 66839/ Phone: (620) 364-8831 </P><P>An Equal Opportunity Employer M/F/HCNET </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>1 ..• ~,</P><P>t ,., </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch (T-5 F52), u.s. Nuclear Regulatory CommisSion, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000482 1 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Calculation Assumptions Lead to Inadequate Procedure, Resulting in LCO 3.0.3 Entry Due to Non-Functional Class 1 E Electrical Equipment Air ConditioninQ Unit </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>I SEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>05 </TH><TD>23 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 005 00 </TD><TD>07 </TD><TD>23 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE Mode 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check al/ that apply) D 20.2201 (b) D 20.2203(a)(3)(i) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) D 50.73(a)(2)(vii) D 20.2201 (d) D 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) D 20.2203(a)(4) D 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) D 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) D 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(x) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) D 50.36(c)(2) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) D 73.71(a)(4) D 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) D 50.46(a)(3)(ii) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) D 73.71(a)(5) D 20.2203(a)(2)(v) D 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) D OTHER D 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) [8J 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) D 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Gautam Sen, Manager Regulatory Affairs (620) 364-4175 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) t8:I NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>~BSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 4, 2012 at 0325 COT, a Class 1 E electrical equipment air conditioning (AlC) train was declared nonfunctional. Technical Requirement (TR) 3.7.23 allows a train to be nonfunctional if compensatory measures are established for the affected unit. During the operability determination and functionality assessment process it was determined that the operability of the associated train Class 1 E electrical equipment could not be maintained without additional compensatory measures and for a limited period of time. Technical Specification (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation 3.0.3 was entered and a plant shutdown was commenced on June 6, 2012 at 0327 COT. On June 6, 2012 at 0505, the Class 1 E electrical equipment AlC train was restored to functional status and the plant returned to 100 percent power. The cause of the event was a calculation that concluded one train of air conditioning was not capable of supporting both trains of Class 1 E equipment while maintaining room ambient temperatures below the maximum specified operating temperature. Control room operators have been directed to enter the applicable TS on a loss of a Class 1 E electrical equipment AlC train. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/>\.: </Figure><P>, </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) U_S_ NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1_ FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2_ DOCKET </TD><TD>6_ LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3_ PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR 1SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -005 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PLANT CONDITIONS AT THE TIME OF THE EVENT Mode 1 100 % power No SSCs were inoperable that contributed to the event other than the nonfunctional Class 1 E electrical equipment air-conditioning (NC) [EllS: VI] trains. BACKGROUND INFORMATION: The Class 1 E electrical equipment NC trains provide a suitable environment for the Class 1 E electrical equipment. These NC trains provide temperature control for the Engineered Safety Features (ESF) switchgear [EllS: EB, SWGR] room components, DC switchgear [EllS: EJ, SWGR] room components, and 125 VDC 1E system battery [EllS: EJ, BTRY] room components. The Class 1 E electrical equipment NC trains consists of two independent trains that provide cooling of recirculated air in the rooms associated with that train. Each train consists of a prefilter, selfcontained refrigeration system (using essential service water [EllS: BI] as a heat sink), centrifugal fans, instrumentation, and controls to provide for electrical equipment room temperature control. DESCRIPTION OF THE EVENT: During the week of May 23, 2012, a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) Problem Identification and Resolution team inspection identified several concerns with the incorporation of calculation GK06-W, Revision 2, &quot;SGK05NB Class 1 E Electrical Equipment Rooms NC Units, Single Unit Operation Capability,&quot; into plant documents. One of the concerns related to the calculation requirements for the use of temporary ventilation fans and the fans not being powered from a safety related source. Operations procedure SYS GK-200, &quot;Inoperable Class 1 E NC Unit,&quot; and the Technical Requirements (TR) Manual 3.7.23, &quot;Class 1 E Electrical Equipment Air-Conditioning (NC),&quot; considered the use of temporary fans as an enhancement. On May 29,2012 at 1625 COT, SGK05B [EllS: VI, ACU] was declared nonfunctional due to degrading oil pump pressure. The compressor was replaced and SGK05B was restored to a functional status on May 31,2012 at 1835 COT. The SGK05B unit was restored to functional status prior to completing a prompt operability determination. On June 4,2012 at 0325 COT, the compressor for SGK05A [EllS: VI, ACU] was found tripped on low oil pressure and the unit was declared nonfunctional. It was determined that the SGK05A oil strainer was clogged with oil sludge and particulate matter. The same type of oil sludge discovered in the oil strainer for SGK05A was also found in the oil strainer for SGK05B. Personnel were able to clean up the sludge, flush the compressor's oil reservoir and replenish it with new oil. SGK05A was restored to functional status on June 6, 2012 at 0505 COT During the operability determination and functionality assessment process, it was determined that the operability of the associated train Class 1 E electrical equipment could not be maintained without additional compensatory measures and for a limited period of time (30 hours). Technical Specification (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.0.3 was entered and a plant shutdown was commenced on June 6,2012 at 0327 COT. On June 6,2012 at 0505 COT, SGK05A was restored to functional status. LCO 3.0.3 was exited and the power decrease was stopped at approximately 88 percent power. At approximately 0900 COT on June 6, 2012, the plant returned to 100 .£.ercent.£.ower. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><P>., </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR 1SEQUENTIAL 1REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -005 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Calculation GK-06-W, Revision 1 was created in 1999 to determine the effect on the Class 1 E electrical equipment room temperatures from heat loads within the rooms in the event a Class 1 E electrical equipment room NC unit is out of service. The calculation revision was used as a basis for the compensatory actions directed by TR 3.7.23 when a Class 1 E electrical equipment NC unit, SGK05A or SGK05B, is nonfunctional. The calculation revision showed that one functional NC unit was capable of maintaining all of the Class 1 E electrical equipment rooms at a temperature below 104 degrees Fahrenheit (F) with the opening of doors between equipment rooms. Approximately 11 years later, errors were identified in the calculation that, when corrected, resulted in the conclusion of Revision 1 being erroneous. Revision 2 of the calculation was released in April 2011 to correct the errors. Revision 2 of the calculation did not support the conclusion that the Class 1 E electrical room temperatures would remain below the acceptance criteria of 104 degrees F, under worst-case initial conditions without taking credit for non-safety related cooling units in the rooms surrounding the Class 1 E electrical equipment rooms. BASIS FOR REPORTABILlTY: This LER is submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) to report a condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. SGK05B was nonfunctional for approximately 50 hours during the event starting on May 29, 2012. SGK05A was nonfunctional for approximately 50 hours during the event starting on June 4, 2012. Because of the essential support function provided by the Class 1 E electrical equipment NC trains, the correct application of the TS, upon discovery of an nonfunctional Class 1 E electrical equipment NC train, is to immediately enter the applicable Conditions and Required Actions under TS 3.8.4, TS 3.8.7, TS 3.8.9, as well as LCO 3.0.3. In both events this resulted in a condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. A review of the last three years revealed multiple instances when one Class 1 E electrical equipment NC train was nonfunctional for greater than one hour. Each of these instances was reportable as a condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. NUREG 1022, Rev. 2, Section 3.2.2, &quot;Operation or Condition Prohibited by Technical Specifications,&quot; indicates that entry into LCO 3.0.3 should be considered reportable under this criterion (10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)) if the condition is not corrected within an hour, such that it is necessary to initiate actions to shutdown. As actions were initiated to shutdown the plant, this event is reportable pursuant to 1 0 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) as an operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's TSs. One Class 1 E electrical equipment NC train and its associated train of Class 1 E electrical equipment were available and remained operable at all times. As such, these events do not constitute a condition that would have prevented fulfillment of the safety functions required of the Class 1 E electrical equipment. Room temperatures remained below the area temperature limits for qualification of electrical equipment. Additionally, an engineering disposition concluded that in the event the Class 1 E equipment is exposed to temperatures in excess of 104 degrees F, the equipment would remain functional at the elevated temperatures. The Class 1 E electrical equipment was originally specified to a mild environment, which specifies a maximum operating temperature of 110 degrees F. Per this requirement, most of the equipment was supplied with a maximum normal operating temperature of 104 degrees F. In the event the Class 1 E electrical equipment were exposed to a relatively short-term duration of increased environmental temperature, the qualified life of the equipment might be affected, but the functionality of the equipment would not be affected. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>• ,J </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -005 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ROOT CAUSE: A calculation completed in 1999 contained incorrect methodology and assumptions, resulting in the conclusion that a single air conditioning unit is capable of cooling both trains of Class 1 E equipment with specific optional compensatory measures. When the errors were recognized and the calculation was revised in 2011, correcting the deficiencies and incorrect assumptions and incorporating revised maximum postulated heat loads and worst-case initial conditions, the calculation conclusion is that one train of air conditioning is not capable in all conditions of supporting both trains of Class 1 E equipment while maintaining room ambient temperatures below the original equipment maximum specified normal operating temperature (104 degrees F). When the new calculation revision was issued the system operating procedures and the technical requirements manual specified compensatory measures did not align with the requirements of the calculation revision. Engineering judgment was used to specify compensatory measures to be taken, via engineering disposition. However, these compensatory measures were not properly translated into the operating procedures and TRM. Consequently, when the TR specification and system operating procedure were utilized, the actions and requirements did not align with the analysis and the analysis did not support Operability in all conditions. Additionally, the engineering judgment was not supported by further analysis. Inability to meet the analysis requirements in all modes of potential operation resulted in entry into LCO 3.0.3 and commencement of plant shutdown. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS: Procedure SYS GK-200, &quot;Inoperable Class 1 E AlC Unit&quot; has been deleted. Essential reading has been issued to the control room operators specifying that the failure of a Class 1 E electrical equipment AlC train will result in declaring the affected Class 1 E electrical equipment inoperable and entry into the Conditions/Required Actions of TS 3.8.4, TS 3.8.7 and TS 3.8.9 as well as entry into LCO 3.0.3. Calculation GK-06-W will be revised. The results of the calculation will be used to incorporate requirements for the Class 1 E electrical equipment AlC trains into the TS, revise the Technical Requirements Manual (if appropriate) and revise operations procedures. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE: The event addressed by this LER is not safety significant. Only one train of Class 1 E electrical equipment was potentially affected by a nonfunctional Class 1 E electrical equipment AlC train at any time. The other Class 1 E electrical equipment AlC unit was functional and its associated train of Class 1 E electrical equipment was operable. Room temperatures remained below the area temperature limits for qualification of electrical equipment. An engineering disposition concluded that in the event the Class 1 E electrical equipment is exposed to temperatures in excess of 104 degrees F, the equipment would remain functional at the elevated temperatures. The Class 1 E electrical equipment was originally specified to a mild environment, which specifies a maximum operating temperature of 110 degrees F. Per this requirement, most of the equipment was supplied with a maximum normal operating temperature of 104 degrees F. In the event the Class 1 E electrical equipment were exposed to a relatively short-term duration of increased environmental temperature, the qualified life of the equipment might be affected, but the functionality of the equipment would not be affected. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P><P>t, </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL I REV YEAR NUMBER NO, </TD><TD>5 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -005 --DO </TD></TR><TR><TH>OPERATING EXPERIENCE/PREVIOUS SIMILAR OCCURRENCES: None </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>