<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-07-10T15:42:50-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-07-10T15:42:50-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-07-10T15:42:50-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>., I.: </P><Part><H1>Wr~LFCREEK
</H1><P>~ </P><P>'NUCLEAR OPERATING CORPORATION </P><P>Russell A. Smith Plant Manager </P><P>July 3,2012 </P><P>WO 12-0057 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Reference: 	Letter WO 12-0047, dated May 31, 2012, from S. E. Hedges, WCNOC, to USNRC </P><P>Subject: 	Docket No. 50-482: Licensee Event Report 2012-004-00, &quot;Two Charging Pumps Capable of Injecting into the RCS Due to Inadequate Definition of Centrifugal Charging Pump in LCO 3.4.12&quot; </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>The enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) regarding two charging pumps (a centrifugal charging pump (CCP) and the normal charging pump (NCP» being capable of injecting into the Reactor Coolant System (RCS) during the specified mode of applicability for the limiting condition of operation (LCO) for Technical Specification (TS) 3.4.12, &quot;Low Temperature Overpressure Protection (LTOP) System.&quot; This event is being conservatively reported under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) as a condition prohibited by TSs as the Required Actions of TS 3.4.12 would not have been met during certain periods of time if the NCP were to be considered a CCP. </P><P>The Reference submitted a request for interpretation of TS 3.4.12. The Reference requested concurrence with the following position: </P><P>LCO 3.4.12 requires, in part, an L TOP System shall be OPERA8LE with a maximum of zero safety injection pumps and one centrifugal charging pump capable of injecting into the Reactor Coolant System (RCS). The LCO is applicable in MODE 3 with any RCS cold leg temperature::;; 368 of, MODE 4, MODE 5, and MODE 6 when the reactor vessel head is on. At the Wolf Creek Generating Station (WCGS), the LCO is met when both safety injection pumps and one centrifugal charging pump are not capable of injecting into the RCS with the second centrifugal charging pump and the normal charging pump capable of injecting into the RCS. </P><P>P.O. Box 411 / Burlington, KS 66839/ Phone: (620) 364-8831 
An Equal Opportunity Employer M/F/HCNET 
</P><P>WO 12-0057 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>This letter contains no commitments. If you have any questions concerning this matter, please contact me at (620) 364-4156, or Mr. Gautam Sen at (620) 364-4175. </P><P>Sincerely, </P></Part><Part><H1>~r!~ 
</H1><P>Russell A. Smith </P><P>RAS/rlt </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: E. E. Collins (NRC), w/e </P><P>J. R. Hall (NRC), w/e </P><P>N. F. O'Keefe (NRC), w/e Senior Resident Inspector (NRC), w/e </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 1013112013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIA/Privacy Service Branch (T-5 F52), u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000482 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Two Charging Pumps Capable of Injecting into the RCS Due to Inadequate Definition of Centrifugal Charging Pump in LCO 3.4.12 </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>ISEQUENTIAL (REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>05 </TH><TD>09 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>2012 004 00 </TD><TD>07 </TD><TD>03 </TD><TD>2012 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE Mode 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITIED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check all that apply) o 20.2201 (b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50. 73(a)(2)(iii) o 50. 73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71 (a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) C8J 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Gautam Sen, Manager Regulatory Affairs (620) 364-4175 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) C8J NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>~BSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On May 9,2012, a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) regional inspector identified that a potential violation of Technical Specification (TS) 3.4.12, &quot;Low Temperature Overpressure Protection (L TOP) System,&quot; occurred during the recent forced outage and in prior refueling outages. Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.4.12 requires an L TOP System shall be operable with a maximum of zero safety injection pumps and one centrifugal charging pump capable of injecting into the Reactor Coolant System (RCS). During the recent forced outage and during refueling outages, one safety related centrifugal charging pump and the non-safety related normal charging pump were capable of injecting into the RCS: The apparent cause for this potential violation is the failure to specifically define in the TS LCO that the centrifugal charging pump is an Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS) centrifugal charging pump. A request for interpretation of TS 3.4.12 was submitted to the NRC on May 31,2012. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) &quot; </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12192A541_img_0.jpg"/></Figure><P>\ </P><P>\\• </P><P>.. 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2_ DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -004 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PLANT CONDITIONS AT THE TIME OF THE EVENT Mode 1 100 % power There were no inoperable structures, components or systems that were inoperable at the start of the event and that contributed to the event. DESCRIPTION OF THE EVENT: On May 9,2012, a Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) regional inspector identified that a potential violation of Technical Specification (TS) 3.4.12, &quot;Low Temperature Overpressure Protection (LTOP) System,&quot; occurred during the recent forced outage and in prior refueling outages. Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.4.12 requires an L TOP System shall be operable with a maximum of zero safety injection pumps [EllS: BO,P] and one centrifugal charging pump (CCP) [EllS: BO,P] capable of injecting into the Reactor Coolant System (RCS) [EllS: AB]. During the recent forced outage and during refueling outages, one safety related centrifugal charging pump and the non-safety related normal charging pump (NCP) [EllS: CB,P] were capable of injecting into the RCS. A review of the Wolf Creek Generating Station (WCGS) licensing basis and the NRC safety evaluations related to License Amendment Nos. 123 and 130 establishes the following position: LCO 3.4.12 requires, in part, an L TOP System shall be operable with a maximum of zero safety injection pumps and one CCP capable of injecting into the RCS. The LCO is applicable in Mode 3 with any RCS cold leg temperature &lt;/= 368 degrees F, Mode 4, Mode 5, and Mode 6 when the reactor vessel head is on. The LCO is considered to be met when both safety injection pumps and one CCP are not capable of injecting into the RCS with the second CCP and the NCP capable of injecting into the RCS. The mass input transient analysis assumes simultaneous injection of both a CCP and the NCP into the water-solid RCS while the Residual Heat Removal (RHR) System and the letdown line are isolated. This assumption is consistent with the TS LCO, which requires all safety injection pumps and one of the two Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS) CCPs be made incapable of injecting into the RCS and therefore, allows a CCP to be operable and the NCP to be functional under these modes of operation. The safety evaluation in Amendment No. 123 for the conversion from current TSs to the improved TSs indicates that the requirements associated with LCO 3.4.12 is specific to ECCS pump capability to inject into the RCS. The NCP is not an ECCS pump. The safety evaluation for Amendment No. 130 specified that the operability of two power operated relief valves (PORVs) [EllS: AB,RV] or two RHR suction relief valves [EllS: BP,RV] or an RCS vent [EllS: AB,VTV] opening of at least 2 square inches ensures adequate flow capacity to protect the RCS from overpressurization from the start of a CCP and/or the NCP injecting into the RCS. The full basis for this position was submitted to the NRC in Wolf Creek Nuclear Operating Corporation (WCNOC) letter WO 12-0047, &quot;Request for Interpretation of Technical Specification 3.4.12, &quot;Low Temperature Overpressure Protection (L TOP) System&quot;,&quot; dated May 31,2012. </TH></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>:&quot;~\' I·~&quot;;:':. ;~1&gt;;,,1t;~ </P><P>(~ ,</P><P>&quot;, \&quot;., </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>I SEQUENTIAL I REV YEAR· NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -004 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>The NCP is a non-safety related single speed, horizontal, centrifugal type pump and is powered from a non-Class 1 E source. The NCP is not an ECCS pump. BASIS FOR REPORTABILlTY: LCO 3.4.12 requires an L TOP System be operable with a maximum of zero safety injection pumps and one centrifugal charging pump capable of injecting into the RCS in Mode 3 with any RCS cold leg temperature &lt;1= 368 degrees F, Mode 4, Mode 5, and Mode 6 when the reactor vessel head is on. With two centrifugal charging pumps capable of injecting into the RCS, Required Action B.1 requires the immediate initiation of action to verify a maximum of one centrifugal charging pump is capable of injecting into the RCS. If the Completion Time of Required Action B.1 is not met, Required Action G.1 requires depressurizing the RCS and establishing an RCS vent of &gt;1= 2.0 square inches. This event is being conservatively reported under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) as a condition prohibited by TSs as the Required Actions of TS 3.4.12 would not have been met during certain periods of time if the NCP were to be considered a CCP. The following table identifies the dates in the prior 3 years in which a CCP and the NCP may have been capable of injecting into the RCS when in the mode of applicability of TS 3.4.12. Dates -one CCP and the NCP capable of Injecting into RCS 3/23/12 to 3/25/12 1/14/12 to 3/19/12 6/2111 to 6/20/11 5/6111 to 5/30/11 3/19/11 to 3/25/11 10/5/10 to 10/15/10 3/4/10 to 3/5/10 10/10109 to 10/15/09 11/9/09 to 11/18/09 A request for interpretation of TS 3.4.12 was submitted to the NRC as WCNOC considers the LCO to be met when both safety injection pumps and one CCP are not capable of injecting into the RCS with the second CCP and the NCP capable of injecting into the RCS. ROOT CAUSE: The apparent cause for this potential violation is the failure to specifically define in the TS LCO that the centrifugal charging pump is an Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS) centrifugal charging pump. The TS 3.4.12 Bases specifies that the term CCP refers to the safety related ECCS pumps only. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS: A request for interpretation of TS 3.4.12 was submitted to the NRC on May 31,2012. </TH></TR></Table><P>;' </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR J SEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO, </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2012 -004 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>The affected Operations procedures will be revised to apply a conservative understanding of LCO 3.4.12 by specifying that the NCP is rendered incapable of injecting into the RCS in the mode or other specified condition in the Applicability of TS 3.4.12 since a CCP is required for a functional boration injection flow path. The TS 3.4.12 Bases will be revised to apply a conservative understanding of LCO 3.4.12 by specifying that the NCP is rendered incapable of injecting into the RCS in the mode or other specified condition in the Applicability of TS 3.4.12. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE: The safety significance of this event is low. The L TOP PORV setpoint limit curve (Pressure and Temperature Limits Report Figure 2.2-1) is determined based on the updated heatup and cooldown limit curves, and the analysis results of limiting L TOP transients. The methodology for this determination is given in WCAP-14040-A, &quot;Methodology Used to Develop Cold Overpressure Mitigation System Setpoints and RCS Heatup and Cooldown Limit Curves,&quot; Revision 4. The limiting L TOP mechanisms analyzed for WCGS under water solid conditions were: a. FOR LIMITING MASS ADDITION L TOP MECHANISM Operation of one CCP and the NCP with instrument air failure resulting in the flow control valve in the letdown line failing closed (letdown isolation) and the flow control valve in the charging line failing open (maximum charging flow), and b. FOR LIMITING HEAT ADDITION LTOP MECHANISM Inadvertent start-up of a reactor coolant pump with a maximum 50 degrees F temperature mismatch between the RCS and the hotter steam generators. These analyses, using the LOFTRAN computer code, take into consideration pressure overshoot and undershoot beyond the PORV open and close setpoints, which can occur as a result of time delays in signal processing and valve stroke times. The maximum expected pressure overshoot and undershoot calculated from the limiting mass input and heat input transients, in conjunction with the 10 CFR 50, Appendix G, pressure limits and reactor coolant pump No. 1 seal pressure limit, are utilized in the selection of the pressure setpoints for the PORV. The mass injection rate assumed in the design basis mass input transient is based on 100% flow capacity of the NCP and one CCP. The maximum combined pump flow has been assumed in order to envelop the maximum flow possible by the operational configuration that uses the NCP for charging with one CCP remaining operable, or the use of one CCP for charging with the NCP remaining operable, during shutdown modes. OPERATING EXPERIENCE/PREVIOUS SIMILAR OCCURRENCES: None </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>