<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-08-20T07:09:48-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-08-20T07:09:48-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-08-20T07:09:48-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:61826c35-68be-4813-be9e-04d7a99b07d5</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:1e26154c-5489-944d-b050-21b07288c669</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>~FCREEK 
</H1><P>NUCLEAR OPERATING CORPORATION </P><P>August 14, 2013 </P><P>A. J. Camp, Jr Plant Manager </P><P>WO 13-0057 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: Docket No. 50-482: Licensee Event Report 2013-007-00, &quot;Nonfunctional Class 1 E Electrical Equipment Air Conditioning Unit Results in Longer than Technical Specification Completion Time&quot; </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>The enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) to report exceeding the Technical Specification (TS) Required Action Completion Time for TS 3.8.4,3.8.7,3.8.9 and Limiting Condition for Operation 3.0.3. </P><P>This letter contains no commitments. If you have any questions concerning this matter, please contact me at (620) 364-4110, or Mr. Michael J. Westman at (620) 364-4009. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>AJC/rit </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: C. F. Lyon (NRC), w/e </P><P>N. F. O'Keefe (NRC), w/e </P><P>S. A. Reynolds (NRC), w/e Senior Resident Inspector (NRC), w/e </P><P>P.O. Box 411 / Burlington, KS 66839/ Phone: (620) 364-8831 
An Equal Opportunity Employer M/F/HCNET 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 10/31/2013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Privacy Service Branch (T-5 F53). U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000482 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Nonfunctional Class 1 E Electrical Equipment Air Conditioning Unit Results in Longer than Technical Specification Completion Time </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>S. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>I SEQUENTIAL I REVYEAR NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>06 </TH><TD>17 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>2013 007 00 </TD><TD>08 </TD><TD>14 </TD><TD>2013 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check all that apply) o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 181 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Michael Westman, Manager Regulatory Affairs (620) 364-4009 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 181 YES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ONO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>09 </TD><TD>30 </TD><TD>2013 </TD></TR><TR><TH>~BSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On June 17, 2013 at 1111 Central Daylight Time (COT), the Class 1 E electrical equipment air conditioning unit, SGK05A, was declared nonfunctional due to an analysis of an oil sample that showed elevated levels of aluminum. As a result, Technical Specification (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.0.3 was entered and a plant shutdown was commenced. On June 17, 2013, enforcement discretion was sought to permit noncompliance with TS 3.8.4, TS 3.8.7, TS 3.8.9, as well as LCO 3.0.3, to permit additional time to complete repairs and restoration of SGK05A before a plant shutdown would be required. An additional 168 hours was requested to restore SGK05A to a functional status such that the Completion Time of LCO 3.0.3 would expire at 1111 COT on June 24, 2013. The Nuclear Regulatory Commission granted approval of the requested enforcement discretion on June 17,2013. The replacement of the SGK05A compressor and testing to restore functionality was completed at 2220 COT on June 21, 2013. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10·2010) NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) NRC FORM 366A (10·2010 </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 --007 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>PLANT CONDITIONS AT THE TIME OF THE EVENT Mode 1 100% power There were no structures, components or systems that were inoperable and contributed to the initiation or limited mitigation of the event. DESCRIPTION OF THE EVENT On June 17, 2013, the results of an analysis of an oil sample taken from the &quot;A&quot; Class 1 E electrical equipment air conditioning (NC) unit [EllS: VI, ACU], SGK05A, showed elevated levels of aluminum. Additionally, the unit was observed to have increased vibration levels and running with elevated Amperes, approximately 20% less than the rated full load amperage of the motor (55 Amperes). This information was discussed with the equipment manufacturer. The compressor's pistons and connecting rods are made of aluminum so the concern was that these parts were damaged. The likely cause of this damage was slugging/hydraulicing of the compressor, which is the introduction of a liquid into a system meant for gas. It was concluded that the equipment could no longer be considered reliable to support the mission time of supported systems. The last maintenance performed on the equipment was on May 28, 2013, when the SGK05A compressor was replaced. Since the unit could not be relied on to meet its required function, the Class 1 E electrical equipment air conditioning (NC) unit, SGK05A, which cools the 'A' train safety related electrical equipment rooms was declared nonfunctional per Technical Requirement (TR) 3.7.23, &quot;Class 1 E Electrical Equipment Air-Conditioning (NC).&quot; TR 3.7.23 requires two Class 1 E electrical equipment NC trains be functional in Modes 1 through 4 ..Because of the essential support function provided by the Class 1 E electrical equipment NC trains, the correct application of the Technical Specification (TS), upon discovery of a nonfunctional Class 1 E electrical equipment NC train, is to immediately enter the applicable Conditions and Required Actions under TS 3.8.4, &quot;DC Sources -Operating,&quot; TS 3.8.7, (Inverters -Operating,&quot; TS 3.8.9, &quot;Distribution Systems -Operating,&quot; as well as Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.0.3. LCO 3.0.3 requires action to be taken within 1 hour to place the plant in Mode 3 within 7 hours, in Mode 4 within 13 hours, and in Mode 5 within 37 hours. The Shift manager entered the applicable TSs including LCO 3.0.3 at 1111 Central Daylight Time (COT) on June 17, 2013. A plant shutdown was started at 1125 COT on June 17, 2013. On June 17, 2013, enforcement discretion was sought to permit noncompliance with TS 3.8.4, TS 3.8.7, TS 3.8.9, as well as LCO 3.0.3, to permit additional time to complete repairs and restoration of SGK05A before a plant shutdown would be required. An additional 168 hours was requested to restore SGK05A to a functional status such that the Completion Time of LCO 3.0.3 would expire at 1111 COT on June 24, 2013. The Nuclear Regulatory Commission granted approval of the requested enforcement discretion on June 17, 2013. When the enforcement discretion was received, the plant shutdown was stopped and stabilized at 150 MWe. The plant returned to full power at approximately 1430 COT on June 18, 2013. The replacement of the SGK05A compressor and testing to restore functionality was completed at 2220 COT on June 21, 2013. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>t------------------------------------------------------------~ NRC FORM 366A (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) U_S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 --007 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>BASIS FOR REPORTABILITY Wolf Creek Nuclear Operating Corporation (WCNOC) requested and received a notice of enforcement discretion (NOED) from the NRC to not enforce compliance with the actions required in TS 3.8.4, TS 3.8.7, TS 3.8.9, as well as LCO 3.0.3. for a period of 168 hours. The SGK05A unit was nonfunctional for a period longer than allowed by the Completion Time of LCO 3.0.3. As such, the event is reportable pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) for any operation or condition which was prohibited by the plant's TSs. LCO 3.0.3 requires action to be taken within 1 hour to place the plant in Mode 3 within 7 hours, in Mode 4 within 13 hours, and in Mode 5 within 37 hours. LCO 3.0.3 was entered in light of the limitations of the Conditions and Required Actions of TS 3.8.7, &quot;Inverters -Operating.&quot; Therefore, absent a support system TS LCO to declare inoperable, the control room staff is required to enter LCO 3.0.3 when a Class 1 E electrical equipment AlC train is discovered to be nonfunctional, resulting in an unnecessary plant transient. Required Actions B.1 and B.2 of TS 3.8.4 would require placing the plant in Mode 3 in 6 hours and Mode 5 in 36 hours if Required Action A.1 (restore DC electrical power subsystem to Operable status) and it associated Completion Time (2 hours) is not met. Required Actions B.1 and B.2 of TS 3.8.7 would require placing the plant in Mode 3 in 6 hours and Mode 5 in 36 hours if Required Action A.1 (restore one required inverter to Operable status) and it associated Completion Time (24 hours) are not met. Required Actions E.1 and E.2 of TS 3.8.9 would require placing the plant in MODE 3 in 6 hours and Mode 5 in 36 hours if Required Actions C.1 and D.1 (restore one AC vital bus subsystem and one DC electrical power distribution subsystem to Operable status) and its associated Completion Time (2 hours) is not met. ROOT CAUSE The cause of this event was slugging/hydraulicing of the compressor, which is the introduction of a liquid into a system meant for gas. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS The SGK05A compressor was replaced and the unit was restored to functional status. Additional corrective actions to prevent recurrence are being developed to address the root cause and will be provided in the supplement to this LER. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL I REVJ NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2013 -007 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The Incremental Conditional Core Damage Probability (ICCDP) and Incremental Conditional Large Early Release Probability (ICLERP) was quantified for the requested additional time for replacing the SGK05A unit. The ICCDP calculated value was 7.038E-8 and the ICLERP calculated value was 6.137E-10. The results of the quantification are within the guidance threshold in Regulatory Issue Summary 2005-01, &quot;Changes to Notice of Enforcement Discretion (NOED) Process and Staff Guidance.&quot; Temporary cooling was put in place for the spaces normally cooled by SGK05A. This cooling was a temporary NC unit (elephant trunk type) powered by reliable non-safety power. A second unit was available in case of failure. Monitoring of room temperature was performed every two hours and a fire watch was established to compensate for the fire barriers that were breached by the temporary AC units. OPERATING EXPERIENCE/PREVIOUS SIMILAR OCCURRENCES LER 2012-005-00 reported a Class 1 E electrical equipment NC train was declared nonfunctional due to a calculation that concluded one train of air conditioning was not capable of supporting both trains of Class 1E equipment. Technical Requirement (TR) 3.7.23 allowed a train to be nonfunctional if compensatory measures were established for the affected unit. During the operability determination and functionality assessment process, it was determined that the operability of the associated train Class 1 E electrical equipment could not be maintained without additional compensatory measures and for a limited period of time. LER 2013-004-00 reported one train of Class 1 E electrical equipment air conditioning had been nonfunctional and one train of control room air conditioning had been inoperable during the previous cycle. This was discovered during refueling outage 19 when the SGK05A compressor terminal box mounting screws were found over torqued. This resulted in a condition prohibited by Technical Specification and a condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of a safety function . . LER 2013-006-00 reported one train of Class 1 E electrical equipment air conditioning had been nonfunctional due to a partial blockage of the thermostatic expansion valves feeding the SGK05A evaporator coils. This resulted in a plant shutdown required by Technical Specifications. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>