<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-03-12T11:57:34-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-03-12T11:57:34-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-03-12T11:57:34-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:91658bb6-9e41-412c-8ceb-d3285debc51f</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:4a2fdbe3-b165-634f-b74b-8a87ff6644cd</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H1>wM.FCREEK 
</H1><P>'NUCLEAR OPERATING CORPORATION </P><P>A. J. Camp, Jr March 6, 2014 Plant Manager </P><P>WO 14-0022 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission ATTN: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555 </P><P>Subject: 	Docket No. 50-482: Licensee Event Report (LER) 2014-001-00, &quot;Failure to Comply With Required Action of Technical Specification 3.4.3 While Performing a Vacuum Fill of the Reactor Coolant System&quot; </P><P>Gentlemen: </P><P>The enclosed Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) as an operation or condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. </P><P>This letter contains no commitments. If you have any questions concerning this matter, please contact me at (620) 364-4110, or Mr. Michael J. Westman at (620) 364-4009. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>AJC/rit </P><P>Enclosure </P><P>cc: M. L. Dapas (NRC), w/e </P><P>C. F. Lyon (NRC), w/e </P><P>N. F. O'Keefe (NRC), w/e Senior Resident Inspector (NRC), w/e </P><P>p.o. Box 411 / Burlington, KS 66839/ Phone: (620) 364-8831 An Equal Opportunity Employer M/F/HCNET </P><P>. 
</P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14071A304_img_0.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 (01-2014) &quot;.&quot;......... EstirrEiOO b.rcB1 iB&quot; resp:nse to cx:rrpy v.ith !tis mrdi:iay a:l1Edicn ~00 In.Js. R3pcrte:JlW!.~. ~ lessa-s leared &lt;Ie irax]Xll1lle:J into tI'e liCS1Sirg pu::ess a&quot;d fa::I ba:k to irrlJstry. Serd\., ~) cxmrerts regardrg t:uden estirrate to tte FaA, Priva::y ard Infooration Cdledions Br&lt;rd1 ..... (T-5 F53), u.s. !'Wea-~atayQmrission, Wlstirgton, DC 20555-&lt;XXl1. or I1t interret e-rrailLICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) to Infoa:Ila::Is.~gJII, ard to tI'e Dlsk Olirer. Olire ri Infooration ard ~atay (See Page 2 for required number of Afflirs, NECJB.10202, (31SQ.0104), Olire ri ~ard Budget, Wlstirgton, DC 2WX3. If a mms lm:l to irrp:Ee en irtarrefu1 al1edion d:es rd dsPaI a rurertIy vaid (}JBdigits/characters for each block) arbd rurtJa&quot;, tte !'oR: I1lJf rd cxrdd or SJXrBl&quot;, a&quot;d a ~is rd ~to ~to. tte infooration a:lledion. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION 05000 482 1 OF 3 4. TITLE Failure to Com~ly With Re~uired Action of Technical Specification 3.4.3 While Performing a Vacuum Fill of the Reactor Coolant Sys em 5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVEDISEQUENTIAL I REV FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER MONTH DAY YEAR YEAR MONTH DAY YEARNUMBER NO. 05000 01 06 2014 2014 -001 -00 03 06 2014 FACILITY NAME DOCKET NUMBER 05000 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Clreek all Orat app(v) 020.2201 (b) 020.2203(a)(3)(i) 050.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 050.73(a)(2)(Vii) 1 020.2201 (d) 020.2203(a)(3)(ii) 050.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 050.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) 020.2203(a)(1 ) 020.2203(a)(4) 050.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) 050.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) 020.2203(a)(2)(i) 050.36(C)(1)(i)(A) 050.73(a)(2)(iii) 050.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 10. POWER LEVEL 020.2203(a)(2)(ii) 050.36(C)(1 )(ii)(A) 050.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) 050.73(a)(2)(x) 020.2203(a)(2)(iii) 050.36(C)(2) 050.73(a)(2)(V)(A) 073.71 (a)(4) 100 o20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 050.46(a)(3)(ii) 050.73(a)(2)(v)(B) 073.71 (a)(5) o20.2203(a)(2)(v) 050.73(a)(2)(i)(A) 050.73(a)(2)(v)(C) OOTHER o20.2203(a)(2)(vi) I!J 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) 050.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Fonn 366A 12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER FACILITY NAME rELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code)Michael Westman, Manager Regulatory Affairs (620) 364-4009 13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE CAUSE SYSTEM COMPONENT MANU-REPORTABLE FACTURER TO EPIX FACTURER TO EPIX 4. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 15. EXPECTED MONTH DAY YEAR DYES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) WNO SUBMISSION DATE ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces. i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) During a review of outside operating experience it was discovered that the Wolf Creek Generating Station (WCGS) had been in violation of Technical Specification 3.4.3, &quot;RCS Pressure and Temperature (PIT) Limits.&quot; Limiting Condition of Operation 3.4.3 requires the Reactor Coolant System (RCS) pressure, temperature and heatup and cooldown rates be maintained within the limits specified in the PressurelTemperature Limits Report (PTLR) at all times. WCGS draws a vacuum on the RCS at the end of refueling outages to fill the RCS using procedure SYS 88-112, &quot;Vacuum Fill of the RCS.&quot; The RCS heatup and cooldown limitations in the PTLR only specify a pressure to 0 psig. A vacuum was drawn on the RCS two times during the past three years which was outside the limitations contained in the PTLR. The apparent cause is inadequate engineering evaluation and procedure reviews resulted in allowing operations below the heatup and cooldown limitations specified in the PTLR. Procedure SYS 88-112 was cancelled to ensure a vacuum is not drawn on the RCS. </Figure><P>NRC FORM 366 (01·2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (01·2014) &quot;&quot;.........l¥.\• c; ;} &quot; I'......... U.S.Nl.OEAA.REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TH>APPROVED BYOMB: NO.3150·0104 EXPIRES: 0113112017 Estimated burden per response b comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are iJlXJ]ll&lt;tEd ilb the licensing pooess and fed back to ind.Jstry. Sene comments regarding burden estim ate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branct (T·5 F53), U.S. Nudear Regulatory Commission, \i\lashington ,DC 20555-0001 ,or by internet e· mail to Infocoliects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs. NEOB-10202, (315().()104). Office of Management ane Budget. Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does no display acurrently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor. and aperson li&lt; nnt r.nllir.n tn r ••nnnn tn tho infnrm.tinn rnll.rtir </TH></TR><TR><TH>1 . F.AOUlYNArvE WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>2.DOCKET 05000482 </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER YEAR /SEQUENTIAL / REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3. PAGE 2 OF 3 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE PLANT CONDITIONS PRIOR TO THE EVENT 100 % Mode 1 There were no structures, components or systems (SSC) that were inoperable at the start of the event and contributed to the event. DESCRIPTION During a review of outside operating experience on January 6, 2014, it was discovered that one utility received a non-cited violation of Technical Specification (TS), &quot;Reactor Coolant System (RCS) Pressure and Temperature (PIT) Limits,&quot; for failure to comply with reactor pressure vessel pressure/temperature limits. The licensee had operated the plant with a vacuum in the reactor pressure vessel. Wolf Creek Generating Station (WCGS) Technical Specification 3.4.3, &quot;RCS Pressure and Temperature (PIT) Limits,&quot; Limiting Condition of Operation (LCO) 3.4.3 requires the RCS pressure, temperature and heatup and cooldown rates be maintained within the limits specified in the PressurelTemperature Limits Report (PTLR). The Applicability for LCO 3.4.3 is &quot;At all times.&quot; The RCS heatup and cooldown limitations in the PTLR only specify a pressure to 0 psig. WCGS draws a vacuum on the RCS [EllS: A8] at the end of refueling outages to fill the RCS, using procedure SYS 88-112, &quot;Vacuum Fill of the RCS.&quot; During the performance of SYS 88-112, a vacuum is drawn on the RCS to between 20 inches Hg and 24 inches Hg. A review of operating history for the last three years found that WCGS drew a vacuum on the RCS on May 8, 2011 and March 30, 2013. REPORTA81L1TY NUREG-1022, Event Reporting Guidelines, Section 3.2.2, &quot;Operation or Condition Prohibited by Technical Specifications,&quot; specifies that a Licensee Event Report is required if a condition existed for a time longer than permitted by the TS even if the condition was not discovered until after the allowable time had elapsed and the condition was rectified immediately upon discovery. Events that occurred within 3 years of the date of discovery are reportable. During the past 3 years, a vacuum was drawn on the RCS on May 8, 2011 and March 30, 2013, using procedure SYS 88-112. TS 3.4.3, &quot;RCS Pressure and Temperature (PIT) Limits,&quot; LCO 3.4.3 requires the RCS pressure, temperature and heatup and cooldown rates be maintained within the limits specified in the PTLR. The Applicability for LCO 3.4.3 is &quot;At all times.&quot; The RCS heatup and cooldown limitations in the PTLR only specify a pressure to 0 psig. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRCFORM366A (01·2014) </P><P>, </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (01-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1.FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3.PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>WOLF CREEK GENERATING STATION </TH><TD>05000 482 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I REV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 3</TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -001 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE Since the Applicability of TS 3.4.3 is &quot;At all times,&quot; and the PTLR does not provide curves associated with a vacuum in the RCS, the plant was not operating in accordance with the TSs. Required Action C.1 requires initiating action to restore parameter(s) to within limits with a Completion Time of Immediately. Action was not taken during the performance of SYS 88-112 to restore parameter(s) immediately. TS 1.3, &quot;Completion Times,&quot; defines Immediately as pursued without delay and in a controlled manner. The events that occurred on May 8, 2011 and March 30, 2013 are reportable as an operation or condition prohibited by Technical Specifications pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8). CAUSE The apparent cause is inadequate engineering evaluation and procedure reviews resulted in allowing operations below PTLR Curve Limits. WCGS implemented a change in the method to which the Reactor Coolant System is filled and vented following a refueling outage without verifying the change complied with Technical Specification 3.4.3. Implementation of vacuum fill and vent of the RCS at WCGS was evaluated in Engineering Evaluation EER 92-88-02 and implemented by use of SYS 88-112 without reference to the fact that the PTLR curves do not have values less than 0 psig. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS Procedure SYS 88-112 was cancelled so a vacuum will not be drawn on the RCS. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE In the development of SYS 88-112, Engineering Evaluation EER 92-88-02 evaluated the effect of drawing a vacuum on the RCS. Precautions necessary to prevent any system or equipment degradation were incorporated into the procedure. As a result, the reduction in RCS pressure would not affect the integrity of the RCS components. OPERATING EXPERIENCE/PREVIOUS EVENTS None </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>