<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Acrobat Distiller 8.1.0 (Windows)</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreatorTool>PScript5.dll Version 5.2.2</xmp:CreatorTool>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-12-23T08:42:49-06:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-12-23T08:42:49-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
         <dc:title>
            <rdf:Alt>
               <rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">Microsoft Word - 1CAN121405</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Alt>
         </dc:title>
         <dc:creator>
            <rdf:Seq>
               <rdf:li>sbarton</rdf:li>
            </rdf:Seq>
         </dc:creator>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:22dec327-9e8b-4464-813b-cf06f7cb7f84</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:a89a74c6-0a32-c942-bc8d-afa829430270</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src="images/2014_12_22_ML14357A098_img_0.jpg"/></Figure><P>Entergy Operations, Inc. </P><P>1448 S.R. 333 Russellville, AR  72802 Tel 479-858-4704 </P><P>Stephenie L. Pyle </P><P>Manager, Regulatory Assurance Arkansas Nuclear One </P><P>1CAN121405 December 22, 2014 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	Special Report Licensee Event Report 50-313/2014-002-00 Arkansas Nuclear One, Unit 1 Docket No. 50-313 License No. DPR-51 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Pursuant to the reporting requirements of 10 CFR 50.73 and 10 CFR 50.46, attached is the subject Special Report (Licensee Event Report) concerning a significant change in peak cladding temperature. </P><P>There are no new commitments contained in this submittal. </P><P>Should you have any questions concerning this issue, please contact me. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>ORIGINAL SIGNED BY STEPHENIE L. PYLE </P><P>SLP/rwc Attachment: Licensee Event Report 50-313/2014-002-00 </P><P>1CAN121405 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>cc: 	Mr. Marc L. Dapas Regional Administrator </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Region IV 1600 East Lamar Boulevard Arlington, TX  76011-4511 </P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector Arkansas Nuclear One </P><P>P.O. Box 310 
London, AR 72847 
</P><P>Institute of Nuclear Power Operations 700 Galleria Parkway Atlanta, GA 30339-5957 </P><P>LEREvents@inpo.org </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366  (02-2014) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104   EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours.  Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA/Privacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection.  </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME  Arkansas Nuclear One – Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000313 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Special Report – Significant Change in Peak Cladding Temperature </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME N/A </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER N/A </TD></TR><TR><TH>11 </TH><TD>25 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 – 002 – 00 </TD><TD>12 </TD><TD>22 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME N/A </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER N/A </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE  1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TD>20.2201(b) 20.2201(d) 20.2203(a)(1)  20.2203(a)(2)(i)  20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 20.2203(a)(2)(iii)  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)  20.2203(a)(2)(v) 20.2203(a)(2)(vi)  20.2203(a)(3)(i)  20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 20.2203(a)(4)  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) 50.36(c)(2)  50.46(a)(3)(ii)  50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(C)  50.73(a)(2)(v)(D)  50.73(a)(2)(vii)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) 50.73(a)(2)(x)  73.71(a)(4)  73.71(a)(5)  OTHER Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100% </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSEE CONTACT Stephenie L. Pyle, Manager, Regulatory Assurance </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 479-858-4704 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>N/A </TH><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE)    NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) This report is submitted pursuant to the 30 day Special Report requirement of 10 CFR 50.46(a)(3)(ii).  The guidance provided in NURGEG 1022, Revision 3, allows the reporting under 10 CFR 50.73 and 10 CFR 50.46 to be combined. On November 25, 2014, AREVA NP Inc. notified Entergy Operations, Inc. of a deficiency in the Arkansas Nuclear One, Unit 1 (ANO-1) Emergency Core Cooling System evaluation model.  When the deficiency is accounted for, the Large Break Loss-of-Coolant Accident Peak Clad Temperature was estimated to exceed 2200°F and the absolute value of the deficiency is greater than the requirement of 10 CFR 50.46(a)(3)(ii).  Exceeding 2200°F resulted in ANO-1 making an 8-hour NRC notification on November 25, 2014. See Event Notification EN 50641.  The purpose of this report is to provide the information required by 10 CFR 50.46(a)(3)(ii). </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (02-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Arkansas Nuclear One – Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000313 </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV. NO. </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -- 002 -- 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>The current Loss-of-Coolant Accident (LOCA) Evaluation Model (EM) for Babcock &amp; Wilcox (B&amp;W) plants uses the fuel performance code TACO3.  The identified deficiency is in the thermal conductivity model in this computer code. The deficiency is that the code does not adequately represent the reduction in fuel thermal conductivity with burnup.  This issue was discussed in the NRC Information Notice (IN) 2009-23 “Nuclear Fuel Thermal Conductivity Degradation”.  Recent comparisons of the fuel temperatures from this code with fuel temperatures from the code GALILEO (a code that has an adequate fuel thermal conductivity model) indicate that the TACO3 code thermal conductivity model may lead to an under prediction of the Peak Clad Temperature (PCT) during a LOCA. TACO3 does not model the thermal conductivity degradation (TCD) with burnup explicitly but has adjustments to the methodology and increases in the LOCA fuel temperature inputs.  These adjustments were intended to compensate for the non-conservative thermal conductivity model in TACO3. The continued use of this code was previously evaluated by AREVA in 2009 following the NRC issuance of Information Notice 2009-23.  In 2009, it was concluded that sufficient conservatisms in both code predictions and LOCA methodology compensated for a lack of TCD models based, in part, on comparisons to an early version of the code GALILEO.  However this conclusion has been invalidated based on recent GALILEO LOCA initialization studies.  Based on these new Large Break LOCA (LBLOCA) initializations, it is concluded that the LOCA EM that uses TACO3 must be modified by application of additional fuel temperature uncertainty to account for the effects of TCD based on COPERNIC2, a code that models TCD adequately. An evaluation was performed by applying the EM change to a Lower-Loop LBLOCA model with an axial power shaped peaked at core elevation 2.506-feet (ft) with a middle-of-life (MOL) burnup condition. For the representative plant, the 95/95 volume-average fuel temperature from the limiting PCT case was increased by 230°F.  The results of the evaluation show that the original limiting MOL case cladding temperatures at the core elevation of 2.506 ft were increased by 481°F for the ruptured node and 288°F for the unruptured node.  The results of this evaluation can be generically applied to all B&amp;W plants. These ruptured and unruptured node cladding temperature deltas were applied to the Arkansas Nuclear One, Unit 1 (ANO-1) full spectrum of MOL cases and led to an increase in limiting PCT of 388°F. An evaluation of the cladding temperatures at end-of-life (EOL) has confirmed that the MOL results were limiting. Also it is noted that the cladding temperatures at beginning-of-life (BOL) remain unaffected by TCD. This LBLOCA EM model change results in a significant increase to the calculated PCT.  When applying the estimated PCT increases with the revised EM approach, the limiting PCT was estimated to be 2396°F, which is in excess of 2200°F.   </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014)  NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)  CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Arkansas Nuclear One – Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000313 </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV. NO. </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -- 002 -- 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>In order to reduce the PCT to less than 2200°F, AREVA recommended linear heat rate (LHR) limit reductions on October 21, 2014, and suggested that it was prudent to administratively implement any changes as a compensatory measure.  The compensatory measures recommended a 2 kilowatt / foot reduction in the MOL LHRs.  Imposition of the compensatory measures reduces the evaluated PCT to be equal to the PCT prior to the EM correction and thus less than 2200°F.  As a precautionary measure pending the completed analysis, ANO-1 implemented the compensatory measures on October 20, 2014. The local oxidation and whole core hydrogen also remain well within the 10 CFR 50.46 acceptance criteria for the LBLOCA scenarios.  With the MOL LHR limit reduction, the core geometry remains amenable to cooling and acceptable long-term cooling is unaffected by these changes.  The impact of the EM correction and compensatory measure is summarized in Table 1 for LBLOCA and in Table 2 for Small Break LOCA (SBLOCA).  The SBLOCA analyses are not sensitive to the initial fuel temperatures and thus the estimated impact on the SBLOCA peak cladding temperature is zero. This deficiency will be corrected in a future LOCA analyses on an NRC agreed upon schedule. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER)  CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Arkansas Nuclear One – Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000313 </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV. NO. </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 -- 002 -- 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Table 1 Summary of Peak Clad Temperature (PCT) Impact of  Large Break Loss-of-Coolant-Accident (LOCA) Changes and Errors Analysis PCT (°F) Delta PCT (°F) Absolute Delta PCT (°F)* Notes Initial LBLOCA PCT [1] 2008.1 9.536-feet (ft) Beginning-Of-Life (BOL) Case Thermal Conductivity Degradation (TCD) issue 2396 +388 388 Evaluation Model (EM) Change with updated uncertainty to account for TCD in TACO3 2.506-ft Middle-Of-Life (MOL) Case MOL Linear Heat Rate (LHR) Reduction 2008.1 -388 Compensatory actions of updated imbalance limits based on 2 kilowatt/foot plant LHR reduction at MOL Final Results 2008.1 0 388 Table 2 Summary of PCT Impact of Small Break LOCA Changes and Errors Analysis PCT (°F) Delta PCT (°F) Absolute Delta PCT (°F)* Notes Initial SBLOCA PCT [1] 1459 TCD issue 1459 0 0 EM Change with updated uncertainty to account for TCD in TACO3 Final Results 1459 0 0 [1] Entergy letter to NRC, “Annual 10 CFR 50.46 Report for Calendar Year 2013 Emergency Core Cooling System Evaluation Changes,” dated June 24, 2014 (0CAN061402) (ML14175B275) </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>