<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-07-16T08:55:46-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-07-16T08:55:46-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-07-16T08:55:46-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>LAfl!S A sub&quot;&quot;'&quot;&quot; of Pinna,&quot; We&quot; Cap;/a1 C&lt;NP0'8tion </P><P>Dwight C. Mims Mail Station 7605 Palo Verde Nuclear Vice President Tel. 623-393-5403 P. O. Box 52034 Generating Station Regulatory Affairs and Plant Improvement Fax 623-393-6077 Phoenix, Arizona 85072-2034 </P><P>102-06212-DCM/RAB/FJO Jl,Jly p~,JP~P </P><P>ATTN: Document Control Desk </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Dear Sirs: </P><P>Subject: 	Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station (PVNGS) Units 1, 2, and 3 Docket No. STN 50-528, STN 50-529, and STN 50-530 License No. NPF 41, NPF 51, and NPF 74 Licensee Event Report 2010-002-00 </P><P>Enclosed please find Licensee Event Report (LER) 50-528/2010-002-00 that has been prepared and submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73. This LER reports a calculation error that resulted in operation prohibited by technical specifications that affected all three units. </P><P>In accordance with 10 CFR 50.4, copies of this LER are being forwarded to the NRC Regional Office, NRC Region IV and the Senior Resident Inspector. If you have questions regarding this submittal, please contact Marianne Webb, Section Leader, Regulatory Affairs, at (623) 393-5730. </P><P>Arizona Public Service Company makes no commitments in this letter. </P><P>DCM/RABITNW/FJO </P><P>Enclosure </P><Table><TR><TD>cc: </TD><TD>E. E. Collins Jr. </TD><TD>NRC Region IV Regional Administrator </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>J. R. Hall </TD><TD>NRC NRR Project Manager -(send electronic and paper) </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>L. K. Gibson </TD><TD>NRC NRR Project Manager -(send electronic and paper) </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>R. I. Treadway </TD><TD>NRC Senior Resident Inspector for PVNGS </TD></TR></Table><P>A member of the STJURS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance -Callaway -Comanche Peak -Diablo Canyon -Palo Verde -San Onofre -South Texas -Wolf Creek </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 08/31/2010 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPriVacy Service Branch (T-5 F52), U.S. Nuclear RePculatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to in ocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station (PVNGS) Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER r-PAGE 05000528 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Main Steam Isolation Bypass Valve Calculation Error Resulting in Operation Prohibited by Tech Spec </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME PVNGS Unit 2 </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000529 </TD></TR><TR><TH>05 </TH><TD>07 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>-002 -</TD><TD>00 </TD><TD>07 </TD><TD>06 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME PVNGS Unit 3 </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000530 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 5/ 1 /1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check al/ that apply) o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) D· 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) [gI 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 0/ 100/ 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME I~ELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Marianne Webb, Section Leader, Regulatory Affairs 623-393-5730 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED IZI YES (/fyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ONO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>09 </TD><TD>30 </TD><TD>10 </TD></TR><TR><TH>I\BSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On May 7, 2010, Palo Verde discovered that a calculation used for the closing force required for Main Steam Isolation Bypass Valves (MSIBVs) was non-conservative. During the Component Design Basis Review (CDBR), it was determined that the closing force would be inadequate to fully close the MSIBVs upon the receipt of a Main Steam Isolation Signal when Steam Generator (SG) pressure is greater than 700 psi. This condition renders the MSIBVs inoperable when SG pressure is above 700 psi. At the time of discovery, Unit 1 was in Mode 5 and the MSIBVs were not required to be operable; Unit 2 and Unit 3 were in Mode 1, and the MSIBVs were required to be operable. Both Unit 2 and Unit 3 entered the applicable Technical Specification (TS) Limited Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.6.3, Containment Isolation Valves. As an immediate corrective action, Unit 2 and Unit 3 ensured the MSIBVs were closed, with their penetration flowpath isolated to comply with the conditions of TS LCO 3.6.3. The event investigation is in progress and the results will be conveyed in a supplement to this LER. No similar events involving a non-conservative calculation for an air operated valve have been reported by PVNGS in the last three years. </TH></TR></Table><P>N&quot;C I-ORM 366 (9-2007) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9·2007) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000528 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTAL 1REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 -002 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) All times are Mountain Standard Time and approximate unless otherwise indicated. 1. REPORTING REQUIREMENT(S): This Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) as an operation prohibited by Technical Specifications (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.6.3, which requires containment isolation valves to be operable. 2. DESCRIPTION OF STRUCTURE(S), SYSTEM(S) AND COMPONENT(S): Each of Palo Verde's units contains two Steam Generators (SG) (EllS: SB / SG) which provide high pressure saturated steam to the main turbines through two 28 inch main steam lines (total of four per unit). Each of the main steam lines is isolated by a Main Steam Isolation Valve (MSIV) (EllS: SB / ISV): SG-UV170 and SG-UV180 for SG 1; and SG-UV171 and SG-UV181 for SG 2. The MSIVs close upon the receipt of a Main Steam Isolation Signal (MSIS). A common header connects each of the four main steam lines downstream of the MSIVs. One main steam line from each SG contains a normally closed MSIV Bypass Valve (MSIBV) (EllS: SB / ISV). The MSIBV SG-UV169 bypasses MSIV SG-UV180 from SG 1 and MSIBV SG-UV183 bypasses MSIV SG-UV171 from SG 2. The valve and actuator are Flowserve / Anchor Darling Models 93-15199 and W30748 respectively. The MSIBVs are 4 inch air operated flexible wedge gate valves. Air pressure opens the MSIBVs and spring force closes the MSIBVs when the air pressure is vented from the actuators. The MSIBVs close on a MSIS and fail closed on a loss of air pressure or control signal. The MSIBVs may be opened to warm-up downstream piping and equalize pressure across the MSIVs to permit opening of the MSIVs during plant startup. The MSIBVs are stroked open and closed for surveillance testing requirements. The safety function of the MSIBV is to close upon receipt of a MSIS. The MSIS actuates to close the MSIVs and MSIBVs upon receipt of low steam generator pressure, high steam generator water level, and high containment pressure. 3. INITIAL PLANT CONDITIONS: On May 7,2010, Unit 1 was in Mode 5 (Cold Shutdown) following refueling, and Unit 2 and Unit 3 were at approximately 100 percent power in Mode 1 (Power Operations). There were </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9·2007) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3, PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station Unit 1 . </TH><TD>05000528 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 -002 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) no major structures, systems, or components that were inoperable that contributed to this event. 4. EVENT DESCRIPTION: On May 7, 2010, during a review of a calculation for piston style Air Operated Valve (AOV) thrust and actuator sizing, Palo Verde identified a deficiency in the calculation. The calculation could not demonstrate the available closing force would fully close the MSIBVs (SG-UV169 and SG-UV183) when the SG pressure is above 700 psi. Further evaluation revealed the calculation error applies to all three units, and undersized valve actuators were installed during original plant construction. Operations personnel declared the MSIBVs inoperable in all three units. Unit 2 and Unit 3 entered LCO 3.6.3, Containment Isolation Valves, and ensured the MSIBVs were closed with their penetration flowpath isolated to comply with the conditions of TS LCO 3.6.3. Unit 1 was in Mode 5 and the MSIBVs were not required to be operable. 5. ASSESSMENT OF SAFETY CONSEQUENCES: The MSIBVs are not required to obtain safe shutdown, and are normally closed valves. An initial evaluation was performed based on both MSIBVs open at the same time. The evaluation determined this condition was bounded by the existing Main Steam Line Break with a MSIV open. Therefore, the calculation error did not result in a condition more severe than those previously analyzed in the PVNGS UFSAR, Chapter 15, Accident Analysis. There was no actual impact to the health and safety of the public as a result of the inability of the MSIBVs to close with SG pressures above 700 psi. The condition did not result in any challenges to the fission product barriers or result in the release of radioactive materials. The 10 CFR 100 offsite dose criteria were never ch9&quot;enged or exceeded. 6. CAUSE OF THE EVENT: The event investigation is in progress and the results will be conveyed in a supplement to this LER. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000528 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTAL IREVISION . NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 -002 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>17. NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) 7. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS: The immediate corrective actions for Unit 2 and Unit 3 were to ensure the MSIBVs were closed with their penetration flowpath isolated to comply with the conditions of TS LCO 3.6.3. Following Unit 1 's refueling outage, the MSIBVs were closed and isolated to comply with TS LCO 3.6.3 prior to the SG pressure reaching 700 psi. Additional corrective actions will be conveyed in a supplement to this LER. 8. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS: No similar events involving a non-conservative calculation for an air operated valve have been reported by PVNGS in the last three years. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>