<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On
        November 22, 2011, at approximately 1925 Mountain Standard Time, during the performance of
        post-refueling low power physics testing, the reactor was manually tripped as required by
        the control element assembly (CEA) malfunction abnormal operating procedure after a subgroup
        of four CEAs slipped approximately 11 to 14 inches. An intermittent failure of a power
        switch assembly which provides electrical power to the control element drive mechanisms
        resulted in the CEA slippage. After troubleshooting was completed, the power switch assembly
        was replaced. Retesting was completed on November 24,2011. The root cause investigation is
        in progress. Actions to prevent recurrence will be identified in the completed investigation
        report. LER 50-52812011-004-00 reported a similar event: An automatic trip of the Unit 1
        reactor occurred on August 6, 2011, which resulted from a dropped CEA caused by a loose
        terminal lug on a CEA power switch assembly.</abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>
        This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73
        (a)(2)(iv)(A) to report a manual actuation of the reactor protective system (RPS)(EIIS: JC)
        that occurred while the reactor was critical. This event was reported to the Nuclear
        Regulatory Commission (NRC) on November 22, 2011, via the event notification system (EN
        47472).</reportingReqs> 
        <structureDesc>The control element
        drive mechanism control system (CEDMCS) (EllS: AA) provides control signals and motive power
        to the coils of the magnetic jacks in the 89 Control Element Drive Mechanisms (CEDMs) (EllS:
        AA) which move, hold, and release the reactor's control element assembly (CEAs) (EllS: AA).
        The CEAs absorb neutrons to control reactivity. Two motor/generator sets are connected in
        parallel to supply 240 VAC, 3 phase power through the reactor trip switchgear (RTSG) (EllS:
        AA). The output from the RTSG is directed through power switch assemblies. The power switch
        assemblies contain silicon controlled rectifiers (SCRs) which convert the 3 phase, AC input
        voltage to a stepped DC output voltage. The conversion is controlled by electronic circuits
        in the power switch assembly and in the CEDMCS subgroup logic housing. These control
        circuits determine the sequence to supply power to the CEDM coils. The RPS provides a rapid
        and reliable shutdown of the reactor to protect the core and the reactor coolant system
        pressure boundary from potentially hazardous operating conditions. Shutdown is accomplished
        by either manual or automatic generation of reactor trip signals. The trip signals open the
        RTSG breakers, which de-energize the CEDM coils and allow all CEAs to drop into the core by
        the force of gravity. . The core protection calculator/control element assembly calculator
        (CPC/CEAC)(EIIS: JC) system monitors reactor core conditions to provide CEA withdrawal
        prohibit signals to the CEDMCS and provides an accurate, reliable means of initiating a
        reactor trip. The CPC/CEAC system is an integral part of the plant protective system in that
        it provides low departure from nucleate boiling ratio (Lo DNBR) and high local power density
        (Hi LPD) trip signals to the RPS. Trip signals are provided to the RPS whenever the
        calculated value of DNBR or Hi LPD exceeds the related setpoint during reactor operation.Each CEAC receives reed switch position transmitter inputs for all CEAs. The CEACs
        compare the positions of all CEAs within each CEA subgroup and determine penalty factors
        based upon CEA deviations within a subgroup. The CPCs also compute penalties for CEA group
        out-of-sequence and subgroup deviation conditions. Low power physics testing is conducted
        during Mode 2 following refueling outages to verify reactor core operating characteristics
        are consistent with design predictions and to provide assurance the core can be operated as
        designed. The low power physics testing procedure provides direction to invoke the low power
        physics testing speCial test exceptions under Technical Specification (TS) 3.1.10 that
        suspends certain limiting conditions for operation (LCOs), including LCO 3.3.3 which
        normally requires two channels of CEACs to be OPERABLE and LCO 3.1.5, CEA Alignment. Both
        channels of CEACs are inoperable during low power physics testing. The CPCs will not
        generate reactor trips based on CEA alignment deviations while CEACs are inoperable. 
        </structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On November 22, 2011, Palo Verde Unit 1 was in Mode 2 (Start-up),
        at less than 1 percent power and at normal operating temperature and normal operating
        pressure. The reactor was critical and post-refueling low power physics testing was in
        progress. CEACs were inoperable at the time of the event as directed by the low power
        physics testing procedure. There were no other structures, systems, or components inoperable
        at the time of the event that contributed to the event.</plantConds>
        <eventDesc>On November
        22, 2011, at 1921, CEA regulating group (RG) #2 was being inserted into the reactor while
        performing post-refueling low power physics testing during the plant start-up following
        refueling outage 1 R16. At that time, the control room staff noted that the four CEAs in RG
        #2, subgroup #17, slipped approximately 11 t014 inches below subgroup #18 CEAs, also in RG
        #2. In response to the deviation between the RG #2 subgroups, the control room staff
        manually tripped the reactor as directed by the abnormal operating procedure, CEA
        Malfunctions, for deviations of CEA subgroups of more than 6.6 inches. An automatic trip was
        not generated by the CPCs because CEACs were inoperable for performance of the testing. All
        CEAs fully inserted and the plant responded to the trip as designed. No other actuations of
        plant engineered safety features systems occurred or were required.</eventDesc>
        <safetyConsequences>This event did not result in a transient
        more severe than those already analyzed in the PVNGS Updated Final Safety Analysis Report
        Chapter 15_ The transient did not cause a violation of safety limits or the specified
        acceptable fuel design limits_ Because the primary and secondary system pressures stayed
        below the respective safety valve opening setpoints, design pressures were not challenged.
        There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components at the time of the event that
        contributed to this event. The event did not result in any challenges to the fission product
        barriers or result in the release of radioactive materials. There were no actual safety
        consequences as a result of this condition. The condition does not represent a reportable
        safety system functional failure under 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(v).</safetyConsequences> 
        
        <eventCause>An
        intermittent failure of a power switch assembly which provides electrical power to the
        control element drive mechanisms resulted in the CEA slippage. The root cause investigation
        is in progress. A supplement to this LER will provide the results of the investigation.</eventCause> 
        <correctiveActions>After troubleshooting was completed, the power switch assembly was
        replaced. Retesting was completed on November 24, 2011. The unit was subsequently restarted
        and entered Mode 1 on November 27,2011. A supplement to this LER will discuss the
        corresponding corrective actions to prevent recurrence prescribed by the root cause
        investigation.</correctiveActions>
        <previousEvents>The root cause investigation is in progress. A
        complete discussion of previous similar events will be provided in a supplement to this LER
        based on the investigation results. Preliminarily, the following events related to failures
        of power switch assemblies were identified. The relationship of these previous events to the
        event in this LER has not been determined. LER 50-52812011-004-00 reported an automatic trip of the Unit 1 reactor that
        occurred on August 6, 2011, which resulted from a dropped CEA (#37) caused by a loose
        terminal lug on the corresponding CEA power switch assembly. On March 4, 2011, Unit 3 CEA #1
        dropped into the core because of an age related failure of an electrolytic capacitor on the
        zero crossing detector card installed in the corresponding power switch assembly. This did
        not require an automatic or manual trip of the reactor and was not reportable. On December
        4, 2009, during a Unit 3 reactor startup while subcritical, subgroup #15 part-strength CEAs
        dropped into the core because of an age related failure of an electrolytic capacitor on the
        zero crossing detector card installed in the corresponding power switch assembly. The
        decision was made to terminate the start-up by manually tripping the reactor. This condition
        was not reportable. Replacements of the electrolytic capacitors on the zero crossing
        detector cards have been completed in Unit 1 and are scheduled for upcoming refueling
        outages in Units 2 and 3.</previousEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>