<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On
        August 6, 2011, at approximately 1119 Mountain Standard Time, during the performance of
        surveillance test 40ST -9SF01, Control Element Assembly (CEA) Operability Checks, the Unit 1
        reactor tripped due to an automatic actuation of the reactor protection system. The
        actuation occurred when CEA 37 of shutdown group B fully inserted causing a deviation of
        greater than 9.9 inches from other CEAs in its subgroup. This deviation generated a CEA
        calculator penalty factor and actuated the low departure from nucleate boiling ratio and the
        high Idcalpower density trips on all four core protection calculator channels. Following the
        reactor trip, plant operators observed CEA 16 of regulating group 5 did not indicate that it
        had fully inserted. While operators prepared to borate the reactor coolant system, full
        insertion indication for CEA 16 was received approximately 1.5 minutes following the reactor
        trip. The cause for the reactor trip was determined to be a loose terminal lug on the CEA
        power switch assembly which developed a high resistance connection and led to the improper
        operation of the control element drive mechanism upper gripper coil. As an immediate
        corrective action, the terminal lug was replaced and retested satisfactorily.
        Troubleshooting of CEA 16 did not identify any problems. Unit 1 returned to service and
        entered Mode 1 at 2140 on August 10, 2011. No similar conditions have been reported by Palo
        Verde in the past three years.</abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73
        (a)(2)(iv)(A) as an automatic actuation of the reactor protection system (RPS) that occurred
        as a result of a dropped control element assembly (CEA) during the performance of CEA
        operability checks. This event was reported to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) on
        August 6, 2011, via the emergency notification system (EN 47133).</reportingReqs> 
        <structureDesc>Control Element Drive Mechanism Control System The
        control element drive mechanism control system (CEDMCS) (EllS: AA) provides control signals
        and motive power to the coils of the magnetic jacks in the Control Element Drive Mechanisms
        (CEDMs) (EllS: AA) which position and hold the 89 reactor CEAs (EllS: AA). Two
        motor/generator sets are connected in parallel to supply 240 VAC, 3 phase power through the
        reactor trip switchgear (RTSG) (EllS: AA). The output from the RTSG is directed through
        power switch assemblies. The power switch assemblies contain silicon controlled rectifiers
        (SCRs) which convert the 3 phase, AC input voltage to a stepped DC output voltage. The
        conversion is controlled by electronic circuits in the power switch assembly and in the
        CEDMCS subgroup logic housing. These control circuits determine the sequence to supply power
        to the CEDM coils. Each CEA is assigned to one of 22 CEA subgroups, with 4 assigned CEAs per
        subgroup, except for subgroup 8 which has five assigned CEAs. The CEDMs for the CEAs within
        a subgroup are provided power from a common power switch assembly. The subgroups are
        arranged into nine groups, including two shutdown, five regulating, and two part strength
        groups. CEAs within a group are moved together to minimize position deviations between the
        CEAs in a subgroup and between subgroups within a group. CEA 37 is assigned to one of the
        five subgroups that make up shutdown group B. CEA 16 is assigned to the one subgroup that
        makes up regulating group 5. Core Protection Calculator/Control Element Assembly Calculator
        The core protection calculator/control element assembly calculator (CPC/CEAC)(EIIS: JC)
        system monitors reactor core conditions to provide CEA withdrawal prohibit signals to the
        CEDMCS and provides an accurate, reliable means of initiating a reactor trip. The CPC/CEAC
        system is an integral part of the plant protective system in that it provides low departure
        from nucleate boiling ratio (Lo DNBR) and high local power density (Hi LPD) trip signals to
        the RPS Trip signals are provided to the RPS whenever the calculated DNBR or
        LPD exceed setpoints during reactor operation. Each CEAC receives reed switch position
        transmitter inputs for all CEAs. The CEACs compare the positions of all CEAs within each CEA
        subgroup and determine penalty factors based upon CEA deviations within a subgroup. When
        generated, a penalty factor is transmitted via fiber-optic data links to the CPCs. The CPCs
        also compute penalties for position deviations between subgroups within a group and for CEA
        group out-of-sequence deviations. The RPS provides a rapid and reliable shutdown of the
        reactor to protect the core and the reactor coolant system pressure boundary from
        potentially hazardous operating conditions. Shutdown is accomplished by the generation of
        reactor trip signals. The trip signals open the RTSG breakers, which de-energizes the CEDM
        coils and allows all CEAs to drop into the core by the force of gravity. 
        </structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On August 6, 2011, Palo Verde Unit 1 was in Mode 1 (Power Operation), at 100
        percent power and at normal operating temperature and normal operating pressure. There were
        no structures, systems, or components inoperable at the time of the event that contributed
        to the event.</plantConds> 
        <eventDesc>On August 6, 2011, at approximately 1119, during the
        performance of surveillance test 40ST-9SF01, CEA Operability Checks, the Unit 1 reactor
        tripped due to an automatic RPS actuation. The actuation occurred when CEA 37 of shutdown
        group B fully inserted which caused a deviation of greater than 9.9 inches from other CEAs
        in its subgroup. This deviation generated a CEAC penalty factor and actuated the Lo DNBR and
        the Hi LPD trips on all four CPC channels. Following the reactor trip, plant operators
        observed CEA 16 did not indicate that it had fully inserted. While operators prepared to
        borate the reactor coolant system, full insertion indication for CEA 16 was received
        approximately 1.5 minutes following the reactor trip. 
        </eventDesc>
        <safetyConsequences>This event did not result in a transient more severe than those already analyzed in the
        PVNGS Updated Final Safety Analysis Report Chapter 15. Because the primary and secondary
        system pressures were controlled below the respective safety valve opening setpoints, peak
        design pressures were not challenged. There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components at the time of the
        event that contributed to this event The event did not result in any challenges to the
        fission product barriers or result in the release of radioactive materials. There were no
        actual safety consequences as a result of this condition. The condition did not result in a
        safety system functional failure as described by 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(v) .. 
        </safetyConsequences>
            <eventCause>The event investigation team determined a loose terminal lug on the CEA power switch
        assembly created a high resistance connection and led to the improper operation of the CEDM
        upper gripper coil, resulting in the full insertion of CEA 37. Once CEA 37 deviated greater
        than 9.9 inches frdm the other CEAs in its subgroup, a CEAC penalty factor was generated.
        This penalty factor resulted in the valid actuation of the Lo DNBR and Hi LPD trips on all
        four CPC channels. The plant protection system functioned as expected by opening all four
        RTSG breakers. To determine the cause of the delayed full insertion of CEA 16, a
        troubleshooting plan was developed which included input from the nuclear steam supply system
        (NSSS) vendor. This plan included steps to rigorously exercise CEA 16, evaluate CEDM coil
        performance, and perform multiple CEA drop time tests for CEA 16 and the other CEAs in its
        subgroup. No abnormal performance issues were identified during the troubleshooting and the
        cause was not determined. 7. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS: As an immediate corrective action, the
        terminal lug for the power switch assembly which supplies power to the CEDM for CEA 37 was
        replaced and retested satisfactorily. The following additional actions are planned: . •
        Accessible terminal and lug connections will be checked during the next refueling outage for
        all three Palo Verde units to verify the tightness of the connections. • A periodic task to
        refurbish the power switch assemblies every tenth refueling cycle will be developed. • A
        design modification will be evaluated to position the CEDM upper gripper in the hold
        position if a voltage imbalance is sensed between the phases of the power supply. Since
        troubleshooting could not identify a cause for the delayed full insertion of CEA 16, an
        action was developed for increased testing of CEAs in accordance with 40ST-9SF01, CEA
        Operability Checks, until the Unit 1 refueling outage in the Fall of 2011. Additional
        troubleshooting actions are planned for the upcoming refueling outage and further actions,
        as necessary, will be added based on the ongoing investigation of the delayed insertion of
        CEA 16. Any additional corrective actions taken as a result of this event will be
        implemented in accordance with the PVNGS corrective action program. If information is
        subsequently developed that would significantly affect a reader's understanding or
        perception of this event, a supplement to this LER will be submitted.</eventCause> 
        <previousEvents>No similar conditions have been reported by Palo Verde in the past three years.</previousEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>