<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract> On March 8, 2012, at approximately 1752 Mountain Standard Time, all Palo Verde units
        entered Technical Specification (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.1.7 Regulating
        Control Element Assembly (CEA) Insertion Limits, Condition 0, when the power dependent
        insertion limit (POlL) alarm setpoint was determined to be non-conservative. The value for
        the POlL alarm setpoint had been incorrect since April 19, 2005, when the specified
        regulating group CEAs fully withdrawn position was raised from greater than or equal to
        (&gt;/=) 144.47 inches to &gt;/=147.75 inches, and the POlL alarm setpoint remained at 144
        inches. lAs an immediate corrective action, the POlL alarm setpoint for all three units was
        changed to 147 inches. This corrective action allowed each unit to exit TS LCO 3.1.7 on
        March 11, 2012. The cause of this event was determined to be the implementation of a change
        that was made to the specified CEA fully withdrawn position in the Core Operating Limits
        Report (COLR) without making the corresponding change to the POlL alarm setpoint. No similar
        events have been reported to the NRC in the prior three years. </abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(i)(B) as an
            operation prohibited by Technical Specification (TS) 3.1.7, Regulating Control Element
            Assembly (CEA) Insertion Limits. The Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) for this TS
            requires that the power dependent insertion limit (POlL) alarm circuit to be OPERABLE.
            If the Required Action and associated Completion Time are not met for LCO 3.1.7
            Condition 0, then LCO 3.1.7 Condition E requires that the plant be in Mode 3 within 6
            hours. The POlL alarm setpoint was incorrectly set and the POlL alarm circuit was
            determined to be inoperable since April 19, 2005, which exceeds the required action
            completion time. </reportingReqs>
        <structureDesc>The control element drive mechanism control system (CEOMCS) (EllS: AA)
            provides control signals and motive power to the coils of the magnetic jacks in the 89
            control element drive mechanisms (CEOMs) (EllS: AA) which move, hold, and release the
            CEAs (EllS: AA). The CEAs absorb neutrons to control reactivity. CEAs are grouped in
            shutdown, regulating, and part-strength groups. Shutdown CEA groups remain fully
            withdrawn during reactor operation to ensure the capability to rapidly shutdown the
            reactor during anticipated operational occurrences evaluated in the plant safety
            analysis. Regulating and part-strength CEA groups are positioned to control core flux
            distribution and reactivity and are normally fully withdrawn during power operations.
            Limits on regulating CEA group insertion have been established and all CEA positions are
            monitored and controlled during power operation to ensure that power distribution and
            reactivity limits related to power peaking, ejected CEA worth, reactivity insertion
            rate, and shutdown margin are preserved. These insertion limits are referred to as the
            POlLs. Core operating limits for each reload cycle are established and documented in the
            Core Operating Limits Report (COLR) as required by TS 5.6.5. POlL Alarm circuits are
            provided to ensure the operating limits on allowable CEA insertion as a function of
            reactor power are maintained consistent with the requirements of the COLR. The POlL
            alarm circuit alerts operators to CEAs that are outside required insertion limits. In
            response, operators ensure either CEA positions are restored or actions are taken to
            limit thermal power or thermal power increases as specified in TSs. The POlL alarm
            circuit is not credited in the safety analysis and it does not directly control any of
            the safety functions in the safety analysis. For an inoperable POlL alarm circuit, TS
            LCO 3.1.7 Condition 0 requires verification that each regulating CEA group position is
            within its insertion limits within one hour of discovery and every four hours
            thereafter, until the POlL alarm circuit is restored. The PDIL alarms are generated
            using the PDIL alarm setpoint programmed into the software of the plant monitoring
            system (PMS) computers. The PMS is comprised of two independent computer systems
            designated as the plant computer (PC) and the core monitoring computer (CMC). The PC and
            CMC functions related to the PDIL alarm circuits are fully redundant and each provides
            the same alarm capabilities. CEA position indication is provided by three separate
            instruments for each of the CEAs. Two safety-related reed switch position transmitter
            (RSPT) indications and one computer generated pulse counter position indication are
            provided for each CEA. The RSPTs measure CEA position via magnetically actuated reed
            switches located on the CEDM housing and input to the plant protection system to provide
            safety related reactor protection system functions and CEA position indications in the
            Control Room. The PMS computers generate pulse counter CEA position indications by
            counting CEDM coil movement electrical pulses at the CEDMCS cabinets and provide
            indications and alarms in the control room and CEA positions for use in the core
            operating limit supervisory system (COLSS) calculations. Each pulse that is counted
            indicates 0.75 inches of CEA travel. The pulse counted CEA positions are used as inputs
            for the PDIL alarm circuits. </structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On March 8, 2012, all three units were in Mode 1, with Units 1 and 2 operating
            at 100 percent power and Unit 3 at 95 percent power during power coast down for a
            scheduled refueling outage. There were no structures, systems, or components inoperable
            at the time of the event that contributed to the event. </plantConds>
        <eventDesc>On March 8, 2012, at 1752, all Palo Verde units entered TS LCO 3.1.7, Regulating
            CEA Insertion Limits, Condition D, when the PDIL alarm setpoint for each unit was
            determined to be non-conservative. During an investigation of an event described in LER
            2-2012-001, Palo Verde personnel determined that the Regulating CEA PDIL alarm setpoint
            was incorrectly set at 144 inches since April 19, 2005, when the specified CEA fully
            withdrawn position was changed from greater than or equal to (&gt;/=)144.75 inches to
            &gt;/=147.75 inches. Changes which altered the fuel configuration began in 1993, when
            the fuel inconel spacer grid assembly was replaced with a redesigned inconel spacer grid
            assembly called the Guardian grid. The Guardian grid fuel assembly was installed in Unit
            1 during Cycle 5, Unit 2 during Cycle 6 and Unit 3 during Cycle 5. The Guardian grid
            raised the active fuel region by 1.589 inches. The reload analysis report (RAR) for
            those fuel cycles concluded that the change in the location of the active fuel region
            relative to the core internals would not impact the results for the various accident
            analyses and no changes to the CEA Insertion Limits were required with the installation
            of the new Guardian grid fuel assembly. On April 19, 2005, changes were made to the COLR
            figures for CEA Insertion Limits versus Thermal Power to revise the CEA Group insertion
            limits by changing the fully withdrawn position to &gt;/=147.75 inches. The change added
            a note to the COLR figures which specified the fully withdrawn CEA position as
            &gt;/=147.75 inches. Corresponding changes should have been made to the PDIL alarm
            setpoint; however, the PDIL alarm setpoint remained at 144 inches. Since the PDIL alarm
            setpoint remained unchanged, the PDIL alarm circuit would not provide operators with an
            alarm when the limit was exceeded. Corrective actions were performed in all three units
            to change the PDIL alarm setpoint to 147 inches, which allowed each unit to exit TS LCO
            3.1.7 Condition D, on March 11,2012. </eventDesc>
        <safetyConsequences>This condition did not adversely affect plant safety or the health and
            safety of the public. The condition did not result in any challenges to the fission
            product barriers or result in any releases of radioactive materials. The safety limits
            for Departure from Nucleate Boiling Ratio (DNBR) and fuel peak centerline temperature
            were not exceeded as a result of this event. An engineering evaluation was performed
            with the minimum PDIL alarm setpoint of 144 inches to determine the impact on CEA scram
            worth and the potential impact to the safety analysis, as well as the impact to flux
            distribution on core power peaking. The evaluation determined that the impact of the
            incorrect PDIL alarm setpoint was bounded by the assumptions made in the safety analyses
            with respect to CEA positions at 144.75 inches vs. the specified COLR limit of 147.75
            inches and did not impact the safe operation of the units. Therefore, there were no
            actual adverse safety consequences as a result of this condition. Additionally, the
            condition did not impact the safety related plant protection system functions performed
            by the core protection calculators (CPCs) and CEA Calculators (CEACs) which provide the
            Linear Heat Rate and DNBR reactor trip functions. Based upon these conclusions, the
            incorrect PDIL alarm setpoint did not adversely affect plant safety or the health and
            safety of the public. The CEA safety functions were not affected by the inoperable PDIL
            alarm circuits. The circuits provide an alarm function only and do not fulfill a safety
            function credited in the safety analysis. Therefore, this event would not have prevented
            the fulfillment of a safety function to safely shutdown the reactor and did not result
            in a safety system functional failure as described by 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). </safetyConsequences>
        <eventCause>The cause of the event was a failure to revise the POlL alarm setpoint in the
            software for the CMC and PC computers following changes to the COLR requirements which
            specified the fully withdrawn position for regulating CEAs. The root cause for failing
            to change the POlL alarm setpoint was determined to be the figures for the Core
            Operating Limits Report (COLR) were not directly tied to any basis document.
            Contributing to this event was the lack of clear procedural guidance for making COLR
            changes. </eventCause>
        <correctiveActions>As an immediate corrective action, POlL alarm setpoint in the software
            for the CMC and PC for all three units were changed to 147 inches for the POlL. This
            corrective action allowed each unit to exit TS LCO 3.1.7 on March 11, 2012.
            Additionally, the following corrective actions are planned: • Develop and institute a
            Safety Analysis Basis Document (SABO) for the COLR. • Revise Setpoint Checklist SABO
            (SABO-5.04.06) to include the checks on PMS POlL files. • Enhance procedural guidance
            for COLR changes. </correctiveActions>
        <previousEvents>No prior similar events were identified in which POlL alarm circuits were
            inoperable because changes to the COLR were not incorporated into the POlL alarm
            setpoint.</previousEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>
