<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-12-06T07:51:56-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-12-06T07:51:56-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-12-06T07:51:56-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H4>ODeM 2.1 </H4><P>LAJIS A subsidiary of Pinnacle West Capital Corporation </P><Table><TR><TH>Dwight C. Mims </TH><TH/><TH/><TH>Mail Station 7605 </TH></TR><TR><TH>Palo Verde Nuclear </TH><TD>Vice President </TD><TD>Tel. 623-393-5403 </TD><TD/><TD>P. O. Box 52034 </TD></TR><TR><TH>Generating Station </TH><TD>Regulatory Affairs and Plant Improvement </TD><TD>Fax 623-393-6077 </TD><TD>' </TD><TD>Phoenix, Arizona 85072-2034 </TD></TR></Table><P>102-06283-DCM/KAC </P><P>November 22,2010 </P><P>ATTN: Document Control Desk </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Dear Sirs: </P><P>Subject: 	Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station (PVNGS) Unit 3 Docket No. STN 50-530 License No. NPF-51 Special Report 3-SR-2010-001-00 </P><P>Attached please find Special Report 3-SR-201 0-001-00, which is prepared and submitted pursuant to PVNGS Offsite Dose Calculation Manual (ODCM) requirements. This report discusses the inoperability of a fuel building ventilation system high range radioactive gaseous effluent monitor for more than 72 hours. </P><P>By copy of this letter and the attachment, this report is being provided to the NRC Region IV Administrator and the PVNGS Resident Inspector. </P><P>No commitments are being made to the NRC by this letter. </P><P>Should you need further information regarding this submittal, please contact Marianne Webb, Compliance Section Leader, at (623) 393-5730. </P><P>Sincerely, </P></Part><Part><H3>$.C~rL-: </H3><P>DCM/MNWIKC/gat Enclosure </P><P>Special Report 3-SR-201 0-001-00, Fuel Building Ventilation System High Range </P><P>Radioactive Gaseous Effluent Monitor Inoperable </P><P>cc: (with enclosure) </P><P>E. E. Collins Jr. NRC Region IV Regional Administrator </P><P>J. R. Hall NRC NRR Senior Project Manager </P><P>L. K. Gibson NRC NRR Project Manager </P><P>J. H. Bashore NRC Senior Resident Inspector (acting) for PVNGS </P><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance </P><P>Callaway • Comanche Peak • Diablo Canyon • Palo Verde • San Onofre • South Texas • Wolf Creek </P><P>Enclosure 
</P><Sect><H3>Special Report 3-SR-201 0-001-00 
Fuel Building Ventilation System High Range 
Radioactive Gaseous Effluent Monitor Inoperable 
</H3><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station 
Special Report 3-SR-201 0-001-00 
Fuel Building Ventilation System High Range 
</P><P>Radioactive Gaseous Effluent Monitor Inoperable 
Docket No. STN 50-530, Unit 3 
</P><P>Reporting Requirement: </P><P>The PVNGS Offsite Dose Calculation Manual (ODCM) contains operability requirements for radioactive gaseous effluent monitoring instrumentation in Section 2.1, &quot;Requirements: Gaseous Monitors.&quot; Action 42 for Table 2-1, Item 5, &quot;Fuel Building Ventilation System,&quot; specifies that when the number of OPERABLE High Range Monitors is less than required by the Minimum Channels OPERABLE requirement, and the required monitor is not restored to OPERABLE status within 72 hours, then the associated actions are to: </P><P>a) 	Initiate the Preplanned Alternate Sampling Program to monitor the 
appropriate parameter(s) when it is needed. . 
</P><P>b) 	Prepare and submit a Special Report to the Commission within 30 days following the event outlining the action(s) taken, the cause of the inoperability, and the plans and schedule for restoring the system to OPERABLE status. </P><P>Initial Conditions: </P><P>At 1405 Mountain Standard Time (MST) on October 21, 2010, Unit 3 was in a refueling 
outage, with the core off-loaded to the spent fuel pool. The fuel building ventilation 
system high range radioactive gaseous effluent monitor (RU-146) was declared 
inoperable due to its 120 VAC Class 1 E power supply (PNB-D26) being removed from 
</P><P>service. 
RU-146 was not restored to OPERABLE status within 72 hours. 
</P><P>Actions Taken: </P><P>The Preplanned Alternate Sampling Program was initiated pursuant to the ODCM </P><P>Requirement 2.1, ACTION 42(a) on October 24,2010, at 1405 MST. On October 28, 2010, at 0845 MST, RU-146 was declared OPERABLE after restoration of power and completion of the channel check surveillance test. There were no radiation level anomalies recorded during the compensatory period that alternate sampling was in </P><P>place. </P><P>Page 1 of 2 </P><P>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station </P><P>Special Report 3-SR-2010-001-00 </P><P>Cause of the Inoperability: </P><P>There was no monitor malfunction associated with the inoperability of RU-146. The cause for exceeding the 72 hours allowed by ODCM 2.1, Action 42(b), was primarily due to the voluntary implementation of a modification to improve the reliability of inverter (PNB-N12) during a time that imposed minimum risk impact to the station. The inverter, the associated Class IE 125vdc bus, and therefore monitor RU-146, were specifically removed from service at a time when the reactor was defueled. This modification was scheduled to work 24/7 during a refueling outage because the scope of this work cannot be performed when the unit is operating. The cumulative effect of the work resulted in RU-146 being out of service for 162 hours and 40 minutes. </P><P>Plans and Schedule for Restoring the Channels to OPERABLE Status: </P><P>On October 28,2010, at 0845 MST, RU-146 was declared OPERABLE after completion of the channel check surveillance test. </P><P>Page 2 of 2 </P></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>