<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2011-03-31T07:42:08-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2011-03-31T07:42:08-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2011-03-31T07:42:08-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>iIIbAflS A subs;di8'Y of Pinnacle Wast Capital &quot;&quot;&quot;&quot;,&quot;,lion </P><P>Dwight c. Mims Mall Station 7605 Palo Verde Nuclear Senior Vice President Tel. 623-393-5403 P. O. Box 52034 Generating Station Regulatory Affairs and Oversight Fax 623-393-6077 Phoenix, Arizona 85072-2034 </P><P>102-06334-0CM/JR March 21, 2011 </P><P>ATTN: Document Control Desk </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Dear Sirs: </P><P>Subject: 	Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station (PVNGS) Unit 3 Docket No. STN 50-530 License No. NPF-74 Licensee Event Report 2011-001-00 </P><P>Enclosed please find Licensee Event Report (LER) 50-530/2011-001-00 that has been prepared and submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73. This LER reports an automatic actuation of the reactor protection system (reactor trip) and auxiliary feedwater actuation signal subsequent to a failed open main feedwater pump minimum flow recirculation valve. </P><P>In accordance with 10 CFR 50.4, copies of this LER are being forwarded to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) Regional Office, NRC Region IV and the Senior Resident Inspector. If you have questions regarding this submittal, please contact Marianne Webb, Section Leader, Regulatory Affairs, at (623) 393-5730. </P><P>Arizona Public Service Company makes no commitments in this letter. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><P>.0.c. 7y/&quot;&quot;:-</P><P>OCMfTNWIMNW/JRlgat </P><P>Enclosure </P><Table><TR><TD>cc: </TD><TD>E. E. Collins Jr. </TD><TD>NRC Region IV Regional Administrator </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>L. K. Gibson </TD><TD>NRC NRR Project Manager for PVNGS (electronic / paper) </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>J. R. Hall </TD><TD>NRC NRR Senior Project Manager (electronic / paper) </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD>M. A. Brown </TD><TD>NRC Senior Resident Inspector for PVNGS </TD></TR></Table><P>A member of the STARS (Strategic Teaming and Resource Sharing) Alliance Callaway • Comanche Peak • Diablo Canyon • Palo Verde • San Onofre • South Texas • Wolf ~~ </P><Part><H2>u(LfL </H2><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 1013112013 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request 80 hours. Reported lessons leamed are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAIPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by intemet e-mail to infocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NE 8-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currenUy varld OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station (PVNGS) Unit 3 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000530 1 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Unit 3 Reactor Trip Due to Failed Open Main Feedwater Pump A Minimum Flow Recirculation Valve </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACIU&quot;nES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>01 </TH><TD>19 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>-001 -</TD><TD>00 </TD><TD>03 </TD><TD>21 </TD><TD>2011 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check a/l that apply) o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) 181 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 5O.36(c)(2) o 5O.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 5O.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. UCENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME I~LEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Marianne Webb, Section Leader, Regulatory Affairs 623-393-5730 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE UNE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>E </TH><TD>SJ </TD><TD>VALVE </TD><TD>L121 </TD><TD>Y </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14_ SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED DYES (Ifyes, oomplete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) 181 NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>~TRACT(Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On January 19, 2011, at approximately 1840 Mountain Standard Time, Unit 3 was at 100 percent power at normal operating temperature and normal operating pressure when the main feedwater pump A minimum flow recirculation valve (mini-flow valve) failed open causing a percentage of feedwater flow to be diverted to the condenser. Subsequently, Unit 3 experienced a reactor power cutback when main feedwater pump 8 tripped on low suction pressure. The combination of the main feedwater pump 8 trip and the main feedwater pump A mini-flow valve failure caused both steam generator water levels to lower causing an automatic reactor trip. 80th steam generator levels continued to drop which initiated an auxiliary feedwater actuation signal. The plant was stabilized in Mode 3. IThe failed open mini-flow valve was caused by a failed diaphragm in a pneumatic 3-way precision relay within ~emini-flow valve control loop. The relay was replaced and Unit 3 was returned to 100 percent power on ~anuary 23, 2011, at approximately 0100. No similar conditions have been reported by Palo Verde in the past three years. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (10.2010) NRC FORM 366A (10·20107) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER NRC FORM 366A (10·20107) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER NRC FORM 366A (10-20107) PRINTED ON RECYCLED PAPER </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A COMMISSION (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station Unit 3 </TH><TD>05000530 </TD><TD>YEAR SEQUENTAL NUMBER REVISION NUMBER </TD><TD>2 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE All times are Mountain Standard Time and approximate unless otherwise indicated. 1. REPORTING REQUIREMENT(S): This Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(iv)(A) to report an automatic actuation of the reactor protection system (RPS) and an auxiliary feedwater actuation signal (AFAS) associated with a failed open main feedwater pump (MFWP) minimum flow recirculation valve (mini-flow valve). This event was reported to the NRC on January 19, 2011, via the emergency notification system (ENS 46556). 2. DESCRIPTION OF STRUCTURE(S), SYSTEM(S) AND COMPONENT(S): The main feedwater system (see diagram) (EllS Code: SJ) consists of piping, main feedwater pumps (MFWP) (EllS Code: JK), high pressure heaters, valves, controls, instrumentation, and associated equipment which supply feedwater to the steam generators (SG) (EllS Code: AB). SEAL WATER FEEDWATER PUMP'S' Mini-Flow Valve Feedwater Simplified Diagram </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A COMMISSION (10·2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station Unit 3 </TH><TD>05000530 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>3 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 -001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE Each MFWP is a turbine-driven pump capable of supplying 65 percent of main feedwater system capacity. There are two MFWPs which serve both SGs. The MFWP mini-flow valves assure there is always adequate flow through the MFWPs to prevent pump damage. Each mini-flow valve has the capability of providing a flow of approximately 7000 gpm to the main condenser (EllS Code: SG). The mini-flow valve is designed to fail open on loss of electrical signal or loss of instrument air to ensure that minimum flow is maintained through the MFWP to prevent pump damage on a loss of downstream flowpath during pump operation. 3. INITIAL PLANT CONDITIONS: On January 19, 2011, Palo Verde Unit 3 was in Mode 1 (Power Operation) at 100 percent power at normal operating temperature and normal operating pressure. There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components at the time that contributed to this event. 4. EVENT DESCRIPTION: On January 19, 2011, at 1840, Unit 3 experienced a reactor power cutback (RPCB) (EllS Code: JD) from 100 percent power to approximately 60 percent power due to MFWP B tripping on low suction pressure. The low suction pressure was experienced by both MFWPs. The MFWP trip logic is designed to trip MFWP B first to prevent simultaneous MFWP trips. The low suction pressure was caused by a failed diaphragm in a pneumatic 3-way precision relay (precision relay) for the mini-flow valve on MFWP A (see diagram) which caused the mini-flow valve to fail open and divert a percentage of feedwater flow from both SGs to the condenser. The precision relay functions to cause full opening of the mini-flow valve when input control air pressure falls below 3 psig. Control air pressure is normally maintained between 3 to 15 psig. The failed diaphragm caused air leakage within the precision relay which lowered the input control air pressure to less than 3 psig and actuated the precision relay to open the mini-flow valve. During this transient, both SG levels decreased to the point that a reactor trip (EllS Code: JC) occurred at 1841. The SG levels continued to lower following the reactor trip resulting in an AFAS (EllS Code: JE). Both auxiliary feedwater pumps A and B started and fed SGs in conjunction with MFWP A. The plant was stabilized in Mode 3. 5. ASSESSMENT OF SAFETY CONSEQUENCES: There were no inoperable structures, systems, or components at the time that contributed to this event. The plant responded as designed for the RPCB, reactor trip and AFAS actuations. The conditional core damage probability for this event was calculated to be </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A COMMISSION (10-2010) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station Unit 3 </TH><TD>05000530 </TD><TD>YEAR 1 SEQUENTAL IREVISIONI NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>4 OF 4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2011 -001 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE 1.26E-6. This event did not result in any challenges to the fission product barriers or result in the release of radioactive materials. There were no actual safety consequences as a result of this event. This event did not prevent the fulfillment of a safety function nor did it result in a safety system functional failure as described by 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(v). 6. CAUSE OF THE EVENT: The cause of the event was a failed diaphragm in the precision relay for the mini-flow valve control loop which resulted in the opening of the mini-flow valve on MFWP A. This allowed a percentage of feedwater flow to be diverted to the condenser, resulting in a MFWP B trip and a RPCB followed by a reactor trip and AFAS. 7. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS: The following corrective actions were implemented: 1. The Unit 3 MFWP A mini-flow valve control system precision relay was immediately replaced. 2. The Unit 3 MFWP B mini-flow valve control system precision relay was replaced on February 18, 2011 as an interim action. The extent of condition evaluation determined that the subject relays are not installed in the Units 1 and 2 MFWP mini-flow valve control systems. To improve maintenance reliability, a modification replaced these mini-flow valves and control systems during previous outages in Units 1 and 2. The same modification to replace the Unit 3 MFWP mini-flow valves and their control systems is planned during the next refueling outage. The preventive maintenance process for these relays will be addressed as part of the corrective actions of this investigation. Any additional corrective actions taken as a result of the investigation of this event will be implemented in accordance with the requirements of the Palo Verde corrective action program. If information is subsequently developed which would significantly affect a reader's understanding or perception of this event, a supplement to this LER will be submitted. 8. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS: No similar conditions have been reported by Palo Verde in the past three years. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>