<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ler>
    <abstract>At 1803 on April 8, 2011, during reactor core offload for the 16th Unit 2 refueling
        outage, Unit 2 entered Technical Specification Limiting Condition for Operation (TS LCO)
        3.3.9 when the Control Room Essential Filtration Actuation Signal (CREFAS) was declared
        inoperable due to both Control Room intake radiation monitors being out of service.
        Irradiated fuel movement was allowed to continue due to an incorrect understanding that the
        already in-service Control Room Essential Filtration System (CREFS) "8" train air handling
        unit fulfilled the required action of the LCO. At 2140, the Outage Shift Manager entered the
        Control Room and noted that the Control Room was not fully pressurized and questioned
        whether the required actions of LCO 3.3.9 were met. At that time, the Control Room staff
        recognized that required dampers had not been closed. Re-alignment of the dampers was
        completed at 2146 to comply with the required actions of the LCO. The root cause was
        imprecise terminology in LCO 3.3.9 Required Action C.1 , which did not specify that CREFS
        shall be placed in the essential filtration mode required for post-accident emergency
        alignment. A License Amendment Request will be submitted to provide more specific direction
        in LCO 3.3.9 regarding alignment of CREFS. The station has not reported any other TS 3.3.9
        violations in the past three years. </abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs> This event is reportable as a condition prohibited by Technical
            Specifications (TSs) per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8).</reportingReqs>
        <structureDesc>The Control Room Essential Filtration Actuation Signal (CREFAS)(EIIS: JE)
            automatically actuates the Control Room Essential Filtration System (CREFS) (EllS: VI).
            The CREFAS is initiated by a control room air intake high airborne radioactivity signal
            from either of two radiation monitors (EllS: IL) RU-29 and RU-30, a Fuel 8uilding
            Essential Ventilation Actuation Signal (F8EVAS) (EllS: VI), or a Containment Purge
            Isolation Actuation Signal (CPIAS) (EllS: VI). A manual actuation feature is also
            provided for the CREFAS. The CREFS consists of two separate, seismically qualified,
            redundant essential flow trains "A" and "8". Each flow train consists of an essential
            air handling unit (AHU) with high efficiency filters and charcoal adsorbers to process
            intake airflow and recirculate air flow to the Control Room envelope. Low leakage
            ductwork and dampers are provided to minimize unfiltered air in-leakage. The Control
            Room post-accident habitability requirements are met by either CREFS train. The "8"
            train CREFS shares ductwork with the Control Room Normal (non-essential) Ventilation
            system and both serve the inverter room and communication room on the 120 foot level
            during non-emergency conditions. The normal AHU ductwork, inverter room, and
            communication room are automatically isolated from the train "8" CREFS upon a CREFAS
            actuation. The "A" train CREFS does not share ductwork with the normal ventilation or
            "8" train CREFS except for final control room outlet ducts. The "A" train CREFS does not
            supply the inverter room or the communication equipment room. Separate ductwork, exhaust
            fans, and exhaust dampers are provided for the kitchen and restroom facilities inside
            the Control Room ventilation envelope_ The kitchen and restroom exhaust dampers close
            when actuated by CREFAS. Upon actuation by a CREFAS, dampers close to isolate the
            Control Room normal AHU, the communication and inverter rooms and the Control Room
            kitchen and Control Room restrooms. Air returning from the Control Room is drawn into
            the Essential AHUs which filter the air and discharge it to the essential supply
            distribution ducts. This post-CREFAS alignment (essential filtration mode) ensures a
            positive pressure exists inside the Control Room to prevent in-leakage from outside air.
            TS Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.3.9 requires only one of the two CREFAS
            channels to be OPERABLE during Mode 6 or irradiated fuel movement. An OPERABLE CREFAS
            channel consists of a CREFAS manual trip, actuation logic, and a Control Room air intake
            radiation monitor. If any of those three components are inoperable, LCO 3.3.9 Condition
            C Required Actions are to either: Place one CREFS train in operation, immediately (C.1),
            or Suspend movement of irradiated fuel assemblies, positive reactivity additions, and
            core alterations, immediately (C.2.1, C.2.2, and C.2.3). The safety function of a CREFAS
            is to actuate CREFS to mitigate the consequences of analyzed accidents, including a fuel
            handling accident, to ensure Control Room habitability is maintained in accordance with
            General Design Criterion 19 of 10 CFR 50 Appendix A. </structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On April 8, 2011, Palo Verde Unit 2 was in Mode 6 (Refueling). The 120 VAC Class
            1 E bus D25 had been deenergized since 0956 that day, which rendered train "A" Control
            Room air intake radiation monitor RU-29 and its associated CREFAS channel inoperable.
            Deenergized bus D25 similarly affected the "A" channels of CPIAS and FBEVAS, which were
            rendered inoperable. The opposite "B" train channels of CREFAS, CPIAS, and FBEVAS
            remained OPERABLE. Reactor core offload was in progress with irradiated fuel movement
            occurring in the Fuel Building. The essential AHU for Train "B" CREFS was in service and
            isolated from normal Control Room ventilation, providing filtered air to the Control
            Room. The isolation dampers for the communication and inverter rooms and the Control
            Room kitchen and Control Room restrooms were open. In this condition, the Control Room
            does not have the positive pressure associated with the CREFS essential filtration mode
            required for post-accident emergency alignment. 4. EVENT DESCRIPTION: On April 8, 2011,
            at 1803, during shift turnover, the train "B" Control Room air intake radiation monitor
            RU-30 was declared INOPERABLE upon notification of a communication failure between the
            radiation monitor and the Radiation Monitoring System Remote Indication and Control
            unit. This communication failure resulted in RU-30 being unable to initiate a CREFAS.
            The Control Room Supervisor (CRS) (utility, licensed) directed the Reactor Engineer
            (utility, non-licensed) to stop fuel movement and gave permission to continue movement
            of the irradiated fuel assembly on the Spent Fuel Handling Machine to place it in a safe
            location, consistent with the bases for LCO 3.7.11. The CRS informed the Shift Manager
            (SM) (utility, licensed), who was engaged in shift turnover, of the loss of RU-30 and
            the direction provided to the Reactor Engineer to cease irradiated fuel movement. The SM
            and the CRS reviewed TS LCO 3.3.9 and concluded that the condition of Required Action
            C.1 (one train of CREFS in operation) was met since the Train "B" Control Room Essential
            AHU, was running. The TS Basis for LCO 3.3.9 was not referenced by either the SM or CRS.
            The SM authorized recommencement of irradiated fuel movement since the Unit was
            understood (incorrectly) to be in compliance with LCO 3.3.9 Required Action C.1. The
            CRS, at 1808 notified the Reactor Engineer that irradiated fuel movement could
            recommence. Following the completion of turnover a Control Room log entry was made to
            document that the Unit was in compliance with LCO 3.3.9 Required Action C.1 and that
            CREFS train "B" was in service. At 2140, the Outage Shift Manager (utility, licensed)
            entered the Control Room and noted that the Control Room envelope was not pressurized to
            the extent expected. The Outage Shift Manager questioned the actions that were taken to
            comply with LCO 3.3.9 Required Action C.1. At this time, Control Room staff determined
            that Control Room ventilation had not been realigned to the CREFS essential filtration
            mode required for post-accident emergency alignment, as stipulated in the LCO 3_3_9
            Technical Specification Basis_ The wording in the basis document states: "Condition C
            applies to the failure of two channels of CREFAS Manual Trip, Actuation Logic, and
            Radiation Monitor channel in MODE 5 or 6, or when moving irradiated fuel assemblies. The
            required actions are immediately taken to place one OPERABLE CREFS train in the
            emergency mode of operation (i.e., fan running, valves/dampers aligned to the post
            CREFAS mode, etc.) or to suspend CORE ALTERA TlONS, positive reactivity additions, and
            movement ofirradiated fuel assemblies. The [ Immediate] Completion Time recognizes the
            fact that FBEVAS, or CPIAS are available to initiate Control Room filtration in the
            event of a fuel handling accident. " At 2146, the Control Room ventilation dampers were
            re-aligned to comply with LCO 3.3.9, Required Action C.1. Irradiated fuel movement was
            not suspended at this time because realignment of CREFS occurred immediately. The
            Completion Time for this LCO Required Action was exceeded by approximately three hours
            and forty-five minutes. </plantConds>

        <safetyConsequences>The safety analysis of record for a fuel handling accident credits the
            CPIAS or FBEVAS to provide the safety function to actuate CREFAS. Those two signals are
            actuated by corresponding radiation monitors in the containment and fuel buildings
            should a fuel handling accident occur. The CREFAS actuation automatically places CREFS
            in the essential filtration mode required for post-accident emergency alignment to
            ensure the corresponding control room habitability safety function is maintained. The
            required "B" train channels for CPIAS and FBEVAS were OPERABLE at the time the condition
            occurred. Therefore, the inoperable control room air intake radiation monitors RU-29 and
            RU-30 would not have prevented the fulfillment of the CREFAS safety function to mitigate
            the consequences of a fuel handling accident. This event did not result in any
            challenges to the fission product barriers or result in the release of radioactive
            materials. There were no actual safety consequences as a result of this event. This
            event did not prevent the fulfillment of a safety function nor did it result in a safety
            system functional failure as described by 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(v).</safetyConsequences>
        <eventCause>The direct cause of the failure to comply with TS LCO 3.3.9 was the decision to
            allow irradiated fuel movement to recommence with Control Room ventilation not in the
            essential filtration mode required for post-accident emergency alignment. The root cause
            was imprecise terminology in LCO 3.3.9 Required Action C.1, in that it failed to specify
            that CREFS shall be placed in the essential filtration mode required for post-accident
            emergency alignment. Contributing causes included: • A latent organizational weakness
            existed in the reinforcement of Operations expectations for Technical Specification
            Decision Making, which allowed the Technical Specification decision to be made without
            consulting the Technical Specification Bases for LCO 3.3.9 Required Action C.1. •
            Inadequate guidance to facilitate meeting the requirements of LCO 3.3.9, Required Action
            C.1 in that there is inconsistent terminology relative to Control Room ventilation modes
            of operation among the LCO, LCO bases, and procedures. • An operator knowledge
            deficiency exists in the area of the Control Room ventilation system and related
            Technical Specifications. 6. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS: The Control Room ventilation dampers
            were re-aligned to be in compliance with the requirements of LCO 3.3.9, Required Action
            C.1 at 2146 on April 8, 2011. To prevent recurrence, a License Amendment Request (LAR)
            will be submitted to the NRC to revise LCO 3.3.9 Required Actions A.1 and C.1 to ensure
            more specific direction is provided regarding the alignment of CREFS when LCO 3.3.9
            Conditions A or C are entered. The LAR will also request similar revision to related LCO
            3.7.11 (CREFS) which contains similar imprecise required actions. Following
            implementation of revised LCOs 3.3.9 and 3.7.11, a simulator scenario in Licensed
            Operator Continued Training will be included that requires crews to exercise the amended
            Required Actions of these LCOs. The following additional corrective actions will be
            taken to address the contributing causes: • Change the Technical Specification Decision
            Making process expectations and procedures to emphasize that Technical Specifications
            and Bases must be used together to understand and comply with the license. • Revise
            Control Building ventilation procedures to support compliance with LCO 3.3.9 and 3.7.11
            Required Actions. • Incorporate additional training into Licensed Operator initial and
            continuing training programs to correct the identified knowledge deficiency. The above
            and any additional corrective actions taken as a result of the investigation of this
            event will be implemented in accordance with the requirements of the Palo Verde
            corrective action program. If information is subsequently developed which would
            significantly affect a reader's understanding or perception of this event, a supplement
            to this LER will be submitted. </eventCause>
        <similarEvents>The station has not identified prior TS violations related to CREFS not being
            placed in the essential filtration mode required for post-accident emergency alignment
            while irradiated fuel movement was in progress. Although not related to irradiated fuel
            movement in Mode 6, an adverse condition report identified a similar event. The adverse
            condition report, generated on June 18, 2007, addressed Control Room log entries that
            incorrectly identified affected LCOs for inoperable, bypassed Engineered Safety Features
            Actuation System functions, including CREFAS. For example, one of the log entries cited
            the following: "LCO 3.7.11 Required Action 0.1 was met due to "B" CR ESS [ "B" Train
            Control Room Essential] AHU Fan running. However the Bases identifies that the train
            must be in "emergency mode of operation (i.e., fan running, valves/dampers aligned to
            the post-CREFAS mode, etc.)." At 0826 on 6/18/07 it was identified that the smoke
            exhaust and communication equipment room isolation dampers were not aligned to the 'post
            CREFAS' mode. JJ The corrective actions of the condition report focused on correcting
            the log entries and did not evaluate the causes for the incorrect log entries regarding
            Required Actions and bases for LCO 3.7.11 with respect to system alignments. Therefore,
            the corrective actions of that condition report would not have prevented this
            event.</similarEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>
