<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On July 1, 2011, at approximately 15:30 Mountain Standard Time, both trains of the
        Qualified Safety Parameter Display System (QSPDS) were declared INOPERABLE when it was
        discovered that the 120 volt class power supply cables to the A and B train QSPDS display
        modems did not meet the physical separation criteria per Regulatory Guide 1.75 and PVNGS
        Installation Specification for Cable Splicing and Terminations 13-EN-0306. Accordingly,
        Conditions A and C of Technical SpeCification Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.3.10,
        Post Accident Monitoring (PAM) Instrumentation, were entered. On July 3, 2011, at 16:05,
        Conditions A and C of Technical Specification LCO 3.3.10 were exited after the power supply
        cables to the A and B train QSPDS display modems were rerouted per work order instructions
        to meet the physical separation criteria. The event investigation is in progress and the
        results will be reported in a supplement to this Licensee Event Report. In the past three
        years, PVNGS has not reported a similar event of nonconformance to Regulatory Guide
        1.75.</abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR
            50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) as a condition prohibited by Technical Specifications (TS). Trains A
            and 8 of the Qualified Safety Parameter Display System (QSPDS)(EIIS: IP) were inoperable
            for an amount of time greater than that allowed by TS Limiting Condition for Operation
            (LCO) 3.3.10, Post Accident Monitoring (PAM) Instrumentation.</reportingReqs>
        <structureDesc> 2. DESCRIPTION OF STRUCTURE(S), SYSTEM(S) AND COMPONENT(S): The QSPDS
            analyzes and processes selected plant parameters and displays them to assist the
            operator (utility -licensed) in quickly assessing plant conditions during accident
            situations. Signals obtained from seismically qualified instrumentation are analyzed by
            class 1 E microprocessors. The output of these microprocessors is transmitted to the
            Control Room for continuous display and recording. These outputs are also transmitted to
            the nonclass Emergency Response Facility Data Acquisition and Display System
            (ERFDADS)(EIIS: IP). The QSPDS consists of two redundant class 1 E channels which are
            seismically qualified and electrically and physically independent for the display of
            safety parameters including inadequate core cooling (ICC) processing information.
            Indications provided include: • Core exit temperature -signal processing and display •
            Reactor Coolant System saturation (or subcooled) margin -computation and display •
            Reactor vessel water level -signal processing and display The ICC detection parameters
            provide the operator with continuous indication of the thermal-hydraulic state within
            the reactor vessel during the progression of an event leading to and from ICC. The QSPDS
            transmits data to the Control Room display units via fiber optic communication modems
            which are installed in control board 804. The fiber optic communication modems receive
            120 VAC power independent of other QSPDS component power supplies. The QSPDS includes
            other independent data transmission interfaces to display equipment on control board 802
            and ERFDADS. </structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On June 29,2011, Palo Verde Unit 1 was in Operating MODE 1 (Power Operation) at
            100 percent power at normal operating temperature and normal operating pressure. There
            were no other major structures, systems, or components that were inoperable at the start
            of the event that contributed to the event.</plantConds>
        <eventDesc>On June 29, 2011, in preparation for a modification to upgrade QSPDS, a walk down
            of the installed system in Unit 1 was performed. During the walk down, it was discovered
            that the 120 volt class power supply cables to the A and B train QSPDS display modems in
            control board B04 did not meet the minimum six inch physical separation criteria per
            Regulatory Guide 1.75 and Palo Verde Nuclear Generating Station (PVNGS) Installation
            Specification for Cable Splicing and Terminations 13-EN-0306. On July 1, 2011, at 15:30,
            following further evaluation by Engineering and Operations, both trains of QSPDS were
            declared INOPERABLE. Conditions A and C ofTS LCO 3.3.10, Post Accident Monitoring (PAM)
            Instrumentation, were entered. On July 3,2011, at 16:05, both trains were declared
            OPERABLE and Conditions A and C of TS LCO 3.3.10 were exited after the power supply
            cables to the A and B train QSPDS display modems were rerouted per work order
            instructions to meet the physical separation criteria.</eventDesc>
        <safetyConsequences>The inadequate separation between the power supply cables to the A and B
            train QSPDS display modems could potentially cause a loss of power, due to a single
            fault, to both of the display modems that feed the QSPDS displays located on the Unit 1
            control board 804. In the event that the QSPDS displays become unavailable, the train A
            Post Accident Monitoring recorders on control board B02, fed directly from the A QSPDS
            instrument chassis, would still remain available to the operators. Additionally, the
            communication link between both trains of QSPDS and ERFDADS would remain available to
            permit full functionality of data retrieval via ERFDADS for the operators and the
            Emergency Response Organization. This event did not result in any challenges to the
            fission product barriers or result in the release of radioactive materials. There were
            no actual safety consequences as a result of this event. This event did not prevent the
            fulfillment of a safety function and did not result in a safety system functional
            failure as described by 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(v). </safetyConsequences>
        <eventCause>The 120 volt class power supply cables to the A and B train QSPDS display modems
            were installed with less than six inches of physical separation, which did not meet
            Regulatory Guide 1.75 Revision 1, 1975, and PVNGS Installation Specification for Cable
            Splicing and Terminations 13-EN-0306 separation criteria. The event investigation is in
            progress and the results will be reported in a supplement to this LER.</eventCause>
        <correctiveActions>As an immediate corrective action, the power supply cables to the A and B
            train QSPDS display modems were rerouted per work order instructions to meet the
            physical separation criteria and both trains of QSPDS were declared OPERABLE. In
            addition, the work order package for the QSPDS upgrade modification has been revised to
            contain Regulatory Guide 1.75 and PVNGS Installation Specification for Cable Splicing
            and Terminations 13-EN-0306 requirements in the work instructions. The event
            investigation is in progress and the results will be reported in a supplement to this
            LER.</correctiveActions>

        <similarEvents>PVNGS has not reported a similar event in the past three
            years.</similarEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>
