<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On January 25, 2012, at approximately 1005 Mountain Standard Time, a reactor power
        cutback occurred in Unit 2 due to the loss of one main feedwater pump. Main turbine load was
        automatically reduced and all regulating group 4 and group 5 control element assemblies
        (CEAs) were automatically fully inserted to lower reactor power to approximately 50 percent.
        The Reactor Regulating System then automatically inserted regulating group 3 CEAs below the
        Technical Specification (TS) Transient Insertion Limits to maintain Reactor Coolant System
        temperature within limits. TS LCO 3.1.7 Regulating CEA Insertion Limits are not applicable
        for two hours after a reactor power cutback and then require CEA positions to be restored to
        within limits in the next two hours or be in Mode 3 within the following six hours. Group 4
        and 5 CEAs were restored to within TS LCO 3.1.7 transient insertion limits at 1144. The
        regulating group 3 CEAs were withdrawn to the upper group stop position of 145.5 inches at
        1124 but were not fully withdrawn to within limits (greater than or equal to [&gt;/=] 147.75
        inches) until 2030, which exceeded the TS LCO 3.1.7 Completion Time by 25 minutes. The root
        cause was determined to be inadequate procedural guidance necessary to ensure regulating CEA
        group 3 was fully withdrawn to comply with the requirements of TS LCO 3.1.7 insertion
        limits. Corrective actions to prevent recurrence include procedure revisions to provide the
        needed guidance to ensure CEA insertion limits are met following a reactor power cutback. No
        similar events have been reported to the NRC in the prior three years. </abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(i)(8) as an
            operation prohibited by Technical Specification (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation
            (LCO) 3.1.7, Regulating Control Element Assembly (CEA) Insertion Limits. The LCO
            requires that the regulating CEA groups shall be limited to the insertion limits
            specified in the Core Operating Limits Report (COLR). If any of the Required Actions and
            associated Completion Times are not met for LCO 3.1.7 Conditions A through D, then TS
            LCO 3.1.7 Condition E requires that the plant be in Mode 3 within 6 hours. TS LCO 3.1.7
            is not applicable for two hours following a reactor power cutback operation.
            Specifically, the Completion Time of TS LCO 3.1.7 Condition E, which requires that the
            plant be in Mode 3 within 6 hours, was exceeded at 2005 on January 25th, 2012. Condition
            E should have been entered at 1405 as a result of exceeding the Completion Time for
            restoring regulating CEA group 3 to within insertion limits as specified by Required
            Action A.1. To comply with TS LCO 3.1.7 at 60% reactor power, regulating CEA group 3
            must be fully withdrawn to meet the transient insertion limit. The COLR defines fully
            withdrawn as greater than or equal to (&gt;/=) 147.75 inches withdrawn. </reportingReqs>
        <structureDesc>The control element drive mechanism control system (CEDMCS) (EllS: AA)
            provides control signals and motive power to the coils of the magnetic jacks in the 89
            control element drive mechanisms (CEDMs) (EllS: AA) which move, hold, and release the
            CEAs (EllS: AA). The CEAs absorb neutrons to control reactivity. CEAs are grouped in
            shutdown, regulating, and part-strength groups. Shutdown CEA groups remain fully
            withdrawn during reactor operation to ensure a rapid safe shutdown of the reactor.
            Regulating and part-strength CEA groups are positioned to control core flux distribution
            and reactivity during reactor operation. Limits on regulating CEA group insertion have
            been established, and all CEA positions are monitored and controlled during power
            operation to ensure that the power distribution and reactivity limits are
            preserved.CEDMCS controls can raise or lower CEAs in groups or individually. When moved
            as a group, withdrawal is limited by the upper group stop (UGS) feature, which limits
            outward group travel to 145.5 inches withdrawn. To fully withdraw the CEAs, past the UGS
            position, the operator must withdraw each CEA individually to the fully withdrawn
            position as defined in the COLR. The reactor power cutback system (EllS: JD) quickly
            reduces plant power, when greater than 75% power, for events such as large load
            rejection or loss of a single main feedwater pump. This function is performed by full
            insertion of regulating CEA groups 4 and 5 and a rapid turbine load reduction (if the
            main turbine is not tripped). The steam bypass control system (S8CS) will operate
            simultaneously to provide additional heat removal, as necessary, to match primary plant
            power with steam demand. The reactor regulating system (RRS) will operate to insert or
            withdraw regulating CEA groups in order to match reactor power with steam demand.
            Following a reactor power cutback, plant power will decrease to approximately 50 to 60
            percent with the RRS, S8CS, Digital Feedwater Control System, and other related control
            systems operating simultaneously to stabilize the plant. </structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On January 25th, 2012, Unit 2 was in Mode 1 operating at 100 percent power.
            There were no structures, systems, or components inoperable at the time of the event
            that contributed to the event.</plantConds>
        <eventDesc>On January 25th, 2012 at 1005, Unit 2 experienced a loss of a non-class 1E 4.16
            KV power bus, which caused a low suction pressure trip of the "8" main feedwater pump,
            resulting in a reactor power cutback. Following the reactor power cutback, regulating
            CEA groups 4 and 5 inserted as designed and were subsequently withdrawn per the reactor
            power cutback abnormal operating procedure to restore CEA group overlap and to restore
            the CEAs to within their insertion limits as required by TS LCO 3.1.7. Regulating CEA
            group 3 inserted as designed and was subsequently withdrawn to the UGS position of 145.5
            inches at 1124. No additional changes were made to regulating group 3 CEA positions for
            the remainder of the day shift. Following shift turnover, the regulating group 3 CEAs
            were individually withdrawn to 149.25 inches at 2030, at which time regulating group 3
            CEAs were in compliance with the insertion limits of TS LCO 3.1.7 and the COLR. During a
            review of plant reactor power cutback response, a reactor engineer noted that initial
            withdrawal of regulating group 3 CEAs was stopped at the UGS position. At 2101, the
            reactor engineer notified the control room staff that regulating group 3 CEAs at the UGS
            position potentially did not satisfy TS LCO 3.1.7 transient insertion limits because the
            COLR required regulating CEA group 3 to be fully withdrawn to &gt;/= 147.75 inches.
            Although in compliance at the time, Operations determined that regulating CEA group 3 at
            the UGS position of 145.5 inches had not met the fully withdrawn requirements of the
            COLR and TS LCO 3.1.7. </eventDesc>
        <safetyConsequences>This condition did not adversely affect plant safety or the health and
            safety of the public. The condition did not result in any challenges to the fission
            product barriers or result in any releases of radioactive materials. The safety limits
            for departure from nucleate boiling ratio and fuel peak centerline temperature were not
            exceeded as a result of this event. Therefore, there were no actual adverse safety
            consequences as a result of this condition. An evaluation was performed to quantify the
            effect of the excess regulating CEA group 3 insertion on the available shutdown margin.
            This evaluation determined that the reactivity effect from regulating CEA group 3 being
            inserted 2.25 inches below its transient insertion limit was sufficiently compensated
            for by the reactivity associated with the positions of regulating CEA groups 4 and 5.
            Therefore, the failure to comply with TS LCO 3.1.7 insertion limits did not reduce
            available shutdown margin below the minimum acceptable value and did not affect the
            associated safety function to safely shutdown the reactor. The small deviation from the
            transient insertion limit did not represent an unanalyzed condition that significantly
            degraded plant safety. This event did not prevent the fulfillment of a safety function
            and did not result in a safety system functional failure as described by 10 CFR
            50.73(a)(2)(v). </safetyConsequences>
        <eventCause>The root cause was determined to be inadequate procedural guidance necessary to
            ensure regulating CEA group 3 was fully withdrawn to comply with the requirements of TS
            LCO 3.1.7 insertion limits. Contributing causes included inadequate procedure use and
            adherence and operator knowledge weaknesses. </eventCause>
        <correctiveActions>To prevent recurrence, the procedures for operation following a reactor
            power cutback event will be revised to include direction on positioning all CEA groups
            above the limits required by TS LCO 3.1 .7 and the COLR. To address related procedure
            use and adherence and operator knowledge weaknesses, licensed operator continuing
            training simulator sessions will be conducted involving the revised abnormal operating
            procedures that will include restoring CEA positions to address compliance with TS LCO
            3.1.7 insertion limits. Licensed operator training tasks will be revised to require
            periodic training on compliance with CEA insertion TSs following reactor power cutback. </correctiveActions>
        <previousEvents>A similar event occurred in 1996 in Unit 3 where several regulating group 3
            CEAs were not withdrawn to the TS required fully withdrawn position following a load
            rejection reactor power cutback event. At that time, TS LCO 3.1.3.6 specified a fully
            withdrawn position of &gt;/= 144.75 inches which was below the UGS position of 145.5
            inches. When regulating group 3 CEA motion was stopped at the UGS position, several
            group 3 CEAs remained below the fully withdrawn position due to normal system operation
            which allows small position differences within a group. During surveillance testing it
            was noted that several regulating group 3 CEAs remained below the fully withdrawn
            acceptance criteria that existed at that time (&gt;/= 144.75 inches). The 1996
            corrective actions did not implement adequate barriers to prevent recurrence because no
            causal evaluation was done and specific guidance was not established to ensure CEA
            insertion limits are restored following reactor power cutback.</previousEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>
