<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On November 22, 2011, at approximately 1925 Mountain Standard Time, during the
        performance of post-refueling low power physics testing, the Unit 1 reactor was manually
        tripped as required by the control element assembly (CEA) malfunction abnormal operating
        procedure after a subgroup of four CEAs slipped greater than 6.6 inches. An intermittent
        failure of a power switch assembly (PSA) which provides electrical power to the control
        element drive mechanisms (CEDMs) resulted in the CEA slippage. After troubleshooting was
        completed, the power switch assembly was replaced. Retesting was completed on November
        24,2011. The root cause was determined to be latent organizational weaknesses with the
        modification and corrective action processes that delayed installation of automatic CEDM
        timer modules (ACTMs) which would minimize the occurrence of dropped or slipped CEAs. The
        corrective action to prevent recurrence is to install the ACTM modification during
        subsequent refueling outages in each of the units. This modification was successfully
        installed in Unit 3 during the 16th refueling outage completed in April, 2012. LER
        50-52812011-004-00 reported a prior similar event. </abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(iv)(A) to report
            a manual actuation of the reactor protection system (RPS)(EIIS: JC) that occurred while
            the reactor was critical. This event was reported to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission
            (NRC) on November 22, 2011, via the event notification system (EN
            47472).</reportingReqs>
        <structureDesc>The control element drive mechanism control system (CEDMCS) (EllS: AA)
            provides control signals and motive power to the coils of the magnetic jacks in the 89
            Control Element Drive Mechanisms (CEDMs) (EllS: AA) which move, hold, and release the
            reactor's control element assemblies (CEAs) (EllS: -AA). The CEAs absorb neutrons to
            control reactivity. Two motor/generator sets are connected in parallel to supply 240
            VAC, 3 phase power through the reactor trip switchgear (RTSG) (EllS: AA). The output
            from the RTSG is directed through power switch assemblies. The power switch assemblies
            contain silicon controlled rectifiers (SCRs) which convert the 3 phase, AC input voltage
            to a initiated in 2003 but active work was not commenced until 2009 as part of the
            equipment reliability improvement initiatives in response to CAL 4-07 -004A. I· </structureDesc>
        <correctiveActions>After troubleshooting was completed, the power switch assembly was
            replaced. Retesting was completed on November 24, 2011. Unit 3 was subsequently
            restarted and entered Mode 1 on November 27,2011. The corrective action to prevent
            recurrence is to complete installation of the ACTM modification during the next
            refueling outage in each of the units. The ACTM modification was successfully installed
            in Unit 3 during the refueling outage completed in April, 2012. The latent
            organizational weaknesses that cancelled and delayed installation of the ACTM
            modification prior to 2009 were addressed by corrective actions in key performance areas
            in response to CAL 4-07 -004A. Those corrective actions substantially improved plant
            equipment performance with respect to resolution of long standing equipment problems,
            corrective action effectiveness, and decision making.</correctiveActions>
        <previousEvents>LER 50-52812011-004-00 reported an automatic trip of the Unit 1 reactor that
            occurred on August 6,2011, which resulted from a dropped CEA (37) caused by a loose
            terminal lug on the corresponding CEA power switch assembly. The corrective action is to
            install the</previousEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>
