<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On April 13, 2011, control room essential filtration system (CREFS) outside air intake
        (OSA) dampers were found to be in the normally closed position instead of the normally open
        position stipulated in the updated final safety analysiS report. This incorrect
        configuration was the result of procedure changes made in 1986. Each train of the CREFS
        system contains two OSA dampers in series, with each damper actuated from one of the two
        separate channels of the control room essential filtration actuation signal (CREFAS). Upon
        identification, Unit 1 and Unit 3 entered Technical Specification (TS) 3.3.9, condition A
        when both channels of CREFAS were determined to be inoperable. In response, both units
        placed an OPERABLE train of CREFS into operation per required action A.1. Unit 2 was
        defueled and irradiated fuel assemblies were not being moved; therefore, TS 3.3.9 was not
        applicable to Unit 2 at the time this condition was identified. In the three years prior to
        this event, a similar legacy issue was reported in which station procedures directed system
        configurations not permitted by the plant design (LER 0500528/529/530/2009-001-00, Safety
        Injection System Recirculation Alignment Results in Unanalyzed Condition).</abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This event is reportable as a condition prohibited by Technical
            Specifications (TSs) per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) and as a common cause inoperability of
            independent trains per 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(vii). This condition was originally identified
            on April 13, 2011, and was incorrectly screened as not reportable. A subsequent review
            completed on July 5, 2011, determined the condition was reportable as a condition
            prohibited by TS. This condition was documented in the Palo Verde corrective action
            program and in NRC inspection report 05000528/529/530/2011003, dated August 11,2011.
            Upon further review of the event, on November 17,2011, it was determined that this event
            also constituted a common cause inoperability of an independent train. This second
            condition was documented in the Palo Verde corrective action program. </reportingReqs>

        <structureDesc>The control room essential filtration actuation signal (CREFAS)(EIIS: JE)
            automatically actuates the control room essential filtration system (CREFS)(EIIS: VI).
            The CREFAS is initiated by a control room air intake high airborne radioactivity signal
            from either of two radiation monitors (EllS: IL) RU-29 and RU-30, a fuel building
            essential ventilation actuation signal (FBEVAS)(EIIS: JE), or containment purge
            isolation actuation signal (CPIAS)(EIIS: JE). A manual actuation feature is also
            provided for the CREFAS. A CREFAS actuated by one channel will also result in a
            cross-channel actuation of the redundant CREFAS channel. The CREFS consists of two
            separate, seismically qualified, redundant essential ventilation flow trains. Each flow
            train consists of an essential air handling unit (AHU) with high efficiency filters and
            charcoal adsorbers to process intake airflow and recirculate air flow to the control
            room envelope. Low leakage ductwork and dampers are provided to minimize unfiltered air
            in-leakage. The control room post-accident habitability requirements are met by either
            CREFS train. The B train CREFS shares ductwork with the control room normal
            (non-essential) ventilation system and both serve the inverter room and communication
            room on the control building 120 foot level during non-emergency conditions. The normal
            AHU ductwork, inverter room, and communication room are automatically isolated from the
            train B CREFS upon a CREFAS actuation. The A train CREFS does not share ductwork with
            the normal ventilation or B train CREFS except for final control room outlet ducts. The
            A train CREFS does not supply the inverter room or the communication equipment room.
            Separate ductwork, exhaust fans, and exhaust dampers are provided for the kitchen and
            restroom facilities inside the control room ventilation envelope. The kitchen and
            restroom exhaust dampers close when actuated by CREFAS. Upon actuation by a CREFAS,
            dampers close to isolate the control room normal AHU. Air returning from the control
            room, mixed with outside air, is drawn into the essential AHUs which filter the air and
            discharge it to the essential supply ductwork. Each essential AHU train receives outside
            air through supply ductwork that contains two electro-hydraulically operated outside air
            intake (OSA) dampers (EllS: JE) in series. Each of the two dampers in a train is
            actuated by one of the two separate channels of CREFAS. This post-CREFAS alignment
            (essential filtration mode) ensures a positive pressure exists inside the control room
            to prevent in-leakage from outside air. The essential AHUs start and OSA dampers open
            automatically upon receipt of a Safety Injection Actuation Signal (SIAS)(EIIS: JE) or
            Loss Of Power (LOP)(EIIS: JE). These actuations are separate from CREFAS actuation
            logic. The OSA dampers also close automatically in response to a control room
            ventilation isolation actuation signal (CRVIAS)(EIIS: JE). The CRVIAS isolates the
            control room from outside air and recirculates the control room return air through
            essential AHUs. The OSA dampers fail in the open position upon interruption of
            electrical power to the electro-hydraulic actuators. To address single failure criteria,
            the design configuration for the OSA dampers relies upon the dampers being maintained in
            a normally open position as stipulated in the updated final safety analysis report
            (UFSAR). TS Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) 3.3.9 requires one channel of CREFAS
            to be OPERABLE during Modes 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 and during movement of irradiated fuel
            assemblies. </structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On April 13, 2011, when the condition was initially identified, Units 1 and 3
            were in Mode 1 and at approximately 100 percent power, and Unit 2 was defueled. There
            were no other systems out of service that contributed to this event. </plantConds>
        <eventDesc>On April 13, 2011, during the investigation for a separate control room
            ventilation system issue identified in LER 05000529/2011-001-00, CREFS OSA dampers were
            found to be in the normally closed position as directed by station operating procedures
            instead of the normally open position stipulated in the UFSAR. Prior to discovery, the
            station operated with both trains inoperable because both outside air dampers were
            closed and the TS actions were not met. Additionally, since the plant configuration was
            inconsistent with the design configuration and the safety analysis for the CREFAS
            assumes the trains to be independent, this condition represents a common cause
            inoperability for independent trains. However, since test documents indicated the CREFAS
            actuations logic and relays functioned each time the system was tested and CREFAS would
            have responded as analyzed, it does not represent an unanalyzed condition. Unit 1 and
            Unit 3 entered TS 3.3.9, condition A when both channels of CREFAS were determined to be
            inoperable. In response, both units placed an OPERABLE train of CREFS into operation per
            required action A.1. Unit 2 was defueled and irradiated fuel assemblies were not being
            moved; therefore, TS 3.3.9 was not applicable to Unit 2 at the time the condition was
            identified. The incorrect procedure direction placing the OSA dampers in a normally
            closed position stemmed from a March 1986 engineering evaluation request (EER). This
            change failed to take into account applicable single failure criteria that, if not met,
            would render the system inoperable. The EER addressed excessive condensation in the Unit
            1 B train essential AHU. The EER concluded the cause and source of this condensation was
            air leakage around the backdraft damper which prevents reverse flow through the AHU. The
            EER recommended that closing the OSA dampers would alleviate this condensation. It was
            intended that once the backdraft damper air leakage problem was corrected the procedures
            would be revised to return the OSA dampers to the original design configuration of
            normally open. In March 1988, modification packages were approved to repair the
            backdraft dampers. The modification packages contained instructions to change the
            position of the OSA dampers back to the normally open position after the modifications
            were completed. The modifications were completed in 1991, 1997, and 1998. However, the
            procedure change requests were not implemented and the OSA dampers remained in the
            normally closed position. </eventDesc>
        <safetyConsequences>In the three years prior to the date this condition was originally
            identified, there were no events that required automatic actuation of CREFAS. If such an
            event had occurred, the CREFAS cross-channel actuation of the redundant CREFAS train
            would have ensured actuation of a single train of CREFS required to maintain control
            room habitability for analyzed accidents; therefore, the safety function provided by
            CREFAS to mitigate the consequences of analyzed accidents would have been fulfilled.
            Additionally, test documents indicated the CREFAS actuation logic and relays functioned
            each time the system was tested and CREFAS would have responded as designed, and it did
            not represent an unanalyzed condition. This event did not result in any challenges to
            the fission product barriers or result in the release of radioactive materials. There
            were no actual safety consequences as a result of this event. This event did not prevent
            the fulfillment of a safety function nor did it result in a safety system functional
            failure as described by 10 CFR 50.73 (a)(2)(v). </safetyConsequences>
        <eventCause>The cause of the condition prohibited by TS 3.3.9 was incorrect procedure
            changes that changed the normal position of the OSA dampers from open to closed,
            contrary to the design configuration. This was a legacy issue that originated in
            1986.</eventCause>
        <correctiveActions>Units 1 and 3 each placed a CREFS train into operation to comply with TS
            3.3.9 upon notification of the OSA damper misalignment. Unit 2 was not in a mode of
            applicability for the TS and did not need to take immediate actions. The procedures for
            operation of the control room ventilation system were changed to require the OSA dampers
            to be in a normally open position as stipulated in the UFSAR. No additional corrective
            actions have been taken. Any additional corrective actions taken as a result of the
            investigation of this event will be implemented in accordance with the requirements of
            the Palo Verde corrective action program. If information is subsequently developed which
            would significantly affect a reader's understanding or perception of this event, a
            supplement to this LER will be submitted.</correctiveActions>
        <previousEvents>This event is similar to legacy issues identified in two LERs. Prior to
            three years ago: • LER 0500528/529/530/2004-009-01, Emergency Core Cooling System Piping
            Voids May Have Prevented Fulfillment of Safety Function, identified that the essential
            core cooling system containment sump and suction line were not filled with water as
            required by the plant's design. Within the last three years: • LER
            0500528/529/530/2009-001-00, Safety Injection System Recirculation Alignment Results in
            Unanalyzed Condition, identified procedure changes that permitted system operation of
            the safety injection system in a configuration not permitted by its design. Both of
            these LERs identified similar issues in which station procedures directed system
            configurations not permitted by the plant design and stemmed from processes used early
            in the plant's operating history. The first listed LER resulted in a Notice of Violation
            (NOV) for operating the station with dry essential core cooling system containment sump
            suction pipes (EA-05-051). A component design basis review of the Safety Injection
            System, a corrective action from the NOV, resulted in the identification of the second
            LER listed above. Additional corrective actions from the NOV that strengthened
            corrective action and evaluation processes, including questioning attitude, at the
            station led to the identification of the misaligned OSA dampers identified in this
            LER.</previousEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>
