<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On October 13,2010, during scheduled surveillance test 73ST-9SI02, "CS Nozzle Air
        Test," of the Containment Spray (CS) system spray nozzles, seven obstructed nozzles were
        identified. Unit 3 was defueled at the time of discovery. The nozzles were obstructed for a
        period greater than allowed by Technical Specification (TS) 3.6.6 Limiting Condition for
        Operation. This represents a condition prohibited by TS and a common cause inoperability of
        independent trains. The root cause was boric acid solution was not removed from low points
        that entrapped water in the CS headers after these headers were filled with borated water
        during past CS header overfill events. The borated water subsequently evaporated causing
        boric acid to precipitate and form obstructions in the nozzles. The nozzles were inspected,
        the residue was removed, and the nozzles successfully passed the surveillance test procedure
        prior to entering Mode 4 at the end of the outage. Actions to prevent recurrence include
        inspection and cleaning of CS headers with low points to remove boric acid residue in Units
        1, 2, and 3. Additionally, the Operations procedure for recovery from shutdown cooling to
        normal operations was revised to initiate corrective actions to drain the affected CS
        headers following overfill events. In the past three years, PVNGS reported one similar event
        in LER 50-530/2007-001-00.</abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) to report a
            condition prohibited by Technical Specification (TS) Limiting Condition for Operation
            (LCO) 3.6.6, Condition B. Specifically, on October 13, 2010, Palo Verde personnel
            determined that Containment Spray (CS) nozzles on each of two separate CS train A and B
            spray headers were obstructed. The obstructions existed for a period greater than
            allowed by Technical Specification (TS) 3.6.6 "Containment Spray System." This condition
            is also being reported under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(vii) as a common cause inoperability of
            independent trains because both trains contained boric acid deposits that obstructed the
            spray nozzles.</reportingReqs>
        <structureDesc>The CS system consists of two independent trains of equal capacity, each
            capable of meeting the design basis requirement. Each train includes a CS pump, a
            shutdown cooling heat exchanger, spray headers, nozzles, valves, and piping. Each train
            is powered from a separate Engineered Safety Feature (ESF) bus. The CS [EllS: BP]
            system, as a subsystem of the Safety Injection [EllS: BP] system, is an ESF designed to
            ensure that heat removal can be attained during post accident periods. During a Design
            Basis Accident (DBA), one CS train is required to maintain the containment peak pressure
            and temperature below the design limits, to remove iodine from the containment
            atmosphere to maintain concentrations below those assumed in the safety analysis, and to
            provide hydrogen mixing. To ensure these requirements are met, assuming the worst case·
            single active failure occurs, two CS trains are required to be operable. TSs require a
            train's CS headers to be filled to a minimum level (113 feet elevation) in order for the
            headers to be OPERABLE.</structureDesc>
        <plantConds>On October 13, 2010, Palo Verde Unit 3 was defueled. There were no major
            structures, systems, or components inoperable at the start of the event that contributed
            to the event. 4. EVENT DESCRIPTION: On October 13, 2010, upon completion of Surveillance
            Test 73ST-9S102, "CS Nozzle Air Test," Engineering personnel determined the following
            spray nozzles were obstructed: (1) Train A header (100' elevation) 3SI-A-430, on the end
            of the header</plantConds>
    </narrative>
</ler>
