<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On
        April 15, 2012, at approximately 12:16 Mountain Standard Time, Unit 3 was manually tripped
        during low power physics testing (LPPT) following completion of its 16th refueling outage.
        An automatic control element drive mechanism timer module (ACTM) was installed on each
        control element drive mechanism (CEDM) during the refueling outage to minimize the
        occurrence of slipped or dropped control element assemblies (CEAs) resulting from CEDM or
        control system (CEDMCS) abnormalities. Regulating CEA group 1 was being inserted during a
        reactor coolant system (RCS) boron dilution test directed by the LPPT procedure. During the
        insertion, the ACTM for CEA 57 stopped movement of the CEA and actuated related alarms.
        Control room staff stopped insertion of regulating CEA group 1 and RCS dilution. Power
        increased, approaching the LPPT procedural limit of 0.5% power because of the residual RCS
        dilution effect. The control room staff manually ripped the reactor to comply with the
        procedural power limit. The LPPT procedure did not provide contingency direction to insert
        other CEA groups to compensate for the RCS dilution. ~he root cause investigation is in
        progress. In response to the event, the LPPT procedure was revised to provide contingency
        direction to insert regulating CEA group 5 in the event planned CEA insertion could not
        continue during the test. Similar events have not occurred in the prior three years.
    </abstract>
    <narrative>
        <reportingReqs>This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73
        (a)(2)(iv)(A) to report a manual actuation of the reactor protection system (RPS)(EIIS: JC)
        that occurred while the reactor was critical. This event was reported to the Nuclear
        Regulatory Commission (NRC) on April 15, 2012, via the event notification system report
        number 47837. 
        </reportingReqs>
        <structureDesc>The control
        element drive mechanism control system (CEDMCS) (EllS: AA) provides control signals and
        motive power to the coils of the magnetic jacks in the 89 control element drive mechanisms
        (CEDMs) (EllS: AA) which move, hold, and release the control element assemblies (CEAs)
        (EllS: AA). The CEAs absorb neutrons to control reactivity. Two motor/generator sets are
        connected in parallel to supply 240 VAC, 3 phase power through the reactor trip switchgear
        (RTSG) (EllS: AA). The output from the RTSG is directed through power switch assemblies. The
        power switch assemblies contain silicon controlled rectifiers (SCRs) which convert the 3
        phase, AC input voltage to a stepped DC output voltage. The conversion is controlled by
        electronic circuits in the power switch assembly and in the CEDMCS subgroup logic housing.
        These control circuits determine 
        </structureDesc>
    </narrative>
</ler>