<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
    <abstract>On
        April 15, 2012, at approximately 12: 16 Mountain Standard Time, Unit 3 was manually tripped
        during low power physics testing (LPPT) following completion of its 16th refueling outage.
        An automatic control element drive mechanism timer module (ACTM) was installed on each
        control element drive mechanism (CEDM) during the refueling outage to minimize the
        occurrence of slipped or dropped control element assemblies (CEAs) resulting from CEDM or
        control system (CEDMCS) abnormalities. Regulating CEA group 1 was being inserted during a
        reactor coolant system (RCS) boron dilution test directed by the LPPT procedure. During the
        insertion, the ACTM for CEA 57 stopped movement of the CEA and actuated related alarms.
        Control room staff stopped insertion of regulating CEA group 1 and RCS dilution. Power
        increased, approaching the LPPT procedural limit of 0.5% power because of the residual RCS
        dilution effect. The control room staff manually tripped the reactor to comply with the
        procedural power limit. The root cause of the manual reactor trip was the LPPT procedure did
        not provide contingency direction to insert other CEA groups to compensate for the RCS
        dilution. To prevent recurrence, the station will incorporate appropriate contingencies in
        the LPPT procedure to stabilize reactor power during reactivity manipulations if abnormal
        conditions with CEAs are encountered. 
    </abstract>
    <narrative>
    <reportingReqs>This LER is being submitted pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73
        (a)(2)(iv)(A) to report a manual actuation of the reactor protection system (RPS)(EIIS: JC)
        that occurred while the reactor was critical. This event was reported to the Nuclear
        Regulatory Commission (NRC) on April 15, 2012, via the event notification system report
        number 47837. 
    </reportingReqs>
    <structureDesc>The control
        element drive mechanism control system (CEDMCS) (EllS: AA) provides control signals and
        motive power to the coils of the magnetic jacks in the 89 control element drive mechanisms
        (CEDMs) (EllS: AA) which move, hold, and release the control element assemblies (CEAs)
        (EllS: AA). The CEAs absorb neutrons to control reactivity. Two motor/generator sets are
        connected in parallel to supply 240 VAC, 3 phase power through the reactor trip switchgear
        (RTSG) (EllS: AA). The output from the RTSG is directed through power switch assemblies. The
        power switch assemblies contain silicon controlled rectifiers (SCRs) which convert the 3
        phase, AC input voltage to a stepped DC output voltage. The conversion is controlled by
        electronic circuits in the power switch assembly and in the CEDMCS subgroup logic housing.
        These control circuits determine the sequence to supply power to the CEDM coils. The control
        circuits for each CEA were modified during the Unit 3 refueling outage which commenced in
        March, 2012. Part of the modification included replacement of CEA timer cards with automatic
        CEDM timer modules (ACTMs). The ACTM controls the sequencing of the coil voltages to the
        CEDM and monitors for CEDMCS abnormalities such as inadequate holding currents and high coil
        currents. The ACTM initiates rapid automatic action to hold the CEA in position, and
        generates alarms both locally and in the Control Room in response to slight variations from
        expected values for monitored conditions. These automatic actions minimize the occurrence of
        dropped or slipped CEAs. The reactor protection system (RPS) (EllS: JC) provides a rapid and reliable
        shutdown of the reactor to protect the core and the reactor coolant system (RCS) (EllS: AS)
        pressure boundary from potentially hazardous operating conditions. Shutdown is accomplished
        by either manual or automatic generation of reactor trip signals. The trip signals open the
        RTSG breakers, which de-energize the CEDM coils and allow all CEAs to drop into the core by
        the force of gravity. Low power physics testing (LPPT) is conducted during Mode 2 following
        refueling outages to verify reactor core operating characteristics are consistent with
        design predictions and to provide assurance the core can be operated as designed. 
    </structureDesc>
    <plantConds>On April 15, 2012, Palo Verde Unit 3 was in Mode 2 (Start-up). The reactor
        was critical and post-refueling low power physics testing was in progress. Reactor power was
        below the point-of-adding-heat (0.005 -0.1 % power) and the reactor coolant system (RCS) was
        at normal operating temperature and normal operating pressure. There were no other
        structures, systems, or components inoperable at the time of the event that contributed to
        the event. 
    </plantConds>
    <eventDesc>During LPPT on April 15, at 11 :25, a dilution of RCS boron
        concentration began at a rate of 80 gallons per minute in support of the testing. As
        directed by the LPPT procedure, regulating CEA group 3 was inserted to offset the dilution
        and keep reactor power level constant. Regulating CEA group 1 insertion commenced after
        regulating CEA group 3 had been inserted to the lower group stop position, approximately 5
        inches withdrawn. At 12: 13, while inserting CEA regulating group 1, CEA 57 deviated from
        its sub-group when it stopped moving. The "CEA Group 1 Minor Deviation" alarm was received
        and CEA regulating group 1 insertion and the RCS dilution were stopped; however, the
        residual positive reactivity in the core resulted in a reactor power increase which
        approached the power limit (0.5%) set forth in the LPPT procedure. The LPPT procedure did
        not provide contingency direction to insert other CEA groups to compensate for the RCS
        dilution. In response, the reactor was manually tripped at 12:16, at which time reactor power was 0.5% as indicated on
        log power channels. Following the reactor trip, all CEAs fully inserted into the core. Plant
        systems operated as expected, and this event was diagnosed as an uncomplicated reactor trip.
        Safety related busses remained energized from offsite power during the event and the offsite
        power grid was stable. Unit 3 was stabilized in Mode 3 feeding Steam Generators with the
        non-essential auxiliary feedwater pump. 
    </eventDesc>
    <safetyConsequences>This condition
        did not adversely affect plant safety or the health and safety of the public. This event did
        not result in a transient more severe than those already analyzed in the PVNGS Updated Final
        Safety Analysis Report Chapter 15. The condition did not cause a violation of safety limits
        or the specified acceptable fuel design limits. The condition did not result in any
        challenges to the RCS pressure boundary or other fission product barriers. The safety limits
        for departure from nucleate boiling ratio and fuel peak centerline temperature were not
        exceeded as a result of this event. This event would not have prevented the fulfillment of a
        safety function to safely shutdown the reactor and did not result in a safety system
        functional failure as described by 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v). 
    </safetyConsequences>
    <eventCause>The root
        cause of the manual reactor trip was the LPPT procedure did not provide contingency
        direction to insert other CEA groups to compensate for the RCS dilution. A contributing
        cause was the ACTM modification impacts on the operation of CEDMCS were not identified
        during the design phase. Additionally, the process for addressing impacts of the
        modification did not identify the appropriate stakeholders that could have identified the
        needed procedure contingencies. 
    </eventCause>
    <correctiveActions>As an interim measure, the LPPT procedure was revised to
        provide contingency direction to insert regulating CEA group 5 in the event planned CEA
        insertion could not continue. To prevent recurrence, the station will incorporate
        appropriate contingencies in the LPPT procedure to stabilize reactor power during reactivity
        manipulations if abnormal conditions with CEAs are encountered. Changes to the design
        modification and project management processes will also be implemented to ensure necessary
        stakeholders participate in the design modification process. The changes are intended to
        ensure impacts of the modification are consistently addressed. 
    </correctiveActions>
    <previousEvents>The station has not experienced prior manual trips related to the recently installed ACTM
        modification. Installation of the ACTM modification was a corrective action related to
        events reported in LERs 50-528/2011-005-00 and 50-528/2011-004-00.</previousEvents>
    </narrative>
</ler>