<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ler>
<abstract>On
      May 9, 2012, a review of the procedural guidance for inoperable essential ventilation
      equipment by an investigation team concluded that a condition prohibited by Technical
      Specifications (TS) had occurred in unit 2 on January 22, 2012, when the TS requirements for
      electrical distribution equipment were not met. On January 22,2012, during surveillance
      testing in unit 2, a control relay did not change state as expected and the essential
      ventilation dampers controlled by this relay did not change position. Operations declared the
      affected essential air handling units inoperable. The TSs do not contain specific Limiting
      Conditions for Operation (LCO) requirements for the affected essential ventilation equipment
      and no TS LCO Conditions were entered. Operations followed existing procedural guidance for
      inoperable ventilation equipment. The procedural guidance required operations to verify that
      there was no loss of safety function and that normal room cooling was available. The cause of
      the event was an inadequate procedure that was based on an incorrect understanding of the
      relationship between essential ventilation equipment that provides a support function to
      electrical distribution equipment and operability of the electrical distribution equipment. As
      corrective action, the affected procedure was revised. Similar reportable events have not
      occurred in the past three years.
</abstract>
      <narrative>
      that provides a support function to electrical distribution equipment and
      operability of the ,electrical distribution equipment. The inadequate procedure guidance was
      established in 1991 and was based on a TS interpretation (developed in March 1991 but since
      cancelled) which incorrectly concluded that the effects of an inoperable essential AHU would
      not render the supported electrical distribution equipment inoperable, provided adequate
      compensatory actions were taken. The 1991 TS interpretation used action requirements from the
      original (i.e., prior to improved TS) TS 3.7.6, "Essential Chilled Water System." The current
      improved TS for the EC system (3.7.10) does not include the same guidance as the original TS
      3.7.6. The ventilation damper control relay failure discussed in the Event Description of this
      Licensee Event Report is not considered to be the cause of this event. The failed relay was an
      element in the event that initiated the questions which subsequently led to the conclusion
      that an inadequate procedure resulted in a condition prohibited by TS. Specifically, the
      procedure permitted placing the plant in a condition that did not conform to the single
      failure criterion without formally entering the TS LCO Actions for the affected equipment.
      Because the procedural guidance was contained in a common unit procedure, the condition is
      applicable to Units 1, 2, and 3. A review of the unit logs over the past three years confirmed
      that the procedure was used in units 1, 2, and 3. Use of the procedural guidance in procedure
      40ST-9EC03 resulted in multiple past violations of TS LCO 3.8.4, 3.8.9, and, 3.0.3 in units 1,
      2, and 3.</narrative>
</ler>