<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-07-26T09:37:22-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-07-26T09:37:22-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-07-26T09:37:22-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>South Texas Project Electric Generating Station PoD. Box 289 Wadsworth. Texas 7748] </P><P>----------------------~~ </P><P>July 19, 2010 NOC-AE-1 0002574 File No.: G25 10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attention: Document Control Desk One White Flint North 11555 Rockville Pike Rockville, MD 20852-2738 </P><P>South Texas Project 
Unit 2 
Docket No. STN 50-499 
Licensee Event Report 2-2010-003: Containment Purge in Operation 
When Not Permitted By Technical Specifications 
</P><P>Pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73, the STP Nuclear Operating Company (STPNOC) submits the attached Unit 2 Licensee Event Report (LER) 2-2010-003 to address an incident in which supplemental containment purge was initiated contrary to Technical Specification requirements. This condition is considered reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) as a condition not allowed by Technical Specifications. </P><P>This event did not have an adverse effect on the health and safety of the public. </P><P>There are no commitments contained in this LER. The STP Corrective Action Program controls processing of corrective actions. </P><P>If there are any questions on this submittal, please contact either P. L. Walker at (361) 972-8392 or me at (361) 972-7158. ' </P><P>L. W. Peter Plant General Manager </P><Table><TR><TH>PLW </TH></TR><TR><TH>Attachment: </TH><TD>LER 2-2010-003: </TD><TD>Containment </TD><TD>Purge </TD><TD>in </TD><TD>Operation </TD><TD>When </TD><TD>Not </TD><TD>Permitted </TD><TD>By </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>Technical Specifications </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR></Table><P>STI: 32703369 
</P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>cc: (paper copy) </P><P>Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 612 East Lamar Blvd., Suite 400 Arlington, Texas 76011-8064 </P><P>Mohan C. Thadani Senior Project Manager </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
One White Flint North (MS 8B 1 A) 
11555 Rockville Pike, 
Rockville, MD 20852 
</P><P>Senior Resident Inspector </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><P>P. O. Box 289, Mail Code: MN116 Wadsworth, TX 77483 </P><P>C. M. Canady City of Austin Electric Utility Department 721 Barton Springs Road Austin, TX 78704 </P><P>NOC-AE-1 0002574 Page 2 of2 </P><P>(electronic copy) </P><P>John Ragan Catherine Callaway Jim von Suskil NRG South Texas LP </P><P>A. H. Gutterman, Esquire Morgan, Lewis &amp; Bockius LLP </P><P>Mohan Thadani </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><P>Kevin Polio Richard Pena </P><P>E. Alarcon City Public Service </P><P>C. Mele City of Austin </P><P>Jon C. Wood Cox Smith Matthews </P><P>Richard A. Ratliff Texas Department of Health Services </P><P>Alice Rogers Texas Department of Health Services </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (9-2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150·0104 EXPIRES: 08/31/2010 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Records and FOIAIPrivacy Service Branch (f-5 F52), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocollects@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an infonnation collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the infonnation collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME South Texas Unit 2 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13. PAGE 05000499 1 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Containment Pur 1e in Ooeration When Not Permitted bv Technical Soecifications </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6_ LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME N/A </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER N/A </TD></TR><TR><TH>05 </TH><TD>22 </TD><TD>10 </TD><TD>2010 -003 -</TD><TD>0 </TD><TD>07 </TD><TD>19 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME N/A </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER N/A </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR§: (Check aI/ that apply) o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 0 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) x 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) speci,7oi~ ~~stra;!~eIOW </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100% </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>NAME ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) Philip L. Walker, Staff Licensing Engineer 361-972-8392 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>NA </TH><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (Ifyes, complete 1S. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) xNO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>A8STRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 1S single-spaced typewritten lines) On May 22, 2010, the Unit 2 Supplemental Containment Purge Subsystem was used to reduce containment pressure. This is a routine operation used to maintain containment pressure consis(ent with Technical Specification requirements. A surveillance test was in progress that required one of the two Solid State Protection System (SSPS) containment isolation automatic actuation logic channels be taken out of service. With one logic channel out of service, containment purge valves are required to be kept closed. Required actions for an inoperable ESFAS instrumentation channel or interlock are shown in Technical Specification Table 3.3-3. With fewer than the minimum of two automatic actuation logic channels operable, operation may continue only if the containment purge supply and exhaust valves are maintained closed. Opening the containment purge valves when only one SSPS train is operable is not permitted under Technical Specifications. This condition is considered reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) as a condition not allowed by the Technical SpeCifications. Initiation of supplementary containment purge with an inoperable SSPS train/channel resulted from inadequate personnel communications and a deficient procedure. Conduct of Operations requirements will be revised to ensure adequate communications and assignment of responsibilities, and procedures will be revised to enhance control over containment purge initiation. There were no personnel injuries, no offsite radiological releases, and no damage to other safety-related equipment. Because containment purge valves could still be closed on a signal from the operable logic channel, this is not a safety system functional failure. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (9-2007) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (1-2001) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>South Texas Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000499 </TD><TD>YEAR I · SEQUENTIAL 1 REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>2 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) I. DESCRIPTION OF EVENT A. REPORTABLE EVENT CLASSIFICATION This event is reportable pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). As required by Action 18-a of Technical Specification Table 3.3-3, when a Solid State Protection System 'channel is inoperable, plant operation can continue only if the containment purge supply and exhaust valves are maintained closed. However, STP Unit 2 initiated containment purge while a channel was inoperable. Consequently, STP Unit 2 was in a condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. B. PLANT OPERATING CONDITIONS PRIOR TO EVENT STP Unit 2 was in Mode 1 at 100% power. C. STATUS OF STRUCTURES, SYSTEMS, AND COMPONENTS THAT WERE INOPERABLE AT THE START OF THE EVENT AND THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE EVENT No other structures, systems, or components were inoperable at the start of the event and contributed to the event. D. NARRATIVE SUMMARY OF THE EVENT On May 22, 2010, preparations were made to perform a surveillance test of the Unit 2 Solid State Protection System (SSPS) Logic Train R. This procedure verifies the Logic Train R SSPS Automatic Trip and Automatic Actuation Logic output functions by simulating input combinations in conjunction with each possible interlock. Placing Logic Train R in test mode prevents it from automatically actuating various features. At 1517 hours, the SSPS Input Error Inhibit Switch was placed in the &quot;inhibit&quot; position in accordance with the surveillance test procedure. An inoperable logic train requires entry in several actions as described in Technical Specification Table 3.3-3, including a requirement that containment purge valves be closed. At approximately 1540 hours, a reactor operator observed an indicator showing reactor containment pressure was near its alarm setpoint. At 1542 hours, the reactor operator initiated supplemental purge of reactor containment for pressure control. The primary reactor operator was informed of the purge activity and noted it in the Unit 2 Control Room logbook. At 1554 hours, containment pressure had been satisfactorily regulated and supplementary purge was secured. The primary reactor operator was informed of the conclusion of purge activity and noted it in the Unit 2 Control Room logbook. Logic Train R was restored at 1601 hours. During the shift change at approximately 1800 hours, the oncoming Shift Manager reviewed the Control Room logbook and recognized the period of concurrent supplementary purge operation and logic train test mode condition as being a violation of Technical Specification requirements. Note that the Train S actuation of purge valve closure was still available during the surveillance. There were no failures that would have prevented Train S from closing the purge valves. Therefore, this is not a safety system functional failure. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (1·2001) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>South Texas Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000499 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>3 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) E. METHOD OF DISCOVERY The violation of Technical Specification requirements was discovered when the control room logbook was reviewed during shift turnover. II. EVENT-DRIVEN INFORMATION A. SAFETY SYSTEMS THAT RESPONDED No safety systems were required to respond during this event. B. DURATION OF SAFETY SYSTEM INOPERABILITY The SSPS Input Error Inhibit Switch was placed to the &quot;Inhibit&quot; position per Surveillance Test OPSP03-SP-0005R at 1517 hours. Containment purge using the supplementary purge system was begun at 1542 hours. Supplementary purge was stopped at 1554 hours. The period of noncompliance with Technical Specification requirements was 12 minutes. C. SAFETY CONSEQUENCES AND IMPLICATIONS OF THE EVENT Technical Specification Requirements: As noted in TS 3.3.2 Action c, with an ESFAS instrumentation channel or interlock inoperable, required actions are shown in Table 3.3-3. As required by Action 18-a of Technical Specification Table 3.3-3, when a containment isolation automatic actuation logic channel is inoperable, plant operation may continue only if the containment purge supply and exhaust valves are maintained closed. Two operable channels is the minimum required to allow containment purge valves to be open; one channel was made inoperable during the surveillance test. Therefore, opening the valves while only SSPS Train S is operable is not permitted under Technical Specifications. If only one train of Containment Purge Radioactivity-High is operable, the inoperable train is to be restored within 30 days. During the 30 days, if in Mode 1, 2, 3, or 4, supplementary purge valves may be open during the allowed outage time for up to two hours at a time for purge operation. However, with the entire logic train inoperable, this allowed outage time is not available. Design Description: Supplementary Containment Purge Subsystem The Supplementary Containment Purge Subsystem provides the capability to reduce gaseous and particulate contamination of the containment atmosphere to enable safe, continuous personnel access under operating conditions. Containment penetrations for this subsystem are 18 inches in diameter. The Supplementary Containment Purge isolation valves are primarily opened as needed in response to changes in containment air pressure. There are two isolation valves included in the Supplementary Containment Purge supply subsystem, and two on the Supplementary Purge exhaust subsystem. For each subsystem, one motor-operated isolation valve is inside containment and one air-operated isolation valve is outside containment. The motor-operated valves fail as-is on loss of power, and the airoperated valves fail closed on loss of air pressure. Each is a butterfly valve with resilient seals. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (1-2001) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>South Texas Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000499 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>4 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) Interlocks are provided to automatically close the valves upon Containment ventilation isolation signal. In the event of a LOCA or other Design Basis Accident (DBA) while the Supplementary Containment Purge Subsystem is in operation, containment isolation occurs such that resultant offsite doses are kept within the limits prescribed by 10CFR100. Containment pressure is monitored and conditions approaching the limits allowed by the Technical Specifications are annunciated. Containment pressure is controlled by periodic operation of the supplementary purge system. Solid State Protection System The Reactor Trip System includes. two redundant logic trains, Rand S, each of which can initiate a reactor trip. The purpose of ESFAS actuation logic and relays is to initiate the integrated system response that accomplishes the design safety function of the applicable engineered safety feature (ESF). Technical Specification Table 3.3-3 Action 18-a applies when the actuation logic for RCB Purge Radioactivity -High is inoperable because it affects both channels. The required action is to maintain the isolation valves closed. Loss of power supply to the output ESF relays of either channel of these monitors will be considered inoperable actuation logic and the isolation valves are to be maintained closed in accordance with Action 18-a. This is because this failure mode will result in the inability of the other actuation signals to close the purge valves if the initial signal is reset. Extent of Condition: Other surveillance procedures have been identified that require entry into Action 18. These procedures include requirements that containment purge not be allowed during performance of the surveillance. Risk Assessment: This condition did not contribute to core damage risk and contributed very little to large early release risk. The insignificant large early release probability is principally due to the exposure time of 12 minutes, or approximately 6 x 10-4 year. A formal assessment was not performed but the STP annual core damage frequency is less than 1 x 10-5 per year. Even with the very conservative assumption that all core damage progresses to a large early release, the incremental Large. Early Release Probability is less than 6 x 10-9 . Therefore, this event had very low safety significance. III. CAUSE OF THE EVENT A. The root cause of this event was inadequate communications between Control Room staff members: • The crew supervisor noted in the log book early in the shift that SSPS surveillance tests would be performed later in the shift. The log entry stated the applicability of Technical Specification Table 3.3-3 Action 18, and the requirement to maintain the containment purge valves closed. The operations crew was not informed by their supervisor that a surveillance procedure would be in progress that prohibited containment purge by Technical Specification requirements. • Containment pressure may vary during the course of normal plant operations. The primary </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (1-2001) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER I </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>South Texas Unit 2 </TH><TD>05000499 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL REVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>5 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2010 003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE (If more space is required, use additional copies of NRC Form 366A) (17) reactor operator observed that pressure indication showed the need to relieve pressure through actuation of the Supplementary Containment Purge Subsystem. Purge was initiated without informing crew supervision. The log was updated to note initiation of containment purge, but the entry for beginning the surveillance procedure was not read. B. In addition, the surveillance procedure does not include a prohibition against performing a supplemental containment purge with the logic train out of service for testing. IV. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS A. Remedial Actions: No remedial actions are required. B. Compensatory Actions: Control room staff is briefed when the unit enters a Technical Specification Limiting Condition of Operation. C. Recurrence Control: Control room staff communications will be enhanced by the following changes: • Revise Conduct of Operations to define control room crew standards for communications regarding Technical Specification requirements. • Revise Conduct of Operations to establish expectations and standards for making and updating logbook entries. • Revise supplementary containment purge procedure to specify notification of control room staff supervision before initiating containment purge. In addition, the supplemental containment purge procedure will be revised to prohibit purging containment atmosphere when a logic train is out of service. These actions are expected to be completed by September 21, 2010. V. PREVIOUS SIMILAR EVENTS Control room logs were reviewed for instances of containment building purges while surveillance procedures that place restrictions on containment purge activities were in progress. No similar violations of Technical Specification Table 3.3-3 Action 18 were found. VI. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION Investigation did not identify an organizational weakness or adverse condition beyond the circumstances of this event. </TH></TR></Table></TaggedPDF-doc>