<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-07-10T11:19:30-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-07-10T11:19:30-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-07-10T11:19:30-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>South TeJcas Project Electric Generating Station P.D. Box 28fJ l-!/adsll'orth, TeJcas 7748] </P><P>----------------------~ </P><P>June 25, 2014 NOC-AE-14003151 10 CFR 50.73 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attention: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>South Texas Project 
Unit 1 
Docket No. STN 50-498 
Cancellation of Licensee Event Report (LER) 2014-001-00 and Supplement LER 2014-001-01: 
Overpower Condition Relating to the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System 
</P><P>Reference: 1) 	Letter from G.T. Powell, STPNOC, to NRC Document Control Desk, &quot;Licensee Event Report LER 2014-001-00, LER 2014-001-00: South Texas Project (STP) Unit 1 Overpower Condition Relating to the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System,&quot; dated March 24, 2014 (NOC-AE-14003113) (ML 14119A068) </P><P>2) 	Letter from G.T. Powell, STPNOC, to NRC Document Control Desk, &quot;Licensee Event Report LER 2014-001-01: Overpower Condition Relating to the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System,&quot; dated April 30, 2014 (NOC-AE-14003128) (ML 14135A190) </P><P>The purpose of the letter is to formally notify the Nuclear Regulatory Commission of the cancellation of STP Nuclear Operating Company (STPNOC) Licensee Event Report (LER) 2014-001-00, &quot;South Texas Project (STP) Unit 1 Overpower Condition Relating to the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System,&quot; and related supplement LER 2014-001-01, Reference 1 and 2 respectively. </P><P>On March 24, 2014, STPNOC submitted LER 2014-001-00 pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8), as a Condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. This LER documented an apparent overpower event that occurred in STP Unit 1 as a result of inside diameter changes in feedwater piping related to possible pipe wall erosion which affected the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System. The feedwater inside diameter is a direct input into the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System software &quot;CROSS FLOW&quot;. </P><P>Subsequent to the submittal of the LER, two independent evaluations were performed using two different approaches based on plant data using detailed plant modeling. STPNOC has reviewed and accepted the conclusions of these reports (Case Study 1 and Case Study 2). The evaluations determined that both STP Unit 1 and Unit 2 were operating below the Technical Specification allowable operating limits. No Technical Specifications violations occurred related to this event. </P><P>..J-l:::'0'-,/,) !l.. </P><P>STI: 33891754 ~Jel</P><P>NOC-AE-14003151 Page 2 of 4 </P><P>Case Study 1 </P><P>This study states that the pipe wall erosion occurred gradually over a period of time, it considered the effects of relevant plant changes within the study period, and used several data analysis methods to evaluate the condition (Le. electrical production, indirect thermal power changes, and key plant parameters of flow through the turbine cycle). </P><P>The study concluded that the error in the flow measurement caused by the erosion was compensated for by other likely flow phenomena, resulting in a change in the flow velocity profile due to a change in the turbulent flow hydraulic characteristics affected by pipe roughness. </P><P>The study further concluded that prior to correcting the input parameter for the internal diameter of the feedwater pipe for STP Unit 1, the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System software CROSS FLOW was within its rated accuracy and STP Unit 1 operated within thermal power limits. The study quantified that the current actual power level (subsequent to correcting the input parameter for internal feedwater pipe diameter) is approximately 1 % conservative and below the licensed core thermal power operating limit. </P><P>Case Study 2 </P><P>This second study used EnergiTools thermal performance software to determine if the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System was performing to the rated accuracy. The accuracy of the EnergiTools Data Qualification method for this study is.:t 0.5% or better, with a 95% confidence level. </P><P>The study concluded that prior to correcting the input parameter for the internal diameter of the feedwater pipe, the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System was within its rated accuracy and STP Unit 1 operated within thermal power limits.. Subsequent to this event, the Ultrasonic Flow Measurement software CROSS FLOW has been corrected to include the change in the inside feedwater pipe diameter. Following implementation of this change, the EnergiTools Data Qualification results indicate that the current Ultrasonic Flow Measurement System measurements have shifted in a conservative direction by 1.3%. </P><P>Conclusion </P><P>The as-found data reported in LER 2014-001-00 and related supplement LER 2014-001-01 resulted in the initial conclusion that Unit 1 was overpowered by approximately 1.8%. The subsequent studies described above provide reasonable assurance that STP Unit 1 did not exceed the Trip Setpoint Total Allowable value for the Power Range Nuclear Instruments (PRNI) High Trip specified in the Technical Specifications. The results of the studies indicate that the total power calorimetric uncertainty with CROSSFLOW in-service remained within the STP instrument uncertainty of 0.6%. Based on this new information, the initial reportable condition pursuant to 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), as a Condition prohibited by Technical Specifications is being retracted. </P><P>NOC-AE-14003151 Page 3 of 4 </P><P>This event did not have an adverse effect on the health and safety of the public. </P><P>There are no commitments in this letter. Corrective actions will be implemented in accordance with the STP Corrective Action Program. </P><P>If there are any questions, please contact Rafael Gonzales at (361) 972-4779, or me at (361) 9727566. </P><P>G. T. Powell Site Vice President </P><P>RJG cc: (paper copy) </P><P>Regional Administrator, Region IV </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 1600 East Lamar Boulevard Arlington, TX 76011-4511 </P><P>Balwant K. Singal Senior Project Manager </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission One White Flint North (MS 8 B1) 11555 Rockville Pike Rockville, MD 20852 </P><P>NRC Resident Inspector </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><P>P. O. Box 289, Mail Code: MN116 Wadsworth, TX 77483 </P><P>NOC-AE-14003151 Page 4 of 4 </P><P>(electronic copy) </P><P>A. H. Gutterman, Esquire Morgan, Lewis &amp; Bockius LLP </P><P>Balwant K. Singal. </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission </P><P>John Ragan Chris O'Hara Jim von Suskil NRG South Texas LP </P><P>Kevin Polio Cris Eugster </P><P>L. D. Blaylock City Public Service </P><P>Peter Nemeth 
Crain Caton &amp; James, P.C. 
</P><P>C. Mele John Wester City of Austin </P><P>Richard A. Ratliff Robert Free Texas Department of State Health Services· </P></TaggedPDF-doc>