<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-06-05T09:28:15-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-06-05T09:28:15-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-06-05T09:28:15-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>Attachment 9 to GNRO-2012/00039 </P><P>Attachment 9 to </P><P>GNRO-2012100039 </P><P>Entergy Nuclear Grand Gulf Nuclear Station License Renewal Environmental Audit -Hydrology Patton -Attachment L labeled &quot;Reporting Documentation -Unit 2 Sumps&quot; . </P><P>Attachment L </P><P>Reporting Documentation -Unit 2 Sumps </P><P>GRAND GULF NUCLEAR STATION ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE </P><Table><TR><TD>01-S-06-5 </TD><TD>Revision: </TD><TD>108 </TD></TR><TR><TD>Attachment II </TD><TD>Page 1 of </TD><TD>2 </TD></TR></Table><P>PAGe 1 OFl </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12157A182_img_0.jpg"/>NRCFOfW.' U.s. NUCIZAA RI!OULATORY COMMISSION fl Z•2OOCI, REACTOR PLANT OPaAT1ONI CDT1!Jl EVENT NOTIFICATION WORKSHEET EN_4b&lt;60Z-NRC a&gt;eRATION TS.EPHONE NUMBER: PRIMARY 301-316-5100 Of' 800-532·3of88&quot;. BACKUPS (1stl301·951-O!iI5O Of' 8(1).449031194.. .urre-. 112nci1301~1~ and !3nI1301~15.Q553 'U__whomalntaln tn.r ~ErS ... DI' MdecI ~IeI-&quot;&quot;.n NO'IR:A11CN TM!I FI'O.SfY OR ORGIHlATQt I~I I~c.~ CALLBAOC. IZl7Z.£771' c...,..,,-, Go.. ,,, ~~~r ,::-,.... k&quot; c..J e-. Vee~I-'131-2..37 '1S~.4-0a., IM!M TN! AlDIe I!\i9fI'DIII.... I'OI\tIIAoalI! !!If'tRI F'OY'oERMXJIN'TBt ofrQ CoOt-&quot; ~/'Z.1/&quot; q~ &quot;l. I MOl)&quot; I qt./! / NtoDG&quot; I EVENT CLASSlFlCAnONS 1·Hr. Non-EmeraWlCY 10 CFR 50.72(b)(11 (yl(A, _SlD~ -G98W.a.ER;ENCY ~ I TS~ !Del (vHII RH\~ -SIT'I! MIAIJoEJIGBCY SIT/N£ ~Hr. No.w:mMlenc:v 10 CP'R !IO.7llll.ll~l (vIlCl CorhI of RaII_ I&gt;H:. H.IRT IUJNI!C (I' TS~SID AIHI (vIlo) -,.,...,.. HIC) I.NJIII.IAL Ir\8fI' I.HJM8C (lvllA' ec:cs~&quot;RC8 AClCS (JeI) ~Mo_ 1M!) ~ SL12~ (-_.........., Ilw)(111 RPS_I~ .'llIlIt L.;I(ltN ~SIClIJAfTV (7171) a:aI IX (iii) 0 __ -80-0.&quot; ODtlon8I 10 CFR 50.731.111 MA~ 8'm SoHr. No ' to CFR 5Ct..72lb1l31 I J_S -#HI ~_wrv tAl' 1(Il)(10) c.w-~ .IQIO Other Un,peclfled RequIrement IIdenllfYl OIKIt~REDofI'. 1---' 1(11)(8) ~~ .ou. I ICNI ~T1ONON.Y -1v)(A' ~av---I ICNIDESCRIPTION _ ~_IId,___inihllng&quot;&quot;-'_&quot;''''''oI_... p___OI''''''''''''.'''' rc--&quot;'-J On 4128/2011 GGNS Unit 2 turbine building sump samples indicated tritium presence. The Unit 2 turbine building is an abandoned, partially constmcted building. Follow·up review and investigation confirmed that water from unit 2 turbine building sump had been pumped to the environment through installed sump pumps and piping connected between the sumps and roof drains on the unit 2 turbine building. The release has been terminated by turning off the sump pumps located in the unit 2 turbine building. Site procedures require notification of off-site agencies, therefore the NRC is being notified in accordance with IOCFR50.72 (b )(2)(xi). , ~ICATIONS VB NO WIU. 811 AHYnflNQ UNUSUAL OR £R YES (Expl'&quot; ~ oNONRC RQIDI!NT ~ NOT UNOeRSTOOD1' STARW )C DID AU. SYSTI!MI i&amp;vES o NO (ElIfIID'I .....)LOCAL )( FUNCTION .... IU!QU1ND7 &lt;mI!Jl GOY I\GIINCaS )(. uooe C7 OPE....no.. \ IEST'....rED toJjA 1AIXJT1CiI'UIC. NfOON IIjOQ( !o8JIAIPREU RII!I.v.aa &gt;&lt;.. ...nLCO~D&quot; RUTART OAre: 0-.. ..aND </Figure><P>HIOC'~.' ('2-2OGGI .....NT!DOOf ..~P_ </P><P>J:ACM SRVS\-rECH PU8\REVrSION\1\1S065.DOC </P><P>GRAND GULF NUCLEAR STATION ADMINISTRATIVE PROCEDURE 
</P><Table><TR><TD>01-S-06-5 </TD><TD>Revision: lOa </TD></TR><TR><TD>Attachment II </TD><TD>Page 2 of 2 </TD></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12157A182_img_1.jpg"/>• ;HICK 011 PL .. !.,....,-lllltClllld e._In.-, 1\ LIQUID RQ.£ASa lGASEOUS REl..EASI! UNPlANNED RS.EASI! ~RB.eASI! I OHGOIHO I J'rERMINATED prCI'IED IUN.IONTORED OFFSITE RS.EASE T. S. exCEBlED 1 RMALAAMS I ~evN:IJATED EXPOSeD OR CONTIIMINATED OFFSlle PROTECTl\IE ACT~RECOMNENOSl ___..... Irt-..... \. Re..... &quot;&quot;'-(CtI.-) &quot;T. S.UMT HOO~ TCUI ActIvtIy (CI) 'IIoT.S.UWT HOOGUIDII NoIIIeO. O.lCV.ea l008CI 10dI.. \. lOuCUMC 0.01 CI P.........~ lllCVaec ImCI ~~.:-&quot; 10 uClllIIID G.1C1 LIquId ~&quot;&quot;'I \. CUC\fmla 'CI TCICIIIAdNfty '\. \. PlJoIfT SfACIC CONDINaBIAIR I!JI!CTOII MAIN ST1!AM U&quot; SGBLOWOOWN ana RAD MONITCA MADNJa\. A&amp;.AIUI SI!TPaNTa \ &quot; T. S. LM1' (It1PfIIIc.&quot;, 1,\ RCa 0lIl sa TU8I! I.I!AK8: CHECK ~FU.INAPI'LICABLI! I1DIII: f-* shouldbe CDYWWd Itt ftWIIf lDCAnDN&quot; TI«! lENC (..... sa'._ ,.., , 1BoK1lA11I UNTa~ T.S.lMI'8 5UlDltIDlLaG_~ LIM STAR!' DA11I -\ CQOUIIIT AI:TMTY -SII:I:HlMY NIIJ'-LIST C6 wwrvMIATID ECIJR&amp;II' PC)'!' 0PEfIA1ICNIL \ 1\1 -,,--</Figure><P>J:ADM_SRVS\TECH_PUB\REVISION\1\LS065.00C 
</P><P>§ 50.72(b)(2)(xi) &quot;Any event or situation, related to the health and safety of the public or on-site personnel, or protection of the environment, for which a news release is planned or notification to other government agencies has been otWlli be,;maqet Such an event may include an on-site fatality or inadvertent release of radioactively contaminated materials. &quot; </P><Part><H4>Provide the following information to the NRC: </H4><P>o 	Estimate when the leak/spill started? (Give range of dates, or is it unknown?) </P><L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Unknown </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Date and time sample(s) confirmed a leak or spill (or discovery of contamination). </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>4/29/11, 08:52 confirmation of a path to storm drains. Sample was collected and confirmed on 4/28/11 18:45 </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Is the leak/spill/source known? </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Water sample was from U2 (unfinished construction, non-functioning unit) Turbine Bid Sump. This location is inside the Protected Area. Source unknown. </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Is this an on-going leak or has the leak source been terminated? </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Leak was terminated on 4/28/11, prior to confirming water flow path to storm drain. </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Radionuclide concentrations in spill/leak source or origin of the contamination. </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Origin is the U2 Turbine Bid Sumps, 87' elevation. 106,400 pCi/L Tritium in East sump, 100,259 pCi/L Tritium in West sump </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Estimated leak rate? </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Unknown, temporary pump was in auto. </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Has any radioactive material from this spill/leak/event reached the unrestricted area? </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>These sumps pump to storm drains, which flOw to Outfall 007 which is sampled monthly. There have been no Outfall 007 sample results that have met reportability thresholds in the last 2 years. </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	What is the estimated volume of plume and curie content of plume? </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>N/A, this was a liquid flow path </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Radionuclide concentrations in environmental soil and water samples. </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Outfall 007 Sample results December 16, 2010: 723 pCi/L Tritium (error: +/-186.09 pCi/L Tritium) </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Does the spill/leak affect ground water, drinking water, or surface water? (Address each one). </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Currently there is no spill/leak so there is no effect on ground water, drinking water, or surface water </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Could the spill/leak affect ground water, drinking water, or surface water or is the spill/leak likely to affect ground water, drinking water, or surface water? </LI></L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Outfall 007 discharges to the Mississippi River so ground water and drinking water could potentially be affected. Surface water will not be affected. </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Are there monitoring wells down gradient? Activity in down gradient wells? </LI></L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Yes there are monitoring wells down gradient. They have tested positive for Tritium but results were below reportable levels. This information is being gathered. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>o 	List the distance from the spill/leak to the site boundary/unrestricted area (1) in direction of travel, and (2) nearest boundary. </P><P>Approximately 700 m (2) to nearest boundary, the direction of travel (1) is further. </P><P>o 	What is the rate of groundwater movement in the area (e.g., meters per year)? </P><L><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>This information is being gathered. </LI_Title></LI><LI>o 	Estimate of when contaminants will reach the site boundary/unrestricted area. </LI></L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>The leak/spilll1as been terminated, so this would have potentially 
happened in the past. 
</LI_Title></LI></L><P>o 	Estimated contaminant concentrations at time when contaminants reach the site boundary. At very least, provide (bounding) estimate of future contaminant concentrations at site boundary relative to 10 CFR 50 Appendix I design objectives. </P><P>Highest result for a groundwater monitoring well sample was 11,600 pC ill on March 2, 2011. </P><P>o 	Are the radionuclide concentrations expected to be below the 10 CFR 20 Appendix B, Table 2 values once the plume reaches the unrestricted area? </P><P>This information is being gathered but there have been no results above 
reportable limits. 
</P><P>o 	What is the calculated dose to a hypothetical member of the public at the source of the leak/spill if the affected water (ground, drinking, or surface) was a drinking water source. (Calculate this value even if the affected water is not a source of drinking water.) Use any valid method or use a conservatively bounding estimate (e.g., for tritium use the proportionality that 4 mrem annual is equivalent to 20,000 pCill annual average concentration.) </P><P>Unknown at this time. Based on the last sample of Outfall 007, the calculated dose would be 0.144mrem annual equivalent. </P><P>o 	What is the calculated dose to a hypothetical member of the public at the site boundary if the affected water (ground, drinking, or surface) at the site boundary was a drinking water source. (Calculate this value even if the affected water is not a source of drinking water.) Use any valid method or use a conservatively bounding estimate (e.g., for tritium use the proportionality that 4 mrem annual is equivalent to 20,000 pCi/1 annual average concentration.) </P><P>Unknown at this time. </P><P>o 	Does the utility plan any remediation or cleanup activities at the current time? </P><P>Information is being gathered and a decision will be made. </P><P>Notifications made for H3.txt </P><P>From: perino, christina </P><P>Sent: Friday, April 29, 2011 4:08 PM </P><P>To: RICHEY, MARTY L; perito, Michael; BROWNING, JEREMY G </P><P>Cc: SCARBROUGH, RICHARD A; TRICHELL, WILLIAM T; EHRHARDT, KARL F; Ford,</P><P>BryanSubject: Notifications made for H3 </P><P>Contacts made for NEI 07-07 industry ground water protection initiative, via </P><P>EN-RP-1l3 Jimmy carson at Mississippi State Dept of Radiological Health Jimmy crellin at MDEQ was not interested in the notification. He stated they did </P><P>not deal in radiology and said MS State Dept of Rad Health was the right</P><P>notification to make. He took my contact info and called me back. said he didn't </P><P>find anyone interested but we could send an email to the head of pollution control. </P><P>I will follow up with him. Gary uricchio at ANI NEI email address per EN-RP-113: GW_Notice@NEI.org NRC 4 hour notification All required notifications made within requirements christina </P><P>Sent from my ipad </P><P>page 1 </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>