<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-10-03T08:15:03-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-10-03T08:12:07-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-10-03T08:15:03-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool>Adobe Acrobat 8.1</xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:f70fd6e1-a2e7-487a-8a50-c57b200c6f1c</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:afda5c5d-64bf-9b46-9ab9-b5823ff69045</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13276A480_img_0.jpg"/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13276A480_img_1.jpg"/>3 </Figure><P>SUBJECT: 	Licensee Event Report 2013-004-00 Operation prohibited Technical Specifications due to inadvertent bypass of Reactor Steam Dome High Pressure Interlock for Residual Heat Removal System isolation Grand Gulf Nuclear Station, Unit 1 Docket No. 50-416 License No. NPF-29 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Attached is Licensee Event Report 2013-004-00, which is a final report. This report is submitted in accordance with Title 10 Code ofFederal Regulations 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B). </P><P>This letter contains no new commitments. If you have any questions or require additional information, please contact Mr. Christopher R. Robinson at (601) 437-7326. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13276A480_img_2.jpg"/></Figure><P>MLRljas Attachment: Licensee Event Report (LER) 2013-004-00 </P><P>cc: (see next page) cc: </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory ATTN: Mr. Alan NRRlDORL Mail Stop OWFN/8 Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector Grand Gulf Nuclear Station Port Gibson, MS 39150 </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION APPROVED BY </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) 
</P><Figure><ImageData src=""/>rli{]it~/'r.h==irair.te~ for each </Figure><P>number of </P><P>2. DOCKET NUMBER 3. PAGE </P><P>1 	05000416 10F3 </P><P>Technical Specifications due to inadvertent bypass of Reactor Steam Dome High Interlock for Residual Heat Removal System isolation. </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13276A480_img_8.jpg"/>5. EVENT DATE 6. LER NUMBER 7. REPORT DATE 8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED NAME N/ADAYMONTH SEQUENTIAL REV NUMBER NO. MONTH YEARDAY YEAR YEAR 08 06 2013 2013-004-00 10 3 2013 N/A 9. OPERATING MODE 11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </Figure><P>20.2201 (b) 20.2203(a)(3)(i) 5O.73(a)(2)(i)(C) 0 5O.73(a)(2}(vii) 1 o 20.2201 (d) 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) 20.2203(a)(1) 20.2203(a)(4) 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) </P><P>1----------1 D20.2203(a)(2)(i) D50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) D50.73(a)(2)(iii) 50. 73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </P><P>10. POWER LEVEL 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) 0 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) 50. 73(a)(2)(iv}(A) o 50.73(a)(2}(x) 
20.2203(a){2)(iii) 50.36(c)(2) 0 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) 
</P><P>93.5 	20.2203(a)(2)(iv) 50.46(a)(3)(ii) 73.71 (a)(5) 20.2203(a)(2)(v) 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) OTHER </P><P>o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(0) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </P><P>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </P><P>FACILITY NAME 	TELEPHONE NUMBER </P><P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>Code) </P><P>Christopher R. Robinson I Manager, Licensing 	(601) 437-7326 </P><P>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </P><Table><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TH>SYSTEM </TH><TH>COMPONENT </TH><TH>MANUFACTURER </TH><TH>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TH><TH>CAUSE </TH><TH>SYSTEM </TH><TH>COMPONENT </TH><TH>MANU-FACTURER </TH><TH>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TH></TR><TR><TD>D </TD><TD>JE </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD><TD>N/A </TD></TR><TR><TD>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED o YES (Ifyes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) ~NO </TD><TD/><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH N/A </TD><TD>DAY N/A </TD><TD>YEAR N/A </TD></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src=""/>actions were exited. </Figure><P>ABSTRACT (Umit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </P><P>On August 6, 2013, at 10:15 Central Daylight Time (CDT) with the unit in Mode 1 at 93.5 percent thermal power, Grand Gulf Nuciear Station (GGNS) discovered that it was not in compliance with Technical Specification (TS) 3.3.6.1, Primary Containment and Drywellisolation Instrumentation. Function 5.c, Reactor Steam Dome High Pressure Isolation of the Residual Heat Removal (RHR) system, was inoperable due to the jumpers that disable the function not being removed prior to startup. Upon discovery GGNS entered TS 3.3.6.1 Limiting Condition of Operation (LCO) Actions A.1, B.1, C.1, F.1 and H.1. Also, TS LCO 3.0.4 was not satisfied. At 11.11 CDT the </P><P>were removed the reactor steam dome high pressure isolation function and the LCO </P><P>The cause of the event was a lack of Integrated Operating Instruction (101) 03-1-01-3, Cold Shutdown to Generator :~rf-Hln,l&quot;l Minimum Load, to include the requirements of EN-DC-136, Temporary Modifications, for adequate prClcecClUral <Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>control of modifications. Additionally, a failure of the Shift Manager (SM) to initiate a potential 'nn,riitir&quot;\n for Record (LCOTR) as Control of Conditions for Operation was identified as a contributing cause. </P><P>The event no threat to <Figure><ImageData src=""/>nrO'\lI(1E==!(1 only for the interlock is not assumed in the sections of the UD(jatE~d </Figure>health and to an intersystem loss of coolant accident </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>accident transient </P><P>NRC FORM 366 (10-2010) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><Part><H4>LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </H4><P>2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER </P><P>3. PAGE </P><P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>2 3</P><P>1 </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13276A480_img_15.jpg"/>1. FACILITY NAME </Figure><P>NARRATIVE REPORTABLE OCCURRENCE </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/>This Licensee Event 1J&quot;&quot;''\I''\r+ or condition which was nrnhini,tori </Figure><P>RINITIAL </P><P>At the time of the event the reactor was in Mode 1 with reactor power at 93.5 nOf&quot;t&quot;Olnt' There were no </P><P>uvI.UI':;;'::'. </P><P>systems, or that contributed to this event </P><P>C. DESCRIPTION OF OCCURRENCE </P><P>On August 3, 2013, at 03:04 Central Daylight Time (COT) Grand Gulf Nuclear Station (GGNS) entered Mode 2 (Startup) from Mode 4 (Cold Shutdown). Subsequently, GGNS entered Mode 1 on August 4, 2013, at 05:31. On August 6,2013, at 10:15 with the unit in Mode 1 at 93.5 percent thermal power, during a supervisory review of procedures in progress, GGNS discovered that it was not in compliance with Technical Specification (TS) 3.3.6.1, Primary Containment and Drywellisolation Instrumentation, (EIIS:JE) due to the jumpers that disable the function not being removed prior to startup. Upon discovery, GGNS entered TS 3.3.6.1 Limiting Condition for Operation (LCO) Actions A.1, B.1, C.1, F.1 and H.1. Also, TS LCO 3.0.4 was not satisfied. This condition existed until 11: 11 COT on August 6, 2013, when the jumpers were removed. </P><P>D. CAUSE </P><P>The cause of the event was a lack of Integrated Operating Instruction (101) 03-1-01-3, Cold Shutdown to Generator Carrying Minimum Load, to include the requirements of EN-DC-136, Temporary Modifications, for adequate procedural control of temporary modifications. Additionally, a failure of the Shift Manager (SM) to initiate a potential TS Limiting Condition for Operation Tracking Record (LCOTR) as required by procedure 02-S-01-17, Control of Limiting Conditions for Operation was identified as a contributing cause. </P><P>E. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>To correct the condition that caused this the were removed restoring the function to an Operable status. A prompt investigation of the issue was performed. A review of 101 03-1-01-3 and 031-01-4, Scram Recovery, was performed. The review included a walkdown of procedurally referenced jumper locations which verified no other configuration control issues existed due to steps not completed. 10103-1-01-1 was revised to require verification that the affected jumpers were removed prior to entering Mode 2 and that all applicable 101 03-1-01-3 steps were completed prior to entering Mode 2. GGNS expectations on the requirements of EN-OP-115, Log Keeping, were revised to provide clarity of the requirements. An action to review all lOis to ensure proper ties exist for transitioning between them, as well as incorporating necessary temporary modification tracking, is currently in progress. An apparent </P><P>cause evaluation (ACE) is </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>NRC FORM 366A LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY CONTINUATION SHEET COMMISSION </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Sect><H5>6. LER NUMBER 	3. PAGE</H5><P>2. DOCKET</P><Sect><H5>1. FACILITY NAME </H5><P>YEAR </P><P>416 </P><P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure>3 3</P><P>Grand Gulf Nuclear Staltloln, Unit </P><Table><TR><TH>NARRATIVE </TH></TR><TR><TH>F. SAFETY AS~)ESSMI=NT </TH></TR><TR><TH>3.3.6.1 Bases </TH><TD>Steam </TD></TR><TR><TH>The Shutdown </TH><TD>Dome </TD><TD>Function is </TD></TR><TR><TH/><TD>This interlock is </TD><TD>for </TD></TR><TR><TH>unrno,,\+ DI&quot;ote:ctlcm to </TH><TD>an </TD><TD>loss Of Coolant Accident </TD><TD>scenario and credit for </TD></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13276A480_img_20.jpg"/>From Technical OrC)VIClea to isolate the shutdown </Figure><P>the interlock is not assumed in the accident or transient in the Up(]atE~a </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13276A480_img_22.jpg"/></Figure><P>health and safety as this interlock is provided for equipment </P><P>protection to an lOCA scenario and credit for the interlock is not assumed in the accident or transient analysis in the updated final safety analysis report (UFSAR). The RHR system isolation valves were able to be remotely opened if needed for post-lOCA shutdown cooling operations. </P><P>Immediate actions nOlI'fI'U'rn.:::.rI by the Operations staff were ClU~:;\.IUICU.~ and The actions incfuded: </P><P>1) 	Review of 101 03-1-01-1, Cold Shutdown to Generator Carrying Minimum load, 03-1-01-2, Power Operations, 03-1-01-3 Plant Shutdown, and 03-1-01-4, Scram Recovery, from forced outage FO-19-5 for jumper configuration items. </P><P>2) 	Verification (through plant walkdowns) that the jumpers are in proper configuration. </P><P>3) 	Performance of 100 percent peer reviews of all procedure and surveillances turned into the control room supervisor (CRS) for review for 7 days. This included both completed and in-progress (at that time) procedures/surveillances. </P><P>4) 	Operations Management implemented guidance to require assistant operations manager (AOM) review and approval prior to transitioning from one 101 to another with incomplete steps. </P><P>During the event, no Technical SpeCification defined Safety limits were challenged. </P><P>Radiological Safety was not affected as there was no radiological release to the public during the event </P><P>Response of the crew did not challenge established industrial safety protocol or requirements. There was no impact to the health and safety of the public, industrial safety or radiological safety as a result of this event </P><P>G. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION </P><P>A review of the GGNS Corrective Action Program and licensee Event Reports, for the past two years, revealed one similar occurrence of a condition prohibited by Technical Specifications caused by a </P><P>lER 2012 -001 -00 reported a Surveillance Test Procedure Inadequate to meet the requirements of Technical Specifications resulting in condition prohibited by Technical Specifications. </P></Sect></Sect></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>