<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-05-28T07:13:36-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-05-28T07:18:12-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-05-28T07:18:12-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:035f5da4-5543-4dc5-b435-db39c80e341e</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:ddba9f28-e944-7a4d-a85c-a6aea24625d8</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>~ </P><P>Entergy Operations. Inc. </P><Part><H2>~Entergy </H2><P>P. O. Box 756 </P><P>Port Gibson, MS 39150 </P><P>James J. Nadeau Manager, Regulatory Assurance Grand Gulf Nuclear Station Tel. (601) 437-2103 </P><P>GNRO-2014/00040 </P><P>May 28,2014 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington. DC 20555-0001 </P><P>SUBJECT: 	Licensee Event Report (LER) 2014-003-00 Automatic Actuation of the Reactor Protection System (RPS) due to Main Turbine Overspeed Protection Load Reject Relay Fault Grand Gulf Nuclear Station, Unit 1 Docket No. 50-416 License No. NPF-29 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Attached is Licensee Event Report (LER) 2014-003-00 which is a final report. This report is submitted in accordance with Title 10 Code ofFederal Regulations 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A). </P><P>This letter contains no new commitments. If you have any questions or require additional information, please contact Mr. James Nadeau at 601,..437-2103. </P><P>sinceri14~ </P><P>JJN/cb </P><P>Attachment: Licensee Event Report (LER) 2014-003-00 </P><P>CC: (See next page) </P><P>GNRO-2014/00040 </P><P>Page 2 of 2 </P><P>cc: with Attachment </P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector Grand Gulf Nuclear Station Port Gibson, MS 39150 </P><P>U. S. NL:Jclear Regulatory Commission AnN: Marc L. Dapas (w/2) Regional Administrator, Region IV 1600 East Lamar Boulevard Arlington, TX 76011-4511 </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission AnN: Mr. Alan Wang, NRR/DORL (w/2) Mail Stop OWFN 8 B1 Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Attachment to 
GNRO-2014/00040 
Licensee Event Report (LER) 2014-003-00 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (01-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See reverse for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAlPrivacy Section (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to infocoliects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Grand Gulf Nuclear Station, Unit 1 </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 13&lt; PAGE 05000416 10F4 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Automatic Actuation of the Reactor Protection System due to Load Reject Relay Fault </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREV NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>03 </TH><TD>29 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 003 00 </TD><TD>05 </TD><TD>28 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TD>o 20.2201 (b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201 (d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(8) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1 )(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1 )(ii)(A) ~50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71 (a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(8) o 73.71 (a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) o OTHER o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(8) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O) Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 087% </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER ITELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) </TH></TR><TR><TH>FACILITY NAME James J Nadeau / Manager, Regulatory Assurance 601-437-2103 </TH></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>E </TH><TD>TA </TD><TD>CAP </TD><TD>S188 </TD><TD>N </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>1~SUPPLEMENTALREPORTEXPECTED o YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DA TE) IZI NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) On March 29, 2014, at 10:08 Central Daylight Time with the plant at 87 percent rated core thermal power, Grand Gulf Nuclear Station experienced an automatic actuation of the reactor protection system and plant scram due to a Main Turbine Overspeed Protection Load Reject Relay (LRR) fault. All control rods fully inserted and safety systems operated as designed. No safety relief valves lifted and no isolation signals were received. Reactor Water Level increased, resulting in a Level 9 SCRAM signal which caused an automatic trip of both reactor feed pumps to reduce reactor water inventory. However, reactor feedwater was promptly restored. The cause of the event was an L-RR fault which caused a fast closure signal to the Main Turbine Control Valves (TCV). The TCV closure resulted in the automatic actuation of the reactor protection system and plant scram. Investigations determined the cause of the LRR fault was a failed ceramic capacitor on a Multiplier Module (MM) card. The failed MM card has been replaced as well as the LRR power supply, power measurement inp~t module and voltage measurement input module. The event posed no threat to public health and safety. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366 (01-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (01·2014) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH><TH>iApPROVED BY OMB: NO. 3150&quot;()104 EXPIRES: 01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory !collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are ncorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. !send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIAIPrivacy Isection (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to ·nfocollects.resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of nformation and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), ~)ffice of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a Imeans used to impose an information collection does not display Is currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct lor sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the 'nformation collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER ISEQUENTIAL I </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Grand Gulf Nuclear Station, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000416 </TD><TD>YEAR REV. NUMBER NO. </TD><TD>20F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 .-003·· 00 </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE A. INITIAL CONDITIONS At the time of the event, Grand Gulf Nuclear Generating Station (GGNS) Unit 1 was operating at 87 percent rated core thermal power. All systems, structures or components that were needed to mitigate, reduce the consequences of, or limit the safety implications of the event were available. B. DESCRIPTION OF EVENT On March 29, 2014, at 10:08 Central Daylight Time with the plant at 87 percent rated core thermal power, Grand Gulf Nuclear Station experienced a Main Turbine Overspeed Protection Load Reject Relay (LRR) [RL Y] fault resulting in an automatic actuation of the Reactor Protection System (RPS) [JC] and plant scram. The main turbine LRR actuated causing the four main turbine control valves (TCV) [SCV] to close momentarily. The LRR actuated four times in only a few seconds, indicating that the Siemens Multiplier Module (MM) card failed four times, followed by catastrophic random failure of a ceramic capacitor on the MM card. Actuation of the LRR due to the failed capacitor on the MM card caused the load reject solenoids to energize and the TCVs to receive a fast closure signal. The LRR is part of the Main Turbine Overspeed Protection [XC] scheme and is designed to respond to load rejection events on the transmission system. The LRR is designed to anticipate an overspeed condition and generate a turbine trip before the Electro-Hydraulic Converter (E/H C) [CNV] speed control and Mechanical Hydraulic Speed Setter [HCU] respond to limit overspeed in order to reduce turbine steam flow when generator power cannot be transmitted. The dispatcher confirmed there were no substantial grid disturbances that caused the GGNS plant SCRAM. Therefore, a v~lid load reject event was ruled out as the cause of the LRR sequential actuation. Investigation determined the LRR actuated multiple times after the initial actuation. As designed, the LRR would actuate only once for a valid event. Visual inspection identified a catastrophically failed capacitor on the MM card 7TL461 O. The LRR could not be calibrated with the as-found module. The MM was replaced and the unit was successfully calibrated. The ceramic capacitor randomly failed resulting in a sequence of events that inadvertently actuated the LRR and a subsequent plant SCRAM. The LRR Converter (power supply), power measurement input and voltage measurement input modules were replaced as a proactive measure to minimize risk. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (01·2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (01-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Grand Gulf Nuclear Station, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000416 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>30F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 003 00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE C. EVENT CAUSE The cause of the automatic reactor shutdown was closure of the TCVs caused by sequential actuation of the LRR due to an age-related failure of a capacitor on the LRR MM card (manufacturer -Siemens). The preliminary cause of the age-related capacitor failure is failure to track implementation of identified and required corrective actions from the developed Single Point Vulnerability (SPV) mitigation strategy and apparent cause analysis and to complete the procurement evaluation in order to find a replacement LRR or rebuild the original. Additional investigation is planned through evaluation of vendor analysis to validate the failure mode. D. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS The MM card has been replaced. In addition, the LRR power supply, power measurement input module and voltage measurement input module were also replaced. A design change is planned to replace the LRR with a modern relay such that no single component failure would cause an incorrect operation or prevent a valid operation. E. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE DETERMINTAION The event posed no threat to public health and safety as the RPS performed as designed. All safety systems responded as designed. There were no significant complications during the scram and recovery. At no time during the event were any technical specification safety limits violated or challenged. There were no Emergency Core Cooling (ECC) [BN] System actuations or malfunctions. The End Of Cycle/Recirculation Pump Trip (EOC/RPT) [IT] system initiated, as designed, to transfer both reacto~ recirculation pumps to slow speed due to closure of the main TCVs. The main generator output breakers opened approximately 1 minute and 10 seconds after the event. The condition described would not have prevented automatic actions from occurring that protect the integrity of the reactor core and vessel. Immediate actions performed by the Operations staff were adequate and appropriate in maintaining the reactor in a safe shutdown condition. Reactor Water Level increased, resulting in a Level 9 SCRAM signal which caused an automatic trip of both reactor feed pumps to reduce reactor water inventory. However, reactor feedwater was promptly restored. Radiological safety was not affected since there was no radiological release to the public during the event. Industrial safety was not affected. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (01-2014) NRC FORM 366A (01-2014) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (01-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Grand Gulf Nuclear Station, Unit 1 </TH><TD>05000416 </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL I NUMBER REV. NO. </TD><TD>40F4 </TD></TR><TR><TD>2014 --003 -00 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE F. BASIS FOR REPORT ABILITY This Licensee Event Report (LER) is being submitted pursuant to Title 10 Code of Federal Regulations (10 CFR) 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) for an automatic actuation of the Reactor Protection System. Telephonic notification was made to the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) Emergency Notification System (ENS) on March 29, 2014, within 4 hours of the event, pu1rsuant to 10 CFR 50.72(b)(2)(iv)(B) for the RPS actuation. G. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION The LRR was replaced in 2005 under a twelve year replacement preventive maintenance strategy using a non-refurbished spare from Unit 2. The LRR power supply card failed in October, 2008, and again in July, 2009. In 2007, SPV mitigation strategies were developed to address age-related components associated with the LRR. Corrective actions issued in 2008 to replace the LRR with refurbished parts were not performed. Long term resolution to eliminate the LRR as an SPV component by implementing Turbine Control upgrade modifications were not performed. The LRR that failed during the March 29,2014 event was previously satisfactorily calibrated in May, 2012. Energy Industry Identification System (EllS) codes and component codes are identified in the text of this report as [XX]. </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>