<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-07-31T07:15:59-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-07-31T07:34:24-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-07-31T07:34:24-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:16c01681-dc07-4880-bec6-9b7b0a419d76</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:aece5649-56f1-9248-9a16-4b276b837e2a</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P>Entergy Operations, Inc. </P><P>P. O. Box 756 Port Gibson, MS 39150 </P><P>James Nadeau Manager, Regulatory Assurance Grand Gulf Nuclear Station Tel. (601) 437-2103 </P><P>GNRO~2014/00049 </P><P>July 31,2014 </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>SUBJECT: 	Report Pursuant to 10 CFR 71.95 (a)(3) and (b) of seven potential instances of noncompliance with Certificate of Compliance No. 9233 for TN-RAM Package, Revision 11 Grand Gulf Nuclear Station, Unit 1 Docket No. 50-416 License No. NPF-29 </P><P>REFERENCE: 	1. AREVA Letter E-38923 -Report Pursuant to 10 CFR 71.95 (a)(3) and </P><P>(b) of As-Built Discrepancies in the TN-RAM Packaging Relative to Certificate of Compliance No. 9233, dated June 18, 2014 (ADAMS Accession No. ML 14171A358) </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Entergy Operations, Inc. (Entergy) hereby submits this report pursuant to Title 10 Code of Federal Regulations (10 CFR) 71.95(a)(3) and (b) regarding seven potential instances in which the conditions of approval in Certificate of Noncompliance (CoC) No. 9233, Revision 11, for the Model No. TN;'RAM Package, Docket No. 71-9233 (Reference 1), may not have been met when making shipments from Grand Gulf Nuclear Station (GGNS). The seven potential instances of noncompliance with the CoC occurred during the calendar years of 1998-2003. </P><P>AREVA notified Entergy of their concerns associated with the CoC on June 19, 2014. Entergy immediately investigated its shipment history to determine if the shipping package in question had been used by GGNS to ship radioactive materials. Seven instances were identified. Attachment 1 of this letter provides a detailed list of the CoC noncompliance instances. This attachment includes the shipment numbers, shipment dates, material shipped, and the final destination of each shipment. </P><P>AREVA, in Reference 1, documented the as-built discrepancies and determined that none of the components and systems of the TN-RAM package was adversely affected by the identified discrepancies. Further, their evaluation determined that the discrepancies did not represent a public health and safety concern. The bases for the conclusions were documented in Attachment to AREVA Letter E-38923. </P><P>GNRO-2014/00049 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>To prevent recurrence Entergy will work with its vendor to ensure all future shipments are made withia shipping package that is in full compliance with its associated CoCo </P><P>This letter contains no new commitments. If you have any questions or require additional information, please contact James Nadeau at 601-437-2103. </P><P>JM/ram </P><P>Attachment: Details on Certificate of Compliance Potential Violations </P><P>cc: </P><P>u.s. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Mr. A. Wang, NRRlDORL 
Mail Stop OWFN/8 G14 
11555 Rockville Pike 
Rockville, MD 20852-2378 
</P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector 
Grand Gulf Nuclear Station 
Port Gibson, MS 39150 
</P><L><LI><LI_Label>u.S. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Director, Division of Spent Fuel 
Storage and Transportation, 
Office of Nuclear Material Safety and 
Safeguards, 
Washington, DC 20555-00001 
</LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>u. </LI_Label><LI_Title>S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission 
ATTN: Marc L. Dapas (w/2) 
Regional Administrator, Region IV 
1600 East Lamar Boulevard 
Arlington, TX 76011-4511 
</LI_Title></LI></L><P>\~ </P><P>Attachment to GNRO·2014/00049 Details on Certificate of Compliance Potential Violations </P><Table><TR><TD>Attachment GNRO-2014/00049 Page 1 of 1 </TD><TD/></TR><TR><TD/><TD>Grand Gulf Nuclear Generating Station Potential Instances of Certificate of Noncompliance </TD></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>Shipment Number </TH><TH>Shipment Date </TH><TH>Material Shipped </TH></TR><TR><TH>98-0401 </TH><TD>04/14/1998 </TD><TD>8 Control Rod Blades (CRBs) and 193 Fission Chambers </TD></TR><TR><TH>99-1001 </TH><TD>10/27/1999 </TD><TD>8CRBs </TD></TR><TR><TH>2003-0605 </TH><TD>07101/2003 </TD><TD>11 CRBs and 10 Velocity Limiters (VLs) </TD></TR><TR><TH>2003-0804 </TH><TD>08/15/2003 </TD><TD>11 CRBs and 6 VLs </TD></TR><TR><TH>2003-0805 </TH><TD>08/28/2003 </TD><TD>12 CRBs </TD></TR><TR><TH>2003-0903 </TH><TD>09/22/2003 </TD><TD>12 CRBs, 13 VLs and 2 channel clips </TD></TR><TR><TH>2003-1001 </TH><TD>10106/2003 </TD><TD>12 CRBs and 11 VLs </TD></TR></Table><P>The final shipping destination for the above shipments was Chern Nuclear in Barnwell, South Carolina. </P></TaggedPDF-doc>