<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2010-05-03T10:04:59-04:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:CreateDate>2010-05-03T10:04:59-04:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2010-05-03T10:04:59-04:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
         <xmp:CreatorTool> </xmp:CreatorTool>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><P><Figure ActualText="• "><ImageData src="images/ML101230323_img_0.jpg"/>• </Figure>Entergy Nuclear South Entergy Operations, Inc. 17265 River Road Killona, LA 70057-3093 </P><P>Tel 504 739 6685 </P><P>Fax 5047396698 </P><P>wsteelm@entergy.com </P><Part><H2>~Entergy </H2><P>William J. Steelman . Acting licensing Manager Waterford 3 </P><P>W3F1-2010-0030 </P><P>April 29, 2010 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC 20555-0001 </P><P>Subject: 	Licensee Event Report 2009-003-01 Waterford Steam Electric Station, Unit 3 (Waterford 3) Docket No. 50-382 License No. NPF-38 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: </P><P>Entergy is hereby submitting Licensee Event Report (LER) 09-003-01 for Waterford Steam Electric Station Unit 3. This report provides a revision to the details associated with higher than expected failure rates of normally energized Tyco model E7024PB electro pneumatic time delay relays. This report contains no new commitments. Please contact William J. Steelman at (504) 739-6685 if you have questions regarding this information. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML101230323_img_1.jpg"/></Figure><P>WJS Attachment: Licensee Event Report 2009-003-01 </P><Figure><ImageData src=""/></Figure><P>W3F1-2010-0030 Page 2 </P><P>cc: 	Mr. Elmo E. Collins, Jr. Regional Administrator </P><P>U. S. Nuclear Regulatory Com mission 
Region IV 
612 E. Lamar Blvd., Suite 400 
Arlington, TX 76011-4125 
</P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector 
Waterford Steam Electric Station Unit 3 
</P><L><LI><LI_Label>P.O. </LI_Label><LI_Title>Box 822 
Killona, LA 70066-0751 
</LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>U. </LI_Label><LI_Title>S. Nuclear Regulatory Com mission 
Attn: Mr. N. Kalyanam 
Mail Stop 0-07D1 
Washington, DC 20555-0001 
</LI_Title></LI></L><P>Wise, Carter, Child &amp; Caraway 
ATTN: J. Smith 
</P><P>P.O. Box 651 
Jackson, MS 39205 
</P><P>Winston &amp; Strawn 
ATTN: N.S. Reynolds 
1700 K Street, NW 
Washington, DC 20006-3817 
</P><P>Morgan, Lewis &amp; Bockius LLP 
ATTN: T.C. Poindexter 
1111 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW 
Washington, DC 20004 
</P><P>Louisiana Department of Environmental Quality Office of Environmental Compliance Surveillance Division </P><P>P. o. Box 4312 
Baton Rouge, LA 70821-4312 
</P><P>R.K. West, lerevents@inpo.org -INP 0 Records Center </P><P>/ </P><P>Attachment 
W3F1·2010-0030 
Licensee Event Report 2009-003-01 
</P><P>&quot; </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (9·2007) LICENSEE EVENT R,EPORT (LER) (See reverse for re~Uired numbe;)of diQits/characters or each block </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES 8/31/2010 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory information collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are Incorporated into the IicensinJl process and fed back to indUS% Send comments regarding burden estimate to the Recor s Management Branch (T·6 E6), .S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet email to b~s1@nrc'80v, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and R,ulato~ Affairs, NEOB-10 02 (315 -0104), Office of Management and BUd~et, Washington, C 20 03. If a means used to impose information collection does not disp ay a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000382 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 6 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Multiple Tyco Relay Failures ) </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR ISEQUENTIAL IREVNUMBER NO </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME NA </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>02 </TH><TD>22 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>2009 -003 -01 </TD><TD>04 </TD><TD>29 </TD><TD>2010 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME NA </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER NA </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE , 1 </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) o 20.2201(b) o 20.2203(a)(3)(i) . 0 50.73(a)(2)(i)(C) o 50.73(a)(2)(vii) o 20.2201(d) o 20.2203(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A) o 20.2203(a)(1) o 20.2203(a)(4) o 50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B) o 20.2203(a)(2)(i) o 50.36(c)(1)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iii) o 50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) o 20.2203(a)(2)(ii) o 50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A) o 50:73(a)(2)(x) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iii) o 50.36(c)(2) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(A) o 73.71(a)(4) o 20.2203(a)(2)(iv) o 50.46(a)(3)(ii) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) o 73.71(a)(5) o 20.2203(a)(2)(v) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(A) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(C) I:8J OTHER . Specify in Abstract below or in' o 20.2203(a)(2)(vi) o 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) o 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL 100 </TH></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>IfACILllY NAME Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station William Steelman </TH><TD>Tt::Lt::t-'HONt:: NUM~t::R (InClUde Area COde) 504-739-6685 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE \ </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLETO EPIX </TD><TD>~'f ~~ l;nt Jgt </TD><TD>CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU·FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLETO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>B </TH><TD>JE </TD><TD>2 </TD><TD>TyeO </TD><TD>y </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED 0 YES (If yes complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) I:8J NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED I MONTH I DAY SUBMISSION I IDATE </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD/></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) This is a Licensing Event Report (LER) to identify a 10CFR21 issue of generic interest. There have been two additional failures of Tyco relay model E7024PB with date codes that had not previously failed since LER 2009':'003-00 was submitted. , Waterford 3 has observed a higher than expected failure rate of normally energized Tyco model E7024PB electro-pneumatic time delay relays produced since 2007. Seven of the eight failures were observed on 2007 or newer date code relays and one was observed on a 2004 date code relay.. The early-in-life failures have been observed on Tyco model E7024PB relays designed as an Off-Delay, 4 pole double throw, 125VDC operating coil, with a time delay range of 0.5 to 5 seconds. All failed relays were replaced. Post failure bench testing at Waterford 3, Tyco, or independent Failure Analysis has not consistently repeated the failures. , </TH></TR></Table><P>( </P><P>NRC FORM 366 (9·2007) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) I CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station </TH><TD>05000382 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>2 OF 6</TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 003 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE REPORTABLE OCCURRENCE This condition is a Licensee Event Report (LER) to report a 10CFR21 issue of generic interest. This condition meets the reporting criteria of 10CFR21 because reduced reliability of Tyco model' E7024PB relays has been established in Waterford 3 Corrective Action Program, the root cause was determined to be manufacturer fabrication less than adequate, and Waterford 3 has Tyco model E7024PB relays in the warehouse. The 10CFR21 two day report was made on 4/21/10 at 1035 EDT under notification number EN45862. This is the follow up 30 day written notification. INITIAL CONDITIONS This LER identifies multiple Tyco model E7024PB electro-pneumatic time delay relay failures that have occurred at different initial conditions. Of interest, four of the eight failures resulted in Waterford 3 entering into Unplanned Shutdown Limiting Conditions of Operation (LCO) of 72 hours (one additional was a 7 day LCO). . EVENT DESCRIPTION Waterford 3 has observed a higher than expected failure rate of normally energized Tyco model E7024PB electro-pneumatic time delay relays produced since 2007. Seven of the eight failures were observed on 2007 or newer date code relays and one was observed on a 2004 date code relay. Waterford 3 had 33 Tyco model E7024PB time delay relays installed in the plant. The Agastat E7000 series timing relay consists of two basic operating types, On-Delay and Off-Delay. The On-Delay models provide a delay period of contact re-positioning on energization and no time delay upon de-energization. The Off-Delay models provide a delay period of contact re-positioning on de-energizationand no time delay upon energization. These relays may be ordered with various electrical characteristics suitable for use specific to each application. The early-in-life failures have been observed on Tyco model E7024PB relays designed as an Off-Delay, 4 pole double throw, • 125VDC operating coil, with a time delay range of 0.5 to 5 seconds. All failed relays were replaced_ Post failure bench testing at Waterford 3, Tyco, and independent Failure Analysis has not consistently repeated the failures. </TH></TR></Table><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) U_S_ NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1_ FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2_ DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station </TH><TD>05000382 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>3 OF 6</TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 003 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE CAUSAL FACTORS A Root Cause Analysis was completed using multiple investigative techniques (Kepner-Tregoe Problem Solving Analysis and Failure Modes Analysis). The root cause of the early in life relay failures is manufacturer fabrication less than adequate. No common specific fabrication issue was identified that would encompass all the relay failures, but the Root Cause Analysis identified eight potential fabrication issues that could not be eliminated during the analysis process. These include: • Cracked contact blocks on relays 09150078, 09030683, and 08350005 • Resistance change to contacts due to clamping force on terminal block • Incorrect recycle spring installed causing 10 CFR Part 21 notification • ' Contact block force spring adjustments (Allen set screw) out of toierance • Loose terminal points discovered on two spare relays • Screw inside the lower contact block assembly (contact set 8-12) is not tight / backed out from stationary contact 0921 • Foreign Material in contact block most likely from manufacturing • Mechanical binding of armature and plunger due to foreign material The eight early-in-life normally energized Tyco model E7024PB electro-pneumatic time delay relay failures with serial numbers 04030244, 08040634, 08040636, 08270633, 09030683, 08350005, 07160240, and 09150078 can be grouped as follows: • Date code 0804 High Pressure Safety Injection (HPSI) Pump B (09/11/2008) and Chemical Volume Control (CVC) Charging Pump A (10/13/2008) Tyco indicated the failures were due to worker error in fabrication-and testing (force balance)_ I -An additional failure occurred during a bench test. This Tyco Relay 08040635 bench test failure (04/13/2009) cause was indeterminate_ • Date code 0903 CVC Charging Pump B (03/13/2009) Southwest Research Institute (SwRl) performed failure analysis and found foreign material in relay_ • Date code 0827 Battery Exhaust Fan A (06/01/2009) Date codes 0808-0835 were identified by the Tyco 10CFR Part 21 Notification dated 11/21/08 as potentially having an incorrect spring installed during fabrication_ The 08270633 relay was returned to Tyco per 10CFR21 and Tyco reported the correct springs were installed_ Tyco could not duplicate the failure_ </TH></TR></Table><P>I_ </P><P>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) </P><P>NRC FORM 366A 	u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION </P><P>(9·2007) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </P><P>2. DOCKET1. FACILITY NAME 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE </P><P>I SEQUENTIAL jREVISIONYEAR NUMBER NUMBER </P><P>Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station </P><P>05000382 </P><P>4 	OF</P><P>2009 003 01 </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>CAUSAL FACTORS CONTINUED </P><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Date code 0835 HPSI Pump B (06/22/2009) The date code 0808 through 0835 relays that were sent back to the vendor per the Part 21 notification, re-certified by the vendor, and returned to Waterford 3 as new relays and the 0835 date code relay failed subsequently. The 08350005 Relay was sent to SwRI for failure analysis with result that the failure could not be duplicated, but minor foreign material was identified. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Date code 0403 Train B Integrated Emergency Diesel Generator/Engineering Safety Features Test multiple components (05/15/2008) </LI_Title></LI></L><P>J </P><P>Bench testing of Jhe failed relay by Electrical Maintenance determined that this normally </P><P>energized relay would chan'ge state if actuated shortly after being energized; however, after </P><P>an extended period of time (-1 hour) the relay would not change state. This was evaluated </P><P>as evidence of a heat related failure mechanism specific to this relay. This relay was </P><P>inadvertently disposed and a formal failure analysis could not be performed. </P><L><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Date code 0915 Low Pressure Safety Injection (LPSI) Pump B (2/22/10) Tyco witnessed relay test at Waterford 3, which confirmed failure mechanism. Tyco returned to manufacturing facility with relay (09150078) to perform failure analysis. This is in the Waterford 3 corrective action process. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>• 	</LI_Label><LI_Title>Date code 0716 Battery Exhaust Fans B (2/27/10). The relay failure mechanism could not be confirmed at Waterford 3. Relay (07160240) was returned to Tyco to perform failure analysis. This is in the Waterford 3 corrective ,action process. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>CORRECTIVE ACTIONS </P><P>\ </P><P>The Root Cause Analysis has identified multiple required corrective actions. The most pertinent are as follows: </P><L><LI><LI_Title>o 	Revised Tyco relay pre-installation testing to include a 24 hour burn in time and cycling the relay 10 times. . </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 	For installed Tyco relays of specific date codes and risk significance, the testing frequency has been increased to proactively assess reliability. </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Title>o 	Implementing modification to replace all Tyco E7024PB relays in safety related applications. </LI_Title></LI></L><P>I 	, </P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9-2007) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station </TH><TD>05000382 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>5 OF 6</TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 003 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE The Waterford 3 EOOS model was used to calculate the risk using the Waterford 3 Revision 4 Change 1 Probabilistic Risk Analysis (PRA). The zero maintenance risk for the Revision 4 Change 1 PRA is 2.292E-06/year. The 2007-2009 Tyco date coded modei E7024PB relays installed have 293 successful actuations out of a total of 300 actuations or 97.67% successful actuations. This results in a failure rate of 2.33E-2. A risk analysis was performed using this 2.33E-2 failure rate. The analysis shows that the only relays having potential risk significance are those associated with the HPSI pumps A and B, Emergency Feedwater (EFW) pump B, and Chilled Water (CHW) pump A If these relays were to fail, the failure to start woulq be readily detected by the operators, who are trained and frequently practice in training where the pumps would be started manually using the switches on the main control room panels. Existing procedures require verifying these pumps start and direct manually starting the pumps if they did not start automatically. The operator actions for manually starting these pumps were conservatively assumed to have a 1.1 E-2 or 2.8E-3 failure probability, depending on the accident sequence. Using these manual actions, the internal events Core Damage Frequency (CDF) is 2.885E-6/yr, which is an increase of 5.93E-7/yr with respect to the baseline CDF of 2.292E-6/yr. The risk impact for external events is 2.30E-7/yr for a total risk impact of 8.23E~7/yr. All the Tyco model E7024PB relays have been reviewed to confirm that the potential relay failures can be mitigated by simple manual action. Thus, the potential reduced reliability of the relays is not risk significant. ' The Public Health and Safety was not adversely affected by this condition. The relay failwes were identified during surveillance or bench testing with the redundant train operable. There were no system or train actuations or initiations resulting from these relay failures. There was not a common mode failure mechanism identified for the relay failures. This condition had no impact on industrial safety or radiological safety. No personnel were injured during these events. The relays are installed outside the radiological controlled areas. No dose was received as a result of these failures. </TH></TR></Table><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366A (9·2007) u.s. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME </TH><TD>2. DOCKET </TD><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>3. PAGE </TD></TR><TR><TH>Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station </TH><TD>05000382 </TD><TD>YEAR I SEQUENTIAL· IREVISION NUMBER NUMBER </TD><TD>6 OF</TD></TR><TR><TD>2009 003 01 </TD></TR><TR><TH>NARRATIVE SIMILAR EVENTS As stated in the event description, Waterford 3 has observed a higher than expected failure rate of. normally energized Tyco model E7024PB electro-pneumatic time delay relays produced since 2007. Seven of the eight failures were observed on 2007 or newer date code relays and one 2004 date code relay. This LER is an outcome of multiple similar events. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION None </TH></TR></Table></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>