<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2012-09-17T15:35-05:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2012-09-17T15:37:45-05:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2012-09-17T15:37:45-05:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>PDF-XChange 4.0.159.0 (Windows XP Professional Service Pack 3 (Build 2600))</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:99d1c6a3-27cd-40a0-8b70-14f25a381993</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:fd130bef-f6ac-4147-8a5e-e1da76971b0b</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Part><H6>Entergy Operations, Inc. </H6><P>17265 River Road Killona, LA 70057-3093 Tel  504-739-6673 Fax 504-739-6698 mmason@entergy.com </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12262A320_img_0.jpg"/><Caption><P>Michael E. Mason </P></Caption></Figure><P>Licensing Manager (acting) Waterford 3 </P><P>W3F1-2012-0075 </P><P>September 17, 2012 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk Washington, DC  20555 </P><P>SUBJECT:   	Special Report SR-12-001-00, Primary Met. Tower Upper Level  Wind Speed Instrument Inoperable for Greater Than 7 Days  Waterford Steam Electric Station, Unit 3  Docket No. 50-382 License No. NPF-38 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam:  </P><P>Attached is Special Report Number SR-12-001-00 for Waterford Steam Electric Station,  Unit 3.  This Special Report is submitted per Technical Requirements Manual 3.3.3.4 and Technical Specification 6.9.2. </P><P>If you have any questions concerning this submittal, please contact Michael E. Mason at  </P><P>(504) 739-6673.  </P><P>There are no new commitments contained in this submittal. </P><P>Sincerely, </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML12262A320_img_1.jpg"/></Figure><P>MEM/WH Attachment: Special Report SR-12-001-00 </P><P>W3F1-2012-0075 </P><P>Page 2 </P><P>cc: 	Mr. Elmo E. Collins, Jr. Regional Administrator </P><P>U. S. NRC Region IV  </P><P>Mr. N. Kalyanam Project Manager, Waterford 3 </P><P>U. S. NRC </P><P>NRC Senior Resident Inspector Waterford 3 RidsRgn4MailCenter@nrc.gov </P><P>Kaly.Kalyanam@nrc.gov </P><P>Marlone.Davis@nrc.gov Dean.Overland@nrc.gov </P><P>Attachment 
W3F1-2012-0075 
Special Report SR-12-001-00 
</P><P>Attachment to W3F1-2012-0075 Page 1 of 2 </P><P>SPECIAL REPORT 
SR-12-001-00 
</P><P>Primary Meteorological Tower Upper Level Wind Speed instrument  
Inoperable Greater Than 7 Days  
</P><P>SUMMARY </P><P>At 13:50 hours on August 29, 2012, Operations personnel at Waterford Steam Electric Station Unit 3 (Waterford 3) declared the Primary Meteorological Tower Upper Level Wind Speed instrument, EM IST0100, inoperable.  Technical Requirements Manual (TRM) 3.3.3.4 Action A requires that, with one or more required meteorological monitoring channels inoperable for more than 7 days, prepare and submit a Special Report to the Commission pursuant to Specification 6.9.2 within the next 10 days outlining the cause of the malfunction and the plans for restoring the channel(s) to OPERABLE status.  Since the instrument was not returned to service within 7 days, this report is submitted pursuant to TRM 3.3.3.4.    </P><P>EM IST0100 was declared operable at 02:35 on September 8, 2012, which resulted in approximately 9.5 days of inoperability.  Since the Primary Meteorological Tower Upper Level Wind Speed instrument is not utilized for emergency planning purposes, the inoperability of the instrument did not pose a health hazard to the general public.  </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>Waterford 3 had just completed a plant shutdown in preparation for the passing of Hurricane Isaac.  At 13:16 hours on August 29, 2012, Operations personnel at Waterford 3 noted that the Primary Meteorological Tower Upper Level (199 ft.) Wind Speed instrument was reading erroneously low and declared the instrument inoperable.  TRM </P><P>3.3.3.4 Action A was entered at 13:50 hours.  The condition was entered in the site corrective action program as CR-WF3-2012-4241 and a work request was initiated. </P><P>Technical Requirements Manual (TRM) 3.3.3.4 Action A requires that, with one or more required meteorological monitoring channels inoperable for more than 7 days, prepare and submit a Special Report to the Commission pursuant to Specification 6.9.2 within the next 10 days outlining the cause of the malfunction and the plans for restoring the channel(s) to OPERABLE status. </P><P>As the Primary Meteorological Tower Upper Level Wind Speed instrument is not utilized for emergency planning purposes, the inoperability of the instrument did not impede assessment of meteorological conditions or adversely affect emergency classification. </P><P>Due to the storm related conditions, sufficient plant personnel are sequestered on site prior to the storm to perform plant operations while shutdown, meet emergency planning requirements, and provide site security.  Following passing of the storm, designated relief personnel returned to site to relieve sequestered personnel and assist in plant restoration. </P><P>Attachment to W3F1-2012-0075 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>Work commenced on September 7, 2012, to restore the Primary Meteorological Tower Upper Level Wind Speed instrument as technicians became available following Hurricane Isaac.  Instrumentation and Controls technicians found that two of the three wind cups were broken off the instrument.  The technicians replaced the local wind speed instrument under Work Order 326002. </P><P>Operations declared the Primary Meteorological Tower Upper Level Wind Speed instrument, EM IST0100, operable at 02:35 hours on September 8, 2012.  The total time of inoperability was approximately 9.5 days. </P><P>PLANT CONTACT </P><P>S. W. Meiklejohn, I&amp;C Maintenance Superintendent  </P><P>(504) 464-3221 </P></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>