<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2013-01-23T08:01:20-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2013-01-24T07:02:26-06:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2013-01-24T07:02:26-06:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>Adobe Acrobat 9.55 Paper Capture Plug-in</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:4d612b35-2ddb-4e8f-98cf-110150958556</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:d1044755-13a7-a64e-a08b-70206b54069f</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13024A204_img_0.jpg"/></Figure><P>Entergy Operations, Inc. </P><P>17265 River Road Killona, LA 70057-3093 Tel 504-739-6685 Fax 504-739-6678 cfugate@entergy.com </P><P>Chester Fugate</P><P>Licensing Manager Waterford 3 </P><P>W3F1-2013-0007 </P><P>January 24, 2013 </P><P>U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Attn: Document Control Desk 11555 Rockville Pike Rockville, MD 20852 </P><P>Subject: Special Report SR 13-001-00 </P><P>Fuel Handling Building Wide Range Gas Radiation Monitor PRMIR3032 </P><P>Inoperable for Greater Than 7 Days </P><P>Waterford Steam Electric Station, Unit 3 (Waterford 3) </P><P>Docket No. 50-382 </P><P>License No. NPF-38 </P><P>Dear Sir or Madam: 
</P><P>Attached is Special Report SR 13-001-00 for Waterford Steam Electric Station, 
Unit 3 (Waterford 3). This special report is submitted pursuant to the requirements of 
Waterford 3 Technical Specification 3.3.3.1 and Technical Specification 6.9.2. 
</P><P>If you have any questions concerning this submittal, please contact Chester Fugate, 
Licensing Manager, at (504) 739-6685. 
</P><P>There are no new commitments contained in this submittal. 
</P><P>Sincerely, 
</P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML13024A204_img_1.jpg"/></Figure><P>CF/WH Attachment: Special Report SR 13-001-00 </P><P>W3F1-2013-0007 Page 2 </P><P>cc: Mr. Elmo E. Collins, Jr., Regional Administrator </P><L><LI><LI_Label>U.S.</LI_Label><LI_Title> NRC, Region IV 
RidsRgn4MailCenter@nrc.gov 
</LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>U.S.</LI_Label><LI_Title> NRC Project Manager for Waterford 3 Kaly.Kalyanam@nrc.gov </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>U.S.</LI_Label><LI_Title> NRC Senior Resident Inspector for Waterford 3 Marlone.Davis@nrc.gov </LI_Title></LI></L><P>Attachment to 
W3F1-2013-0007 
Special Report SR 13-001-00 
</P><P>Attachment to W3F1-2013-0007 Page 1 of 2 </P><P>Special Report 
SR 13-001-00 
</P><P>Fuel Handling Building Wide Range Gas Radiation Monitor PRMIR3032 
Inoperable for Greater Than 7 Days 
</P><P>SUMMARY </P><P>During refueling outage RF-18 for Waterford Steam Electric Station Unit 3 (Waterford 3), a scheduled calibration of the Fuel Handling Building Wide Range Gas Radiation Monitor PRMIR3032 exceeded the duration allowed by Waterford 3 Technical Specifications. During the calibration, the high range detector required replacement. The new detector required changes to the calibration procedure for conversion factor and count rate calculations. Once procedure changes were made, the calibration was successfully completed and radiation monitor operability was restored. As the duration specified in the Technical Specification action was exceeded, a special report to the Commission is required. </P><P>NARRATIVE </P><P>At 12:54 CST on January 10, 2013, during refueling outage RF-18, Waterford 3 Operations declared the Fuel Handling Building (FHB) Wide Range Gas Monitor (WRGM) PRM-IR-3032 inoperable so that a scheduled channel calibration could be performed The applicable Technical Specification (TS) 3.3.3.1 actions were entered. TS Surveillance 4.3.3.1 requires a channel calibration on this instrument loop at an 18 month frequency. In accordance with TS 3.3.3.1 Action 27 (1), Health Physics (HP) personnel implemented the preplanned alternate method for monitoring FHB effluent gas. TS 3.3.3.1 Action 27 (2) requires that if the monitor is not restored to OPERABLE status within 7 days after the failure, prepare and submit a Special Report to the Commission pursuant to Specification 6.9.2 within 14 days following the event outlining the action taken, the cause of the inoperability and the plans and schedule for restoring the system to OPERABLE status. The 7 day requirement was exceeded on January 17, 2013 at 12:54. This is captured in the site corrective action program under CR-WF32013-0318. </P><P>Maintenance personnel were utilizing Work Order 52335214 and Procedure MI-003-371 (Fuel Handling Building Ventilation System Emergency Exhaust High Range Noble Gas Radiation Monitor Channel Calibration PRMIR3032) to perform the 18 month calibration. </P><P>On day 6 (January 16, 2013) of the calibration, the high range detector was found out of calibration per MI-003-371 section 9.11. Performing the calibration procedure did not bring the detector into the desired range (CR-WF3-2013-0282). Replacement of the detector required procedure changes for conversion factor and count rate calculations.  Once the procedure was revised, a detector calibration was performed and the required adjustments to the low level discriminator were made. </P><P>Attachment to W3F1-2013-0007 Page 2 of 2 </P><P>The calibration of FHB WRGM PRM-IR-3032 was successfully completed on January 18, 2013. The radiation monitor was declared Operable by Operations on January 18, 2013 at 07:35. The duration of inoperability was approximately 7.8 days. </P><P>PLANT CONTACT </P><P>S. W. Meiklejohn, I&amp;C Maintenance Superintendent </P><P>(504) 464-3221 </P></TaggedPDF-doc>