<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 --><TaggedPDF-doc><?xpacket begin='﻿' id='W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d'?><?xpacket begin="﻿" id="W5M0MpCehiHzreSzNTczkc9d"?>
<x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 4.2.1-c043 52.372728, 2009/01/18-15:56:37        ">
   <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/">
         <xmp:CreateDate>2014-12-18T14:21:58-06:00</xmp:CreateDate>
         <xmp:ModifyDate>2014-12-18T16:09:46-06:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
         <xmp:MetadataDate>2014-12-18T16:09:46-06:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/">
         <pdf:Producer>PDF-XChange Printer 2012 (5.0 build 263) [Windows 7 Ultimate x64 (Build 7601: Service Pack 1)]</pdf:Producer>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
         <dc:format>xml</dc:format>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:pdfx="http://ns.adobe.com/pdfx/1.3/">
         <pdfx:PXCViewerInfo>PDF-XChange Viewer;2.5.204.0;Jul 17 2012;19:37:45;D:20141218142221-06'00'</pdfx:PXCViewerInfo>
      </rdf:Description>
      <rdf:Description rdf:about=""
            xmlns:xmpMM="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/">
         <xmpMM:DocumentID>uuid:92771668-6665-4d92-90df-27bd879eb387</xmpMM:DocumentID>
         <xmpMM:InstanceID>uuid:27eb5d15-eb0b-794a-ae1d-4dc4c79274e8</xmpMM:InstanceID>
      </rdf:Description>
   </rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                                                                                                    
                           
<?xpacket end="w"?><?xpacket end='r'?><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14352A449_img_0.jpg"/></Figure><Part><H6>Entergy Operattions, Inc. </H6><P>17265 River Road Killona, LA 70057--3093 Tel 504-739-6685 Fax 504-739-66988 jjarrel@entergy.coom </P></Part><Part><H6>John P. Jarrell III </H6><P>Manager – Regulaatory Assurance Waterford 3 </P></Part><Part><H5>100 CFR 50.733 </H5><P>W3F1-2014-0077 </P><P>Decemmber 18, 20 14 </P><P>U.S. NNuclear Regulatory Commmission Attn: Document CControl Deskk 115555 Rockville PPike Rockvville, MD 208852 </P><P>Subject: Liccensee Evennt Report (LEER) 2014-0004-00 </P><P>Waaterford Steaam Electric SStation, Unitt 3 (Waterforrd 3) </P><P>Doocket No. 50--382 </P><P>Liccense No. NPPF-38 </P><P>Dear SSir or Madamm: </P><P>Enterggy is herebyy submitting Licensee Evvent Report ((LER) 2014--004-00 for WWaterford Steamm Electric Staation, Unit 33 (Waterford 3). This repport providess details asssociated withh a conddition that coould have immpacted the past operabbility of both trains of thee Emergencyy Diesel Generator Fuel Oil Feeed Tanks annd subsequeently both traains of the E mergency Diesel Generatorss. </P><P>Basedd on plant evvaluation, it wwas determiined that thiss condition iss reportablee pursuant too 10 CFFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), 10 CCFR 50.73(aa)(2)(v)(D), aand 10 CFRR 50.73(a)(2))(vii). </P><P>This report contains no new ccommitmentss. Please coontact John P. Jarrell, RRegulatory Assurrance Managger, at (504) 739-6685 iff you have qquestions reggarding this information. </P><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14352A449_img_1.jpg"/></Figure><P>Attachhment: Liccensee Evennt Report 2014-004-00 </P><P>W3F1-2014-0077 Page 2 </P><P>cc: Mr. Marc L. Dapas, Regional Administrator </P><L><LI><LI_Label>U.S.</LI_Label><LI_Title> NRC, Region IV 
RidsRgn4MailCenter@nrc.gov 
</LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>U.S.</LI_Label><LI_Title> NRC Project Manager for Waterford 3 Michael.Orenak@nrc.gov </LI_Title></LI><LI><LI_Label>U.S.</LI_Label><LI_Title> NRC Senior Resident Inspector for Waterford 3 Francis.Ramirez@nrc.gov Chris.Speer@nrc.gov </LI_Title></LI></L><P>Attachment to 
W3F1-2014-0077 
Licensee Event Report 2014-004-00 
</P><Table><TR><TH>NRC FORM 366 U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) (See Page 2 for required number of digits/characters for each block) </TH><TH>APPROVED BY OMB:  NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES:  01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours. Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry. Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information Collections Branch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or by internet e-mail to Infocollects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is not required to respond to, the information collection. </TH></TR><TR><TH>1. FACILITY NAME    Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station </TH><TD>2. DOCKET NUMBER 05000382 </TD><TD>3. PAGE 1 OF 5 </TD></TR><TR><TH>4. TITLE Emergency Diesel Generators Rendered Inoperable By Potential Water Intrusion Into Diesel Fuel Oil Feed Tanks </TH></TR><TR><TH>5. EVENT DATE </TH><TD>6. LER NUMBER </TD><TD>7. REPORT DATE </TD><TD>8. OTHER FACILITIES INVOLVED </TD></TR><TR><TH>MONTH </TH><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>SEQUENTIAL NUMBER </TD><TD>REV NO. </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>10 </TH><TD>22 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>2014 -004 -00 </TD><TD>12 </TD><TD>18 </TD><TD>2014 </TD><TD>FACILITY NAME </TD><TD>DOCKET NUMBER 05000 </TD></TR><TR><TH>9. OPERATING MODE </TH><TD>11. THIS REPORT IS SUBMITTED PURSUANT TO THE REQUIREMENTS OF 10 CFR §: (Check all that apply) </TD></TR><TR><TH>1</TH><TD>  20.2201(b)</TD><TD>  20.2203(a)(3)(i)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(i)(C)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(vii)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2201(d)</TD><TD>  20.2203(a)(3)(ii)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(ii)(A)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(A)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(1)</TD><TD>  20.2203(a)(4)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(ii)(B)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(viii)(B)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(i)</TD><TD>  50.36(c)(1)(i)(A)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(iii)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(ix)(A) </TD></TR><TR><TH>10. POWER LEVEL100</TH><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(ii)</TD><TD>  50.36(c)(1)(ii)(A)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(iv)(A)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(x) </TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(iii)</TD><TD>  50.36(c)(2)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(v)(A)</TD><TD>  73.71(a)(4)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(iv)</TD><TD>  50.46(a)(3)(ii)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(v)(B)</TD><TD>  73.71(a)(5)</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(v)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(i)(A)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(v)(C)</TD><TD>  OTHER</TD></TR><TR><TD>  20.2203(a)(2)(vi)</TD><TD>   50.73(a)(2)(i)(B)</TD><TD>  50.73(a)(2)(v)(D) </TD><TD>Specify in Abstract below or in NRC Form 366A </TD></TR><TR><TH>12. LICENSEE CONTACT FOR THIS LER </TH></TR><TR><TH>LICENSEE CONTACT    John Jarrell </TH><TD>TELEPHONE NUMBER (Include Area Code) 5047396685 </TD></TR><TR><TH>13. COMPLETE ONE LINE FOR EACH COMPONENT FAILURE DESCRIBED IN THIS REPORT </TH></TR><TR><TH>CAUSE </TH><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX CAUSE </TD><TD>SYSTEM </TD><TD>COMPONENT </TD><TD>MANU-FACTURER </TD><TD>REPORTABLE TO EPIX </TD></TR><TR><TH>C </TH><TD>EK </TD><TD>TK </TD><TD>B515 </TD><TD>Y </TD><TD/><TD/><TD/><TD/></TR><TR><TH>14. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT EXPECTED YES (If yes, complete 15. EXPECTED SUBMISSION DATE) NO </TH><TD>15. EXPECTED      SUBMISSION      DATE </TD><TD>MONTH </TD><TD>DAY </TD><TD>YEAR </TD></TR><TR><TD>02 </TD><TD>16 </TD><TD>2015 </TD></TR><TR><TH>ABSTRACT (Limit to 1400 spaces, i.e., approximately 15 single-spaced typewritten lines) </TH></TR><TR><TH>During a walkdown of the Emergency Diesel Generator Feed Tank A and B vent lines on October 22, 2014, an NRC Component Design Basis Inspection inspector identified corrosion on the Emergency Diesel Generator Feed Tank A and B vent lines where the vent lines pass through the roof.  A visual inspection was performed and revealed that the corrosion had created through wall holes that could allow water into both the train A and B Emergency Diesel Generator Feed Tanks. Follow up analysis has determined that some rainfall amount less than the postulated Probable Maximum Precipitation event could have resulted in water intrusion into the Emergency Diesel Generator A and B Feed Tanks that exceeds the 0.1 percent water content allowed by the vendor technical manual.  This could have potentially affected the operability of both the A and B Train Emergency Diesel Generator Feed Tanks and subsequently both trains of the Emergency Diesel Generators.  It is unknown how long this corrosion has existed. Compensatory measures were put in place to prevent water ingress should a large rainfall event occur. This condition is reportable under the following criteria: 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B), 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D), and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(vii). </TH></TR></Table><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14352A449_img_2.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET APPROVED BY OMB:  NO. 3150-0104 EXPIRES:  01/31/2017 Estimated burden per response to comply with this mandatory collection request: 80 hours.Reported lessons learned are incorporated into the licensing process and fed back to industry.Send comments regarding burden estimate to the FOIA, Privacy and Information CollectionsBranch (T-5 F53), U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Washington, DC 20555-0001, or byinternet e-mail to Infocollects.Resource@nrc.gov, and to the Desk Officer, Office of Informationand Regulatory Affairs, NEOB-10202, (3150-0104), Office of Management and Budget, Washington, DC 20503. If a means used to impose an information collection does not display a currently valid OMB control number, the NRC may not conduct or sponsor, and a person is notrequired to respond to, the information collection. 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station 05000382 YEAR SEQUENTIALNUMBER REV NO. 2 OF 5 2014 -004 -00 NARRATIVE INITIAL CONDITIONS On October 22, 2014, Waterford Steam Electric Station Unit 3 (Waterford 3) was in Mode 1 at approximately 100% power. EVENT DESCRIPTION On October 22, 2014, a walkdown of the Emergency Diesel Generator (EDG) [EK] was conducted as part of the NRC Component Design Basis Inspection (CDBI).  An NRC inspector identified corrosion on the EDG Feed Tank [DC][TK] vent lines where the vent lines pass through the roof.  Visual inspection revealed the corrosion was through wall.  It is unknown how long this corrosion has existed. Follow up analysis has determined that some amount of rainfall less than the postulated Probable Maximum Precipitation (PMP) event could have resulted in sufficient water ponding on the Reactor Auxiliary Building (RAB) [NF] roof to allow water intrusion into the EDG A and B Feed Tanks that could exceed the 0.1 percent water content allowed by the vendor technical manual.  This could have affected the operability of both the A and B Train Emergency Diesel Generator Feed Tanks and Emergency Diesel Generators. System Description: Waterford 3 is a Combustion Engineering design pressurized water reactor [AC] with two recirculating type steam generators [SG]. The EDG engines are started by means of compressed air, which is admitted to the cylinders in sequence.  The air is supplied by the starting system and is admitted to the engine through one or two air operated valves.   The valves are opened by the control system in response to either an automatic or manual control signal.  The engine will start to turn over and will accelerate under the pressure of the starting air. When sufficient engine speed is reached, fuel oil will be injected, and the engine will begin to operate as a  diesel and  will  accelerate  to a speed  at  which  the  starting  air  will  be  cut  off.    Further acceleration will bring the unit to its rated speed. The engine speed is controlled by the governor, which regulates the fuel oil supply to the engine injectors.  Fuel is pumped from the feed tank to the engine fuel headers and injector pumps by an engine driven pump.  The storage tank contains the bulk of the fuel supply, and a transfer pump automatically supplies fuel to the feed tank to maintain the level in the feed tank. Fuel is supplied to each engine by gravity flow from its feed tank.  Each feed tank is kept full by transferring oil from the fuel storage tank as required by means of the transfer pump.  The pump is started and stopped by level switches on the feed tank. Fuel from the feed tank is supplied through either of two parallel connected strainers and either of  two  parallel connected  filters  to  the  engine  fuel  oil  supply  header. Booster pumps are provided at the engine to ensure that the header pressure is sufficient for satisfactory operation of the engine at all loads. The booster pumps are of the positive displacement type, delivering a constant volume of fuel.  Surplus fuel in excess of engine load requirements is returned to the feed tank via relief valves. </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14352A449_img_3.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station 05000382 YEAR SEQUENTIALNUMBER REV NO. 3 OF 5 2014 -004 -00 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET A DC motor  driven  booster pump  is  provided  to ensure  that  as the engine  is started,  the  fuel header is primed for prompt firing as the engine speed increases.  When the speed is sufficient, an  engine  driven  pump will  develop  sufficient  head for  continued  operation  of  the  engine,  and the  DC motor  driven  pump  is automatically  shut  down.   Check valves are provided in parallel with each pump so that the fuel can flow past an idle pump. Fuel  is injected  into the  cylinders  at  the  correct  point  in the  cycle  by  cam  operated  injector  pumps,  which supply  a metered  quantity  of  fuel  to  the corresponding  injection  nozzles  on the engine.  The amount of fuel is controlled by the engine governor. The  unavoidable  leakage  from the  injectors,  caused by the  high oil pressure  and small  but necessary clearances  in  the moving  parts, is  collected  by drains and returned  by gravity  to the storage tank. Each Feed Tank has a vent and flame arrestor. TIMELINE Engineering review of the available meteorological tower data shows peak rain rates of 3.8 inches per hour have been experienced at the site in in the last two years.  Based on the follow-up evaluation, these rainfall rates could have potentially resulted ponding on the RAB roof that would allow in water ingress into the EDG Feed tanks. These rain events have been followed by successful EDG monthly tests. The monthly EDG operability surveillance is performed in accordance with Operations procedure OP-903-068.  Part of this procedure requirement is to visually inspect and drain any accumulated water from the EDG Feed Tank. Based on periodic review of the EDG surveillance date, no water has been observed or drained from the EDG Feed Tanks. REPORTABLE OCCURANCE Technical Specification (TS) 3.8.1.1 requires, in part, two separate and independent diesel generators.  This requirement is applicable in Modes 1, 2, 3, and 4.  An allowed outage time (AOT) of up to 72 hours is specified, or be in at least Hot Standby (Mode 3) within the next 6 hours and in Cold Shutdown (Mode 5) within the following 30 hours. The requirement for restoration to operable status within 72 hours may be extended to 10 days if a temporary emergency diesel generator is verified available. Additionally, the two separate and independent diesel generators will each have diesel oil feed tanks containing a minimum volume of 339 gallons of fuel, a separate diesel generator fuel oil storage tank, and a separate fuel transfer pump.  If these criteria cannot be met, operability of the remaining A.C. circuits must be tested within 1 hour and at least once per 8 hours after.  An AOT of 72 hours is specified or be in at least hot standby (Mode 3) within the next 6 hours and cold shutdown (Mode 5) within the following 30 hours.  The requirement for restoration to operable status within 72 hours may be extended to 10 days if a temporary emergency diesel generator is verified available. T.S. Surveillance Requirement (SR) 3.8.1.1.2.b requires at least once per 31 days and after each operation of the diesel where the period of operation was greater than or equal to 1 hour that accumulated water from the diesel oil feed tanks be checked for and removed. Engineering evaluated this condition and determined that rain rates within the design basis rainfall will cause ponding on the RAB roof that would potentially allow in water ingress into EDG Feed Tanks A and B. Rain rate history was reviewed and determined that peak rain rates of 3.8 inches per hour had been experienced within the last two years at the Waterford 3 site.  A rain rate of this intensity for the measured </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14352A449_img_4.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station 05000382 YEAR SEQUENTIALNUMBER REV NO. 4 OF 5 2014 -004 -00 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET duration could have resulted in a water intrusion percentage above the 0.1 percent allowed by the vendor technical manual in both the EDG A and B Feed Tanks.  If required to operate after a Design Basis rainfall event over the past 3 years both the train A and B EDGs could have been inoperable due to water intrusion into the EDG Feed Tanks through the corroded holes. This condition is reportable under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(i)(B) because the corrosion, and therefore the potential for water intrusion greater than that allowed by the vendor technical manual, has existed for longer than the AOT of the applicable TSs.  This condition is also reportable under 50.73(a)(2)(v)(D)  and 10 CFR 50.73(a)(vii)because the corrosion was found on the vent lines for both trains of EDGs. CAUSAL FACTORS An Apparent Cause Evaluation is ongoing to determine causal factors for this condition. A proposed violation of 10 CFR 50 Appendix B, Criterion 16 for failing to identify a through wall corrosion issue on both Emergency Diesel Generator Feed Tank Vents that challenged the operability of both EDGs was exited by the NRC CDBI Team.  The Engineering procedure for Systems Walkdowns provides guidance for the conduct of walkdowns of systems, components, and structural commodities.  Accessible is defined in this procedure as: capable of being inspected through pathways designed for human access, using permanently-installed ladders, platforms, and portals.  Although fall protection is required, a permanent ladder gives access to the RAB roof and walkdowns of the area could have been performed. CORRECTIVE ACTIONS As an interim action, a stainless steel pipe clamp with a rubber liner was installed around EDG Feed Tank vent pipe to prevent water intrusion.  In addition, concrete grout pads were installed upstream of each pipe to divert rain water away from the pipes.  Work packages to repair the piping are being planned and scheduled for implementation.  Follow up evaluation is also still in progress. A memo was issued to Systems Engineering re-enforcing the requirements to perform system walkdowns of all accessible areas as procedurally required. As discussed above, an Apparent Cause Evaluation is being performed and additional actions may be identified as a result of that evaluation. SAFETY SIGNIFICANCE Industrial Safety: There was no industrial safety significance associated with this issue. Radiological Safety: There was no radiological safety significance associated with this issue. Nuclear Safety: The safety significance determination is not yet completed.  Although rain rates received at the Waterford 3 site could have resulted in water intrusion into the EDG feed tanks greater than 0.1 percent as allowed in the vendor technical manual, monthly EDG surveillances have been completed satisfactorily. Safety significance will be included as a planned update to this licensee event report. SIMILAR EVENTS No similar events at Waterford 3. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION </Figure><Figure><ImageData src="images/ML14352A449_img_5.jpg"/>NRC FORM 366A U.S. NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION (02-2014) 1. FACILITY NAME 2. DOCKET 6. LER NUMBER 3. PAGE Waterford 3 Steam Electric Station 05000382 YEAR SEQUENTIALNUMBER REV NO. 5 OF 5 2014 -004 -00 NARRATIVE LICENSEE EVENT REPORT (LER) CONTINUATION SHEET Energy industry identification system (EIIS) codes and component function identifiers are identified in the text with brackets [ ]. </Figure></Part></TaggedPDF-doc>