<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<ler when="2012-09-19" id="3972012006">
   <abstract>On September 19, 2012, Energy Northwest (EN) identified that both divisions of Residual
      Heat Removal (RHR) Shutdown Cooling (SOC) Reactor Vessel isolation valves were inappropriately
      made inoperable at the same time on multiple occasions in support of maintenance and
      surveillance testing during the 2011 refueling outage (R-20). This planned inoperability of
      the SOC isolation valves was performed using procedure SOP-RHR-SDC-BYPASS. SOP-RHR-SDC-BYPASS
      contains the specific steps for preventing the closure of each of the SOC isolation valves and
      the subsequent restoration steps. SOP-RHR-SDC-BYPASS did not contain guidance to allow both
      divisions SOC isolation valves to be inoperable at the same time. Since both divisions of SOC
      isolation valves were made inoperable without procedural guidance, this is being reported as a
      condition that could have prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of systems that are
      needed to remove residual heat and to mitigate the consequences of an accident.</abstract>
   <narrative>
      <eventDesc>On September 19, 2012, Energy Northwest (EN) identified that both divisions of
         Residual Heat Removal (RHR) Shutdown Cooling (SOC) [EllS: BO] Reactor Vessel isolation
         valves [EllS: ISV] were inappropriately made inoperable at the same time on multiple
         occasions in support of maintenance and surveillance testing during the 2011 refueling
         outage (R-20). This issue was identified and entered into the Columbia Generating Station
         (Columbia) corrective action program following review of the NRC Operating Experience Smart
         Sample (OpESS) 2012/02, Revision 1. All required Technical Specification (TS) Conditions
         for inoperable primary containment isolation valves were entered when the valves were made
         inoperable, and compliance with TS Actions was maintained. No operations with a potential
         to drain the reactor vessel were in progress. Columbia was in Mode 5 with the vessel
         flooded up. During R-20, EN implemented a plant modification to change the Group 1
         containment isolation valves [EllS: ISV] isolation signal of reactor water level from level
         2 to level 1. The NRC granted permission for this change to TS in a letter dated August 18,
         2009 (TAC NO. M09598). This planned inoperability of the SOC isolation valves, in support
         of the maintenance and surveillance activities associated with the modification to change
         the isolation signal from level 2 to level 1, was performed using procedure
         SOP-RHR-SOC-BVPASS. SOP-RHR-SOC-BVPASS contains the specific steps for preventing the
         closure of each of the SOC isolation valves and the subsequent restoration steps.
         SOP-RHR-SOC-BVPASS did not contain guidance to allow both divisions of SOC isolation valves
         to be inoperable at the same time. Since both divisions of the SOC isolation valves were
         made inoperable and the approved procedure did not provide specific guidance for removal of
         both divisions at the same time, this is being reported as a condition that could have
         prevented the fulfillment of the safety function of systems that are needed to remove
         residual heat and to mitigate the consequences of an accident. This condition is reportable
         under 10 CFR 50.73(a)(2)(v)(B) and 50.73(a)(2)(v)(O).</eventDesc>
      <extentConds>An extent of condition review was performed. In the last three years, both
         divisions of RHR SOC isolation valves being inoperable at the same time was during R-20.
         There were multiple instances in which this occurred in R-20. A similar issue occurs during
         transfer of a Reactor Protection System bus. Both divisions of containment isolations
         valves for RHR SOC and Reactor Water Cleanup [EllS: CE] are made inoperable.</extentConds>
      <correctiveAction>No immediate corrective action was required.</correctiveAction>
      <eventCause>Apparent Cause: The operating crews inappropriately de-energized both divisions of
         RHR SOC isolation valves in the effort to minimize the potential for the loss of shutdown
         cooling without adequate procedural guidance.</eventCause>
      <previousEvents>This had not previously occurred at Columbia. A similar issue was discussed in
         Operating Experience Smart Sample (OpESS) 2012/02, Revision 1.</previousEvents>
      <correctiveActions>Training for Licensed Operators will be conducted on the requirement of TS
         bases 3.0.2 for intentionally entering TS Actions as identified by the Performance
         Analysis. Selected plant procedures will be revised to discuss &quot;Operational
         Convenience&quot;.</correctiveActions>
      <safetyConsequences>Each occurrence took place when the plant was in Mode 5 with the reactor
         vessel in a flooded condition. No operations with a potential to drain the vessel were in
         progress. The inoperability of the RHR SOC isolation valves was not due to equipment
         failure. If a loss of reactor level was detected, the isolation valves could be quickly
         restored to an operable condition. All required TS conditions were entered. Compliance with
         all TS actions was maintained. There was no significant impact on safety
         consequences.</safetyConsequences>
   </narrative>
</ler>
